
   
   
      
         
             Guilt by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acquisition</ENAMEX>

            When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> maker
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> announced plans to acquire a controlling share of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler Corp.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Ozick</ENAMEX> announced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> that
she would never buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> (some of whom would never buy a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> because they'd only ever buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX>) saw the issue very
differently. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last May</TIMEX>, shortly after the merger was announced, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
Bulletin carried an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Weinstein</ENAMEX> surveying the range of
opinion, particularly among <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>. The responses ran the
predictable gamut. Some agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ozick</ENAMEX>. But others, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>, took their cues from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deuteronomy</ENAMEX>, which admonishes that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fathers</ENAMEX>
shall not be put to death for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, neither shall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> be put to death
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>." "Going by that verse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>, "I cannot
blame this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>'s analogy
treats the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> that
employed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>. From a strictly legal perspective, the analogy
is inaccurate: Under the law, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> lives forever. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">controls Chrysler</ENAMEX> is exactly the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that collaborated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>,
not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendant</ENAMEX>.

            But it would be wrong to view an essentially moral question
from a strictly legal perspective. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> is not a moral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>; it's
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>'s flesh and blood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> who are moral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. From that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX>'s analogy fails in a different way: The current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> are not, by and large, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX>. Stocks trade hands <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.

            That observation seems to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strengthen Alexander</ENAMEX>'s position. If we should not punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for the sins
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, then surely we should not punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for the sins of
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countrymen</ENAMEX>. But that analysis can be definitive only to those
who believe that nothing can be added to the words of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deuteronomy</ENAMEX>; otherwise
there's more to be said.

            When is it permissible to punish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for the wrongs
of another? The question is a tangle of moral and economic issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Morally,</ENAMEX>
we're concerned with things such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>, fairness, and individual rights.
Economically, we're concerned with creating good incentives.

            To see how uncomfortable
it can be when economic and moral issues brush up against each other, consider
the revision of accident law that's been proposed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist-iconoclast</ENAMEX>-law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Friedman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> suggests that when
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> collide causing a total of, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> worth of damage, everyone who
was within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> of the accident should be required to pay a fine of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>.
That way, anyone who sees an accident about to happen will take all
cost-justified measures to prevent it (perhaps by honking furiously to warn of
impending danger). To my knowledge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s proposal has never struck anyone
as fair, but at least it gets the incentives right.

            Or does it? My own view is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> plan fails
even by its own strictly economic criteria, because it creates an incentive for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to avoid high-accident areas and take inefficiently long routes to
wherever they're going--or to cancel their trips entirely. In principle, it
could even increase the accident rate by scaring potential good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Samaritans</ENAMEX> off
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. Enforcement, of course, would be a nightmare.

            Those objections aside,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s proposal does illustrate the tension between economic and moral
considerations. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX>'s innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystanders</ENAMEX> are at least partly
analogous to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX>'s innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>. Let's keep those lessons in
the back of our minds as we revisit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DaimlerChrysler</ENAMEX> controversy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> can be punished for misdeeds in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. One is a consumer boycott and another is a (voluntary or involuntary)
fine. Both kinds of punishment have been visited on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> (though
arguably at levels that are small compared with the underlying offenses). In
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $11 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave laborers</ENAMEX>.

            Who exactly suffers from
those punishments? You might think the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> came from the pockets of
those who owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> stock in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, but that's not necessarily the
case. Suppose, for the sake of argument, that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> it becomes foreseeable
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> will eventually make reparations. Then every share of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daimler-Benz</ENAMEX> stock sold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1950 and 1980</TIMEX> sells at a discount reflecting
that expectation. Without the discount, nobody would buy the stock. So given
sufficient foresight, the prospect of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> punishment hurts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1950</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>,
even if they sell in the interim. And those who buy stocks after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> are not
punished at all, because the discount compensates them for the fine.

            Therefore, if all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are permanently on notice that
bad behavior will eventually be punished, they have an incentive to behave well
at all times. That's an outcome that seems both fair and economically
efficient: The punishment falls on the sinners and thereby deters the sin. But
here are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> caveats:

            First, even if punishment is inevitable, it falls
not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> at the time when the sin is committed, but on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> at
the time when the sin is discovered. After all, it's not till the discovery
that the stock price falls. So punishing past corporate sins is not like fining
everyone who was present when an accident occurred, but when it was reported,
which seems both unfair and pointless. But this caveat has a countercaveat: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> of future punishments gives you an incentive to investigate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>'s history before you buy, which improves the chance that bad
behavior can be uncovered while the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> can still be
punished.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, it's hard to
maintain a consumer boycott, especially when the goal is to punish the past
rather than to influence the future. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> can quite reasonably argue that
history can't be changed and so is best forgotten. As a result, corporations
have little to fear from boycotts unless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> commit themselves to
maintaining the boycotts even when they serve no purpose. It's hard to imagine
how such commitments might be maintained, which suggests that fines are more
effective than boycotts, especially if they are written into law rather than
imposed on an ad hoc basis.

            If you're looking for a firm conclusion to all this, you'll
have to look elsewhere; I hope I've at least illuminated some of the attendant
moral and economic issues--though even these can become very different in
situations that are superficially similar. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for an example.)

            And punishing evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> is very different
from punishing evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case, we punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> who
invested voluntarily, while in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> we punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> who might have
bitterly opposed their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s policies. But that is a topic for another
column.

         
      
   
