
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">167</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East/West&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fill in the blank. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Salick</ENAMEX>'s entrepreneurial ideas may play in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, but they'll never make it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Enker</ENAMEX>. "Not too
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want ____________ at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 a.m.</TIMEX>, so it's not that great a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gimmick</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               Thurs
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 166</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AC</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>?":
            

            
               Rule <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Impeachment Rules</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, "At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:30 o'clock</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>, or at such other
hour as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> may order ... the legislative and executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> shall be suspended, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> shall give notice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> ...
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is ready to proceed ... in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Chamber</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> is
prepared with accommodations for the reception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>."
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Graver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy Steyer Graver</ENAMEX> ask: What sort of
accommodations?
                
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fatal</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfa-Betty Olsen</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real-time</ENAMEX> stock market big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. 'Another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> points off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ</ENAMEX>,'
remarked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, 'and we'll nail that slick sumbitch.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
O'Grady
            

            
"Trained <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> with trays of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lengieza</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
small, dark <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> filled with the screams of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodians</ENAMEX>. Oh, no, wait.
That's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s accommodations in hell. Never mind."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            "I
don't know, but I'm sure it's a waste of my tax dollars (my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s
philosophy on everything)."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

             

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Most replies envisioned a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of corrupt,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">childish</ENAMEX>, lubricious egomaniacs--much like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Flies</ENAMEX> , but with
overt sex and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piggy</ENAMEX>.

            Or, to put it another way, perhaps the reason the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> risked in-office eroticism rather than taking her to a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is
that there is no nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. Not the right kind of nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. If we live in an
age of rampant infidelity (generally the most popular kind, by the way), it is
in spite of the failure of the free market to provide seductive accommodations.
Oh, there are hot-bed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> out near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, a lovely thing for those who
can only function sexually in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>; the waterbeds and mirrors must be a great
comfort. It's like bad pornography expressed as architecture.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, there are romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> available for
passionate afternoons well away from any flight path. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> are small, there are "love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>" in a goofy and playful variety of
styles. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> are small, there is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starbucks</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> cater to the business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traveler</ENAMEX>; there are high-resolution fax
machines but low thread-count sheets. And neither is available just for a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">languorous afternoon</TIMEX>.

            Or to put it another way,
why is there no hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX>? In their restless effort to offer the guest
simulated luxury, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> provide a sewing kit, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shampoo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> gel, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX>, a robe, and a shower cap, but no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX>. Why not? Just say you were
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> seeking a stolen hour of bliss; where would you go? Just say you were
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> who looked like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piggy</ENAMEX> and cared about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, sensual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delights</ENAMEX>, and good oral hygiene; what kind of accommodations would you
want?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>'s
Follow-Up
            

            "While
the imagination runs the gamut from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter Thompson</ENAMEX>-esque 'Ether ... and a
fax machine' to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Halen</ENAMEX>-esque 'no red M&Ms!!!!,' we are reminded of a
real memo we once read, written by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>, describing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accommodations</ENAMEX> demanded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Diller</ENAMEX> in his hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX>. 'A box of fresh
butterscotch <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candies</ENAMEX> must be present on the desk. Shake the box--you'll be able
to hear if they're fresh or not.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Graver</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Headline</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helper Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Attention business
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>: Get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> start accumulating the clichés demanded by the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> monetary system. And you general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> can get a leg up on the
stories you'll want to skip all through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Help yourself, courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EUROPEN FOR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BUSINESS</ENAMEX>: Now that the money is a different color, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> will be
able to buy a lot more things, or perhaps a lot fewer.

            
               ON A
EUROLL: With the new international money, everyone finally knows what
everything costs--it's all surprisingly affordable, apparently--and they're
buying it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EURONLY AS RICH AS</ENAMEX>
YOU FEEL: Buying stuff is making everyone happy, even when it turns
out they'd misread the price tag--they thought it was in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pesetas</NUMEX>--so now
everyone is in debt but euphoric.

            
               NO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUBLIC</ENAMEX>
EURONATION: A cold splash of reality from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ,
insisting that poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not be made to feel good at the expense of rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feeling better.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EURO, EURO, EURO</ENAMEX>
YOUR BOAT: A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are sailing those huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> trawlers up
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Atlantic</ENAMEX> to mock the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Danes</ENAMEX> for missing out on all the
shopping. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stupid Danes</ENAMEX>.

            

               ISN'T IT EUROMANTIC: It's tough to explain to the
noneconomist, but wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> turn out to have a lot of fun and some sex, as
predicted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX>. This is good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. Or perhaps
bad.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
