
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impeachment Upstaged</ENAMEX>

            The impeachment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was upstaged on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s front pages in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX>'s dramatic survival of a parliamentary censure motion, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s shock decision to end all production of nuclear energy, and
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> by fraud in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> lottery; but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> it was reported with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> pomp and circumstance.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>
dedicated its entire front page to impeachment under the headline "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 14</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> went on trial." The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , no
admirer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, made a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">deck</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> column headline out of words from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sensenbrenner</ENAMEX>: "His lies were not few or isolated but
pervaded his whole testimony." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> led with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> begins for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s survival"
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> with "Trial of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> begins."

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> to devote an editorial to the matter. This accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> of
committing a strategic error by falling into "the temptation of picking at the
witness testimony in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case," thus making it "imperative that
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> be called to testify, so that disputes on points of fact can be
resolved." It said, "The result is to undercut Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s own desperate
effort to prevent any live <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> being called."

            The editorial added that
the cross-examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> was "likely to open up a can
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX>." Few were aware, it said, that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Lewinsky</ENAMEX> received a telephone
call from Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 a.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 17, 1997</TIMEX>, suggesting that she issue
a false affidavit to pre-empt a subpoena in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit"; or that
"on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 21, 1998</TIMEX>, Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, falsely, that
Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was a 'stalker,' setting in motion the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> smear campaign
against the defenceless, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>-struck, exploited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>." The editorial concluded,
"These are little vignettes of caddishness that could start to damn the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> in the eyes of a fair-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. The longer the trial goes on,
the greater the risk that Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s famous luck will break."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera carried an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Allred</ENAMEX>,
who said that the impeachment crisis had "lacerated the women's rights
movement, which feels obliged to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> because he has raised many of
us to positions of power." She added, in reference to the throwing out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, "It is sad to note that the victory
of the supposed feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has set our movement back by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>."

            The failure of the directly elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> to pass a censure motion against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unelected</ENAMEX> executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>) over allegations of fraud and
mismanagement was condemned as a "surrender" in another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX>
editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. "Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> and the parliament
are now thoroughly discredited," it said. "They have shown themselves to be
ready to tolerate serious malpractice rather than allow the unification of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> to be impeded." Another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europhobic British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Mail , called the vote a "fiasco" and said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> had "scuttled away
from its challenge to corruption and cronyism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europhile</ENAMEX> papers
took a different view. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>, despite its
victory, had got "a bloody nose" and that the vote had been "an important round
of what may prove to be a long struggle." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Parliament</ENAMEX> must now try
"to become more than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">terrier</ENAMEX> snapping at the heels of policymakers: it can
become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">guard dog</ENAMEX> with a respected bark." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> called the vote
"a political earthquake" with which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Parliament</ENAMEX> had finally
"justified its existence." Nothing will ever be the same again, it said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavisimaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> nuclear power industry had a very difficult year in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. Strikes
by power <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> because they received no wages and a general slackening of
labor discipline in the industry caused a rise in accidents, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.
All in all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">102</ENAMEX> nuclear power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> "malfunctions" were recorded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> more than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), and there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> unscheduled power shut-offs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
(compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>). The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> injured in nuclear
power accidents fell from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38 to 20 last year</TIMEX>, of which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> died--compared with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two the year before</TIMEX>. "Still, this doesn't give any grounds for optimism since
one power <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> has already been killed since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 1999</TIMEX>," the paper
said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, the semi-official press has been busy
denying "misrepresentation" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wanted Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> ousted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. "For <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> to criticize the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> ... does not at all mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> is
inciting the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to overthrow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. That would violate a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cardinal</ENAMEX> principle of its policy which is characterized by transparency and
avoidance of behind-the-scenes conspiracies and maneuvers," the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> evening
paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Mesaa</ENAMEX> said.

            The leading semi-official
daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Ahram</ENAMEX>
said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the attacks some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had made
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> will not deter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> from standing by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and trying to prevent further <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> "cannot accept
any new aggression against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> ... and cannot accept the principle of external
interference in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s affairs whatever regime it may have, especially when
that intervention lacks any international cover or consensus."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> Le <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> 's editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was devoted to the financial
crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, which it said had not merely brought a premature end to
"europhoria" about the new single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency but had "destabilized an
international financial system which was just beginning to recover from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> crises." On the same theme, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>
warned that the world economy has yet to feel the knock-on effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s
traumatic devaluation. "Don't loosen your safety belts yet," it said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s best-selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloid</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , announced as a front-page "world exclusive" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friday</ENAMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> model <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Hall</ENAMEX> has started divorce proceedings against aging rock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">star Mick Jagger</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. She has "ignored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mick</ENAMEX>'s please
for forgiveness" over his affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciana Giminez Morad</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

             

         
      
   
