
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">175</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Dis Incentive&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "This is a horrible thing that's going on," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Spinney</ENAMEX>. "All
it's going to do is reward the pathological behavior that created the problem."
What's going on?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 174</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Odd Lott</ENAMEX>":
            

            
               You be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decorator</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> keynote speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> said: "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> stand for the right principles and the right philosophy.
Let's take it in the right direction and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>." Describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Descriptions</ENAMEX> are not permitted because they would violate the sacred oath of
Klan secrecy."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Crimmins</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">padded</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> biblical quote away from declaring itself a sovereign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Terns</ENAMEX>
            

            "Filled
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who stand up for what they believe in no matter the cost, and so
who in protest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> reluctantly canceled their subscriptions to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barely Legal</ENAMEX> ."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Geer</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "He was
told it stood for 'North <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Married Brotherhood League of America</ENAMEX>.'
Really."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Anderson</ENAMEX>
            

            "Oh,
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>'s sake! Just because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> addresses a few white-supremacist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, is that any reason to harp on and on about it? Why, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> addressed the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>! Or, anyway, he would have, if he'd been a
race-baiting, knuckle-dragging reactionary."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Andrew "Pink curtains</ENAMEX>!"
Solovay
            

             

             

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Devoted to metaphors of field and stream, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
won't shoot sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> in a barrel. Good jokes surprise you, and
what's an unpredictable comment about racism: that it's bad? Perhaps the task
is not to shoot the sitting duck but to sneak up on it, loop a rope around its
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">webbed feet</NUMEX>, hang it upside down, and hit it with a stick until it bursts
apart, raining toys and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> cavorting below--something surprising
yet delightfully violent.

            And what if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>
piñata dropped <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX>, spit, and tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX>, the artifacts of debased
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> culture? Would the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX> be <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX>, or are they fair game for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>
scorn? Fire away, but only if you wrote your reply between acts at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>, after laying down your edition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>. If you
composed your response within eyesight of a TV set or a slice of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>, it's
time to reconsider your sense of regional superiority and just go fishing.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabastard</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sorry</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alabaster Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> gave the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> keynote speech to the national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Conservative Citizens</ENAMEX>, the retro-successor to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klannish White Citizens Councils</ENAMEX>. Despite frequent appearances at its
meetings and photographs of him smiling with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> persistently
denies any association with the "pro-white" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.

            And after a hard day of lying and racism, then
what?

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> likes order, neatness, things in their
place. So he has developed little routines, one of which is this: When he
arrives home from work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each evening</TIMEX>, he drops his briefcase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> upstairs to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>, and changes into his <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton pajamas</ENAMEX>. Then he bounds back down the
steps to have dinner with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tricia</ENAMEX>," writes a cheerfully nonjudgmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Merida</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thanks to Kate Wing</ENAMEX>.)

            Or to put it another way,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capable</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Attractive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> inquires: Why does every black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who
ever shook hands with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> have to apologize, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> is
walking around free? In his pajamas?

            
               Sweatless
Extra
            

            Garment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and human
rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> filed suit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, charging that
their clothing is manufactured in appalling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saipan</ENAMEX> sweatshops. But apparently
it was all a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">merry mix-up</ENAMEX>, judging by the response of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
involved.

            THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAP</ENAMEX> "does not tolerate this type of conduct in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> where we do business." I'm convinced.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WAL-MART</ENAMEX> has a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>-tolerance position with regard
to illegal or unethical working conditions." Good enough for me.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.C. PENNEY</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saipan</ENAMEX> offers a "consistently
reliable source of reasonably priced, high-quality fashion items for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer customers</ENAMEX>." I'm sorry I doubted them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TOMMY HILFIGER</ENAMEX> said,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music</ENAMEX> is my strongest inspiration, and I feel that it encompasses the true
style of fashion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stones</ENAMEX> are the greatest rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in the world,
and I cannot think of another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who have made such an impact on
the world of fashion. Departing from my past ad campaigns, the rock pictorials
portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> who are fresh, young, and all-American, in a cutting edge, high
energy, and modern environment." This may refer to a slightly different aspect
of his operation, but any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mick</ENAMEX>'s ...

            Other undoubtedly
innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> named in the suit--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Merchandising Corp.</ENAMEX>, Cutter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">&</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dress Barn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gymboree Manufacturing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Crew</ENAMEX>, Jones
Apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane Bryant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Limited</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May Department Stores Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstrom</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OshKosh B'Gosh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears Roebuck & Co.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warnaco</ENAMEX>.

            
               Cell Phone
Finals--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anecdotal Evidence Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Light, inexpensive, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contemptible</ENAMEX>, the cell phone inspires stories, sneers, and songs, except for
the songs.

            "Recently in a university
lecture I was giving, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in the front row got a call on his cell phone,
and took the call, letting the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> wait and stare at him while he
chatted with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan E. Snow</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max-Planck-Institut</ENAMEX> für
Chemie

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing</ENAMEX> in the wine
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> of my local market, I listened to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> call someone in the meat
department (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 10 yards</NUMEX> away) to check on whether she should buy white or
red. Why have a face to face conversation when you can exist as a disembodied
voice on their remote answering service? The only plus about cell phones is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> they make their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> look like the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who shuffle around
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> talking to themselves."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            "I am befuddled by those
who think that the public use of a cell phone is a status symbol. Rather, a
cell phone is a device of convenience, clear and simple. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Folks</ENAMEX> who ascribe more
importance to it than that are the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are for more
than driving, vacations are for more than relaxing, and clothes are for more
than wearing. What I find interesting is this: Those who think that cell phones
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> cans with an invisible string are those who want others to
see them with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vuitton</ENAMEX> bag on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> as they slide into the buttery
leather of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Range Rover</ENAMEX> on the way to that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vail</ENAMEX> getaway. Give it a rest,
Mr. and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insecure</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Spencer</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Race
Results
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> junk
culture.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
