
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">182</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Reign Delay&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Out of deference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> postponed something
until after he left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> and returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. What?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 181</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sit Up</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cheer</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  "This is great news for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who are not
getting enough physical activity," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Lenfant</ENAMEX>. What
is?
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>-loathing burns as many calories as running."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Hammocks on sale at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IKEA</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>
            

            "Meals
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wheels</ENAMEX> now delivering not just to the elderly and infirm but also to the
merely indolent."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Advance word from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Louis</ENAMEX> speech: Heaven's dropped the chin-up
entrance requirement!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Milner</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global</ENAMEX>
warming. 'It's like a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sauna</ENAMEX>.' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"-- Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is rehiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joycelyn Elders</ENAMEX> ."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay D. Majors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hostess</ENAMEX> cupcakes come when you call them."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Vance</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            While many of you made fat jokes, sedentary is not
synonymous with portly. It can also mean frail, although it is tougher to mock
the weak and physically ineffectual, unless you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leni Riefenstahl</ENAMEX> or an
old-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gym teacher</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, all sports were square and right-wing, unless
you considered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frisbee</ENAMEX> a sport instead of its traditional designation,
"nuisance." There were exceptions: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Edwards</ENAMEX> inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> track stars
to raise the black power fist at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mexico City Olympics</ENAMEX>. But the contemporary
meaning of athletics was reiterated on every <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hope</ENAMEX> TV special, when he
trotted out a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herd</ENAMEX> of college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> to boost the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.

            Now there are hip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>--snowboarders, sullen
teen skateboarders, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rollerbladers</ENAMEX>, dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bikers</ENAMEX>--fighting for public space
across barriers of age, class, and hairstyle. This is not merely the triumph of
individual over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> sports. Figure skating and gymnastics remain square; just
listen to the music, if you dare.

            It's easy to overstate the new athletics as a force
for social change, but don't count on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> opposing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ludicrous</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>-revival anti-missile plan. And while mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> and rock
climbing are terrific, they've already been appropriated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> as mass market
rather than mass movement.

            If sports hasn't turned
into progressive politics, at least it has been demilitarized, rejecting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boot</ENAMEX> camp model of recreation, and that means more fun for more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Not so
bad. So if you want me, I'll be on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX>, pedaling past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leni Riefenstahl</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>, tossing rocks. See if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s Star Wars system can block that.

            
               Take <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Easy</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

suggest that performing "lifestyle" exercise--raking <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX>, climbing
stairs--can improve heart and lung fitness as much as a vigorous workout. The
studies (noncontroversial, nonpolitical, and in no way intended to affect the
impeachment process) found that while moderate exercise does not burn many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">calories</ENAMEX>, it is beneficial to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who spend most of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> sitting.

            
               What Is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>"
Extra
            

            Fun with pronouns. Match
each ambiguous "it" with its antecedent.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> buys it, so
what, and if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> doesn't buy it, so what?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maryann Keller</ENAMEX>, easygoing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ING Baring</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> The farm

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. ING Baring</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX> brokerage

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. Volvo</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "If it can prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> from being maimed, disfigured, or killed, it will
serve its purpose."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Roche</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Hiring</ENAMEX> more police

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Hiring</ENAMEX> even more police

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> A proposed "dangerous
dog" law

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "It's perky, it's
active, it's eating."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Wharton</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Maryann Keller</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Insert</ENAMEX> your own sex joke here

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> A female, thick-billed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parrot</ENAMEX>, the only animal ever stolen (and just recovered) from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Zoo</ENAMEX>

            

               Answers
            

            
               1-C,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-C, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3-C</NUMEX>.
            

            
               Race
Results
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remote</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>.

            
               For <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Dancing</ENAMEX>
Pleasure
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Feb. 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen Week</ENAMEX> begins at the
online site of the humor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McSweeney's</ENAMEX> , featuring pieces from the out of print
Diary of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Flying Man</ENAMEX> .

            Open fires prohibited
without proper permit.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
