
   
   
      
         
            War and Pieces

            No movie in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX>
has succeeded in psyching out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> as fully as the powerful,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rambling</ENAMEX> war epic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Thin Red Line</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Malick</ENAMEX>'s return to cinema
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>. I've sat through it twice and am still trying to sort out my
responses, which run from awe to mockery and back. Like Saving Private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> , the picture wallops you in the gut with brilliant, splattery battle
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">montages</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goyaesque</ENAMEX> images of hell on earth. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malick</ENAMEX>, a certified
intellectual and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchonesque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> who directed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Badlands</ENAMEX> and
Days 
               of 
               Heaven in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> and then disappeared, is in a
different philosophical universe from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>. Post-carnage, his
sundry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> philosophize about their experiences in drowsy, runic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>-overs that come at you like slow bean balls: "Why does nature vie with
itself? ... Is there an avenging power in nature, not one power but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>?" Or
"This great evil: Where's it come from? What <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX>, what root did it grow from?
Who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doin</ENAMEX>' this? Who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killin</ENAMEX>' us, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robbin</ENAMEX>' us of life and light?" First you
get walloped with viscera, then you get beaned by blather.

            Those existential
speculations don't derive from the screenplay's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, an archetypal but
otherwise down-to-earth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Jones</ENAMEX> (who also wrote From Here
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eternity</ENAMEX> ) about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> invasion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> island of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadalcanal</ENAMEX>. They're central to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malick</ENAMEX>'s vision of the story, however, and not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specious</ENAMEX>. In the combat genre, the phrase "war is hell" usually means nothing
more than that it's a bummer to lose a limb or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, or to see your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> get
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> blown off. A true work of art owes us more than literal horrors, and
Malick obliges by making his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> of war the setting for nothing less than a
meditation on the existence of God.

            He tells the story solemnly, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parts, with a
big-deal cast (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Penn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Nolte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX>) and a few other major stars
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Harrelson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX>) dropping by for cameos. After
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edenic</ENAMEX> prelude, in which a boyishly idealistic absent without leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pvt. Witt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Caviezel</ENAMEX>), swims with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> to the accompaniment of a
heavenly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part sees the arrival of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> forces
on the island, introduces the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (none of whom amounts to a
genuine protagonist), and lays out the movie's geographical and philosophical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrain</ENAMEX>. The centerpiece--the fighting--goes on for over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> and features
the most frantic and harrowing sequences, chiefly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s initially
unsuccessful frontal assault on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> hilltop bunker. The coda lasts
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 minutes</TIMEX> and is mostly talk and cleanup, the rhythms growing more
relaxed until a final, incongruous spasm of violence--whereupon the surviving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> pack their gear and motor off to another <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> battle. In the
final shot, a twisted tree grows on the waterline of the beach, the cycle of
life beginning anew.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thin Red</ENAMEX>
Line has a curious sound-scape, as the noise of battle frequently recedes
to make room for interior monologues and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Zimmer</ENAMEX>'s bump-bump, minimalist
New Age music. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pvt. Bell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Chaplin</ENAMEX>) talks to his curvy, redheaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
viewed in deliriously sensual flashbacks. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love:</ENAMEX> Where does it come from? Who
lit this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX> in us?") Lt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte</ENAMEX>), a borderline lunatic passed over
one too many times for promotion and itching to win a battle no matter what the
human cost, worries groggily about how his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> perceive him. The dreamer Witt
poses folksy questions about whether we're all a part of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big soul. If the
movie has a spine, it's his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>and-on dialogue with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sgt. Welsh</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX>), who's
increasingly irritated by the private's beatific, almost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Budd</ENAMEX>-like
optimism. Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welsh</ENAMEX>, "In this world, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> himself is nothin', and there ain't
no world but this one." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Replies Witt</ENAMEX>, high cheekbones glinting, "I seen another
world." At first it seems as if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witt</ENAMEX> will indeed be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Budd</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vindictive Claggart</ENAMEX>. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witt</ENAMEX> is ultimately an ethereal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> turns
out to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX>-like romantic who can't stop feeling pain in the face of an
absent God. He speaks the movie's epitaph, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darkness</ENAMEX> and light, strife and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">love: Are</ENAMEX> they the workings of one mind, the feature of the same face? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soul</ENAMEX>, let me be in you now. Look out through my eyes. Look out at the things
you made, all things shining."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malick</ENAMEX> puts a lot of shining things on the screen:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX>, parrots, bats, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX>, visions of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX> by way of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> and of the Fall by way of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malick</ENAMEX>'s conception
of consciousness distributes it among the animate and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inanimate</ENAMEX> alike; almost
every object is held up for rapturous contemplation. I could cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
images: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> in a rocking boat hovers over a letter he's writing, which is
crammed from top to bottom and side to side with script. (You don't know the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, but you can feel in an instant his need to cram everything in.) A small,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">white-bearded Melanesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> strolls nonchalantly past a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon</ENAMEX> of tensely
trudging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grunts</ENAMEX> who can't believe they're encountering this instead of a
hail of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> shots bring down the first pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> to
advance on the hill; a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> later, the sun plays mystically over the tall,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yellow</ENAMEX> grass that has swallowed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Toll</ENAMEX>'s camera rushes in on a
captured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garrison</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> shrieks; another, skeletal,
laughs and laughs; a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> weeps over a dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comrade</ENAMEX>. The face of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier encased</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> speaks from the dead, "Are you righteous? Know that I
was, too."

            Whether or not these pearllike epiphanies are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strung</ENAMEX> is another matter. Malick throws out his overarching theme--is
nature <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-sided, at war with itself?--in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first few minutes</TIMEX> but, for all
his startling juxtapositions, he never dramatizes it with anything approaching
the clarity of, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian De Palma</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Casualties of War</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>). Besides
the dialogue between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Witt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Thin Red Line</ENAMEX> 's other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizing</ENAMEX> story involves a wrenching tug of war between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambition-crazed Tall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Staros</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elias Koteas</ENAMEX>), who refuses an order to
send his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on what will surely be a suicidal--and futile--assault on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bunker</ENAMEX>. But matters of cause and effect don't really interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malick</ENAMEX>.
Individual acts of conscience can and do save lives, and heroism can win a war
or a battle, he acknowledges. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Staros</ENAMEX> is ultimately sent packing, and Malick
never bothers to trace the effect of his action on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Guadalcanal</ENAMEX> operation.
In fact, the entire battle seems to take place in a crazed void. Tall quotes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>'s "rosy-fingered dawn" and orders a meaningless bombardment to "buck the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> up--it'll look like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japs</ENAMEX> are catching hell." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> shoot at hazy
figures, unsure whether they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men collide</ENAMEX>, blow
themselves in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> with their own mishandled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">grenades</ENAMEX>, stab themselves
frantically with morphine needles, shove cigarettes up their noses to keep the
stench of the dying and the dead at bay. A tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>, mortally wounded,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flutters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malick</ENAMEX> is convincing--at
times overwhelming--on the subject of chaos. It's when he tries to ruminate on
order that he gets gummed up, retreating to one of his gaseous multiple
mouthpieces: "Where is it that we were together? Who is it that I lived with?
Walked with? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. ... One mind." I think I'd have an
easier time with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malick</ENAMEX>'s metaphysical speculations if I had a sense of some
concomitant geopolitical ones--central to any larger musings on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of
nature as viewed through the prism of war. Couldn't it be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> fascist orders were profoundly anti-natural, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Allies</ENAMEX>'
cause was part of a violent but natural correction? You don't have to buy into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincolnesque</ENAMEX> pieties in Saving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> to believe that
there's a difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> (or, for that matter,
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and the invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grenada</ENAMEX> or our spats with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>). While he was
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malick</ENAMEX> might have peeled himself off the lap of his pointy-headed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mentor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Cavell</ENAMEX>, the philosopher and film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>, and checked out a
few of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Waltzer</ENAMEX>'s lectures on just and unjust wars. Maybe then he'd view
Guadalcanal not in an absurdist vacuum (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> come, they kill and are
killed, they leave) but in the larger context of a war that was among the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rational</ENAMEX> (in its aims, if not its methods) fought in the last several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>. For all his visionary filmmaking, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malick's Zen</ENAMEX> neutrality sometimes
seems like a cultivated--and pretentious--brand of fatuousness.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>'s empty nightclub impersonation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in Primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colors</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>) had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> positive result: It gave him a
jump-start on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Schlichtmann</ENAMEX>, the reckless personal injury <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center of A Civil Action</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travolta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlichtmann</ENAMEX> is much more redolent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: slick and selfish and corrupt in lots of ways but basically on the
side of the angels, too proud and arrogant to change tactics when all is
certainly lost. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Schlichtmann</ENAMEX> pursued--and more or less blew--a civil liability
case against the corporate giants <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.R. Grace</ENAMEX> over the allegedly
carcinogenic water supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woburn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass. Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Harr</ENAMEX>, in the
book the movie is based on, went beyond the poison in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Woburn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> to evoke
(stopping just short of libel) the poison of the civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, where platoons
of overpaid corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> can drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> with pockets less deep and
psyches less stable into bankruptcy and hysteria.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zaillian's</ENAMEX> version doesn't capture the mounting rage that one experiences while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reading Harr</ENAMEX>'s book, or even the juicy legal machinations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford</ENAMEX>
Coppola giddily manipulated in his underrated adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>'s
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainmaker</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Civil Action</ENAMEX> is a sturdy piece of
work, an old-fashioned conversion narrative with some high-tech zip.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlichtmann</ENAMEX> doesn't take this "orphan" case--brought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>--because he wants to do good but because he
figures that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrice</ENAMEX> will fork over huge sums of money to keep the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> from testifying publicly about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX>. He might
succeed, too, if it weren't for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome Facher</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Duvall</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who knows how to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlichtmann</ENAMEX> shadowboxing while his small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
financial resources dwindle to nothing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zaillian</ENAMEX> is at his most assured when he cuts back and forth
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Facher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law School</ENAMEX> lectures on what not to do in court
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlichtmann</ENAMEX>'s fumbling prosecution. The sequence has the extra dimension
of good journalism: It dramatizes and comments simultaneously. Plus, it gives
Duvall a splendid platform for impish understatement. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX> has become more
fun to watch than just about anyone in movies.) Elsewhere, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zaillian</ENAMEX> takes a
more surface approach, sticking to legal minutiae and rarely digging for the
deeper evil. As in his Searching for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Fischer</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), the outcome
of every scene is predictable, but how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zaillian</ENAMEX> gets from beat to beat is
surprisingly fresh. He also gets sterling bit performances from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sydney Pollack</ENAMEX>
as the spookily sanguine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William H. Macy</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlichtmann</ENAMEX>'s rabbity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accountant</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Quinlan</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Quinlan</ENAMEX>
knows that when you're playing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who has lost a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you don't need to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emote</ENAMEX>--you reveal the emotion by trying not to emote.

            To the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woburn</ENAMEX> tragedy, the
real climax of this story isn't the downbeat ending of the book or the sleight
movie. The climax is the publication of a book that takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' side
and that remains on the best-seller list in hardcover and paperback for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
The climax is the movie starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatrice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace</ENAMEX> made out OK
legally, but some of us will never use their products again without thinking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about Travolta</TIMEX> losing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> in the name of those wasted-away little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
