
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sewers Need</ENAMEX>
Cleaning
            

            In his article "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> attempts to show
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should not be removed from office. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unwittingly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> has
provided the most compelling argument why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> must be removed.

            Let us concede for the moment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s point that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> were at least as corrupt as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. (I think sincere people
can differ, but let's make the assumption for the sake of argument.) According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has had an unbroken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 18 years</TIMEX>. That being the case, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> should give some thought to
how we might end this plague of corruption. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s solution is to look the
other way <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time !

            Perhaps the corruption
persists because it is so consistently condoned?

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett G. Farr Albuquerque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M.</ENAMEX>

            
               It's Not the
Cover-Up. It's the Sex!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>'s article "" is elegant in its
explanation of why he wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> impeached. Mainly, it's because he is
disgusted by the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> representing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some months ago</TIMEX>, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "," he wrote about how much he respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was a
"civil, serious, dedicated, judicious, and highly intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> also did "not feel I have the wisdom and moral elevation to [judge
him]."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s different
reactions make it clear why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is so hated--it was not the perjury or the
laws of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It was the sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s refusal to admit his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indiscretions</ENAMEX> in front of everyone. Such self-righteousness--and the
willingness to cover it up in statements about the rule of law and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>--appalls me as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lust.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viswanath Subramanian Cupertino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               Save It for the
Ballot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>'s article
"He Has To Go" asks, "Is this the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I want to represent ..." I couldn't help
but wonder whether he had ever wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. I actually did and do want this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>--that's why I voted for him twice. I suspect this is just the sort of
question the technique of electing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> was designed to answer.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Augenblick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidency</ENAMEX>
Isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Popularity Contest</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Stein</ENAMEX>'s article "He Has To Go" illustrates
the fuzzy thinking surrounding the impeachment proceedings. I'm sorry that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> cannot decide whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> was generated by a
wish to divert the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. I am sorry that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> is distressed by the sight of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s distress is not, however,
an impeachable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> nor is his perception, even if accurate, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
unable to lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and the world. Leadership ability is an issue for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">electorate</ENAMEX>, which has spoken on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> occasions regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and which will
speak again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> (through votes, not polls).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> must keep its
focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> and not on such amorphous standards as
"embarrassment," "reckless personal behavior," or "inability to lead." Thank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goodness Stein</ENAMEX> didn't include "setting a bad example for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>" among
the high crimes and misdemeanors that would warrant the removal of an elected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> from office.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles A. Trainum Jr. Fredericksburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>

            
               Cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forest</ENAMEX>,
Not the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trees</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" has a very selective interest in
spending of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31, 1998</TIMEX>, column frets that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> wasted money rescuing some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who were ballooning around the world. Not fretting because they were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rescued</ENAMEX>, but fretting because they are rich. Also, those who tilt a bit to the
left have worried a lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slick Willie</ENAMEX> investigation.

            Put it all in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>. The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $3 million</NUMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day of the year</TIMEX>. Why not concern yourself with that startling number
rather than worry about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in a hot air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloon</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> full of hot
air such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? You should tame the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class warrior</ENAMEX>" tendencies that color
your commentary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W.R. Lewis Mandeville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La.</ENAMEX>

            
               Get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Bookie</ENAMEX>,
Perhaps?
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 29, 1998</TIMEX>, ""
column says:

            
               In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where betting is legal, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lists some of the "unusual bets for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX>" accepted
by a leading bookmaker. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hill</ENAMEX> has offered odds of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-to-1</NUMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> would announce divorce proceedings during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20-to-1</NUMEX> that
the controversial "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium Dome</ENAMEX>" would be scrapped, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100-to-1</NUMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> would marry his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>' former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nanny</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiggy Legge-Bourke</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million-to-1</NUMEX> that the world would end in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.
            

            Exactly how would an
individual betting on the end of the world go about collecting their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">winnings</ENAMEX>?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould Kokomo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ind.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
