
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trial</ENAMEX>

            

               Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth Time</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Charm</ENAMEX>?
            

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> open the prosecution of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the real obstacle they face is not the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> or
the dismal poll numbers. It is redundancy. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s exhibition marks, by my
count, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> official presentation of the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ninth</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than three months</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> recounting of the same story, same
evidence, same charges. (The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> are, in chronological order: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the supporting documents, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Schippers</ENAMEX>' opening
presentation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s testimony to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Schippers' closing presentation, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s final report,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s presentation to the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) the briefs filed this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>.)

            Fortunately for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> co-managers, they have a captive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. No matter how bored they may
be, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> will sit silently and listen (or at least pretend to) for
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three day</TIMEX> opening argument. The guidelines for senatorial conduct
distributed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> make it very clear that perfect attendance and good
behavior are required of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>.

            After the opening prayer--only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> does a
chaplain thank God for guiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to unity "in matters of
procedure"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> takes to the podium in the well of the chamber. His opening
lines strike one of the main themes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>: bald-faced flattery of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> have criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> for being too pushy, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyde & Co.</ENAMEX> are in full lickspittle mode. "We want you to know how much we
respect you as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> says. Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asa Hutchinson</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, slobbers that he knows the case will be settled fairly because "I
believe in you. I have faith in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Senate</ENAMEX>."

            Most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>'s brief statement addresses the
sanctity of the judicial oath, a favorite subject of his. He recounts the story
of Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas More</ENAMEX>, who chose to be beheaded rather than swear an oath he did
not believe. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beheading</ENAMEX>--that's a novel alternative punishment .) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> also
introduces his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and recites their legal credentials. The most
remarkable fact here is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> advocate
general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX>--that is, they were military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. Military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are
tougher on adulterers than are civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, making me wonder whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ex-JAGs</ENAMEX> may be inclined to judge the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> more sternly than other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sensenbrenner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>, follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> to
the podium for an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourlong</TIMEX> outline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>' case. It soon becomes
clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX> has chosen to embrace the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX>-time problem rather
than flee from it. Instead of trying to dazzle the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> with something
new--which would be impossible because there isn't anything new--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>
are practicing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> water torture method of prosecution. Beat them
senseless with repetition. Sensenbrenner plods through the points everyone has
heard <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> times already. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is above the law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s perjury in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case--"a civil rights lawsuit"!--undermined the judicial
system. (Sensenbrenner mysteriously insists on calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> have been impeached for grand jury perjury, so is there going
to be one law for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and one for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? Perjury is a high crime
because it is as bad as bribery. The judicial oath is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. There is a "<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in the body politic," e pluribus unum , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, etc.

            Sensenbrenner, who has a stupendous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> accent
and a tiny, pinched voice that sounds silly in such a beefy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, does not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dazzle</ENAMEX>. A cloud of fatigue settles on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Del.</ENAMEX>, issues the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> yawn. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Graham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, soon follows.
The few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> who are taking notes stop. During a break, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Stevens</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, "I'm taking these antibiotics. It's tough as hell to
stay awake." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fritz Hollings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX>, is wearing sunglasses--no doubt for
a medical reason--but he could be in full snooze for all anyone knows.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Bryant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, then offers a chronology of
the case. It is just as familiar and soporific as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensenbrenner</ENAMEX>'s presentation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> is succeeded, mercifully, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, who argues the case for
obstruction of justice. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> considered and rejected the
idea of trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> removed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> on the grounds that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> serves in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> may be regretting their
mistake. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asa Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, who may be the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> who emerges from
Flytrap with his reputation polished, is superb. He has a warm voice,
persuasive manner, and a gift for one-liners. (When he describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
spent late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> and early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> desperately trying to ensure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">silence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> mocks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s current fave phrase, "The president
had some time to work. That work was not 'the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.' "

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX>'s case for obstruction of justice is
frightfully cogent. He carefully explains how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spurred witness <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to lie, coached potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> to lie, found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
a job in exchange for a false affidavit, got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to conceal
gifts, and deceived <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podesta</ENAMEX> so that they would lie
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. His chronology of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> cover-up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1997</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX> is by far the best account of that so far. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> begs the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> to confirm his obstruction of justice claims, and
after a presentation this good, I can't imagine that too many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will
resist his pleas.

            I leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> just
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Rogan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, begins the final argument of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. Outside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> I am accosted by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>: "Tell everyone you know to face
God <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> times." Unfortunately, she's wrong. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> will be presenting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two more days</TIMEX>.

            
               Illustration on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table of Contents</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Stamaty</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
