
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Payback
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX> plays a
hard-boiled bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> intent on recovering some stolen money in this adaptation
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Stark</ENAMEX>'s novel The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX> (which was also the basis for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boorman</ENAMEX>'s acclaimed modern noir <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Point Blank</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>). This version is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Confidential</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Helgeland</ENAMEX>, and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pan</ENAMEX> it: "The film is utterly devoid of narrative ingenuity and visual and
dramatic flair. ... What one word might best describe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payback</ENAMEX> ? How about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Loathsome</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Complaints: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The
violence is over the top: "Watching it is like riding a roller coaster through
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat grinder</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> is too chipper for a noir <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>: "[H]e's like a
chipmunk with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith & Wesson</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> calls it "inflated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocket Books</ENAMEX> pulp." A small cadre, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, praise the movie
as a sort of film noir parody. (Check out the official site, and read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review .)

            
               
                  Simply
Irresistible
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). Negative reviews for
this Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chocolate</ENAMEX> -style magical food romance. Buffy the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Michelle Gellar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> in love and in
trouble. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> blast the sappy romance as well as the "dismayingly formulaic
view of enchantment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX> is signified by levitating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> à la <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>
Poppins , playing wind-chimes on the soundtrack or flooding a scene with dry
ice" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> (who manages to
work the odd sexual euphemism "the old rumpy-pumpy" into his review for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>) defends the movie as fun fluff: "The movie is as
light as a soufflé, as fleeting as a breath of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pumpkin pie</ENAMEX> on the breeze from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>'s window" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). (This fan
site has loads of pictures of the lovely Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gellar</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Rushmore
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> lavish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Anderson</ENAMEX> and co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Wilson</ENAMEX> (who performed similar duties
on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bottle Rocket</ENAMEX> ) with praise for their film about a bright but
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">underachieving</ENAMEX> high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misfit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Schwartzman</ENAMEX>) who ends up competing
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Murray</ENAMEX> for the affection of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>: "an exuberantly original
comedy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> has won several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' awards for his performance, but now that the film is in general
release (it had a brief run in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> to qualify for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>), a
few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissenters</ENAMEX> have surfaced, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenstern</ENAMEX> and 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>, who says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
"spend a lot of time patting themselves on the back for being aggressively
unconventional." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> a clip from the movie here and read
the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review .)

            
               
                  Dry
Cleaning
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strand Releasing</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> farce
remarkably tame and wonder if an industry known for its cheerful sex romps has
lost its edge. The story follows a bourgeois small-town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> with a dry
cleaning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> whose lives are turned upside down after a young drag
performer they meet in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> ends up moving in with them. This sounds like
racy stuff, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the story has the "structure and implacable
momentum of a stern moral fable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) and is
more interested in dissecting the slow tragedy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s disintegrating
marriage than in high jinks. (Find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miou</ENAMEX>-Miou
here.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Werewolves</ENAMEX> in
Their Youth
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Chabon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinite Jest</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talent</ENAMEX> is its own expectation. ... You
either live up to it or it waves a hankie, receding forever," and many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> seem to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hankie</ENAMEX> waving here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> wonder who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> ago
wowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mysteries</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> . As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Gorra</ENAMEX>
says in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Books Review</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promising</ENAMEX> is still the word
I'd choose" to describe this collection, "but after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> books
that adjective has to seem a disappointment." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say that despite a few
outstanding exceptions, most of the collection is overly self-conscious and
marked by stories that start out interesting but end up failing when Chabon
ties them all up too neatly at the end. (Read an excerpt courtesy of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> [free registration required].)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  You're a Good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ambassador Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broadway</ENAMEX>'s
revival of this amateur-theater staple gets solid reviews and a few performers
get all-out raves, most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Chenoweth</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Brown</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">describes Chenoweth</ENAMEX>'s performance as "perfection" and says that after the show
he wanted "to wrap her in tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and take her home" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> );
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> describes her performance as "one of those break-out performances
that send careers skyward" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say
several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> aren't up to portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but that those who
succeed make the whole show worthwhile. (Find out about show times and ticket
prices here; you can get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shockwave</ENAMEX> animations of various
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanuts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> here.)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  She's All That ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">24 Hour Woman</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Still <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- My Name Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Mothers Didn't Tell Us: Why Happiness</ENAMEX>
Eludes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Woman</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Crittenden</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabelle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Strout</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heavy Water</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie
                  --
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --
                  Playing by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another Day</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stahl</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Face-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Tarloff</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Miss Nobody , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomek Tryzna</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Varsity Blues</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- At First Sight</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- In Dreams</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duane</ENAMEX>'s Depressed , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry McMurtry</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intuitionist</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colson Whitehead</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Fosse: A Celebration in Song and Dance</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadhurst Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Affliction ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hi-Lo Country</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> Era , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Weinstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Vassiliev</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --Note <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Found in a Bottle: My Life</ENAMEX> as a Drinker , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Cheever</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glamorama</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bret Easton Ellis</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
