
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta: &quot</ENAMEX>;It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All Dick Morris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fault&quot</ENAMEX>;

            In an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Panetta</ENAMEX>, the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>, lashed out at former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> and blamed him squarely for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s troubles. Asked if impeachment had
been avoidable, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX> replied, "Of course. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> needed to do was to
tell the truth at once, instead of listening to the advice of his
double-crossing ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX>, immediately after the
scandal exploded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, who explained to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> would never
forgive him for his escapades with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>. I had warned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from the
beginning about the bad influence of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who cares only about opinion
polls, bends with the wind of the moment, and doesn't give a damn about moral
and political principles."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
in a state of enormous anxiety because "he knows he has damaged the historical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inheritance</ENAMEX>, which he valued more than anything else." His mental equilibrium
is preserved by his powers of work and concentration, and his ability "to
separate problems into categories, choosing which drawer to open at a time. ...
But grief and rage are eating his liver out," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panetta</ENAMEX> said. In reply to a
question about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, he said that she is "such an inexhaustible source of
inner strength that it was unthinkable to imagine that she could abandon him
just at this most crucial moment." He added, "Nobody knows how the crisis may
have affected their marriage: but those who know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> well know that
she is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of great strength, with very broad shoulders."

            The same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Wynette</ENAMEX> qualities cannot be credited to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ex-wife of British Foreign</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX>, who left her to marry his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>. In a new book serialized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Cook</ENAMEX> excoriates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> as a serial adulterer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>, and drunk. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s
best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , made the most of the scandal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with
a front-page headline asking "Would YOU sleep with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?"--complete with
phone numbers that allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to offer a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yes" or "No</ENAMEX>" response. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX>
is, frankly, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX>," it said. "He has been likened in the past to a
garden gnome and even a prawn. ... And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> would dearly love to know
the secret of his pulling power." But in an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> said he
should not be fired because "he performed well over the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and has
built up a solid relationship with his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> opposite number <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> are owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, who was condemned Monday
in an editorial in the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> for "intrusion into the sad, sorry lives
of others." It said, "An uncomfortable pattern is beginning to emerge. ... In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News International</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> on alert, whether
by 'outing' [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Brown</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> of the
World or dishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Cook</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> . In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> runs (later disproved) hokum about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> love-child, as if doing its bit to drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> concluded that "perhaps it's time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> was held to account--not for his private life, as he insists on
doing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, but for the poisoning of public life across the globe."
In another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> newspaper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rees-Mogg</ENAMEX> wrote an
op-ed piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> comparing the cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>. "Cast both stories
as novels, and ask what is the core of the plot," he wrote. "A mature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is
married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who is a perpetual adolescent; he is clever and good with
words, but lacks a sense of self-worth, and relieves his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> with
recurrent affairs of varying importance."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, back from
vacation to try to weld together his fractured and scandal-riven <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
was mocked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas</TIMEX> issue of the satirical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Eye</ENAMEX> for
publishing so many articles in newspapers. Under the spoof headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> wins
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Journalist of the Year' Award</ENAMEX>," it wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> had
"presented himself with the award for writing the greatest number of articles
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>." The trend continued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, not only in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> but also abroad. There was a piece in a recent Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> about the launch of the euro, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more
--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> leading the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish News</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>, one
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lib√</ENAMEX>©ration
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, and one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stampa of Turin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> (the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> defending <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s participation
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>).

            In a front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Stampa</ENAMEX> editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Biancheri</ENAMEX>, took issue with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> and
claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s part in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> bombing "had above all the function of
covering up what would have otherwise been an excessively visible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
isolation." He wrote, "To pretend that this was done to strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and faith in its credibility is frankly to expect too much
of our credulity."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> devoted a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> page to the alleged role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNSCOM</ENAMEX> as "a toy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> espionage
services" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and carried a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> about the "decisive" role
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in eavesdropping on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> itself, the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> led Monday
with a report that former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshe Arens</ENAMEX>, who appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> as his top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, has
decided to stand against his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prot√</ENAMEX>©g√© for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud</ENAMEX>
Party and as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> elections. He made the
decision after commissioning his own opinion poll, which showed that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
has a credibility problem with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud Party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who
will vote in the primaries."

             

         
      
   
