
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religious Persecution</ENAMEX>

            The chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> national soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> amid huge controversy over his
eccentric religious beliefs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Hoddle</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who steered the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> team
to failure in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> in an
interview that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled people</ENAMEX> were disabled because of things they had done
wrong in previous lives. This created political uproar and sharply divided the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press about whether or not he should be allowed to keep his job. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Football Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>'s ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, fired him after he refused to sever
connections with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eileen Drewery</ENAMEX>, a faith healer.

            In an editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoddle</ENAMEX> had to go because "he had failed to
separate his rights of free speech from his duties as one of the most
influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in a game with vast influence over the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>." But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> criticized his dismissal, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoddle</ENAMEX>'s views on the
disabled were shared by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhists</ENAMEX> around the world. The
story was big across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, especially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> papers, which ran it on
their front pages. "Fired for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karma</ENAMEX>" was the headline in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>,
which said he was perhaps the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> th year
to lose his job for his religious convictions.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> reported on its front page
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MI6</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> external espionage service, was having to
consider withdrawing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> identified him as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hurran</ENAMEX>, whose
cover had been acting as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX>, was exposed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIS</ENAMEX>, after he made a written complaint about the head
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karel Vulterin</ENAMEX>, who was fired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as a
result.

            "The letter that led to
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vulterin</ENAMEX>'s dismissal is believed to have followed leaks from within the BIS
revealing a successful MI6 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s leading spymaster in the
region defected to the West," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> said. This was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jabir Salim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
Mukhabarrat operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>, who disappeared before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>,
telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> needed
urgent medical treatment in neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>. An interesting revelation in
the report was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intelligence services, which previously
excluded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> for security reasons, no longer see them as a risk if they
are open about their sexuality.

            There was anger in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> over suggestions in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> might now need <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> "protection" against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> or other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, who might seek to exploit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> to destabilize
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> was quoted in the pan-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab Al Hayat</ENAMEX> as saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
does not sense any danger threatening its security or stability from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> or
any other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> "has always been and continues to be capable
of defending itself against any threat regardless of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> or
objective."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as saying that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the ruling
coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> decided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> there is no constitutional prohibition
against private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> transporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, munitions and military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> in emergency situations around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>." This cleared a major hurdle in
the revision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> defense cooperation
agreement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestia</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on a ruling by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional Court</ENAMEX> that nobody should be
sentenced to death again until all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are guaranteed the right to trial
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. But the paper commented that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> might decide that, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s current economic circumstances, it is too expensive to provide juries
to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and that therefore capital punishment should be
banned altogether.

             

         
      
   
