
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Drawing upon her rich experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions about manners, personal relations, politics, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prudence</ENAMEX>@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please
indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably including your
location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I recently got
married and wonder if there's a "correct" answer to the following question: How
should our address labels read? I think it should be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s name <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>,
e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Stevenson</ENAMEX>." But my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> thinks it should be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s
name <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Stevenson</ENAMEX>." Who's "right"? Thank
you.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mic</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prudie</ENAMEX> checked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, on your
behalf. Here is the response (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is trying to keep a straight face as
she writes): There is no label etiquette because ... well, labels are beneath
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> acceptability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stationery</ENAMEX> , however, can be "Mr. and Mrs.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">" And</ENAMEX> to
quote the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>: "It usually stops fights if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s name is
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>."

            As for your own
situation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX> dilemma, why don't you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sets of
labels printed? They are inexpensive, after all, and that way you can each
affix what you consider the "right" label to a letter.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, compromisingly

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hey,</ENAMEX>
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Stop the presses! of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yours</ENAMEX> complained about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">waitress</ENAMEX> writing in a "suggested" <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17.5 percent</NUMEX> tip, about which he was ticked.
He will be thrilled to know that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Fishbein, has sued an eatery ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo & Maxie</ENAMEX>'s") for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX> for
holding him hostage when he refused to pay the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18 percent</NUMEX> service charge added
to his bill. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fishbein</ENAMEX> refused to pay its idea of a gratuity because he found
the management "rude and obnoxious" to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Affairs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fishbein</ENAMEX> has a shot at
winning the suit because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> are allowed to add a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> charge for
parties larger than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> is told in advance--but the surcharge
is limited to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX>.
            

            
               Thought you'd like to
know the latest.
            

            

               --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hands Clapping</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>,

            Prudie, like you, is
watching these developments with fascination. Perhaps, if successful, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fishbein</ENAMEX> might take the 
                  Slate
                staff to dinner--and you, too, of
course.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, mischievously

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Perhaps you backed down a bit too quickly with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> regarding the "" silliness. This offends almost as much as that other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">staple</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How are you?</ENAMEX>"--my retort to which is usually "Do you have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an</TIMEX>
hour<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
            

            
               How am I? Well,
perhaps you wish to hear about my problems, but I don't think so. I find such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linguistic</ENAMEX> tics simply sloppy semantics.
            

            

               --Careful in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, carefully
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Care</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is grateful for your linguistic support,
though on the question of what is required by the question "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How are you?</ENAMEX>" she
is more forgiving. Perhaps because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> taught her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How</ENAMEX>
are you?" is a greeting, not a question.

            To respect your
feelings, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would not mind if, the next time you are asked the
irritating query, you begin a recital of exactly how you are--no details
spared. And do let us all know how many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> elapse before your
conversational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> makes a getaway.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, tellingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I have had it with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talking into their fists and mumbling up their sleeves. All these calls
on the hoof can't be that important. Plus, they interrupt innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystanders</ENAMEX>.
Is there an accepted etiquette for the mobile phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and anything the
rest of us can do about them?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anti-Cell Phone Annie</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Ant</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, there is no etiquette, per se, regarding cell
phones, though some high-end <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> have tagged them verboten .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is noticing that concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> now have printed
announcements requiring their restriction, as well. Little by little, various
establishments are making house rules.

            As for what the rest of
us might do about them, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is afraid the answer is: not much. A cross look
of disapproval is always worth a try. The best hope of integrating this
technological "advance" into society is to hope that those so important they
cannot be out of telephonic touch will themselves arrive at some feeling of
mobilesse oblige. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is somewhat hopeful on this score, having recently
seen some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> phonies remove themselves to the sidelines, as it were, at the
ring of the bell. She has even seen an apologetic smile or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> as these people
get the call. We will hope for the best.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, wishfully

         
      
   
