
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I am a bit confused
by your answer to "," 
               who was seeking advice about a gentleman
preceding a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> into a public place. When exiting a building it is very easy
for a gent to both precede the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and hold the door for her because outside
doors swing out. However, when entering a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, the outward swinging door
makes both holding and preceding an awkward maneuver--at least in my
experience. Is there a technique to gracefully precede a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and hold the door
for her that I am unaware of? Thanks.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Awkward</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Paul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Awk</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is having trouble
following the movement of all these doors. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is not even sure there is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> protocol for the way doors swing. To be perfectly candid, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does
not really care, finding this bit of politesse rather inconsequential. Just do
what feels comfortable.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, permissively

            
               
                  Dear
Prudence
               ,

            
               As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>, I take issue with your response
to "." 
               I find your evaluation that she is wonderfully clear-eyed about
her situation way off base. While shifting to a position of no sex may well be
a good starting point and help restore some needed self-esteem, if she
continues to think that the problem is with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> she is attracted to then
she will never get to the root of things.
            

            
               Sooner or later she's
going to have to investigate the "whys" within herself for her attraction to
them. What will eventually arise is a confrontation of her own availability for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intimacy</ENAMEX>, which she never has to examine as long as these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are
"unavailable." They are not the problem, just symptoms.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
            

            
               -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. David Forbes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M.D.</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Standardsville, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thanks you for
expanding on her answer, as she is always deferential to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, humbly

            
               
                  Dear
Pru,
               
            

            
               Although we've lived in a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> for
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX> now, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>-in-law have failed to visit, even for a quick
look-see (despite a welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX> that is always unfurled for them). Several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>, we were informed that they were going to eat dinner at a restaurant
ACROSS THE STREET from our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. When we invited them to come over for a
quick post-dinner visit, they begged off.
            

            
               Quite often, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>-in-law invite us to their abode and expect us to make the trip. In
light of their unwillingness to extend themselves, is it appropriate to just
stop going?
            

            
               Thanks,
            

            

               --HRUMPH
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear HRUM</ENAMEX>,

            There is some little missing piece here. Your
relationship is apparently good enough for the beloved's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to invite you
both to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, but they are unwilling to come to yours--and a new place
they've never seen, yet.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is wrinkling her
forehead wondering what's the deal. You (or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX>) might
flat out ask what is their aversion to being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>. You might even add that
you are developing hurt feelings about this. If the answer is evasive, or a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonstarter</ENAMEX> ... such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, we're just happier having you come over here,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes you will respond with the following: "We have decided that we're
going to alternate visits. Seems like it's your turn to pay us a call." If they
still won't cross your threshold, you have a problem that likely will be
the forerunner to estrangement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks you'll survive.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, wonderingly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Love your column and
the advice; never tried the white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> remedy for (hmmm ... perhaps an instance
of throwing good after bad?). But the one antidote I will swear by is club
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX>. Twice in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 15 months</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have spilled <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a glass</NUMEX> of red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> on
my light tan carpet, and both times I accessed an unopened bottle of club soda
(any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brand</ENAMEX> will do) and several towels. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Voilà</ENAMEX>! Wine gone, no stain.
Guaranteed to work. If I could bottle it myself and sell it I'd be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">millionaire</ENAMEX>, but since it's already on the market, the advice is free.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorri A.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Lor</ENAMEX>,

            But of course . Why
didn't Prudie think of that? <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Club soda</ENAMEX> is the wonder cure for stains but
perhaps most effectively at the time of the calamity. Our last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, with the
Persian rug, was alas trying for a remedy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> after the spill. If you do
decide to bottle club <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorri</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Stain Remover</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> will not
breathe a word.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, spotlessly

         
      
   
