
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintometer</ENAMEX>:
            

            

               
                  2/8/99
                The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX> and defense deliver
closing arguments, but everyone agrees that neither impeachment article will
get the requisite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> votes, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> think the perjury article won't
get even a majority. Speculation turns to whether: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>
will be able to filibuster a post-trial censure resolution to death; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> committed perjury when he denied peddling nasty
stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to the press. The naive scenario: Rather than let
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> escape unpunished, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will prolong the trial to subpoena more
testimony about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>. The sophisticated scenario: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will escape
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unpunished</ENAMEX> and, in his stead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> will be prosecuted afterward.
Chance of removal from office: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zero</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               For the complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintometer</ENAMEX> and links to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's Flytrap
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">coverage,</ENAMEX> click .
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s King
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> has gone home to die . He left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayo Clinic</ENAMEX> after his body
rejected a bone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow transplant</ENAMEX> (to stave off <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>) and his organs began to
fail. Now that everyone realizes how ill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> was when he recently dumped
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> and replaced him with his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marveling</ENAMEX> in retrospect at the king's decisiveness, resolve, and composure.
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are rushing to suck up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>. The old spin: Is he
competent to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and will he maintain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s role as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
peace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX>? The new spin: Of course. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/5/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
 <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Williams</ENAMEX> decided to rehire a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> who had
resigned for using the word "niggardly." The word means "stingy" and is
unrelated to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> word," but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had misunderstood it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Howard</ENAMEX>, had then resigned, saying his use of the word was insensitive;
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> had accepted his resignation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> now says he "acted too
hastily." The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bravo</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> for admitting his error and refusing
to bow to ignorance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> should take a less visible job because his
rapport with black city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> is crippled. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> says the episode was
"really not about me or the use of the word niggardly. ... It was about
feelings underneath the surface. ... I used to think it would be great if we
could all be colorblind. That's naive, especially for a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Shut
up and take the job. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/5/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> rebuked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> for running a cover story on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The profile, while essentially positive, dwells on a negative context:
how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal is stressing out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> and affecting her personal
life (e.g., the headline is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grace Under Fire</ENAMEX>: An intimate look at the deep
bond of love that sustains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> women through their painful family
ordeal"). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> reportedly tried to spike the story on security
grounds, then condemned it as an invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX>'s privacy. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> are good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who are trying to protect their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
They're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocrites</ENAMEX>, since they've used <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> and other popular
magazines for publicity about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> when it suits them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> game because she's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> and a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The article was nice
to her. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Well, at any rate, it could have been a lot meaner.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/5/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presented his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> budget . Highlights: a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.3 percent</NUMEX> spending
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hike</ENAMEX>, offset by an even greater revenue hike (thanks to economic growth),
leaving a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$117 billion</NUMEX> surplus. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposes to set aside <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> of
surpluses over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 15 years</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> wants an across
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> tax cut, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposes smaller targeted tax breaks (e.g., for
long-term health care) instead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> calls his budget "progressive but
prudent." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> calls it more big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Editorial spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
should be applauded for spending less and saving more than the "big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">critique</ENAMEX> admits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are right that he's using the surplus to avoid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjusting Social Security</ENAMEX> taxes and benefits so the program will remain
solvent. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) But their tax cut would only make things worse. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/3/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
An <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> jury
ordered anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$107 million</NUMEX> in damages for
running a Web site that tracks the murders of abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. The site,
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Nuremberg Files</ENAMEX>," identifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby butchers</ENAMEX>") in the
format of a "most wanted" list, along with their home addresses, license plate
numbers, and the names of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' names are
crossed out as they are murdered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' spin: The site is "a hit list
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>" and is also intended to scare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> out of the business. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>' spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> doesn't explicitly advocate violence against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and the damage award violates the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> look
forward to an ultimate resolution in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/3/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D-Mo.</ENAMEX>, decided not to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
Instead, he will campaign for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in the hope that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will recapture the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and he will become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. This leaves
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, alone against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. The
official spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> is sacrificing his ambition for the good of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.
The unofficial spin: He smells <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who have antagonized
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> by crusading for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment. The unspoken
spin: He's getting whipped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> in the polls. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/3/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX> apologized for saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> must be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> . At a
prayer breakfast, he said, "I apologize to my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> here and around
the world and I apologize to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> here for having created any kind of
rift. ... I apologize not for what I believe, but for my lack of tact and
judgment in making a statement that served no purpose whatsoever." The spins:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semite</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) No, the only reason he had said the Antichrist
must be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is supposed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resemble Jesus</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> had nothing to apologize for other than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insensitivity</ENAMEX>--another triumph of political correctness. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) If resemblance to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> were the only issue, why didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> must be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">carpenter</ENAMEX>? (For more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Falwell Antichrist</ENAMEX> flap, see in

                  Slate
               .) ( <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/3/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> say
they have found the source of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> . They traced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX>, the virus that has
caused most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> epidemic, to a related virus carried by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
chimpanzee subspecies. They theorize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> contracted the virus by
hunting these chimps and handling their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) By studying how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chimps</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> or immune system defeat the related virus, we can learn how to
defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) By tracing the virus's journey from chimps to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>,
we can learn how to recognize dangerous viruses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> and prevent another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-type epidemic. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) We'd better move fast before <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> and meat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> finish slaughtering the chimps in question. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/1/99</NUMEX>) 
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> won their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> straight <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>, beating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Falcons</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34-19</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Elway</ENAMEX>, who passed for
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">336 yards</NUMEX> and ran for a touchdown to put the game away. The goat was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX>
safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Robinson</ENAMEX>, who was arrested <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before the game for
allegedly trying to buy oral sex from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>. Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> mercilessly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scrutinized Robinson</ENAMEX>'s errors in the game (notably, getting burned on an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>
yard touchdown pass) and partly blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX>' sloppy performance (several
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">muffed</ENAMEX> touchdown opportunities and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">second-half</TIMEX> turnovers) on the attendant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dismay</ENAMEX> and distraction. The runner-up goat was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Reeves</ENAMEX>, whose
defeat at the hands of his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elway</ENAMEX>) and an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> he
fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Shanahan</ENAMEX>), made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Reeves 0-4</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>. The postgame hype revolves around whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elway</ENAMEX> will attempt a
"threepeat" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> or will retire on top as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> did.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/1/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Family-values
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activist Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> announced he would form an exploratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to
run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The political spin is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>: He lacks experience in elected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and is too conservative for most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> (he plans to make anti-abortion legislation a cornerstone of his
campaign), but he will have plenty of diehard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caucus</ENAMEX>-goers from the religious right. The media spin is that his announcement
illustrates how long-shot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> milk attention by dragging out their
announcements. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> hinted at his candidacy in speeches, then announced he
was taking a leave of absence from his job, then set up an "announcement"
interview on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , then persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to write preview
stories about the TV announcement--all before he had even filed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> to
set up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that would set up his eventual campaign.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times punished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s milking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> by publishing a follow-up story
about how he milked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/1/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> has offered a huge
bounty to any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> who shoots down a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>,
according to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. The reward for downing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dinars</ENAMEX>, with a bonus of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 million dinars</NUMEX> for capturing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>. This is only
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,000</NUMEX>, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> terms it is a fortune. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/1/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
