
   
   
      
         
            

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintometer</ENAMEX> is back. Click for the latest update.
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incoming House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> confessed to adultery . "I have on occasion
strayed from my marriage," he said. Roll Call broke the story (there are
rumors it may have come through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> spilled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to head off the story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s spins:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) "I sought marriage and spiritual counseling and have received forgiveness
from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "I was running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, not sainthood." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
"These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indiscretions</ENAMEX> were not with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) "I have never
been asked to testify under oath about them." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) "To avoid harm to others," he
won't say more. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> working together with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>" are out to get
all us <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) "I will not be intimidated." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> gleefully
anticipated that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> would exploit the story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
impeachment debate. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> embraced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>, said his case is
different from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s, and suggested that the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>, who are leaking nasty stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/18/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> continued to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> . Military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">briefers</ENAMEX> say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> at
weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. The international debate is over whether the attack was
justified. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX>
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pawn and demanded his resignation, but nobody seems angry enough
about the attack to make a serious effort to stop it. The prevailing view is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> may not achieve success in disarming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, but diplomacy had
definitely achieved failure. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/18/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
began debating impeachment . The chief controversy is whether the
impeachment vote and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> bombing should be going on simultaneously.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> for bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> just when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> was about to begin
the impeachment debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> blame <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for beginning the
impeachment debate just after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> began the bombing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> is taking the brunt of editorial criticism for questioning the
bombing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s motives. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> impugns the other's integrity and
patriotism while calling the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> shamelessly cynical for impugning its
own integrity and patriotism. For a roundup of the spins, see

                  Slate
               's "" on the latest "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX> the dog" charges.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/18/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wye</ENAMEX> peace agreement is collapsing . First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> halted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s promised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troop</ENAMEX> withdrawals from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> violence. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> went to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX>, supervised the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>' annulment of their
charter language calling for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s destruction, and urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> to
resume troop withdrawals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> refused, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
must take further steps against terrorism and renounce their aspirations to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">statehood</ENAMEX>. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> says that if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> fails to endorse his
policies by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, he will call new elections. The opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX>,
which accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> of trying to kill the peace process, welcomed the
opportunity to get rid of him. The idealistic spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> wants the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> to accept his conditions so peace can go forward. The cynical
spin: He wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> to reject his conditions so he can posture
against them in the election. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/16/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawton</ENAMEX>
Chiles, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, died at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>. He had a heart attack while working out on his
exercise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX>, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> before he was to turn over his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to
Gov.-elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeb Bush</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant governor</ENAMEX>, who lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, gets to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in the interim. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> lauded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiles</ENAMEX>' civility and efforts on
behalf of the environment, fiscal responsibility, and public accountability.
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo Udall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, died at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's disease</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> applauded his "liberal conscience" in the face of conservative
public opinion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Higginbotham Jr.</ENAMEX> died at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> after a stroke.
He was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most accomplished black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> spoke
approvingly of his "unambiguous liberalism," his stalwart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downtrodden</ENAMEX>, and his attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/16/98</NUMEX>)
            

            
Pundits debated
the fallout from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s latest lobbying
and testimony before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lies are offensive. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' charges are excessive. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> refuse to admit
anything that could put him in legal jeopardy. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Duh. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) The pro-impeachment
closing argument: The rule of law is at stake. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) The anti-impeachment closing
argument: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> is at stake. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) Impeachment is excessive, so vote
instead for censure. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) Impeachment without conviction is censure. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>)
Impeachment is too serious to treat as censure. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>) Impeachment is only a vote
for a trial. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) A trial would be too awful because it would paralyze the
government and force the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to delve into sexual details. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>) The
impeachment juggernaut is good because it has scared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> into
embracing heavy censure. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>) Impeachment is good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> because it
would hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> more than it would hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will persuade
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> not to impeach him because they both care more about their own skins
than about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. (For more on a possible escape route for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> see,
"" in 
                  Slate
               . (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/14/98</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
