
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">165</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Whine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Bottle&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI Special Agent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Scafidi</ENAMEX> says, "Everybody gets freaked. You shut down the operation. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perp</ENAMEX> got his kick. This is just the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> version."
            

            

               What new thing is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> version of what old thing?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 164</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX>!":
            

            
               "My joy is that
we're still in business and we're alive."
            

            

               Who said this about what?
            

            "A bus
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX>, about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic City</ENAMEX> run."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> pharmacy first identified as a 'missile silo.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
Star (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ballard</ENAMEX> )

            "Rebbe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schneerson</ENAMEX> said it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, because he was feeling
so goooooood."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Efron</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>, forced by inclement weather to abandon his attempt to
become the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to circumnavigate the globe riding on the back of an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Poniewozik</ENAMEX>
            

            "Oh, so
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have said this, giving too little thought to how their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
would survive without them should fate intervene. And that's why I wanted to
talk to you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about life insurance."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Just to see someone with a capacity for joy is my
own personal joy. It's a word that seldom appears in public unaccompanied by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Procter & Gamble</ENAMEX> logo. My immediate cause for seasonal joy: "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> in
Review" stories, particularly that classic slab of reheated journalistic hash,
the list of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top News Stories</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>." There's perspective to be gained
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perusing Yahoo</ENAMEX>'s list, which slots in at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">No. 9</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Hartman Killed</ENAMEX>." I'm sure
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Africa</ENAMEX> would mourn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartman</ENAMEX>'s death,
were they not distracted by the deaths of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) or themselves.
I'm also filled with joy to learn that more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get their news from
the Internet. Wait, sorry: Someone's filled with something, but it's not me and
it's not joy.

            Of course, the
interesting detail--interesting in the sense of causing shrieking head pain--is
not the trivial poop that's included (the deaths of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda McCartney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Sosa</ENAMEX> due to an overdose of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>, if I read correctly--and
I don't) but what's excluded. Make up your own list; find your own bottle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tylenol</ENAMEX>; I'll be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> swilling down a bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX>.

            
               Why Her Service?
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reporter Helen Thomas</ENAMEX> reflects on her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Press International</ENAMEX>.

            The once powerful news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, whose principal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheik Walkid al-Ibrahim</ENAMEX>, a brother-in-law of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>, has just named its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnaud de Borchgrave</ENAMEX>.
Formerly of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sun Myung Moon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> , he
plans to take the floundering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPI</ENAMEX> "upscale." He'll have to, suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, who calls UPI a "sclerotic, corrupted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>"
staffed by "tired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPI</ENAMEX> currently employs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-tenth</NUMEX> of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> stringers. It has lost
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120 million</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX>.

            
               Last Minute
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            In much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> world there are indeed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days of Christmas</TIMEX>. And if, like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>, your list of imaginative gifts fades
around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 3</TIMEX>, you might consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston Presents</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> ,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> videocassettes filmed on location at the actual sites of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Testament</ENAMEX> action, as advertised on television.

            Tell me more about this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> delight, you'd probably reply if online technology were not in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infancy</ENAMEX>. I'm happy to, in convenient Q & A form, with all A's taken
verbatim from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>'s infomercial.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>: Are they pretty
good stories?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>: There simply are no
greater stories to tell.

            NQ: How does it feel to
watch these tapes?

            Photogenic blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>: I
actually felt like I was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">River Jordan</ENAMEX>.

            NQ: What about younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>? Did they find the experience similarly disorienting?

            Some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>,
they seemed to be enthralled!

            NQ: Was it possible the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were--how can I put it?--smelly, lethargic, and incoherent?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>: Let's do it!

            NQ: And the cost?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Announcer</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Just two</TIMEX>
payments of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29.99</NUMEX>, plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.99</NUMEX> for shipping and handling, which to the slow
witted sounds remarkably like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29.99</NUMEX>, but it's not!

            But wait, there's more.
Order now, or at any other time, and receive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston Presents</ENAMEX> the
Word , a video reading of many psalms--moving, profound, and in the public
domain. [I paraphrase ever so slightly.]

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Operators</ENAMEX> are standing by,
presumably poking one another in the ribs and smirking. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">537-7887</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX>:
Let's do it!

            
               Last Minute
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shopping Extra No. 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courtesy of Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            Why not download the
Ready
Rooster coloring book, and learn that sometimes it's good to be a
chicken.

            "When I
get too jaded by living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, I always find it refreshing to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deere</ENAMEX>, where I realize I can't identify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the implements featured on the
page."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">K.W.</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
