
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">183</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Three Times To&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               The answer, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s counterterrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>, is: "To extort
us, to intimidate us, to get us to abandon our foreign policy."
            

            

               What's the question?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 182</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reign Delay":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               Out of deference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> postponed something
until after he left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> and returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. What?
            

            "The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> running of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutherans</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Consoli</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hug a</ENAMEX>
Married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Strauss</ENAMEX>
            

            "
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Margaret Sanger Night</ENAMEX>' at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hooters</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Spiegel</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "An
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-male production of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ Superstar</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
execution of triple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darrell Mease</ENAMEX>, via (in a delicious twist!)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crucifixion</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Barth</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Hypocrisy is the homage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> pays to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC Standards</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Practices</ENAMEX>. That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Rochefoucauld</ENAMEX> said about the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX> show
when the generic air crash joke <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> told at the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 p.m.</TIMEX> taping turned sour
by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the 12:30 a.m.</TIMEX> broadcast, due to an actual air disaster around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>: "But
if it was now wrong to mock the charred remains of the dead, surely it was
wrong <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX>, and would still be wrong a week hence when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> resumed
airline ridicule. And if it were in fact an honorable joke, then why not tell
it any time?"

            Another scenario. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> drops by for dinner
on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster banquet</ENAMEX>, you change the menu--not
because there's anything discreditable about eating sea and sty, but as a
matter of tact. You're not having it both ways; you're being considerate.

            Test case. A condemned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is having his last <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">meal</TIMEX>, trayf , on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">747</NUMEX>. His seat-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> is a
religious personage. The No. 2 engine flames out. You be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>: What do
you announce over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> in the form of a maxim.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delayed Is</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Divine Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            The rapid pace of religious life has outdistanced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX>. When the question was posted, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> had just said he'd
wait to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darrell Mease</ENAMEX> until the pope left the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, postponing the
execution, originally set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX> as part of the papal welcoming ceremony
(or perhaps not; I've misplaced my program), until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX>.

            After prolonged pontifical exposure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carnahan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commuted Mease</ENAMEX>'s sentence to life imprisonment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> assured
disappointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> that he will execute other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: "I continue to
support capital punishment, but after careful consideration of [the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s]
direct and personal appeal and because of a deep and abiding respect for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pontiff</ENAMEX> and all that he represents, I decided <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to grant his
request."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> has executed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> since the death
penalty was reinstated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have killed more. Under
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> law, a death sentence may be commuted if someone really famous speaks
up for the condemned. (Or perhaps not, I've misplaced my copy of the penal
code.)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A day</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s
departure, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> put another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to death.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Minute</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Valentine's Day</TIMEX>, rather than the too familiar
tokens of love--<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>, betrayal, recriminations--why not order your
gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Country Supply Inc.</ENAMEX>
Some lovely items from its mail-order catalog:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COWBOY MAGIC</ENAMEX>. Instantly breaks down <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> and unwanted matter without
damaging hair. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.98</NUMEX>--I believe that was the title and plot summary of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s first play. And all the rest of them. Except for the part about
"without damaging."

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MUCK MASTER</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.25</NUMEX>--If it's half the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> it could be, you'd
better have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STUD CHAIN</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>" training <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>" wide swivel eye. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.50</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> step
in the training: Stop swiveling that eye, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buster</ENAMEX>.

               THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULTIMATE CORDURA PAD</ENAMEX>. On the bottom is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a quarter inch</NUMEX> layer of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orthopedic</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Absorb-Felt</ENAMEX>" for its ability to hold up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times its weight in
moisture. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36.95</NUMEX>--His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> say after a hard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>'s caucusing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX> has the same ability.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CHICAGO SCREWS</ENAMEX>. Keep a package in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>, and a spare
package in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.39</NUMEX>--For that special single entendre someone.

               Various saddles are available, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRAIRIE ROPER</ENAMEX>, THE RAMBLER, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOLDEN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLEASURE</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COUNTRY PLEASURE</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$289-$569</NUMEX>--I believe "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Country Pleasure</ENAMEX>" was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> handle, back when he was a long-haul <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trucker</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABLE TRAINING</ENAMEX> NOSEBAND WITH <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEADSTALL</ENAMEX>. This effective device is designed
to apply pressure to the ... poll and nose. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.50</NUMEX>--I say if it's that much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hassle</ENAMEX>, you can do without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PROFESSIONAL NIPPERS</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.80</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PROFESSIONAL CLINCHER</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27.90</NUMEX>)--Call me
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">square</ENAMEX>, but I think paying for nipping and clinching degrades everyone
involved.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LEATHER BREEDING HOBBLE</ENAMEX>. This professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hobble</ENAMEX> is designed for the
serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeder</ENAMEX>. Fully adjustable and comes with panic snaps and pulley system.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84.95</NUMEX>--And you'd be nuts to mess around with a pulley system without the panic
snaps.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIG RED APPLE</ENAMEX>. Cuts down on stall boredom,
cribbing, weaving, and chewing. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12.90</NUMEX>--You order that leather breeding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hobble</ENAMEX>,
you can forget about stall boredom.

            

            
               Race Results: What
We Know About <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Show Me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Branson</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. The arch

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX>

            
               For <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Listening</ENAMEX>
Enjoyment
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen Week</ENAMEX> begins
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at the online site of the humor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McSweeney's</ENAMEX> , featuring stories
from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary of a Flying Man</ENAMEX> , a collection published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX> and
currently sold only by street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
