
   
   
      
         
             My <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Son</ENAMEX>, the Antichrist

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anti</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defamation League</ENAMEX>
is hopping mad at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX> for his speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingsport</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, where he told a gathering of prophecy-heeding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is "probably" alive and, as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">full-grown counterfeit of Christ</ENAMEX>," is
without a doubt a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADL</ENAMEX> said the remarks were typical of "an
especially vicious tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> theological anti-Judaism."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>? It does sound bad, especially given the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000 year</TIMEX> history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
persecution by cranky <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>. The speech was also confusing to longtime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Falwell buffs</ENAMEX> and those of us who have watery knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revelation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Testament</ENAMEX> text that causes all this prophecy hubbub. Isn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> a longtime "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>"? Then why is he making anti-Semitic
comments? And does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revelation</ENAMEX> really say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> must be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>?

            The answers: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Yes, he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) In his
mind and heart, he wasn't making an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> comment. As for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), it's
difficult to say whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, because there's no mention
of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Revelation</ENAMEX>, though there is mention of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beast</ENAMEX> whose number
is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">666</NUMEX>, who is presumed to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>. The word "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Antichrist</ENAMEX>" is
mentioned in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX>, but
in prophecy matters he's a "premillennialist," which simply means he thinks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mankind</ENAMEX> is living in a time prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand year</TIMEX> period of
peace that will ensue once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> returns and kicks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>'s butt. More
precisely, he's a "pretribulational dispensationalist," an unwieldy label that
refers to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate but intertwined beliefs that were popularized in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1800s</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Nelson Darby</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> and a special sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screwball genius</ENAMEX> whose ideas later spread to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darby</ENAMEX> put his eyes too
close to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripture</ENAMEX> pages and decided that history, past and future, was a
series of "dispensations": divinely ordained historical epochs in which the
Chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> had been and would be tested and found wanting by God, always
leading to the next dispensation.

            Most of these dispensations, such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> Under the
Law," are behind us. The most recent was the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church Age</ENAMEX>," when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was alive
and spread the Word. Next up is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millennium</ENAMEX>, followed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eternal State</ENAMEX>.
Right now we're living in a weird between-dispensations limbo known to premills
as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Parenthesis</ENAMEX>." This kicked in after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was crucified, a moment
they crisply refer to as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messiah</ENAMEX> cut off." Next up--according to an
exceedingly complex timetable that is pieced together with help from
future-specific "time texts" such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Testament's Book of Daniel</ENAMEX>--is the
Tribulation, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven year</TIMEX> period when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will bring wrack and ruin
to this world, before God dishes out his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrath and Christ</ENAMEX> returns to fight the
Battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX>.

            Pretribulational
premills such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> believe an early highlight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribulation</ENAMEX> will be
an event called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapture</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> will rescue the souls of righteous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> by "meeting them in the air." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapture</ENAMEX> isn't mentioned in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revelation</ENAMEX>, either. Try <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Thessalonians</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> nce that happens, you're finally into the Technicolor
material that is found in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revelation: the Whore</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Horsemen of the Apocalypse</ENAMEX>, and so on. The action starts when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revelation</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, sees a vision of a heavenly throne surrounded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> white-robed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elders</ENAMEX>. The throned figure, God, holds a book with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> seals that are
successively broken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, who is represented as a slain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb</ENAMEX>.

            Each broken seal brings
forth visions of terrors to come. When the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> seal is broken, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> learns
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">144,000</NUMEX> faithful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> each from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, together
with great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">multitudes</ENAMEX> who "came out of the great tribulation," will ultimately
appear before God, who promises them salvation.

            It goes on and on like this, often incomprehensibly. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
is all-important because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premills</ENAMEX> believe the final dispensation couldn't occur
until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were restored to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. This is why they've been so supportive
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">since 1948</TIMEX>. Now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are back, the Tribulation
could happen at any moment. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> also said he thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Coming</ENAMEX> will
happen within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>.) When the hard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> falls, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> would gladly tell
you, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> come out relatively OK. With the raptured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> gone,
everyone else--including dud <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> who have been judged unworthy, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>, atheists, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Agers</ENAMEX>, pagans, you name it--will be left behind to duke
it out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> and his gruesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX>. Above all, they must not
accept the "mark of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beast</ENAMEX>," or they'll be damned for eternity.

            When the worst is over,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 144,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> will make it, possibly many more, though they'll all have
to convert to pass muster. It's true that many, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> will be killed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Walvoord</ENAMEX>, a major pretrib <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, recently wrote that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israelites</ENAMEX> will perish" during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribulation</ENAMEX>. But that seems equitable
enough. Many, many of everybody will be killed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the End of the World</ENAMEX>.
What did you expect?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> never clearly says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is a male <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>.
It doesn't say much of anything on the subject. Premills basically believe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will be a charming rogue and great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communicator</ENAMEX> who will dupe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX>
into following his lead, and then will turn on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to destroy
them. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> would probably say yes, since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is a false <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messiah</ENAMEX>, he'll have to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> himself.
Otherwise, who'll be duped? But throughout history, others haven't seen it that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, and past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> have included <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nero, Napoleon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>,
and good ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, with his "mark of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>" forehead.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James BeauSeigneur</ENAMEX>, a premill from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>,
has written a fictional trilogy dramatizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">End Times</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BeauSeigneur</ENAMEX> says
most premills figure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>--but not all. For instance,
in a hot-selling series of novels co-authored by the well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
LaHaye, he's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanian</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">BeauSeigneur</ENAMEX>'s novels, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, for
sure, but he's also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was produced in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> by misguided scientists
using cells taken from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shroud of Turin</ENAMEX>.

            So the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> may be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, but he's cloned.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> can relax.

         
      
   
