
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">190</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Unworkable&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Speaking on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>
said, "I think some of them are not going to work, and they will cause
significant problems." Referring to ... ?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 189</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slogan's Run":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 The slogan "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feed the</ENAMEX>
rush" is being replaced with "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>'s a scream."
Why?
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            "Why
indeed? Didn't they just CHANGE the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few MONTHS ago</TIMEX>?!!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Barth</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> found 'Feed the rush' way too gay."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Krause</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX> had similar answers.)

            "I
don't really have an answer for this, but I did want to tell everyone that WHAT
I'M READING RIGHT <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">NOW</TIMEX> is the fabulous new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Be Cool</ENAMEX> .
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delacorte Press</ENAMEX>, available from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> at a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX> discount, plus
shipping, which kind of wipes out the discount, but what the heck.) If you like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authors LIKE ELMORE LEONARD</ENAMEX> or are IN THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOOD FOR MYSTERY</ENAMEX>, check this one out.
It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DESTINED FOR GREATNESS</ENAMEX>. (Small fee paid for this mention by Delacorte
Press, but I would have recommended the book anyway. Really.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
Graver
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX> likes the roller coaster allusion. Plus, 'Hey, you never
know' was already taken."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Becauseitsafullyloadedcitrusbeverageright? Yeah! Right! <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SUUUURGE</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SUUUURGE</ENAMEX>!
Mustgorunaroundongolfcourse untilbeveragewearsoff."<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Kate Wing</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            With its limited advertising budget--limited to
zero--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> has no spokesmodel (despite my rambling, drunken <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> phone
calls to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Barkin</ENAMEX>), no Happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meal</ENAMEX> ("Aw, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, I already have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>!
Make them take it back."), and no slogan. Unable to afford a professional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slogan</ENAMEX>, something hip and hot and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">happenin</ENAMEX>' (Do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> still say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">happenin</ENAMEX>'
with the apostrophe and all, or is there some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swingin</ENAMEX>' new punctuation?), we
must make do with the public domain. Under consideration:

            

               "Human life is everywhere
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in which much is to be endured, and little to be enjoyed."

               "The natural flights of the
human mind are not from pleasure to pleasure, but from hope to hope."

               "You will see in me an
extraordinary example of the effects of a bad education."

               "The
truly comic is the blossom of the nettle."

            

            All T-shirts <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cotton</ENAMEX>.

            
               Heavy Citrus
Answer
            

            The new slogan is meant to induce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>- to 24-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> to drink <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>'s Surge instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mountain Dew</ENAMEX>, the
dominant soda pop in the "heavy citrus" category. Or, in the delightfully
jargon-laden prose of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Jackson</ENAMEX>, senior brand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for Surge, to
"energize the brand for the next phase of growth."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> rejects their
previous ads: "The campaign was grounded in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> core teen values of action
and sociability, but was initially focused on the intensity more than the
sociability," he says without a trace of embarrassment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> notes that the
casts of the new ads have "a more urban feel," i.e., include <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>.
"And with urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today, there's more of a melding of the races." The new
campaign will begin on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with what he calls "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>-targeted media spike"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX>, with commercials during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photo Fun</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Match the organization
with the photo it retouched to remove an offensive cigarette.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pravda</ENAMEX>
            

             

            

               Photo
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Guitar</ENAMEX>-playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Johnson</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Paint-splattering Jackson</ENAMEX> Pollock

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Gestating Courtney Love</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D. Parade</ENAMEX>-watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Stalin</ENAMEX>

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. A and B. The new Pollock stamp and an earlier
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> stamp, both based on photographs, eliminate the cigarette from each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s mouth, and the adulterous gleam from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX>'s eye.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Brown</ENAMEX> said she didn't approve of pregnant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> smoking so she had the cigarette airbrushed out. Presumably, she did
approve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> photographed in other issues.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. On Stalin</ENAMEX>'s own
order, they retouched a photo of him on the reviewing stand in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Square</ENAMEX> for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949 May Day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parade</ENAMEX>. He felt the long rhinestone cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> undercut
his butch image. I read that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commentary</ENAMEX> . Or maybe I didn't.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limbaugh</ENAMEX>--a fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named
Rush.

            
               Slogan
Citations
            

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boswell</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleridge</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
