
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">191</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Enlistment Drive&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> are rumored to be on a list of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">118</NUMEX>.
            

            

               List of what?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 190</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unworkable":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              
                                 
                                    Speaking on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> said, "I think some
of them are not going to work, and they will cause significant problems."
Referring to ...
?
                                 
                              
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>' plan to fire its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and restaff using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laborers</ENAMEX> borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leary</ENAMEX>
            

            "Whoopi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s smug political jokes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscars</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "Those
wacky ideas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayn Rand</ENAMEX> put in her books."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Strauss</ENAMEX>
            

            "My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> after they graduate."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Stewart</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            
"Internet sites that attempt to charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.95</NUMEX> per year for wry
political and cultural commentary."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> (similarly, Faxon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bishop</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mueller</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> speaks,
everyone listens because we have money riding on his remarks. Whether through a
mutual fund, mortgage, or credit card, we've each placed a bet on the economy,
and it's a lot more exciting to watch the game when you have a little something
on it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, I watched an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> basketball playoff game at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caesar</ENAMEX>'s
sports book in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX>. It was the most intensely engaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> I'd ever seen
at any dramatic production. And that's the basis of my election reform plan.
Forget motor-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> will go to the polls if you let them bet on the
outcome. You can already do it legally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and, except for royal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marriages</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX> book advances, their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> is intact. Here's how it
would work. When you vote, you get a ticket that allows you to legally bet on
the election at any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTB</ENAMEX>. Try it next time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, and turnout will go
up by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 50 percent</NUMEX>. I'd bet on it.

            

               Greenspanswer
            

            Addressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banking Committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> was referring to the current wave of mergers.
While some will undoubtedly fail, he said, there will be no bailouts using
public money. Asked if he was concerned about the increased concentration of
economic power, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> replied, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cop Shopper</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX> is past,
but if you still need handcuffs, evidence kits, radar <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, battering rams, and
some very attractive clothing, try the catalog from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gall's Inc.</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> to public safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>." I use the print version, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gall's</ENAMEX> and parent company
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aramark</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> catering) are online. A few highlights:

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friskmaster Gloves</ENAMEX>. Searching for evidence can be
a dangerous business. That's why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gall's</ENAMEX> is proud to introduce the ultimate
armor for your hands. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36.99</NUMEX>."--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> when you slip on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friskmasters</ENAMEX>.

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thunderwear® Holster</ENAMEX>. This unique design allows you to hide your weapon
inside the front of your trousers. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42.99</NUMEX>."--No fancy symbolism, no easy irony,
no dime-store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freud</ENAMEX>, just straightforward gun underwear. Oh yes, my cynical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>, that is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> in my pants and I am glad to see
you.

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">StabPro Vests</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">They Have Nothing To Lose</ENAMEX>. It can happen anywhere:
in the yard, in cell extraction or transporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>. Suddenly, they
attack you with razor blades, shanks, picks, shivs, or sharpened rebar. They
swing chair legs, pipes and mop handles. And when nothing's left, they use
their fists and their feet. Because what are you going to do? Toss them in
jail? <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$459.99</NUMEX> and up."--I'll never complain about those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seventeen</ENAMEX>
magazine editorial meetings ever again.

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trico's Transport Cell</ENAMEX>. Transporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> can be tough on your
vehicle interior. Blood stains on the carpet and seats, torn headliners, marred
door panels, not to mention broken windows all add to your frustration.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$699.99</NUMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>! Don't make me stop this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and come back there!

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Straight Knife Tool</ENAMEX>. Opens key-operated filing cabinet locks and padlocks.
A good basis for starting an opening kit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master/Presto Tool</ENAMEX> opens
combination-lock briefcases in less than a minute without damaging the locks.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14.99</NUMEX> each."--Only slightly more expensive than a legally obtained search
warrant.

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polycarbonate Riot Batons</ENAMEX>. This virtually indestructible baton is great
for use in riot & <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> control situations and comes with a lifetime
warranty. Impact strength is greater than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> or aluminum batons. Will not
warp, dent, or splinter. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$49.95</NUMEX>."--It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>-tough,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>-affordable.

            

            After shopping, relax
with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Line of Duty: true life</ENAMEX> experiences from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>." The
current issue, stapled between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pages</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170 and 171</NUMEX>, includes a story from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sgt.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Bugarin</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, which begins: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer morning</TIMEX> I was dispatched to a non-injury accident within a residential
area." If you can find a better example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>-speak, buy it.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
