
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Drawing upon her rich experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions about manners, personal
relations, politics, and other subjects. Please send your questions for
publication to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in
length. Please indicate how you wish your letter to be signed, preferably
including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I work in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. While I
have cordial but hardly warm relations with several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>, the only person
I genuinely like is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was hired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight months ago</TIMEX>. We have
become quite friendly, verging on affectionate. I sense a mutual attraction
(and I know she is available). We're both in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-30s</TIMEX>. Since I both like her
and find her desirable, I am considering pursuing a relationship. However, my
track record isn't great: The last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six and eight months</TIMEX>,
respectively (though I have remained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>). If this current
attraction were to blossom into a relationship, I could foresee some happy and
soul-supportive times--but not permanence. By the way, since she exited a
long-term relationship just before she joined our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, I suspect she's not
interested in permanence either.
            

            
               So, do you think
it's worth going into an office relationship that probably won't last? We don't
work closely together but, then again, I wouldn't want to hurt or alienate the
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">office</ENAMEX> whom I really like. And how much disclosure about my
track record do you think I should reveal?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wondering</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Won</ENAMEX>,

            Since we only live once until further notice,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks it would be a shame to pass up a promising romantic opportunity
simply because it may not turn out to be perfect--or permanent. You are
wonderfully thoughtful about looking ahead, but try not to plan things that
are, after all, emotional and evolutionary. It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s guess that if you
tell the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in question of your interest, as well as of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>,
her response will be the guide you are seeking. As for revealing your strikeout
record, that kind of information always gets out during the course of what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prudie</ENAMEX> refers to as the "what did you major in?" discussions.

            Your remark that "it probably won't last suggests
faulty reasoning. You are pessimistically assuming that because no one has
interested you on a permanent basis so far, no one will.

            For some reason, Prudie
feels hunchy about your situation and thinks this romantic friendship has
possibilities. You can't not try to find out. And do keep us all posted.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, encouragingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Am I an idiot? I already know I am an idiot, but
am I to be a happy idiot or a miserable one? Recently I went on a press junket
to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>, hosted by dull technologists. There, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>, I
fell in with another trapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>. In the way of such things, we now say
we are in love. On the bright side, she is a beautiful, terrifyingly honest
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, I am (problematically) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>, balding,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, and bitter.
            

            
               My question: She
wants to move out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, where I live. I want her to move out. We know
nothing about each other. What should I do?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eager To Be Told What I Want To Hear</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Eag</ENAMEX>,

            Let her come. This must be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s day to play
Cupid, because like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chap</ENAMEX> who wrote the previous letter, you sound as though
you have serendipitously found someone terrific. Take a chance. The worst
scenario is that you will be dropped on your head; in which case you will pick
yourself up and begin again--without having to wonder if you passed up the love
of a lifetime.

            And about the bitter
business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prudie</ENAMEX> assumes this refers to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> situation. The fact that
you acknowledge it, however, reveals a useful self-understanding. As for being
balding, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is surely not alone in finding that look attractive, even sexy.
Once again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels hunchy that the melding of très charmant and
jolly good could work out brilliantly.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, sighingly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I put before you an etiquette quandary that I
faced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> and may face again. I was going regularly to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
hair <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salon</ENAMEX> and getting my hair cut by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>. Was I supposed to tip
him? Even <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a hefty $10</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> tip seemed a paltry thing to put in the hand of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salon</ENAMEX>. To me he was "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>," and tips only seemed
appropriate in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. I therefore refrained from handing him a
potentially demeaning tip but was still left with the feeling that I should do
something.
            

            
               After a few visits
(and no clear advice from my usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage friends</ENAMEX>) I resolved to give him a
copy of a book I had written. As a personal gift with no measurable value, it
seemed a better way to thank him than to price my gratitude at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> bucks. I have
moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, but if I had stayed I am not sure what I would have given
him next. What should one do in such a situation?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Striving for Graciousness</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Strive,</ENAMEX>

            Well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX> married her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hairdresser</ENAMEX>, but that seems an excessive thank-you. Because you've left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, your question is hypothetical, unless, of course, you wind up in the same
situation again.

            As for not tipping an
establishment's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, in terms of etiquette you are correct. Prudie, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classically</ENAMEX> trained <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salon</ENAMEX>-goer, recommends a grand gift at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmastime</ENAMEX>. Such
a  gift could cost the equivalent of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s tips if one were so inclined. BTW
(as we say on the Internet) or "by the way," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> was recently on your
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">wonderful Bloor Street</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, grandly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Several of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and I have noticed that our new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> repeatedly interrupts us
when we are talking on the phone with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. She can see the phone, she
can hear us talking, yet she bursts in, unwilling to wait. This leaves us in
the awkward position of wanting, but not being able, to tell her to go away (or
at least to cool her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>) or being inexcusably rude to others. Granted, we all
have quirks, but this is highly unnerving to many of us. Your thoughts,
please.
            

            

               --Trying <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Very Hard To Hear You</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
Try,

            It sounds as though your
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 years old</TIMEX> and hellbent on instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gratification</ENAMEX>. Prudie
would suggest that you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> go to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior</ENAMEX> and
spell out the problem. If for some reason this is not feasible, write a memo
signed "Everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>" saying you don't wish to be disrespectful,
but her habit is counterproductive, annoying, and unnecessary. Feel free to
point out that callus interruptus is bad for business.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, uninterruptedly

             

         
      
   
