
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 26</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story and editorial say deflation threatens the global economy.
Deflation caused by overcapacity and flaccid demand could send the world into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> must ease their tight monetary policies to boost
consumer demand. ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> stories urge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> to compromise with its
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> rather than continue to oppress it. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> don't demand
separation, only limited autonomy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> ought to grant that to keep the
peace. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the pieces begins with the mysterious sentence, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cockahoop</ENAMEX>.") ... A piece notes the demise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaman Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, a
drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that paid rainforest folk healers to supply healing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that
could be turned into advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The lesson: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced</ENAMEX> screening technology,
which allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to speedily test lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> for medicinal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">properties</ENAMEX>, is better than folk wisdom.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The editorial heartily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endorses Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s contemplated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> run, because it will finally
stop her from injecting her politics into her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s job. "We're far from
certain that her brand of righteous liberalism is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
want or need," say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, "but we are sure that it would be healthy for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to find out." ... An article tallies the early achievements
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Body</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>. He and his centrist brain trust
have concocted progressive and equitable ways to spend the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s budget
surplus and tobacco settlement bounty. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akhil Reed Amar</ENAMEX>
calls on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to let the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> statute (a "constitutional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankenstein"</ENAMEX>) die and to replace faulty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decisions on executive
privilege with a comprehensive bill on presidential legal liability. (For more
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amar</ENAMEX>'s critique of the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> statute, see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s ".")

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story
proclaims the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s decline and fall. From the dismantled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lords</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s integrated suburbs, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> is finally paying more attention
to its cosmopolitan future than to its oft-eulogized past. ... A piece
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">profiles Linux</ENAMEX>, an operating system which might pose the biggest threat to
Windows. Written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linus Torvalds</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX> who couldn't afford to
buy a commercial operating system, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linux</ENAMEX> is free, is maintained by a vast
network of loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer programmers</ENAMEX>, and never crashes. ... The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> introduces a redesigned front section, which grandly aims to chronicle
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Way We Live Now</ENAMEX>." Included is a new ethics column (written by

                  Slate
               's own -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Cohen</ENAMEX>), a feature on draft-dodging in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and a guide to spotting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bologna sandwiches</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The newsweeklies chronicle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s denouement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story toasts the sunny side of the impeachment scandal.
It sparked a vigorous debate about morality, introduced role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> who defied
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stereotypes</ENAMEX> (powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in wheelchairs, patrician female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>),
and demonstrated that the political process is "sturdy and forgiving." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s closed deliberations on impeachment were a bonding experience, and
their frankness and intimacy will encourage more teamwork in the future.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's cover
story is darker, emphasizing the trial's lingering stink in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The only figure to emerge untainted is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>,
whose approval rating is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> percentage points higher than it was before the
scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> 's cover
story moans that notoriety has become acceptable--even desirable--for
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>'s only silver lining: a new concern about the
erosion of privacy. A related
story conveys the isolation felt by many religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> in the
wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s acquittal: Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1925 Scopes monkey trial</ENAMEX>, Flytrap
may encourage them to withdraw from mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. "We have never been a
moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>," concedes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports on
a peculiar development in medical research: fake operations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> are
performing "placebo-controlled surgical trials" in which they cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> open
and sew them back up without doing anything. Afterward, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> compare the
results of the placebo surgeries with those of real operations. ...

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">profiles Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mystic</ENAMEX> and faith healer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Master Li</ENAMEX>, who
peddles a combination of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> healing and American-style revivalist
preaching to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> can't decide whether to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suppress Li</ENAMEX> or co-opt him for their own agenda.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22 and March 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> publishes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-themed double issue. Arranged marriage is alive and well in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, says a profile of an imaginative young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> reluctantly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">steeling</ENAMEX> herself to accept her appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">betrothed</ENAMEX>. She uses her real name in
the hope that a suitable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX> might pick her out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> instead.
... An article chronicles the entwined histories of the rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Daily News and New York Post</ENAMEX> , which are as colorful,
scandalous, and gritty as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>' front pages. A highlight: After
Post <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Hamill</ENAMEX> was fired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> revolted and
published a protest issue mocking the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>. ... The magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profiles Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX> General <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Volpe</ENAMEX>, who began his career
as a set-building carpenter and now rules the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> with workmanlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">practicality</ENAMEX> and a diva-sized temper. (In a revealing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>
slip-up, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volpe</ENAMEX> piece misspells the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>. In a
passage about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s dictatorial, brutal style, the text calls him
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Adolf</ENAMEX>, whatever.)

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> enlists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> to opine about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s acquittal. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> calls Flytrap the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Dreyfus Affair</ENAMEX>, revealing the rot and corruption at the heart of our
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Another compares it to the German triumph at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunkirk</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superficial</ENAMEX> and premature victory that will be overshadowed when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>
wins the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> nomination for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Another argues that the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> distorted the impeachment process: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> should have
been allowed to conduct a more direct and aggressive investigation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, unfettered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> reprints a poem by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.B. Yeats</ENAMEX>
("the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twentieth century</TIMEX>"), urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to
"be secret and exult" in their martyrdom.

         
      
   
