
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">177</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Them</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               In his inaugural address <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
should celebrate them in festivals, we should enjoy their traditions in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>, we should share them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>." What?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 176</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrecking Ball</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  "It did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> and me a lot of good to pick up
those hammers and crowbars and tear something down," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. Tear what down?
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twirler</ENAMEX>'s frilly little underth ...--oh, I meant the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> of racism and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homophobia</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Wolitzer</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
chains that bind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> of the world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was speaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">metaphorically</ENAMEX>, of course, about his achievements in estate tax
relief."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habitat for Humanity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. 'Sometimes he just doesn't listen,' apologized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> to the bewildered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "Lani
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guinier</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Vance</ENAMEX>
            

            "All
ideological differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Banker</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

             

             

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            I believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>
was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> to
convincingly wield hand tools. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> tend to be better at this sort of
thing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> looked at home with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> saw, although he badly gashed
his leg attempting to read a book for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was befuddled by a supermarket scanner, which isn't even a real hand tool,
and besides, no one expected him to operate it, just carry the bags of
groceries out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX> liked to take a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9 pound</NUMEX> sledge hammer
out to the woods and pound a moose into the ground up to its antlers. He said
it impressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spaniards</ENAMEX>. The real purpose of these sweaty efforts is a
display of manliness and blue-collar virtue. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, this
meant the conquest of nature. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>'s was a more modest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> carpentry.
Maybe someday we'll have a true liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, secure
enough in her ideology to put down the tools, pick up the phone, and call a
repair <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>.

            
               Hard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hat Area</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            At a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> helped demolish a wall to make room for a health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinic</ENAMEX>, an activity meant, in some weirdly elliptical way, to commemorate the
life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Response</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Because so many people
turned off the set right after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s speech, then stumbled toward the
liquor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX>, clutching their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and moaning, they missed these highlights
from the opposition. If you read between the lines, you can infer what new
measures are being proposed.

            
               From <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>
            

            

               "I know how that knot in the pit of your stomach feels; I've been
there."--Some say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s wire-tapping measures are grotesquely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intrusive</ENAMEX>, but apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want to deploy some sort of shrinking
machine that can inject a tiny congresswoman right into your digestive
system.

               "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is not in crisis. There are no tanks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>."--She
seemed so disappointed. I think what she's getting at is a crime-fighting plan
involving larger, more heavily armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeep</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cherokees</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               From <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>
            

            

               "I got to live every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s dream: playing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Football</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>."--Actually, my dream involves a time machine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Lombard</ENAMEX>, and a
thermos of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattans</ENAMEX>, but that's not an actual government policy. Not
yet.

               "It wasn't until after I was elected that I attended a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> function
where a banner hung that read 'GOP.' I had to ask someone what those letters
stood for."--You'd think at that point, mortified by his own ignorance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX>
would have resigned. Maybe this signals an interest in on-the-job
training?

               "True liberty and freedom come from
God."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX> may have mixed up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOD</ENAMEX>; he did get hit in the head a lot
living out his dream (whereas in my dream, Ms. Lombard and I say amusing things
to each other in the bathtub and then slip into attractive robes and then the
camera slowly zooms in on the fireplace). I'm not sure how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX>'s idea
translates into policy, but I'd look for these words in any bill he introduces:
human sacrifice.

            

            
               Race
Results
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: Betrayal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s legacy.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
