
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">162</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Check It Twice&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               The list includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Vuitton</ENAMEX> handbags, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mont Blanc</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pecorino cheese</ENAMEX>, and cashmere sweaters, pullovers, sweat shirts, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">waistcoats</ENAMEX>. List of what?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">161</NUMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rapoportable":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Rapoport</ENAMEX> led the search for something
"that was sweet rather than violent, that lingered for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>, and that
suggested a feeling of cleanliness and well-being rather than of filthiness
being covered up." What was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapoport</ENAMEX> looking
for?
                     
                  
               
            

            
"An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unshowered</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Sawyer</ENAMEX> on a lazy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Spiegel</ENAMEX>
            

            "An
alternative to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> impeachment trial."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Graver</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
Tullis , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bonin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Barbero</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX> had
similar answers.)

            "An
undiscovered type of drunken sex."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Lyle</ENAMEX> (similarly, but sober,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> ; but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sol clean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Tullis</ENAMEX> )

            
"Whatever it was, if he was looking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, he probably had to look for a
long time."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ballard</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
scent to improve the smell of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paris Metro</ENAMEX>. He's chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            It's a tough position for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>
(as many of you are) to be put in--invited to joke about scents and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensibilities</ENAMEX>. How can you gain the moral high ground, that lofty crag from
which to hurl down scorn, when your native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>--what's the
word?--stinks.

            The best tactic for a situation tainted by your own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperfection</ENAMEX> is to define yourself as the happy medium, superior to those on
both your left and right. Thus, cleaner than we are and they're prigs (like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss</ENAMEX>); dirtier than we are and they're <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> (like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>). Or as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> explains it, my history of adultery is only human (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> human than
that of those unsinning prigs, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>), and I confessed to everything the
moment I was sure I'd been found out (unlike our perjuring, porcine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>).

            Fouler even than the odor of contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> was that of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> anywhere. Late in the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 14, 1773</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Boswell</ENAMEX> welcomed to his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> his great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>. "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> and I walked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>-in-arm up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Street</ENAMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James's Court</ENAMEX>; it was a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusky night</TIMEX>; I could not prevent his being assailed by
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> effluvia of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>. A zealous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotsman</ENAMEX> would have wished Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> to be without one of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> senses upon this occasion. As we marched
slowly along, he grumbled in my ear, 'I smell you in the dark!' "

            Look for that phrase at
the impeachment trial.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olfactory Worker</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherman</ENAMEX> and others knew, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rapoport</ENAMEX> was seeking a perfume to nasally improve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> metro. After screening 500 scents, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> selected a fragrance they
named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>," after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>' most noisome <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each month</TIMEX>, a ton and a
half of it will be added to the cleaning products used throughout the subway
system.

            
               What's the Trouble
Extra
            

            
Fill in the blank by matching each problem with its
cause.

            
               The Causes
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">coyote</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. The Vienna Boys Choir</ENAMEX>

            
               The Problems
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Explaining what led to her resignation,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl-Heinz Schenk</ENAMEX> said, "The trouble with Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grossmann</ENAMEX> is, at some point, she
began to believe that she personally was _______."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Contemplating trouble on the range, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Luce</ENAMEX>
said, "They are in our chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, killing our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, killing our barn
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>. A lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sportsmen</ENAMEX> consider them a target. That puts the wolf in a
bad situation, because he looks just like _______."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Musing on the recruiting trouble in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>,
Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel DeMilio</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're</ENAMEX> never going to be __________."

            
               Answers
            

            1-C,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-A, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-B.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
