
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blacklist</ENAMEX> and Backstory

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences</ENAMEX> announced that it would award an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honorary Oscar</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX>. What was surprising about this news
was the amount of controversy it generated: virtually none. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>
has been reviled as the most notorious of those who "named names"--identified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Communists</ENAMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>--before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Committee on Un-American</ENAMEX>
Activities. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Film Institute</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Film Critics Association</ENAMEX> have turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> down for honors that no one
disputes are merited by his films, which include <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East of Eden</ENAMEX> and A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Streetcar Named Desire</ENAMEX> . But this time the vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>'s favor was
unanimous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> looking to reprise the old conflict had a hard time
finding anyone who still bears him a grudge.

            Why have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>'s enemies
suddenly dropped their complaint? Several articles on the subject have ritually
invoked "the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>" as an explanation. But it's not clear why the
collapse of Communism should smooth matters over. Many wars end in a reckoning
rather than in forgiveness and forgetting. A more plausible explanation is
probably that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">89</TIMEX>, has outlived most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> and that the
fury of the rest has lost its edge. It may indeed be time to excuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> for
what he did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>. But if so, it shouldn't happen because no one can be
troubled to remember or sort out the morality of his actions.

            A synopsis: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> got his start in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>, a left-wing theater <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX> that was home to the legendary directors
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Strasberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Clurman</ENAMEX>, as well as the radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odets</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> "cell" inside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX>. He quit after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> received orders to take over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX> and turn it into an "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> collective." Despite his
resignation/expulsion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> remained sympathetic to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> into the
1940s, when he began directing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> films. But that sympathy was long gone
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>, when he was called before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUAC</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time he
testified, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> took a principled position: He would discuss his
own involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> but not the others who had been in it with him. So
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> called him back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and put him under oath. Under
pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>, he reversed himself. Since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> already knew the names it wanted, "naming names" was a loyalty test
and humiliation ritual, not part of a real investigation. There is a chilling,
Darkness at Noon quality to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>'s questioning by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Tavenner Jr.</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>:

            
Tavenner: I understand that you have voluntarily requested the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to
reopen your hearing, and give you an opportunity to explain fully the
participation of others known to you at the time to have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>:
That is correct. I want to make a full and complete statement. I want to tell
you everything I know about it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>'s prepared statement offered up the names of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> others who were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Group Theater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. The names included
Odets, who subsequently named names himself, and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> since
forgotten, in part, perhaps, because they were blacklisted.

            It was not just his
testimony that made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> figure of his time. After all,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odets</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUAC</ENAMEX> the same names, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Leverett</ENAMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group Theater</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumnus</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> named. But many others who named names did so under
ostensible protest, or later castigated themselves publicly for crawling before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> embraced his inquisitors. Soon after he testified, he took
out an ad in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> to defend himself. "I believe that any
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who is in possession of such facts has the obligation to make them
known, either to the public or to the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government agency</ENAMEX>," he wrote.
"Whatever hysteria exists--and there is some, particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>--is
inflamed by mystery, suspicion and secrecy. Hard and exact facts will cool it."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> made his case more memorably in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> film On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waterfront</ENAMEX> ,
in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlon Brando</ENAMEX> plays a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">longshoreman</ENAMEX> faced with a choice about whether
to "rat" on the murderous and corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. His decision to
testify is portrayed as an act of courageous whistle-blowing, not betrayal or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cowardice</ENAMEX>.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> afterward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> kept his silence about the
episode. "I don't think there's anything in my life toward which I have more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambivalence</ENAMEX>, because, obviously, there's something disgusting about giving
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s names," he acknowledged in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> interview. But he also refused
to apologize and defended his choice. In his fascinating autobiography,
published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> expresses a range of justifications. He wasn't telling
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> any names it didn't know; as an immigrant, he was eager to
demonstrate his patriotism; he was faced with a choice of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> evils.

            Did he do wrong? The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question to ask is what the right thing would have been. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> might have
stood by his original policy, asserting that while he hated Communism, he would
not assist in a violation of civil liberties. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>'s soon to be ex-friend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Miller</ENAMEX> did something like this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years later</TIMEX> when he refused to
answer questions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> claimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> (right to freedom of
speech and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>) rather than taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth</ENAMEX> (right against
self-incrimination). This was the more principled stand, since taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth</ENAMEX>
implied agreeing that simply being a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> was a crime. Also, there is no
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX> right against incriminating others. Unfortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court had never ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> could be used in this way.

            With McCarthyism much weaker by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> avoided prison
and continued to have his plays produced. But for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s stance
before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUAC</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> would almost certainly have meant a contempt citation and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in jail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> would not have made films for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, if ever again.
For a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> to immolate himself to protect the rights of
lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, or more precisely in a quixotic attempt to protect those
rights, would have been heroic. But failing to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> did not make him a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">villain</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> were the blacklisters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> was one of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.

            But failing to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">villain</ENAMEX> doesn't make him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, either. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX> did go wrong was in
casting an evil he couldn't avoid as a good. His statement that the "facts"
about Communism were the cure for anti-Communist hysteria was disingenuous. The
real cure for anti-Communist hysteria was a courage that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazan</ENAMEX>, like most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, did not possess. But this bit of gratuitous groveling pales next to the
sins of others--both those who remained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalinists</ENAMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> and those who
did not just acquiesce in, but advocated, McCarthyism. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion Picture Arts and Sciences</ENAMEX>, which actually enforced the blacklist, to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reject Kazan</ENAMEX> for his comparatively minor offenses would have been the sheerest
hypocrisy.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> have argued recently that new information
makes all forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> anti-Communism, including even McCarthyism, look
better in hindsight. They contend that the so-called Venona intercepts, a few
of which have been released, show definitively not only that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX> and the
Rosenbergs were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> but also that there was far more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> string-pulling
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Communism than anyone ever knew. But none of these revelations
improves the case that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> Communism was a significant threat to
democracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray Kempton</ENAMEX> got this story right in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>, in his book Part of
Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>, most of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX>, were
overpaid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>, not dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>. The examples of "propaganda"
they slipped into scripts are few and laughable. The high point of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kempton</ENAMEX>'s
essay on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> is a list of the folderol the blacklisted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriters</ENAMEX> actually produced--with excerpts from the glowing reviews they
received from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Daughters of the American Revolution</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX> wasn't a hack, and he didn't try to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. He deserves an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> as much as anyone living--for best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, not for
best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>. Who in the movie industry qualifies for that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one
anyway?

         
      
   
