
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> Yens

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> led its
front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a headline saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> was anxious about the
new single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency, the euro. "Just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is trying to get
out of a recession, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> fears that the yen may be relegated to the rank of a
regional currency," it said. According to the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> paper,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keizo Obuchi</ENAMEX>, due in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> at the start of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> tour, was going to press the case for a new "tri-polar" monetary
system based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar, the euro, and the yen. "The birth of the euro
and the preparation of a 'yen <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX>' in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> will be at the heart of the
subjects discussed during his trip," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> said.

            In a front page
editorial signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Rousselin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> noted that although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is
still the richest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the world, if judged by its investments and
balance of payments surpluses, it wouldn't have dared address the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
so frankly about its ambitions for the yen if the euro hadn't been born. But
now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obuchi</ENAMEX> has spoken openly of wanting the yen to be "one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> world
currencies," which Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figaro</ENAMEX> said was "in itself a fine tribute to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euro</ENAMEX>, a currency which has only just been born." But the editorial warned,
"After the difficulties linked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> have
recently rediscovered their old complicity. In relation to the yen and the
dollar, the euro is going to have to find its place, remembering that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">m√©nage √†</ENAMEX> trois usually ends as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> against one."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s biggest selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> , led <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with the discovery of a diary showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirohito</ENAMEX> never considered abdication at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, even though
his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was in ruins and he was worried about being prosecuted by the
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoshihiro Tokugawa</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grand chamberlain</ENAMEX> of the imperial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> a conversation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> said he had always ruled
out the possibility of giving up the throne because he had considered it a
"sacred duty to pass this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, which I inherited from my ancestors, on to
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>." Before the diary was found, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> believed
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> had at least contemplated abdication.

            Despite the imminence of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the story got little coverage around the
world, though it was the subject of an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> . The
paper came out in favor of an abbreviated hearing ending with a "test" vote,
which would probably be followed by a motion of censure. "An early vote would
see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> address from the outset the core issue in this sorry saga," the
editorial said. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, it is about proportionality. Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lied about
his relationship with Ms <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. But is that sufficient cause to depose a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?"

            Of much greater interest to the world's press was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> seeking the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> nomination. Her photograph
dominated the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neue Z√</ENAMEX>ºrcher
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitung</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX> ran a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> page feature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> headed
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> vs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> (the rematch)" about the prospect of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary-Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
battle for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. "Both are hugely attractive assets to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>," the article said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> has emerged beatified from the
Monicagate saga, a wronged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who perhaps did more than any other single
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> to rescue the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> elections for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>."

            With most of the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> dominated in
midweek by domestic issues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> that flight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathay Pacific</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> that promises "warmth and friendly
service straight from the heart," were threatening to stop smiling at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> if their pay demands weren't met. "Our contracts do not say we have
to smile," a union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Daily</ENAMEX> reported
the establishment of a new national anti-smuggling police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of an initial
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. "Smuggling can wreck the economy, and destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>, the
military and maybe even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luo Gan</ENAMEX>, a senior government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>,
was quoted as saying at the launch.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> devoted an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to a disaster affecting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> hamburger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has taken out
newspaper ads to apologize for running out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Macs</ENAMEX> after an unexpected
public response to a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> for the price of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>" special offer. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>
running out of Big Macs? It's like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> running out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>," the editorial
said. But it went on to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> special offer could also be
looked at as "an unusual example of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Keynesian</ENAMEX> stimulus within the service
industries just when the [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>] economy is slithering into recession."
Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> should consider doing something similar in other countries
where consumer demand is frozen, it said, "and where better than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> where
the economy is in danger of sustained contraction because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>
simply refuse to spend their own money (of which they have huge quantities)."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> concluded, "They too look ripe for a topical dose of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macflation</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
