
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Travails of Jordan</ENAMEX>

            The homecoming of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Hussein</ENAMEX> was marked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX>'s mass circulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Ra'i</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
by an editorial asking that God might show him mercy "equal to the size of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prayers</ENAMEX> and love for our beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> press was unable to
report on the possible repercussions of his likely death because of
government-imposed censorship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London's Middle East</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Walker</ENAMEX>, reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> that "public jitters could turn
to panic despite efforts by palace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to convey the impression of a
smooth transfer of power to the new Crown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX> had
been increased by "a clumsy purge of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>" that had involved the
imposition <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 day</TIMEX> detention order on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">nationalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Majd</ENAMEX> after it had published the first full account
of the deposition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>, the king's younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crown prince</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Majd</ENAMEX> had revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>, had laid down his revolver
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> and asked to be shot if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> thought he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX>. As
part of the same purge, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Arab al-Yawm</ENAMEX> were fired by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, also for publishing
unofficial accounts of the succession crisis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> wrote. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">language Arab Daily</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s clampdown on
"bad news" has "opened the door to rumors, inflicting a higher toll on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than the truth would achieve."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>'s health crisis led the front pages of many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> both carrying front-page editorials about him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica</ENAMEX> 's editorial, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Little Great King</ENAMEX>," recalled that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> had come to the throne in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>, when "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> was still alive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>
still in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Downing Street</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> still to conclude his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." The paper doubted that Crown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>
has the experience to face the current dangers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and concluded
that "if the void left by the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> isn't filled, the whole of the
region--not only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>--will be regretting the loss of 'the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>.' "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> said his death will "further complicate a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX> crisis fed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s difficulties and the paralysis caused by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s turbulent election campaign." It said, "Everyone will miss King
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>. Soon we will know how much."

            Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">River Jordan</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> pronounced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement "buried,"
adding that far from achieving its purpose of extricating the peace process
from an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 month</TIMEX> impasse, it had instead thrown up new barriers to progress.
For this it put most of the blame on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. "More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
after the signing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accord, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> has turned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli-Palestinian</ENAMEX>
relations and the entire peace process back into a zero-sum game," it said. "He
cannot prove his claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Wye accord</ENAMEX> is better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> accord
because he is not implementing it, nor can he attribute the current quiet to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unimplemented</ENAMEX> agreement. It is not yet too late to carry out the agreement, but
there is no reason to expect that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> will respect even his own
signature."

            Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> continued their outcry
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian Gazette</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that "virtually everybody agrees that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s despicable and shuddering deeds qualify him for the title of
the world's most notorious despot." But, like practically every other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>
paper, it condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> plans to replace him. It predicted that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> were
removed, he would be replaced by a "puppet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>," which would "spark bitter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rivalries</ENAMEX>" and lead to a carve-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. "This chaos is bound to spill
over beyond the border into neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>," it concluded.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bahrain</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akhbar al-Khaleej</ENAMEX> rejoiced at the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Indyk</ENAMEX> to obtain endorsement for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s plans from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> he visited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX>. Their refusal to support the toppling of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> would oblige <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> either to reconsider or to press ahead
unilaterally in defiance of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and international law, the paper
said.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> is to host the next <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX>
Games, the row about corruption in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX>
continued to dominate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. In an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> said the rot was systematic and that,
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Antonio Samaranch</ENAMEX> must carry the ultimate
responsibility for the crisis that is engulfing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> movement." It said,
"He is not an answer to the problem. He represents the problem. ... This means
that Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samaranch</ENAMEX> must resign now to allow a reformist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> to restore the
shattered ideals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> led
its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with a report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had started to ease
the sanctions it imposed after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s nuclear tests <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. It saw
significance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> having given the go-ahead for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> loan for a
power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">project</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Andhra Pradesh</ENAMEX> and its invitation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of the</ENAMEX>
Army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Staff General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.P. Malik</ENAMEX> to attend a military ceremony in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> later
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX>
reported a thaw in relations between their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, the newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klan</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> had become a paradise for drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> because of the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. The war made it impossible for them
to use their traditional routes through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, so they had turned to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, it said. "With its porous borders, inefficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and extreme
poverty, it was the perfect alternative," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klan</ENAMEX> added. "Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has changed from being an isolated backwater into the chief
departure terminal for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s drug trade."

             

         
      
   
