
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Patch
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Adams</ENAMEX>
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> pan this inspirational "based
on a true story" dramedy about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who cures with laughter. (Ignoring the
bad reviews, moviegoers gave the film a record-breaking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas weekend</TIMEX> box
office haul.) As played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patch Adams</ENAMEX> is first an
"insufferable, sermonizing medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> ) and later an in-your-face clown-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> with a bedpan on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and squeaky balloon <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in his hands. The film is sappy and grating:
Even the easy to please <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Siskel</ENAMEX> calls it "utterly unctuous" and asks, "Who
would want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mork</ENAMEX> at their bedside<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official site.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Faculty</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). Teen horror screenwriting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX> does it again in this "rip-snorting hunk of giddy, self-aware genre
trash" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Harvey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breakfast Club</ENAMEX> meets
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invasion of the Body Snatchers</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> misfit high-schoolers try to save
the world from their alien-inhabited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> credit the teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elijah Wood</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unknowns</ENAMEX>) and the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Famke Janssen</ENAMEX>, Bebe
Neuwirth, and others) with solid performances. It's a film that "ably gives the
audience what it wants: hope, revenge, and gross-out jokes" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Kehr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> ). (Check out preliminary models of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> at
this
site.)

            

               
                  Stepmom
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Entertainment</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>
plays the nightmare stepmom (i.e., beautiful, successful, sweet) to
über <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Their rivalry dissolves, of
course, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarandon</ENAMEX> is diagnosed with terminal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call this
tear-jerker manipulative and trite, deriding its mandatory
sing-along-to-Motown-hits female bonding scene, stiff-upper-lipping by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarandon</ENAMEX>, etc. Female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are kinder than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>, and the New York
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarandon</ENAMEX> "make the film a lot
more watchable than it has any right to be." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> an interview with the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> here.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mighty Joe</ENAMEX>
Young
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> deem this "shaky remake
of a hoary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">King Kong</ENAMEX> knockoff" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenstern</ENAMEX>) mildly amusing. The story: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big</ENAMEX> ape
has special relationship (which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX> calls "vaguely
unseemly") with beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> want to poach big ape, big ape gets
put in zoo/nature preserve, goes on rampage, and saves little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kiddies</ENAMEX> from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">burning Ferris</ENAMEX> wheel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlize Theron</ENAMEX> (the object of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ape</ENAMEX>'s affections) is a
stunner, and the giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX> is stunningly realistic, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the
rest of the movie is too predictable to be anything more than strictly OK.
(Check out the movie poster from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> original.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hundred</ENAMEX>
Dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McKibben</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKibben</ENAMEX>'s earlier books (mostly on the ways he has reduced his environmental
impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>) were slammed as having "the homiletic tone of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sermon</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild</ENAMEX> ), this one strikes a positive chord with most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>. They
praise his proposal that we reduce the commerciality of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday season</TIMEX>, and
only a few mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hundred Dollar Holiday</ENAMEX> recycles ideas from the
10-year-old voluntary simplicity movement. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX>
dissents from the pack, complaining of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKibben</ENAMEX>'s books in general--"his
combination of arrogance and sincerity, narcissism and asceticism, is riveting
and infuriating at once"--and of this book in specific--"The thesis is ancient
and hard to argue with, though something in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McKibben</ENAMEX>'s pious manner may make
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> want to try." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read Kirn</ENAMEX>'s review here.)

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vintner</ENAMEX>'s
Luck
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Knox</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). Mixed
reviews greet this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. This story of a long and stormy love affair between a fallen angel and
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vintner</ENAMEX> is described alternately as having "a
ferocious display of inventive power" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkus Reviews</ENAMEX> ) and as having "a
disconcerting hollowness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree on the flashes of brilliance in her writing; the disagreement is
over how consistently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knox</ENAMEX> puts it all together. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> more about the book at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blind Man's Bluff: The Untold Story of American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Submarine Espionage</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Sontag</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Drew</ENAMEX>, with Annette
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Drew</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book--
                  Opened Ground: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selected Poems</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966-1996</TIMEX> , by Seamus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heaney</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Unknown Matisse: A Life</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Matisse</ENAMEX>, The Early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years, 1869-1908</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilary Spurling</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Star Trek: Insurrection</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rushmore</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Simple Plan</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Frost</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tempest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Room</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hare</ENAMEX> (Cort
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Psycho</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Central Station</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Hard Core Logo</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Voice</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McEwan</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edo: Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1615-1868</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>);

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Electra</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophocles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ethel Barrymore Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>).

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Babe: Pig in the City</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Fries</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>: Ringmaster ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Very Bad Things</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Rum Diary: The Long Lost</ENAMEX>
Novel , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
