
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Drawing upon her rich experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions about manners, personal relations, politics, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries
should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your letter
to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Pru!
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> married (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years ago</TIMEX>) a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who,
while talented and charming when in the mood, turned out to be very abusive
(verbally) and have a major bad temper. This affected her well-being but,
instead of concentrating on the marriage or seeking treatment for him, she
decided to blame our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> for all her ills ... including the choice of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
            

            
               She spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
talking about the "abuse" we were subjected to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were
not perfect, but about average, or maybe a drop below. I believe that dwelling
on the past is just an excuse and easier than dealing with the present. What
can be done to convince her that, despite all the psychobabble we are exposed
to, the past is not as important as the present? I want her to get on with her
life, get help for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, and stop driving my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and everybody in
the family nuts.
            

            
               Respectfully,
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forward-Looking</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear For,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s guess is that your sib has not been
receptive to your suggestions, so save your breath to cool your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX>. Your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s life has not turned out as she had hoped, and her way of coping is to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apportion</ENAMEX> blame. Unfortunately, in her game of emotional Tag, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are
"it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes you will
disengage from the marital psychodrama and be as supportive as possible to your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>. Also, in the name of self-defense, you might decline to listen to your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s version of her difficulties. Simply say that you, for whatever reason,
did not experience any parental abuse, and you wish her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> in what is,
essentially, a private matter: her marriage.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, palliatively

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Why assume that a benefaction to animals
wouldn't be beneficial to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--including the homeless? (See the letter from
"."
               ) Here in our unnamed fair <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, we have a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of feral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>--and our share of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX>. Feral <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> have been known to attack
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> and their food supplies! Feral <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> in poor neighborhoods like
mine spread <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, and their large number can make you feel you're living in
a litter box.
            

            
               Please send some of
those animal dollars our way and neuter these poor neglected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> ... for
all our sakes.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear D.</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> is not the dispenser of the windfall
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, but she cannot disagree with any of the points you make. She had
always been aware of feral <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodness</ENAMEX>, if the city
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> don't get a hold of this situation, there's going to be Rigor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> on a grand scale ... loosely translated, too many dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you
badger the proper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to do something about all the
livestock roaming the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, supportively

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               Weighing in on the "Have a nice day" debate
(for a recent entry, click ); look up the etymology of "nice" in a good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictionary</ENAMEX> (I used <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX> ), and you'll find that the root
meaning of the word is "stupid, foolish, ignorant." If you think about this,
this explains a lot. "Have a nice day" is a subtle insult, and instinctively we
all know this.
            

            
               Personally, I like
to say, "It's good to see you" (when it is). Otherwise I just say,
"Hello."
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rosenthal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sedona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dave</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels so much
better knowing the subversive underpinning of that goofy greeting. Bless
you.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, appreciatively

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               The reason "" does not have a long-term
relationship that is good for her is due to her willingness to settle for
crumbs, i.e., "something is better than nothing." The fact is, her attitudes
are actions that have led to her current state.
            

            
               She needs to get rid
of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>, get herself into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insight psychotherapy</ENAMEX>, and get rid of
anyone in her life who tells her all the good ones are married or gay. If she
is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX>, she needs to get rid of that, as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> do not go for fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, regardless of the stories one may hear.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faithful Reader</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Faith</ENAMEX>,

            Thank you for being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX>.

            What, by the way, is
"insight psychotherapy"? And just for the record, there are, in fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--called "chubby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chasers</ENAMEX>"--who, for whatever reason, do like generously
proportioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, expansively

         
      
   
