
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">192</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Where It's At&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fill in the blank in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville Gilbert Brim</ENAMEX>'s report on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 year</TIMEX>
study funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacArthur Foundation</ENAMEX>: "On balance, the sense we all have is
that ________ is the best place to be."
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 191</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enlistment Drive":</ENAMEX>
               

               

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> are rumored
to be on a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">118</NUMEX>. List of what?
               

               "Those
brave enough to have lunch with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfa-Betty Olsen</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Star</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

               "Less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lame</ENAMEX>-ass settings for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Misanthrope</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wherever Uma Thurman</ENAMEX> thinks she is."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
               

               
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oppressors</ENAMEX>. By the way, I'm a sophomore in college."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen</ENAMEX>
Werthmann
               

               "And if
you don't think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> can be a setting for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molière</ENAMEX>, you obviously haven't seen my modern-dress <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scapin</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trickster</ENAMEX> set inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ehrlichman</ENAMEX>'s rotting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>
               

               "Former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> of the late, great <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Juliet Prowse</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
               

               "They
all play chess by mail with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn vos Savant</ENAMEX>, and she kicks their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ass</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
               

               Click
for more answers.

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
               

               In lieu of the usual wrap-up, here's a little more
from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Line of Duty: true life</ENAMEX> experiences from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>," a
supplement to the catalog of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gall's Inc.</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> to public
safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>." It's an excerpt from a story by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Webb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX>, of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Munson Urgent Care Clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Traverse City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>

               "Surprise! No bullet in the pelvis! An abdominal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> also failed to turn up the elusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>. Where could it be? There was
nothing that could be construed as even a fragment of a bullet. Certainly,
nothing was evident over the pubic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>. Nor was the bone fractured. Bullets
don't just vaporize!

               "While pondering this, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> remembered that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramedics</ENAMEX> had a lot of difficulty getting his zipper down. She looked at his
pants more closely, noting that the zipper was deformed. Behind the zipper and
in front of the protective cloth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> overlying the zipper, she found the
spent bullet."

               It's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Humor in Uniform</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>? He's going to be just fine. "He was started on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antibiotics</ENAMEX> and discharged with follow-up instructions and pain medication."
Happy ending.

               
                  Dynamite
Answer
               

               All are thought to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace</ENAMEX>
Prize.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geir Lundestad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel Institute</ENAMEX>,
confirmed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have been nominated for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prize</ENAMEX>, but he may not reveal particular names.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s parliaments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> of law or history, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureates</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peace Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> may make nominations. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> member
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> meets on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 26</TIMEX> to pare down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> to a short list.
International <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> will be chosen to report on those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The winner
named in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $965,000</NUMEX>, a gold medal, a diploma, and the
knowledge that he's done as much for peace as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>.

               
                  Either/Or
Extra:
               

               

                  "If you're a camper, it can be
a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">treat</ENAMEX>. They run right over your face when you're in a sleeping bag," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Davis</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Channel Islands National Park</ENAMEX>--referring either to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> scavenging for gags or to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer mice infested</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hantavirus</ENAMEX>.

                  "This is a very obedient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. When they were told to come, even if they did not really understand this
issue, they came," said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Zilbershlag</ENAMEX>--referring either to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
contributing to the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> theme issue or to demonstrating
ultra-orthodox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Before Schindler</ENAMEX>'s
List , I found actual events dry and boring," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>--referring to the revivifying effects of either mass death or to
non-fiction storytelling.

                  "At our meetings there's
panic," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio Pinetti</ENAMEX>--referring either to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> as it contemplates the next elections or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian Vending</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> as it contemplates the massive task of retrofitting his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
machines to accept euros.

                  "The fundamental question is
would we be better off fighting it together or separately?" said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> action against either those pesky Wayans
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brothers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smugglers</ENAMEX>.

               

               
                  Common
Denominator
               

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gaydar</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
