
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> Grieves

            A wave of emotion swept the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> following the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, but nowhere
more than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Maariv carried a huge picture of him under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>," while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> printed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew</ENAMEX> and
Arabic the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalom</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eitan Haber</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to the late <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX>, wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> , "If they lay a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">thousand flowers</ENAMEX> on your grave, one will be mine. ... If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> tears soak
your final resting place, one will drip from my eyes. ... I want to thank you,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost, for the peace. And I have no doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX> joins
in these warm thanks. He is waiting for you with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>'s handshake."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maariv</ENAMEX> , Chemi
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shalev</ENAMEX> also dwelt on the king's relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabin</ENAMEX>: "They were so
different, these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, yet they were very close. An introvert and impatient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> and a noble and generous monarch, whose objectives and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> joined."
He imagined them "up there" together, lighting cigarettes for each other and
talking old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' talk. Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maariv</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yosef Lapid</ENAMEX> wrote that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> might have made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> grave mistakes--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> when he joined <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s
abortive attempt to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> when he supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>--but he was nevertheless "the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> saw as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'an</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> who became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.' "

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Rubinstein</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> affairs,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">contrasted Israel</ENAMEX>'s outpouring of grief over the king's death to
the relative indifference of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. There are no special signs of
mourning among the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, he wrote, quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">East</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> is sadder and more concerned than we are."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubinstein</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Jerusalem</ENAMEX> were principally concerned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the weekend</TIMEX>'s fall in the value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> currency, the dinar, in
which they kept most of their savings. And he noted that in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nablus</ENAMEX> in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> there has been more pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> on display than of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hashemite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>.

            Other comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> focused on the aftermath of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s death and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
prospects under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Rothchild</ENAMEX>, a
former intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defence Forces</ENAMEX>, predicted that the
transfer of power in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> will take place "without many shocks" but that
there will be hard times ahead for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> economy
is in a deep recession, he wrote, and will get even worse unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX>
government urgently tackles unemployment, the stability of the currency, and
the trade balance. Another urgent problem is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> shortage, he
added, "If they do not solve it immediately, a drought in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> will lead
to intolerable dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothchild</ENAMEX> wrote that the "external threat" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> does
not seem especially grave at the moment, though there is the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
subversion with so many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> exiles on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> soil and at its borders. But
he said the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> will have to focus a lot of attention on preserving calm
within the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, which until now has been kept in order by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>,
with his absolute authority and "almost obsessive" concern for the maintenance
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> unity. On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the continuation of
the peace process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothchild</ENAMEX> urged that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> be allowed to deal with
other problems first. "All those with the welfare of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>,
as well as ours, at heart would do well not to force him to confront these
complex and sensitive issues at this time," he wrote.

            Writing for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zvi Bar'el</ENAMEX> noted that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX> had dubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> for the Internet age" and
suggested this might make his relations difficult with veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hosni Mubarak</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hafez Assad</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>. "Won't he have to prove that his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> credentials are no less solid
than theirs<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" he asked. But in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>'s favor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar'el</ENAMEX> pointed out that he
was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> monarch not to be weighed down by the trauma of losing
national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> not to have taken part in fateful
decisions about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and someone for whom peace with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> was a given
reality that did not need to be justified.

             

         
      
   
