
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">158</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prereq?</ENAMEX>"

            

               Clearance from the vice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX>, permission from a male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX> degree. Which does not belong? Why?
            

             

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 157</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst Things First":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               In his most recent public apology, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said that
congressional condemnation would be pretty bad, but "there is no greater agony"
than something he's suffered already. No greater agony than what?
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patch Adams</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Rickey</ENAMEX>
            

             

            
"Dandruff caused by the dry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Israeli winter</TIMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

             

            
"Finding out the hard way about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s new <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> foot buffer law."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

             

            "Being
crossed off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> card list."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Zicklin</ENAMEX>
            

             

            
"Finding that little note in the playbill that said, 'Due to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, the role
usually played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX> will be performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Schlessinger</ENAMEX>.'
"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

             

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Go to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, think
about what you did, and don't come out until you're really sorry. But how is
true remorse displayed? Many jailed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> demonstrated reformation by
finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. (I believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Colson</ENAMEX> found him in the weight
room.) Unfortunately for him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is already a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and so would gain
little by going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> to prove how sorry he is as a way of avoiding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>.
After a sitcom tiff, remorseful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>. (Wasn't it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> who,
after suspending habeas corpus, gave a single white rose to every registered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>? Well no, but he should have.) Another TV gesture of regret is
voluntarily giving up a desired pleasure, most often tickets to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rock</ENAMEX>
Concert forsworn by a chastened teen. (After packing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> had his little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fala roasted</ENAMEX> on a spit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Garden</ENAMEX>, if
memory serves. National forgiveness was instantaneous.) We knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Gleason</ENAMEX>
had learned his lesson when, at the end of an episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Honeymooners</ENAMEX>, he'd
turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audrey Meadows</ENAMEX> and say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby</ENAMEX>, you're the greatest," and then they'd
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hug</ENAMEX> and all was forgiven. Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> could say it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX>, her
generation's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Day</ENAMEX>, the personification of national virtue. She'd look him
in the eye and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> the sincerity of his apology--she'd know, too--and then
they'd hug and kiss (but no tongues!) and our long national nightmare would be
over. But of course, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> he'd have landed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> again, the
scamp! I of course refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Gleason</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truly Penitent</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            "Painful though the condemnation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
would be, it would pale in comparison to the consequences of the pain I have
caused my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. There is no greater agony."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also observed
that while he'd give anything (!) to go back and undo what he did, "that is
simply not possible," perhaps because of technical problems with that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> time
machine because if they could go back and undo stuff, I'll bet they'd save
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> or kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> long before they took trips for frivolous reasons, like
undoing sexual high jinks. Unless, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX> was in the mood for a
joy ride. You know, the nonsexual but pointless kind.

            
               Crime and
Punishment Extra
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Citywide Standards of Conduct and Uniform Disciplinary Measures</ENAMEX>,"
an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> page brochure issued to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, lists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> infractions in
ascending order of seriousness. Can you rank these infractions?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "Failing to wear the
required school uniform"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. "Wearing</ENAMEX> apparel that is
unsafe or materially disruptive to the educative process"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> "Smoking"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gambling</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Using</ENAMEX> profane or
obscene language or gestures"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. "Lying</ENAMEX> or giving false
information to school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. "Using</ENAMEX> slurs based upon
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, ethnicity, national origin, religion, gender, sexual orientation, or
disability"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H.</ENAMEX> "Defying the lawful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> of school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. "Possessing</ENAMEX> or using a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firearm</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>
"Using any weapon other than a firearm ... to inflict injury"

            

               Answers
            

            A-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>,
B-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-9</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-12</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-13</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-14</ENAMEX>, H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-36</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J-37</ENAMEX>.

            
               Extra
Credit
            

            Societies prescribe the
laws they feel they need. With that in mind, which of the following are listed
as <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Prohibited Weapons</ENAMEX>: Category <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Machine</ENAMEX> gun

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX> that conceals a
knife or sword

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. Bombs</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Dirk</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E. Acid</ENAMEX>
or deadly chemicals

            

               Answers
            

            All are Category 1
weapons except <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX>, that's Category 2.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
