
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintometer</ENAMEX>:
            

            

               2/12/99 Amid expectations that neither impeachment article
will get majority support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, both sides gear up for the aftermath.
Everyone agrees censure is doomed. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leak:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is furious at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for impeaching him and is determined to
drive them from office. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> leak: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is furious at the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>" who leaked that story before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote and is determined to
drive them from office. Chance of removal from office:
Zero.
            

            

               For the complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintometer</ENAMEX> and links to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's Flytrap
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">coverage,</ENAMEX> click .
            

            
A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> jury
found <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> liable for several deaths and injuries inflicted with
illegally obtained <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> concluded that negligent marketing and
distribution of handguns by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> was a "proximate cause" of three
recent shootings, despite the absence of proof that any particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
product was involved in any of the shootings. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> awarded damages
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> case. Gun control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> hailed the verdict as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in a
wave of lawsuits against <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, likening their movement to the one
against tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Libertarians</ENAMEX> and gun industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> condemned it
for the same reason. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/12/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> kicked off her image rehab tour. In
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> interview, she says <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) she acted in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
"best interest" by saving her from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s abuse; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) she had feared
that the affair would cause <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to harm herself; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) she regrets any pain
she has caused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) "As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, especially with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> close in age
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, I would hope some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would do for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> what I did for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica"</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) taping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, giving her name to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and
giving the tapes to the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s ideas. The
Times dryly offered that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s self-portrayal "might strain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">credulity</ENAMEX>." Biggest surprise: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> says that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should be censured,
expelling him from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> would be excessive. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/12/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>
scandal is spreading to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> issued an
investigative report on possible shenanigans in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano</ENAMEX>'s successful bid for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter Olympics</ENAMEX>. They say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> may
have violated minor rules by visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano</ENAMEX> more than once to evaluate the
site and/or bringing too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) they found no
other problems (contrary to previous reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were given
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">meals</ENAMEX>, geishas, and other favors); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) they regret that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano</ENAMEX>'s bid committee
burned its records <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the fact that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> sit on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> and that some served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Nagano</ENAMEX> bid committee posed
no conflict of interest. The upbeat spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano</ENAMEX>'s bid was more honest than
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>'s. The cynical spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s investigation is less honest than
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>'s. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/12/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Award nominations were announced. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare in Love</ENAMEX> gathered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nominations</ENAMEX>, beating Saving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> (which won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) and coming
within one of the record. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> agreed that the big theme is <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Thin Red Line</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about Guadalcanal</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful</ENAMEX> (about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>) were nominated for best picture.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> figures concocted shallow theories for this revival: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
want to learn from history; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) we want to understand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> because it's
now ending; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) boomer filmmakers are revisiting the great world events of their
childhood; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) they're visiting the war because they didn't fight it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> says his current film helped
veterans come to terms with the war, just as his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s
List helped <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>: "I feel privileged to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s
seat for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> films that helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to speak the truth." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> added the obligatory ethnic spins, noting that "black-themed
movies" were overlooked and that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> seemed to have colonized the
acting categories." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> is examining whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> misled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> when they sought approval to
investigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
Previous reports have said that beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1997</TIMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> had conversations with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> affiliated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. However, "newly disclosed notes" indicate that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> sought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s approval in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX>, they claimed to have had
"no contact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> wants to know whether this
assertion concealed a conflict of interest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has challenged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>'s authority to look into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s files.
The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> should fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> because he's become
a self-protecting monster. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> fires <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
will have become a self-protecting monster. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the T
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eletubbies</ENAMEX> is gay . Teletubbies
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in an eponymous TV show for preschool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Liberty Journal</ENAMEX> notes that one of the ostensibly male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX>, carries a purse, "is purple--the gay-pride color," and
"his antenna is shaped like a triangle--the gay-pride symbol." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> says
these "subtle depictions" are deliberate and that "role modeling the gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifestyle</ENAMEX> is damaging to the moral lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>." A Teletubbies
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX> carries a "magic bag," not a purse; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the magic
bag "doesn't make him gay"; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) "to think we would be putting sexual innuendo in
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s show is kind of outlandish"; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> is besmirching
"something sweet and innocent" to advance his right-wing agenda.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               King 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> died. The media praised
him as a great statesman, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of peace," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> called him "everyone's favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> moderate."
Speculation turned to whether his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>, can shore up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s ailing economy, retain the allegiance of its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>, and
advance the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process. While acknowledging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s
misdeeds--attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, hosting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and siding with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf War</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">editorialists</NUMEX> lavished
excuses on him: He feared a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> revolt if he didn't attack <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>, atoned for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> war by sitting out the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allied</ENAMEX> himself with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> because he feared an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> invasion or
collateral economic damage from the war against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> politely
overlooked the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> is still a monarchy. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Podhoretz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midge Decter</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s inflated reputation.)
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/9/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> is in the hot seat for testifying that he never
mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "stalker" description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist couple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carol Blue</ENAMEX>
signed affidavits claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> told them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
was a stalker. Blue says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had told him that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
had made unwanted "sexual advances." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subpoena Hitchens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> declined. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> now think the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> will look into the
matter. Cynics groaned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitchens</ENAMEX> was aiming at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> but has clumsily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shot Blumenthal</ENAMEX> instead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchens</ENAMEX>' spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) I was aiming at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) I said
no more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> has already admitted. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) I said no more than I had
already written. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) I'll go to jail rather than testify against my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> as "another human sacrifice" to appease the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of impeachment. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click for Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s take on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snitchensgate</ENAMEX>.")
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/9/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The
impeachment trial is spinning off new stories . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>
are inviting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> to investigate a rumor that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> taping system may have recorded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s phone
conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> says there's no such
system. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to look into allegations that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> improperly tried to cut an immunity deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> during their
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1998</TIMEX> sting without her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> present. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> note that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> has already ruled his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> broke no laws. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> voted overwhelmingly to oppose the renewal of the independent
counsel statute, concluding that it forces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to spend too much time
and money examining "minor matters" in pursuit of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/9/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
