
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in
Love
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who are in love: Gwyneth Paltrow
is gorgeous, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Fiennes</ENAMEX> is dashing, and the movie is "smart and giddily
entertaining" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiennes</ENAMEX>' young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
has an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paltrow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> that becomes the basis for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Norman</ENAMEX>'s screenplay is full of amusing
references to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> plays, but is not so erudite that it won't please
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crowds</ENAMEX>, and the dialogue "percolates with bubbly finesse" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX> puts a slight
damper on the general festivities: He says the film starts out muddled, though
it livens up by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. (Check out stills
from the film on this page, and read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s pan in

                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  Star <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trek:</ENAMEX>
Insurrection
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> installment in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> franchise unfolds like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hour</TIMEX> episode of the TV
series--"as warm and cozy as a pair of tribble fur-lined Spock ears on a cold
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">winter</ENAMEX>'s night" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). The action
takes place on a planet whose fountain of youth properties make it the envy of
malicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> will laugh at the inside jokes and
not mind the low-tech special effects. Everyone else will find the film hokey
and overburdened with "pseudoscientific terminology" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               , and visit the official <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> site, where
you can buy <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek mugs</ENAMEX>, posters, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards.)

            
               
                  Rushmore
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). "[B]lessed with a vivid sense of humor and an artistic
integrity unlike those of any other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX> working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>" is how
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX> describes the work of writing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team Owen Wilson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Anderson</ENAMEX> (who also paired up on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> underground
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hit Bottle Rocket</ENAMEX> ). The film, directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>, follows newcomer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jason Schwartzman</ENAMEX> as a dorky, overachieving high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who competes with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Murray</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s affections. The film is "from deep in left
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>--immaculately written, unexpectedly touching" and is full of "exuberance
and innocence" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Giles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). A few complain that the movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lags</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rainier</ENAMEX> criticizes it for "callowness."
(Visit the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Murray Action News</ENAMEX>" page, which follows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s every move.)

            
               
                  A Simple
Plan
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Raimi</ENAMEX>'s dark morality fable impresses
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>: It's a "rivetingly accomplished crime thriller" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> who happen on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> that's crashed into a snow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Bob Thornton</ENAMEX>
turn in performances that "can be described only as flawless" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> have some reservations: The moral
deterioration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> is hard to watch, and the inevitability of the
plot's outcome can be stifling. But the overall verdict is that the director
has a sure hand. (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> likes the film but
calls some of the plot devices "a bit cheap." Read the rest of his review
here.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Frost</ENAMEX>
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). This film about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> reincarnated as a snowman so that he may
comfort his grieving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is said to be "treacly and fake" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). The animatronic snowman (with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Keaton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>) looks like a "large, wisecracking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marshmallow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>" (the New York
Times ) and is described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX> as "the most repulsive single creature in
the history of special effects." ("Never have I disliked a movie character
more," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX> adds.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX> calls <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last hour of</TIMEX>
the film "brain-damaging." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>,
the film's only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, praises its "sweet spirit and astute humor." (Visit the official site.)

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  The
Tempest
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shakespeare</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 13</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> racks up
another bust. This loose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil War-era</ENAMEX> adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tempest</ENAMEX> is called "[a] miscalculation of epic proportions ... at times
laugh-out-loud awful, at times offensive" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daryl H. Miller</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ). The film uses only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lines of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s actual poetry (but is
otherwise peppered with cheesy "I reckon"s). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Fonda</ENAMEX>, who plays the
Prospero equivalent, is called "stone-faced and clueless" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Parks</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). (
Read this interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonda</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX>
Room
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hare</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cort Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX> bares
all! Who cares what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hare</ENAMEX> did with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schnitzler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Ronde</ENAMEX>
when there's celebrity flesh to be drooled over? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>! They receive
the play coldly, even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> run is almost sold out. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Blue Room</ENAMEX> "a deft, efficient and
sometimes amusing piece of work ... [t]he entire <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> is not unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kidman</ENAMEX>'s
much-discussed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>: smooth, pale, and slender." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the play has
"outlived [its] raciness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Patrick Stearns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). Although
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Ronde</ENAMEX> was banned at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>, nowadays its account of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexual</ENAMEX> encounters among various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (all played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidman</ENAMEX> and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iain Glen</ENAMEX>) seems pretty tame. The play is "an aesthetic non-event, an
anticlimax of proportions inevitably commensurate with its avalanche of advance
publicity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Isherwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> ). (Order tickets to the show
online.)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Psycho</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Central Station</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Hard Core Logo</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Voice</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McEwan</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edo: Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1615-1868</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>);

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Electra</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophocles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ethel Barrymore Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>).

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pig</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Fries</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>: Ringmaster ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Very Bad Things</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Rum Diary: The Long Lost</ENAMEX>
Novel , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 25</TIMEX>:
            

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Enemy of the</ENAMEX>
State;

               
                  Movie --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rugrats Movie</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waking Ned</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devine</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Bug</ENAMEX>'s
Life ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- I Will Bear Witness: A</ENAMEX>
Diary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years, 1933-1941</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Klemperer</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- American Beach: A Saga</ENAMEX>
of Race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wealth</ENAMEX>, and Memory , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Rymer</ENAMEX>;

               

                  Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winchell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>).

            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 18</TIMEX>:
            

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Meet Joe</ENAMEX>
Black ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- I'll Be Home for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- I Still Know What You</ENAMEX>
Did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Summer</TIMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dancing</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lughnasa</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Fashionable Nonsense:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postmodern Intellectuals' Abuse of Science</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sokal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bricmont</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Spirit</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jewel</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
