
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintometer</ENAMEX>:
            

            

               
                  1/29/99
                Along party lines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> kills a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> plan for the rest of the trial (skip the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and forbid
videotaping of their testimony) and passes a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> plan (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>,
videotaping, and likely completion of the trial by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 12</TIMEX>, with the option of
a majority vote to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> guilty on the facts but not remove him from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> say the guilty-without-removal verdict is unconstitutional.
The conventional media spin: It's a partisan meltdown. The conspiratorial spin:
Both sides are faking a partisan meltdown so they can each look good to their
respective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX>.. Chance of removal from office:
Zero.
            

            

               For the complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintometer</ENAMEX> and links to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's Flytrap
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">coverage,</ENAMEX> click .
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is worrying about the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Hussein</ENAMEX> , who has
brokered key peace efforts between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, has
suffered a relapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lymphatic cancer</ENAMEX>. Everyone expects him to die soon. A few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days ago</TIMEX>, he flew home, dismissed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>, as his successor
and replaced him with the king's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>
and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of political intrigue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of the move say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>
will make a more stable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> because, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>, he has solid ties to the
military and to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX> is older and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wiser</ENAMEX> and an established economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> lacks political
and economic experience. Some think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> has lost his mind. Everyone hopes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> lives up to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s legacy. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/29/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, accepted the resignation of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> for using the
word "niggardly ." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> is black; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Howard</ENAMEX>, is white.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> context: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Niggardly</ENAMEX>" means stingy. It is totally unrelated to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
word." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) In a meeting with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> said, "I will have to be
niggardly with this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> because it's not going to be a lot of money." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) One
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, who was black, stormed out, and rumors spread that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
had uttered a racist remark. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> resigned because although his remark
bore no racist intent, he had failed to consider how it would be perceived. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> accepted his resignation on the same grounds. Conservative talk radio
is having a field day with the story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Bond</ENAMEX> says people
shouldn't have to censor their own speech to accommodate their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>'
ignorance. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) This is political correctness run amok. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It's about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensitivity</ENAMEX>, not intent. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It's about black <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>. (A leading black lawyer
asked, "Do we really know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegians</ENAMEX> got the word?") <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) It's
political correctness gridlock, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> is gay, and gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> are
now pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> to rehire him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> shamefully caved. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> had to cave because he lacks credibility with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, because he's
"not black enough." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/29/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel</ENAMEX>
Carnahan, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D-Mo.</ENAMEX>, spared a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>'s life at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s request. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">murderer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darrell Mease</ENAMEX>, was scheduled to die <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX>. While visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnahan</ENAMEX> to spare him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnahan commuted Mease</ENAMEX>'s
sentence to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> but said he still supports the death penalty and
made an exception for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mease</ENAMEX> only because of "the coincidence of the pope being
there" and "making a personal request that I chose to respond to." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pondered</ENAMEX> why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s request worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>, whereas similar pontifical
pleas for mercy have failed in the past. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> is teaching
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> that capital punishment is wrong. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are
teaching the pope that face-to-face visits and requests for personal favors are
more effective than appeals to principle. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mease</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, "God
was on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darrell</ENAMEX>'s side and God is the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> you can get. He's never lost a
case." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/29/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
Pope
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul II</ENAMEX> made his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> mainland. His
official message was that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> must turn away from a "culture of death" that
includes abortion, assisted suicide, and capital punishment. The latter issue
stirred the most controversy, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> had executed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> shortly
before the pope arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>. Oddest moment: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>'s comparison of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelism</ENAMEX> to the home run exploits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Sosa</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, escorted him, and pledged that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would pursue "justice," virtues," and "goodness." The pope
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clasped Clinton</ENAMEX>'s hands, smiled at him, said nothing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
scandal, and focused on policy instead. Reporters marveled anew at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
ability to change the subject, milk world icons for their moral stature, and
repeatedly seduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/27/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> could not use statistical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sampling</ENAMEX> to adjust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> count for congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reapportionment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of the traditional method (counting each household)
argue that this method misses isolated and hard-to-track <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, which are
disproportionately black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>. Since these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> tend to vote
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to use sampling, i.e., mathematical projection, to
theorize as to how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the head count missed in various locations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> vehemently oppose this idea. The superficial analysis is that the
court struck down sampling and hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. The sophisticated analysis
is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> nixed sampling only for the apportionment of congressional
votes among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, not for drawing district lines. Therefore, within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will try to use sampling to give black and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> areas more
representation at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> expense. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> spin is that "every
individual ought to be counted." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> spin is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> shouldn't have
to pay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two</TIMEX> census methods. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/27/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>
suffered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its worst</TIMEX> earthquake since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1875</TIMEX>. The quake killed at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 180,000</NUMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> coverage of the story
rapidly descended from humanitarian anguish to material cynicism to petty
curiosity. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Colombia Quake Toll Passes 700</ENAMEX>."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>'s headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quake Survivors Guard Belongings</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>'s headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quake Won't Hurt Coffee Production</ENAMEX>." The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> story
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> remaining worry is not that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> will be unavailable
            

            
The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> expelled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> for
accepting cash and other gifts as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>'s successful lobbying
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter Olympics</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have resigned or are still
being investigated. Meanwhile, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said he gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> just before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> awarded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer Olympics</ENAMEX> by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-vote margin. Cynics, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, (which hosted the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Winter games</ENAMEX>) have already burned their
documents, predict the expanding investigation will show that corruption has
permeated <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> site selection for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> promises to stop this
corruption by taking away <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX>' voting rights and halting their visits to
prospective host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>' spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> is corrupt throughout, and
the expulsions are a cover-up. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> won't really be cleaned up until
embarrassed corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> threaten to pull out. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/25/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The first
hand transplant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was performed. This follows a hand
transplant performed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX>. Prior to that, an attempt in the
1960s had failed because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> rejected the new hand as foreign
tissue. The rosy spin: Potent anti-rejection <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> now make it possible to
prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> from rejecting a new hand. The grim spin: The anti-rejection
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> can cause infection and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and since a hand isn't an essential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">organ</ENAMEX>, it isn't worth that risk. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/25/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
