
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Triple
Threats
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Re Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>'s
"Chatterbox" item "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Achenbach</ENAMEX> explained the three
name serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> phenomenon in a column included in his book Why Things
Are . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> names for such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to minimize the number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with similar names mistakenly thought by distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>, high-school
sweethearts, and potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> (and to minimize possible
lawsuits from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy Gacys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Onderdunk Tuckers</ENAMEX> of the world).
Of course, it's hard to imagine anyone making that mistake in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
case--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> they're impeaching the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> who used to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> tires over <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">at Pep Boys?</ENAMEX>" So you are correct to say the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-namedness is
rather unnecessary here.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randolph B. Cohen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>

            
               Time Is What's
Heavy
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atul Gawande</ENAMEX> throws out
some interesting hypotheses about the link between obesity and poverty in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "." Here's another: Perhaps the future is more valuable to rich people
than to poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Every time someone eats a piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> (or smokes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cigarette</ENAMEX>), they are implicitly trading "future life minutes" for current
sensual pleasures. If we assume that almost everyone derives the same amount of
pleasure from a given piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>, then the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> you will eat
depends upon how much "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>" you assign to your life in the future. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> may be happier overall and may therefore attribute more value to the
"future life minutes" that they would be giving up by eating that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>. This
would cause <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> to eat less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> (and to quit smoking and to exercise
more).

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim DeRoche</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real Skinny on</ENAMEX>
Being <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fat</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re Atul Gawande</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Why Money Won't Buy Fat": Has Dr. Gawande</ENAMEX> never shopped for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX>?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> in a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> tells the tale. Healthy eating is
expensive .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Kimball Middleton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways To Say</ENAMEX>
"I Cheated on You"
            

            I liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s article "." Here's a
political glossary that might be helpful in interpreting future lies.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Indiscretion": Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Prior indiscretion(s)": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youthful</ENAMEX> indiscretion(s)": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Private matters": Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Deeply private matter": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Zone of privacy": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Private lives of public figures": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Prior misjudgment(s)": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "My poor judgment": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inappropriate relationship": Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inappropriate behavior": Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Not sex": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Not relations": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Strayed from my vows": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "This poor sinner": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "I'm no saint": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "What I did was wrong": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pain in my marriage": Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Between me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "It gets lonely in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "Power is an aphrodisiac": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            "It's none of your
business": <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adultery</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Mashberg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>

            
               Lies <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are Lies Are</ENAMEX>
Lies
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Re Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lies, Damned Lies, and Impeachment</ENAMEX>": If you want a starker example of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> lying, what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>? Yes, I know that there is no
definite proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> lied under oath to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> subcommittee
when he said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>'s allegations were false, but if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> believes that felony perjury is impeachable, aren't they obliged to
thoroughly investigate the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> lied?

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Srinivasan Sethuraman Princeton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

            
               Guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Guilty Is</ENAMEX>
Guilty
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lies, Damned Lies</ENAMEX>, and
Impeachment" seems to argue that if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> criminal "gets away with it," then all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> should be able to do likewise. That hardly seems defensible.

            The only valid argument
is that you don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> actually broke the law. If you believe that
he broke the law, then he must be held accountable. Whether that's now or after
his term is over I suppose could be up for discussion, although it's hard for
me to believe that any rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could believe that in the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">atmosphere Clinton</ENAMEX> will be able to be an effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (regardless of who
is to blame).

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Tavares</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>

            
               The Greatest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Since Nixon</ENAMEX>
            

            More and more--and
particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lies, Damned Lies</ENAMEX>, and
Impeachment"--I notice that the main line of defense for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is to
compare him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might be worse. This usually means <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Isn't there any argument to be made that originates in some
redeeming value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Keller St. Albans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.V.</ENAMEX>

            
               Laughing All the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
            

            As a sometimes evidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, I read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gottlieb</ENAMEX>'s item "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Blind Must Justice Be?</ENAMEX>" with interest. He states, "If by
laughing [the] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> intended to say 'we don't believe you,' it is hearsay
and therefore inadmissible." This is wrong both as a statement of the hearsay
rule and as a prediction of the likely outcome in this case.

            First, the rule: A large amount--probably most--of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hearsay</ENAMEX> is admissible. That's because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Rules of Evidence</ENAMEX> (which
apply at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial) contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> exceptions to the hearsay rule, some
of them gaping. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rule 807</ENAMEX>, the so-called "catch-all exception,"
permits hearsay to be admitted if it is the best available evidence of a
material fact and "the interests of justice will best be served by [its]
admission"--a big window!

            Now, application of rule
to facts: If the question posed ever came up, I am sure the evidence would be
admitted, under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rule 807</ENAMEX>. That's because the danger that the out-of-court
statement is a lie (the primary danger against which the hearsay rule protects)
is negligible when it is the simultaneous statement of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. This
is what my evidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Graham</ENAMEX>, referred to as "Surreptitious
Principle No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>." A little bit of hearsay is bad, but a whole lot of it is
good!

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernstein New York City</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
