
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">STARTING MONDAY IN</ENAMEX> 
               
                  Slate
               
               :
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Podhoretz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midge Decter</ENAMEX> chew over the news in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>."
And save your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skip</ENAMEX> the talk shows and let "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundit Central</ENAMEX>" brief you on
them; it's posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>.
            

            
               Length
Matters
            

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> complained about the length of last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
               . This is the document available by
e-mail or download around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, containing a week's worth
of 
                  Slate
                goodies nicely formatted for printout on standard size
paper. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>'s was especially long (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX> pages) because it included our
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> "
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>" list of rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ranked by their
contributions to charity. But even in a normal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, 
                  Slate on
Paper
                has been running around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55-60</NUMEX> pages.

            Meanwhile, some America
Online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have complained about not getting their 
                  Slate
               
e-mail at all. This was an AOL screw up, but we've straightened it out. We
hope.

            As for the length problem: We used to limit 
                  Slate on
Paper
                to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> pages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> complained that we were leaving out their
favorite stuff. So, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>, we asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> whether they would prefer
a file containing everything in 
                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>. The overwhelming
answer was "yes." Even though it will take longer to download? Yes. Even though
it will require more pages to print out? Yes. You're absolutely sure, are you?
Oh yes. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mommy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Daddy</ENAMEX> don't want to send you a great big file if
you're not going to want it. Oh yes, we want it.

            So for those who think

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                is too long, you're apparently in the minority.
And like all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> in our melting-pot society, you should try to blend in
and not be so conspicuous. Keep quiet and work hard. Consider marrying an
"include-it-all" and raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that way. They'll grow up to play
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> and download the long version of 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
               , and you'll
feel like a real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> did raise a good question: Why doesn't the

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                file allow you to choose which articles you wish
to print out instead of all or nothing at all? The answer, as to so much in
life, is: We're working on that. (Or, as 
                  Slate
               's crack software
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> puts it, in the strange argot of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>: "Yeah, yeah,
yeah, we're working on that.")

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> has wasted far too much time
poking around the many byways and cul-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">de</ENAMEX>-sacs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX>, looking for
some quick and dirty solution to this dilemma. Although we say so as a sister
division of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, Word is an amazing and underappreciated piece of
software. Amazing for the things it can do and underappreciated because no one
knows about them. No one knows about them primarily because software
instruction manuals get thinner and thinner. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Word</ENAMEX>'s online Help (in recent
versions an annoying talking paper clip that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> quite rightly refuse
to interact with) doesn't seem to know about some things the program can do.
What other industry besides software goes to the trouble of improving its
product and then keeps the improvements a secret?

            Nevertheless, if you use
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Word</ENAMEX> version of 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate on Paper</ENAMEX>
                (we also offer an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe Acrobat</ENAMEX> version) a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word</ENAMEX>'s features can help you to print out
just the articles you want. They're a bit clumsy for this purpose, but they do
the job.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Outline View</ENAMEX>. With the slate.doc file on your screen, on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">View</ENAMEX> menu, click Outline . (Or, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> versions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Word,</ENAMEX> click the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> in the lower-left corner of the Word
window--just above the page number.) If you then click <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> on the
Outline toolbar that will have appeared (with any luck), you
should get a list of 
                     Slate
                  's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>"
through "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>." At the left of each item is a plus sign. If you click once
on the plus sign, you have selected that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. You can then print the
selection (an option on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word Print</ENAMEX> menu). Or you can select and
delete all the articles you don't want and print the whole remaining
document. Or, if you want to get fancy, you can create a blank document in a
new window, and then drag and drop the articles you want into it.

            

            
               You also can
double-click the plus sign for any one listing or hit one of the higher numbers
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outline</ENAMEX> toolbar to affect the whole file and expose various
sub-levels of headline, posted date, etc. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> (such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moneybox</ENAMEX>," etc.) that consist of multiple items, you can hit the plus
sign and do your stuff for just the items you want.
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master Document</ENAMEX> view. This is a recherché
variation on Outline view, also available on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">View</ENAMEX> menu. It
allows you to turn various subdivisions of a file into separate files, which
you can then move around or otherwise submit to your will. Try this: Select a
department you want to print (it can't be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>, for
some damned reason) and hit the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Create Subdocument</ENAMEX>" toolbar icon. (It's a tiny
horizontal rectangle inside a vertical rectangle with a turned-down upper-right
flap--just as you would have guessed.) Your selected piece is now a separate
file, set in an attractive gray box. You can drag'n'drop the other stuff you
want into that box, double-click the little square icon in the upper-left
corner of the box to expand the file, then hit Print . It might
work.

            

            There has got to be a way--using these and other Word
features such as macros, templates, fields, styles, and so on to make a simple
selective-printout menu that either could be built into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>'s 
                  Slate
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX>
                file or could be offered as a downloadable tool. What about
using "hidden text"? (Hidden from screen view but printed? Or visible on screen
but not printed?) Or the automatic table of contents generator? (Could the
whole text be turned into a table of contents? What on earth for?) Strictly as
an amateur, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> has tried them all and admits defeat.

            Is there another amateur among 
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who would like to pick up the challenge? If you beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> to a
solution, we will name it after you, and you'll be immortalized in this little
corner of cyberspace.

         
      
   
