
   
   
      
         
            Ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Fischer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwartzman</ENAMEX>), the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Anderson</ENAMEX>'s well-reviewed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">comedy Rushmore</ENAMEX> , looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> with his face pinched between a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX>'s thumb and forefinger so that his tiny eyes are squashed together and
his big nose and teeth pop out. With his thick black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glasses</ENAMEX>, he looks as if
he's being photographed through a fishbowl, an effect that the director
intensifies by shooting much of the movie with a fishbowl lens. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at a
prestigious prep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushmore Academy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> travels amid décor that has
a cartoon flatness of perspective and is painted in near luminous primary
colors, with some added deep brown, green, crimson, and gold leaf to convey the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX>'s toniness. Intent on erecting a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aquarium</ENAMEX> to
impress a prim <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> with whom he's obsessed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> himself seems
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">king fish</ENAMEX> of a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tank</ENAMEX>.

            How we are intended to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">view Max</ENAMEX> is the overriding--albeit unstated--question raised by
Rushmore , which played the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New York Film Festival</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX>, opened
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> to qualify for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Awards, and begins a nationwide run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. My first impression was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max</ENAMEX>
is supposed to be vaguely repulsive, but after spending some time with him (and
seeing the movie again) I decided that there was nothing vague about it--he's
just repulsive. My take, I concede, is not the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Wilson</ENAMEX> (who starred in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>'s last film, the tediously
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">quirky 1996 Bottle</ENAMEX> 
               Rocket ), play a funny game with their
indefatigable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, they let us know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> is a screw-up
and a hustler; on the other, they collude with him in myriad ways, to the point
of warping their mise en scène to reflect his worldview and enhance his
stature. It's this tension that leads some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to regard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rushmore</ENAMEX> as
having dramatic complexity, but I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> are just trying to
have it both ways. Like their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, they spend a lot of time patting themselves
on the back for being aggressively unconventional.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> died when he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> and whose elderly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is a barber, attends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rushmore</ENAMEX> on a scholarship but is one of the
school's worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The movie merrily relates the ways in which he
compensates for poverty and academic disgrace. He tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that his father
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neurosurgeon</ENAMEX>. He is shown leading the debate society, the fencing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, the chess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, and the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Fischer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Players</ENAMEX>," who perform
wildly inappropriate dramatizations of such films as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serpico</ENAMEX> to
undiscriminating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>. He has, we are told, spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">petitioning</ENAMEX> to have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> expunged from the curriculum; now, to impress the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teacher</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olivia Williams</ENAMEX>), he campaigns to have the course restored. When a
self-made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire businessman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Murray</ENAMEX>) delivers a cynical, derisive
speech to the privileged student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> recognizes a kindred spirit and
aggressively befriends the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX>, eventually enlisting him in his extravagant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aquarium</ENAMEX> scheme.

            How, I repeat, are we
supposed to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>? Are we to cheer his ludicrous efforts to bed a woman
twice his age? Is it supposed to be cute when he sites the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">aquarium</ENAMEX> in the
middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamond</ENAMEX> and brings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bulldozers</ENAMEX> without
informing anyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> are poker faced:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>'s obnoxiousness might be meant as a state of grace.

            R ushmore does captures something of adolescence that
few movies come near: It often unfolds in a narcissistic trance. That's not a
negligible feat. What I wanted, however, was a larger perspective, something
more insightful than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-thing-after-another existential whimsy that made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottle Rocket</ENAMEX> such a trial. In one scene, ripped off from My Left
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foot</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> gets drunk in the course of a celebratory dinner and
insults the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX>: "I have a hit play. What did you ever do?" His
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">churlishness</ENAMEX> isn't compelling, it's just an embarrassment, a callow cry for
attention. "<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> me!" says the character, and you say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Why?</ENAMEX>"

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>
has the right combination of standoffishness and warmth, but she's more
colorless than this passive part requires. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, in a dry, "straight" turn,
lowers the volume on his wiseacre act, confining his trademark irony to an
occasional glint in the eye and, in the face of crisis, an escalating air of
gonzo dissolution. He's fine, but the raves (and the awards) for this
performance are baffling. Much more fun is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Cox</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushmore</ENAMEX>'s headmaster.
A truly weird <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhunter</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), made for an eerier
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannibal Lecter than Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cox</ENAMEX> rules with the kind of settled
irritability that suggests why prep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are petri dishes for acts of
adolescence defiance.

            In the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts & Leisure</ENAMEX>" section of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> recounts how he traveled to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshires</ENAMEX> to
show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushmore</ENAMEX> to the retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline</ENAMEX>
Kael, from whose writing, he says, he learned to watch movies. Hoping for an
ecstatic reaction from this most vital of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, he found instead an old
woman hobbled by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's disease</ENAMEX>, and one whose response to his film was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gnomic</ENAMEX> and gently dismissive. Bummer, huh? So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> turned around and wrote
up the encounter, in a way designed both to deflate his own persona and to make
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sport of Kael</ENAMEX>'s infirmities and memory lapses.

            I met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kael</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX> while I was writing
criticism for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> , but only got to know her after she
retired from The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> . In general, she's a lot more lucid
than, for instance, me. The memory lapses over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> were caused by
something else, specifically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sinemet</ENAMEX>, a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that has been
the talk of various Web sites devoted to the disease. The consensus is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication mitigates</ENAMEX> crippling tremors but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> need to have their levels
monitored carefully because too much can leave you muddled. It was in this
phase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kael's Sinemet</ENAMEX> trial that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> made his appearance with film cans
in tow--and poised to tell the world that she no longer remembered who Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> was.

            Given the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of her health at the time, it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gracious of Kael</ENAMEX> to entertain this chucklehead for even a minute--a mistake she
probably won't make again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, probably doesn't realize that
he did anything unseemly. "What do you expect?" said a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. "He's like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rushmore</ENAMEX> , a callow narcissist." At least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in
Rushmore confines his aesthetic offenses to high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditoriums</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
