
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 23</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial chastises <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for remaining
loyal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, calling their fidelity "a mixture of opportunism
and delusion." The opportunism: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have stuck with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> because his
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">poll</ENAMEX> numbers are high and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have botched impeachment. The delusion:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> credit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for national prosperity he has nothing to do
with. ... A story notes the decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s political right, which
now runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> country in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. As in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> left has co-opted the right's policies. The emerging, alarming trend:
Center-right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are beginning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> with neofascists such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Front</ENAMEX>. ... A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> page package on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nordic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--it's more
interesting than it sounds, OK?--concludes that they're not all alike. They are
badly split over the questions of the euro and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordic</ENAMEX> neutrality. But all still
have thriving economies, lavish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, and too-high taxes.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover bypasses
impeachment and instead goes with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>package. A review slams
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soros</ENAMEX>' "embarrassingly banal" new book, which was "rushed into print" in order
to play up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX>' views on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> crises. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soros</ENAMEX>' economic
theories, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> (an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>) argues, are naive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simplistic</ENAMEX>, and occasionally flat-out wrong. Another article asks: Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX>
kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> ruble by predicting its death? (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Answer: No.</ENAMEX>) ... On the
impeachment scene, one hand-wringing article decries the triumph of
partisanship over any meaningful ideological principle. Another proposes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> take a constitutionally permitted "temporary leave" while the
impeachment trial continues (he can come back after he wins in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>).

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 24</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX> relives the enviable rise--and precipitous fall--of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term</ENAMEX>
Capital. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, a Wall Street convert himself, interviews media hermit and
Long-Term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mastermind</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Meriwether</ENAMEX> and his legion of smart "young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>"
who gambled on market hyper-rationality to power their finance strategy (as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> explains, "things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did with money when they were frightened was an
opportunity for more reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to exploit"). What sequence of events
beat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000-to-1</NUMEX> odds and crunched Long-Term? Retrospectively, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> ruble debacle was but the precipitating event; an expanding web
of media and finance market rumors, plus Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX> out to plunder
Long-Term, ensured the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s collapse. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meriwether</ENAMEX> and his multimillionaire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> are back where they started--sentenced to work for a piteous <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> at
conventionally dreary Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. ... An article profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon</ENAMEX>
Wieseltier, the crack literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> . Wieseltier
virtually dropped out of sight after hobnobbing with the literati elite during
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'80s</TIMEX> "summit of punditry." But his new hot-selling book,
Kaddish , returns him to visibility.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> cover story focuses on off-the-court <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>. He mostly hangs
out with a group of older, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, who call him "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jumper" and "Black</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cat</ENAMEX>." They reveal that he swears a lot, drives like a terror, quizzes his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state capitals</ENAMEX> (he was a geography major), and viciously holds a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grudge</ENAMEX>. A sidebar repeats the traditional wisdom that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> helped
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> become colorblind. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover warns that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Too Much Homework</ENAMEX>." The article
is full of anecdotes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 11-year-olds</TIMEX> who don't finish their schoolwork till
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX> The amount of homework done by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-olds to 9-year-olds</TIMEX> has tripled
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. Conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homework</ENAMEX> is critical at reinforcing lessons and
building discipline, but sometimes less is more.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> says
that a whistle-blower could help <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in their
lawsuits against gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hass</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> for
marketing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith & Wesson</ENAMEX>, has testified that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> did nothing to
stop the flow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> could have monitored
distribution better but didn't because it wanted to keep its hands clean, Hass
has said. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> makes yet another contribution to what must be the most tired idea in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>: the story of the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where they're indifferent to
impeachment. Time visits <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emporia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan.</ENAMEX> (Why do they always go to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>? What's wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>?), and finds
that--guess what?!--Kansans care deeply about their local affairs and not at
all about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover
story on the Internet stock bubble <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> the obvious warnings:
Internet stocks are wildly overvalued, and the traditional rules of investing
haven't changed. But it can't quite bring itself to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to sell:
After all, day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stock pickers</ENAMEX> are making a fortune on
the stocks. The only Internet stock that may not be overvalued, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">America Online</ENAMEX>. ... A grim article describes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> life in a northern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> town
where there is no heat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, the local industry--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX>-era
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gulags</ENAMEX>--has vanished, most of the able-bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have moved away, and
those who remain have been reduced to hunting for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. ... A
piece warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> receiving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> disability payments not
to sell them. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> sums of cash to accident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> (and
others receiving annuities) in exchange for their regular payments. This may
seem attractive, but it's almost always a bad deal.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A long piece chronicles
the horrific civil war in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have died, millions
more have been displaced, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> have been enslaved, without any end in
sight. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in the north is waging a brutal
campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and animist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in the south. The government
forces kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, and enslave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> but don't care enough to
intervene. ... An article ponders the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoration Hardware</ENAMEX> phenomenon.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> promotes the notion that its yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are making the world
better by buying handsome goods made the old-fashioned way. In fact, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are just shopping. (For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>'s take on the phenomenon, see ""
in 
                  Slate
               .)

         
      
   
