
   
   
      
         
            More <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Than Monica</ENAMEX>

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> published a survey of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s media agendas from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> around
the world. Headlined "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>: More than just <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>," it highlighted the news
priorities that prevailed in different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> during the period. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
for example, the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> had been the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s self-proclaimed
diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">triumphs</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>'s visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> it had been the
collapse of the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> financial system and the humiliation of market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> the disintegration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> amid
bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace process; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> the report
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth and Reconciliation Commission</ENAMEX> on apartheid-era crimes; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> election that ousted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX> and brought the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schröder</ENAMEX> to power; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s success in
qualifying to join the new euro currency; and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> its soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-0</ENAMEX>
victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> in the final of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>.

            But if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> involved
"more than just <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>," it was also certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Hers was a story,
which, more than any other, united all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> of the world in a common
obsession. However, there was widespread reluctance around the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
to report the allegations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may
be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>. Only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
did the story play prominently. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> even led its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> front page with it, under
the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> faces DNA test on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the
press showed more responsible news priorities, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung</ENAMEX>
leading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> announcing the biggest increase in defense spending
since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>.

            But the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> around the world as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> began
was the launch by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> of the new single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency, the euro.
The reporting of this event in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> was imbued with euro-euphoria except in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where euro-skepticism continues to predominate. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> papers--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> --are campaigning vigorously against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>
joining the euro, as are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Black</ENAMEX>'s papers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Telegraph</ENAMEX> . But even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> had to agree with the
rest of the world that the launch of the euro, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> of planning, was
an historic achievement.

            It was especially
welcomed outside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> yearning for an alternative to dependence
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar. For example, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juventud</ENAMEX> Rebelde
announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> would be the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the region to substitute the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euro</ENAMEX> for the dollar in its foreign commercial transactions. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From January 2000</TIMEX>,
it said, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would be obliged to use the euro for their trade with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>. Granma , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, described the euro
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for "tranquility and stability" and "a challenge to the economic and
financial hegemony of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> devoted its main editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to the euro under the headline "An epochal
experiment." It said that the euro could benefit developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> by
mounting an effective challenge to the dollar. "The global preference for the
dollar as a reserve currency has not only meant that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has had access to
inexpensive funds but also that the rest of the world effectively finances its
chronic account deficit," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindu</ENAMEX> concluded. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>, the
Straits
Times led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a story anticipating that the euro
would boost the value of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> currencies against the dollar.

            Among various hyperbolic
editorials in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> press, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> appealed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to a reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> to overcome its fears
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> loss of sovereignty and to join the single currency. "Englishmen," the
editorial began, "it's now your turn to play! The euro awaits you, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and
its infant currency need you." It continued, "Your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s participation in
the euro is also, for us <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frenchmen</ENAMEX>, a necessity. ... The euro needs <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s
diversity--to be neither a clone of the deutsche mark nor a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siamese</ENAMEX> twin of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lira</ENAMEX>. The support of your culture--of your pragmatism and your distrust
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>, etc.--is indispensable to the stability and solidity of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euro</ENAMEX>. With you present, the euro is more likely to become one of the great
international currencies. As an ancient superpower, you know the advantages we
can all draw from that."

             

         
      
   
