
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saved</ENAMEX> by a Scoundrel

            Every impeachment junkie
has by now heard the tale of the valiant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Ross</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX> broke party ranks to acquit the impeached <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ran a long paean to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>
left and right sing his praises. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX>, an
anti-impeachment stalwart, endorses the expert judgment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>, who
wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Profiles in Courage</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>' "heroic" vote "may well
have preserved ... constitutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Turley</ENAMEX>, a devout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX>, recalled
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wistfully</ENAMEX> in a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> column that for his "selfless
act," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> was "shunned, physically assaulted and ruined both politically and
financially." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turley</ENAMEX> proposes erecting a statue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> of the otherwise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obscure Kansan</ENAMEX>.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> agree
that in voting to acquit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> did the right thing--but, they would
add, for the wrong reasons. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a little more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s record.)
Those who have researched the issue conclude that, contrary to legend, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross</ENAMEX>
acted for motives anything but high-minded. That popular wisdom holds otherwise
testifies not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>' integrity but to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> for self-promotion.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Ross</ENAMEX> was a little-known newspaperman with no
political experience when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> named him to fill a vacant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1866</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> had committed suicide.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six months</TIMEX>
later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> won re-election with the financial help--some believe bribes--of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry Fuller</ENAMEX>. Once in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, the newcomer copied many of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and took up the cause of controlling his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s patronage--then the
coin of politics. With a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that was tiny compared with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s power lay largely in deciding who would receive plum jobs
with the postal service or, in the West, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>. Hungry for
power, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> tangled with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>' senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Pomeroy</ENAMEX>, and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Clarke</ENAMEX>, eschewing the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>'s weightier battles over rights
for freed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slaves</ENAMEX> and reconstructing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were impeaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, a stubborn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, who was
consistently defying their will on various <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Reconstruction</ENAMEX>-related measures.
(For more on the issues surrounding the impeachment, see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1998</TIMEX>'s "." )
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX> naturally assumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> would vote with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, but when it became
clear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1868</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Radicals</ENAMEX> wanted to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Wade</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> pro tem of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> began to think
twice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX> was likely to grant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pomeroy</ENAMEX> the control over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> appointments
that had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>'. Wanting neither to alienate his party-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX> nor lose his
meal ticket in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> tried to avert a vote altogether. He pressed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> for concessions on certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconstruction</ENAMEX> issues in exchange for his
vote and those of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fence sitters</ENAMEX>.

            When judgment day came on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 16</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> survived by a
vote of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35-19</NUMEX>, one shy of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> needed to convict. Since the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had declared their intentions before voting, the
ensuing attention focused on the apostasy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>, whose vote came as the
biggest surprise. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>' vote wasn't the lone act of bravery it was later
made out to be. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least four</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> were prepared to oppose conviction
had their votes been needed--a fact that has been forgotten, maybe, because it
doesn't square with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">High Noon</ENAMEX> portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of
principle facing down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> wasted no time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploiting Johnson</ENAMEX>'s debt to him. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 6</TIMEX>, he wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> to have him
install <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cronies</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> affairs, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> agreed to oust his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in order to comply. Sensing opportunity,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> kept upping the ante, like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> henchman running a protection racket.
("Nice little presidency ya got here--hate to see anything happen to it.") On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23</TIMEX>, he wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> to secure a position for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry Fuller</ENAMEX>, his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1867</TIMEX>
election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>, he asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> to make his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> a federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mail</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10</TIMEX>, he pressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for jobs for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, invoking his impeachment vote, just in case <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> had forgotten.

            The legend about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> is correct in that his stand earned
him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> compared him to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benedict Arnold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson Davis</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judas</ENAMEX>. And he did lose his re-election bid, as did the other pro-acquittal
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. But so did many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti -Johnson Republicans</ENAMEX> from the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and there's little evidence to suggest the impeachment votes turned the
elections in any of these cases. All "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> martyrs," as they've been lionized,
stayed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and campaigned for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulysses S. Grant</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>. Their troubled
fortunes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that followed are most plausibly chalked up to the
turbulent climate of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1870s</TIMEX>, when the makeup of both parties--and of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> itself--was in constant flux.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> didn't see it that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>. Stung by charges that his vote was bought, he turned the tables on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX> and charged them with orchestrating the whole impeachment
campaign so as to get their hands on the controls of patronage. He got the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> to investigate charges of bribery involving his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pomeroy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>--which in fact turned up some damning evidence against them.

            Till his dying day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> continued to paint himself as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">martyr</ENAMEX>. He wrote numerous articles as well as a book etching his self-serving
version of events into the historical record. In a passage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> quoted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> wrote in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1896</TIMEX> memoir: "I almost literally looked down into my
open grave. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friendships</ENAMEX>, position, fortune, everything that makes life
desirable to an ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> were about to be swept away by the breath of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mouth</ENAMEX>, perhaps forever." This grandiose account was adopted almost uncritically
by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Bumgardner</ENAMEX>, and then by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>
Prize-winning sampler of hagiographies cemented it in the public mind. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
for more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s warped portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> and the impeachment.)

            Perhaps in an
unconscious act of denial--an inability to face up to his complicated but
altogether human motives for voting as he did--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> after his vote, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross</ENAMEX>
wrote to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>: "This storm of passion will soon pass away, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, will thank and bless me for having saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by my
single vote from the greatest peril through which it has ever passed, though
none but God can ever know the struggle it has cost me." Of course, in a funny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, he turned out to be right.

            
               If you skipped the
links while reading the article, click for a fast read on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presidency</ENAMEX>, and for a summary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s hagiography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Ross</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
