
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Drawing upon her rich experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions about manners, personal relations, politics, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries
should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your letter
to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               On a scale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, my problem is maybe a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.5</NUMEX>, but it's a problem nonetheless. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s
business requires us to entertain at home quite a bit. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> (which pays
the bills) uses a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caterer</ENAMEX> with whom I do not get along. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in
charge seems to resent my suggestions, though I am always polite, and it has
come back to me that she is bad-mouthing me whenever she can. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmas</ENAMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s coming up, we will be seeing more of her than ever. I do not
need this aggravation, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prudie</ENAMEX>, and fear she is harming my reputation. Any
solutions?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hostess With the Cateress From Hell</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Host</ENAMEX>,

            Oh, how sharper than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX>'s tooth. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Alas,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> helping in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> are always in a position to carry tales outside.
But to be pragmatic, here are your options. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Discontinue making any
suggestions. And to close down the catering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, make it a point to tell her
that you have decided to defer to her professional experience. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Ask the
appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> if you might have the leeway of
choosing your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caterer</ENAMEX>. If the answer is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>," see Solution 1.

            Good luck, and just
remember this: Using caterers may have a few attendant problems, but it beats
cooking.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, practically

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               I fear that a certain software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> may
be a nut job. (No, not your software <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX>.) The one who has my dander
up--pardon the animal metaphor--is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Duffield</ENAMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. He has pledged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> for homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>. What
about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HOMELESS PEOPLE</ENAMEX>?
            

            
               I am disgusted and
wonder what you think of this.
            

            

               --Burned Up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern California</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Burn</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks the old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adage</ENAMEX> is true: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX> doesn't care who has it. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> knows that animal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> are a fiercely loyal lot (and vociferous too), there is no recourse from
these monetary gifts to fur-bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>. You feel disgust, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels
regret, but you must put aside your mad-on and get back to business.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, philosophically

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I just noticed that
you used the word "empathetic." Please see the attached letter previously sent
to 
                     Slate
                   (but not published) as to why
"empathetic" should not be used. Despite my letter I see that

                     Slate
                   has let that word slip through
again.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Al</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> never intended to
go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX>-land with linguistic matters ... but what the hell! Here
are the highlights of your (unpublished) letter for the edification of those
Prudie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> who might be
interested:

            

               

                  
                     Slate
                   contributes to the continuing degradation of
the language. It seems that only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> know that the word is
"empathically," not "empathetically," as used in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unmade Beds</ENAMEX> . While you will find "empathetic" in some dictionaries,
that is only because so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have (mis)used it, thinking if it is
sympathy/sympathetic it must be empathy/empathetic. Not so.

               Have
you noticed that almost no one uses "reticent" correctly anymore? And now, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after I predicted it, I notice that some dictionaries offer "reluctant"
as a meaning for "reticent." And of course "disinterested" has come to mean
"uninterested." Where will it all end?

            

            Oh, probably with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have</ENAMEX>
a nice day."

            
--Prudie

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               This is a heartache
for me, though it is actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s problem. She is married to a
womanizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">louse</ENAMEX> who takes no particular pains to cover his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>. They have
been married for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX>, and "the trouble" was apparent soon after they
married. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is torn about whether to cut the creep loose or to hope
against hope that he will change. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. You are experienced, and
I am assuming you have a thought-out opinion on this type of situation. Thank
you.
            

            

               --Heartsick
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Heart</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees with the late and witty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo Udall</ENAMEX>, who
said, in another context, "That condition can be cured only with embalming
fluid." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> also thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> like this are lucky if they're not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bobbittized</ENAMEX>.

            It is likely that you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> have
discussed this, but the next time it comes up you might point out that tomcat
habits are not likely to change and, further, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are not benefited
by having tense and angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. Additionally, through some kind of family
osmosis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> pick up that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> is a philanderer, and this, in turn,
gives an unspoken OK to such behavior. The decision must be hers.

            As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> herself,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> hopes you can disengage on a gut level from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s difficult
situation and that you can achieve some peace of mind knowing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> get
to make their own decisions about their lives. Be a shoulder for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>,
and let's hope she decides the best course for herself and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, maternally

         
      
   
