
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>

            The business press played
the birth announcement of sothebys.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> as another story about the
frenzy for e-commerce. The snooty <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> auction house, founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1744</TIMEX>, was
going to remodel itself after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hour</TIMEX> electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> sale! Out the
window went centuries of snobbery, mystique, and pretension. Up, up went
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> stock, on the basis of a Web site that didn't yet exist and that
wouldn't be selling anything for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>.

            But the dotcomming of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> is about more than a fusty old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> chasing fresh loot. It's a
harbinger of the dramatic transformation that's about to sweep the entire
business of buying and selling rare and precious things. The market for art,
which has long behaved very differently from markets for other kinds of goods,
is about to be transformed by the irresistible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of the Internet. The
upscaling of the online auction fad is one aspect of this change, but perhaps
only a small part of it.

            The trade in art has always been anomalous in economic
terms. What's unusual about the business is its secretiveness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vendors</ENAMEX> of most
other kinds of goods--household appliances, cut-up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> parts, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condominiums</ENAMEX>--generally advertise what they have for sale and how much it
costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transparency</ENAMEX> benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, who can compare prices, features, and
quality. If you want to buy a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">19 inch</NUMEX> color television set, you start by
checking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> for advertised prices. In markets where price
comparisons aren't easily available--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> rugs or new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> are at a
conspicuous disadvantage. The buying experience is unpleasant because consumers
suspect they're being fleeced. Market secrecy tends to break down, because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> have to reveal their prices if their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> do. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>,
this has happened with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> carpets.

            In the art world,
however, secrecy has survived. Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> seldom advertise prices and
sometimes won't even quote them if they're not convinced a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> is on the
hook. There was an outcry among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
passed a law requiring them to post prices for works that are actually on
display. Most follow it, but grudgingly. "We're sheepish about posting prices,"
says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> I know at a high-end <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoHo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>. "Why give out free
information?" And don't even bother asking what they have for sale. At
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildenstein & Co.</ENAMEX>, which has the world's largest private collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Master</ENAMEX> and Impressionist paintings, not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are allowed to know
what's inside the vaults.

            There are a variety of reasons for these
practices--historical, cultural, and economic. Art dealing as a profession
originated mainly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, where it began its long association with social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">snobbery</ENAMEX>. The art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> cultivates his aura (and the more mystical aura of the
art object) by casting himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">connoisseur</ENAMEX> rather than as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>. He
flatters his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of taste and distinction rather than a mere
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. As a consequence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> tend not to behave the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> do in
other fields. But the most potent factor is the economic logic of selling rare
or unique goods. Comparison shopping is hard. Even in the case of
multiple-edition prints, where a sizable number of identical lithographs may
exist, you're not likely to find them competitively priced in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">adjoining</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">storefronts</ENAMEX>. And virtually everything else is subjective. Which is better: a
green <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol Marilyn</ENAMEX> or a red <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol Marilyn</ENAMEX>? A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX> or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rauschenberg</ENAMEX>? By making intrinsically difficult comparisons nearly impossible,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> augment their power over the market. In other words, they can get
prices higher than what they would get if everything were laid on the table
with a price tag attached.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> check on the
power of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> has always been auctions, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> can buy and sell,
bidding is public, and prices are published. Selling more art at auctions and
expanding the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can participate in auctions, which is what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> is trying to do by holding them online, will bring more efficiency
(if less drama) to the art market. But the real way the Internet stands to
revolutionize the economics of the art business is simply by breaking down the
secrecy that prevails in the nonauction sector of the market. If some dealers
are willing to sell art to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> via the Internet--and almost all of them are
now fanatically eager to do so--those who remain coy about what they have and
how much they want for it will put themselves at a competitive disadvantage.
They'll be denying themselves access to the fastest expanding sector of the
international art market.

            The chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> for this transformation isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX>.
It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ArtNet</ENAMEX> , on online service which now provides access to the
wares of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> around the world, and which is adding new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> at the
rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ArtNet</ENAMEX> is the brainchild of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans Neuendorf</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> dealer
who started the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> international art fair, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cologne</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>--the first
actual art market. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neuendorf</ENAMEX> founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ArtNet</ENAMEX> as a database for
auction results. Now he has turned it into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> offering
wares directly over the Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is headed for--you guessed it--an
IPO. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neuendorf</ENAMEX> says he wants to challenge the way the art business works
directly. "This tendency to keep everything secret, to take little advantages
of information, has resulted in a suffocation of the market," he says. "If you
wanted to set up a system to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> away from buying art, it would be very
close to what we have now."

            The theory behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuendorf</ENAMEX>'s business is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> will expand the market not only by
spreading information but also by making art into a more liquid asset. Web
auctions like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sotheby's</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuendorf</ENAMEX> plans to launch in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
should significantly reduce the transaction costs associated with selling
art--for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> and private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> doesn't have to pay a
commission, as in an off-line auction. Gone will be the need for expensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">catalogs</ENAMEX>, transparencies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FedExed</ENAMEX> around the world, and multiple packing,
shipping, and insurance costs as the work goes from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> to auction house to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purchaser</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the sale of a work of art can add <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> to the purchase
price and take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>; an efficient online sale might add <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 10 percent</NUMEX>
and take but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>.

            There are a variety of smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> consortiums, similar
in principle to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ArtNet</ENAMEX>, which allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> to browse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> stock and view
whole exhibitions online. They encourage the kind of comparison shopping that
was previously impossible in the art world. Not all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> give prices, but
enough do to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> the upper hand occasionally. For example, looking
up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Close</ENAMEX>, I found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> different lithographs for sale online,
including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> copies from the same edition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> prints titled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodcut</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> offering this print advertised it at shockingly
different prices. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pace Gallery</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">57 th Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> had it
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kempner Fine Arts</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> specializing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th century</TIMEX>
prints, had it for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,500</NUMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kunsthaus Schaller</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stuttgart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, had it for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">38,000 deutsche marks</NUMEX>, which is just over
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22,000</NUMEX>.

            In the art business, old ways die hard. I e-mailed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX>, asking them to explain the disparity in their prices. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pace</ENAMEX>
responded that they had made a mistake. Their price was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Kempner</ENAMEX>
also claimed a misunderstanding, saying that his price, curiously enough, was
really the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pace</ENAMEX>'s--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,000</NUMEX>. He subsequently offered to sell it to me
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,000</NUMEX>. (I never heard back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>). I'm not sure how
with a pair of e-mail messages I managed to effectively double the price of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Close</ENAMEX> lithographs. But you can see why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> are reluctant to give out
prices: It makes it harder for them to raise them at a moment's notice when an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s stock rises, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX>'s did when he had a big retrospective at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX>. In any case, if I had actually been
interested in buying the print, with the help of the Web, I would have been in
a far better position to negotiate a favorable price.

            What, you might ask, do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> stand to gain from
making information available online if it merely gives leverage to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>? The answer is that the Internet stands to expand the market as a
whole more than enough to compensate them for having to compete with each
other. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geneva</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> can now sell artwork to someone who never
leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa City</ENAMEX>. Some even think that while Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX> may drive
prices down initially, prices will rise as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX> are matched with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> and
the market clears. Neuendorf, for one, says he expects the Web to drive art
prices through the roof. Judging from what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pez</ENAMEX> dispensers are fetching on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>,
he might just be right.

         
      
   
