
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> on Love

            When he
wasn't out cavorting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Shakespeare</ENAMEX> wrote some
sonnets that turn out to be apt commentary on the tabloids continuing
examination of the pain and promise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> love. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sonnet 129</ENAMEX> nicely
sums up the situation between the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>:

            

               The expense of spirit in a
waste of shame

               Is lust in action; and
till action, lust

               Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perjur'd</ENAMEX>, murderous,
bloody, full of blame,

               
Savage, extreme, rude, cruel, not to trust.

            

            Though even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, for all her wheedling, couldn't convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to give her a
tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>, the tabs have no trouble penetrating
that sanctum sanctorum, providing bulletins from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s intimate
moments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports, for example, "[The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>]
dissolved into tears after a bitter screaming match with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. They were
both sobbing and screaming. It was a scene like none other in the history of
their relationship." Just as often, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> refuses to speak to him.
"Meals with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX> have been silent, ominous affairs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Servants</ENAMEX> said
they hardly look at each other." All this, and the pain he's inflicted on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, has driven the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to a "secret collapse," the publication
reports. And "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d</ENAMEX>]espite the rage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> feels toward Bill" she's convinced "he
needs acute psychiatric help, therapy and probably antidepressant
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>."

            
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , however, things
aren't quite so hopeless at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1600 Pennsylvania Ave.</ENAMEX> With the help of a New Age
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counselor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is learning to forgive Bill. As <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sonnet 35</ENAMEX> says:

            
               No more be griev'd
at that which thou
hast done;
....
For to thy sensual fault I bring in
sense--
Thy adverse party is thy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>.
            

            Returning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Houston</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
ago advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> to have imaginary conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX>. "A
controversial psychic is helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> draw inner strength," says the
publication. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> says she
has not had any contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> insists
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Houston</ENAMEX> has taught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> to "tap the power of her guardian angel." As proof,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> offers a photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> wearing what it describes as a
guardian angel pin but which instead looks suspiciously like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian eagle</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Houston</ENAMEX> has also supposedly given the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> "nonconfrontational techniques
to resolve the problems that arise in a marriage." For instance, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was
told to sit quietly, close her eyes and imagine that her and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's</ENAMEX> positions
were reversed." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> does not report whether this method resulted
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> making a pass at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>.

            
While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> may not be what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> had in
mind when he wrote of his "dark <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>," he does offer some commentary on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s awaited literary endeavor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sonnet 80</ENAMEX> :

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>, how I faint when I of
you do write,

               ....

               Then if he thrive and I be
cast away,

               The
worst was this;--my love was my decay.

            

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s book
will portray the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the world as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Knotts</ENAMEX> of romance,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quivering</ENAMEX> in fear that a steward might bust in on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his inappropriate
physical contact sessions. ("Even as I was pleasuring him I'd see his eyes
flicking anxiously over my head towards the door!") And by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s telling,
the colder the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> got, the more desperate she became until she
threatened to "get on the phone and call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX>" and tell
them about the affair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> begged her not to do it. ("Please don't tell
them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> would kill me and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> would disown me as her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.") <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
finally backed down after she reduced him to tears. One can only imagine that
at that moment <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> probably wished he could go back in time to undo the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of events--that is, kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Graham Bell</ENAMEX> before
he ever invented the damned telephone.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports
that the book will also include "never-before told details about the sex life
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>." Perhaps the book should also come with a do-it-yourself
lobotomy kit to make sure any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who come upon this passage have a way to
permanently forget it.

            
Then there was the blaring cover story in last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>: I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Going to Have a Baby</ENAMEX>." Or as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>
put it in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sonnet 124</ENAMEX> :

            
               If my dear love were but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of
state,
It might for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX>'s bastard be
unfather'd.
            

            In this case it will be unmother'd as well because,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> makes clear, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> is not pregnant. Continuing the
strategy of looking for love in all the wrong places, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> has decided, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> alleges, to become pregnant, because with a baby "for the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in my life I will have true, unconditional love." After all she's been
through, she might want to work up to that level of love by starting with, say,
a goldfish. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports she's committed to her plan and is
currently looking over possible inseminators. Don't apply unless you are
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Handsome</ENAMEX>, preferably a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> footer, college educated, athletic and schooled in
the fine arts." Blessedly that means <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX> is out of the running.

            Being ecstatic over one's
unconceived progeny is a tabloid trend. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weeks</TIMEX>, the new Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bronson</ENAMEX>, has announced, "We're having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX> is as excited as I am." They needn't invest in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diaper Genie</ENAMEX> just yet,
since the new Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> (or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">38</NUMEX> according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> ), is not
yet pregnant by her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. She is apparently using him to hone
her maternal skills, though. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , when they dine out,
she does all the ordering for him, and she was even recently seen feeding
him.

            
The marriages of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> are unlikely
to make it to the being fed like a baby stage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mick Jagger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> would probably agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonnet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">121</ENAMEX> :

            All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are bad, and in
their badness reign.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jagger</ENAMEX> denies that he
has fathered the baby-to-be of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> beauty, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Hall</ENAMEX>, mother
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, is suing for divorce anyway. Jagger, according to the
Star , begged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> to reconsider and promised, again, never to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unfaithful</ENAMEX> again. This seems about as likely as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Anderson</ENAMEX> vowing never to
expose her cleavage again. According to one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jagger</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriends</ENAMEX>, he
has bedded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 7,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> retained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s divorce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagger</ENAMEX> shot back that they couldn't get divorced because they weren't
actually married--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their wedding</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bali</ENAMEX> was not legal. After that public
relations coup, perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagger</ENAMEX> could do damage control for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Committee</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Stewart</ENAMEX> has infuriated his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, model <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Hunter</ENAMEX>,
by being both an incorrigible flirt and an old bore. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX> fumed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">To Rod</ENAMEX>, life is about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, sex,
music, drinking and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model trains</ENAMEX>--I want something more." Clearly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>
needs to expand his interests to include such masculine pursuits as lying on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> with the remote control. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> also ran a photo of the
couple having a fight in front of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> after a
less-than-successful celebration of their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> anniversary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> angrily
towers over the sheepish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, who looks like nothing so much as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who
had just been caught by his mother stuffing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tootsie Roll</ENAMEX> into the VCR.

            Even young love goes
awry. The romance between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love star Gwyneth Paltrow and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">actor Ben Affleck</ENAMEX> is kaput. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paltrow</ENAMEX> was seeing
her co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Perfect Murder , Viggo Mortensen</ENAMEX>, while still involved
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affleck</ENAMEX>. Paltrow, meanwhile, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , was hearing
rumors that while on location <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affleck</ENAMEX> was having a "local beauty come to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trailer</ENAMEX> for quickies." Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> they confronted each other with their
mutual suspicions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paltrow</ENAMEX> broke it off, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affleck</ENAMEX> heartbroken,
reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . Ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>, if only you'd taken this advice from
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sonnet 138 :</ENAMEX>

            When my love swears that she is made of truth,

            I do believe her, though
I know she lies.

            
Finally, there is a flicker of hope that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> can find enduring love if they work at it. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX> are taking courses in order to be more alluring to their
respective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> is studying <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> because she's "enthralled by
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Latino lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Bratt</ENAMEX>'s romantic language," according to the
Star . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aniston</ENAMEX> "hired an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> to give
her a crash course in architecture and collectible furniture," because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> is an "antiques buff." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Bob Thornton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Dern</ENAMEX> are taking a less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cerebral</ENAMEX> approach to keeping love alive, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bought a
leather bra, erotic videos, and edible panties at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pleasure</ENAMEX>
Chest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX> would certainly approve. As he writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sonnet 57</ENAMEX> :

            Being your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>, what should I do but tend

            Upon the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and times of your desire?

         
      
   
