
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Sheet</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> is more
than the supreme law of the land. It's the supreme political <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. If you
oppose an idea--say, censure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or the effort to establish
"findings of fact"--just damn the idea as "unconstitutional" to silence the
opposition. Whatever your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s politics, he'll have to . Constitution
worship extends beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>--notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX> and Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>--who embrace the , the belief that we should obey the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>'s meaning as intended by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX>.

            The problem with all
this veneration is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> quarreled openly about what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>
meant when it was adopted. Few thought it unassailable, and not even its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> claimed that their views should be fixed for eternity. So how did the
Constitution become sacred? And when did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> decide they must recover its
"original" meaning?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> grew out of a convention held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabal</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite politicians</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Madison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Hamilton</ENAMEX>, who
decided that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s founding document, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Articles of Confederation</ENAMEX>, was
too weak to hold the . But many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> eyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Constitutional Convention of</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1787</TIMEX> warily, worrying that a strengthened federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> would metamorphose
into precisely the sort of tyranny they had just toppled. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Henry</ENAMEX> said he
"smelled a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>" and stayed home. Such self-selection screened out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> so
that those who gathered agreed on most key questions. Contrary to myth, the men
who would become known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Fathers</ENAMEX> spoke for no cross section of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> opinion. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>, wasn't represented at all.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> built their
Constitution on shaky ground. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Articles of Confederation</ENAMEX> explicitly stated
that revision required the consent of every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
conventioneers, doubtful they'd achieve unanimity, lowered the threshold to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--on no authority but their own say-so.

            To placate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> emphasized not the glory of
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> but its imperfections, promising it would be improved over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>--with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX> as a down payment. (Even then, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> didn't ratify until after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> had been sworn in as
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.) In No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> of The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Federalist Papers</ENAMEX> --a
series of editorials that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Jay</ENAMEX> wrote to sell the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX> opined: "It is a matter both of wonder and regret, that
those who raise so many objections against the new <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, should never
call to mind the defects of that which is to be exchanged for it. It is not
necessary that the former should be perfect; it is sufficient that the latter
is more imperfect." In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Federalist 85</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> added, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> must bring
it to perfection." Far from sacrosanct, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> was billed as a work
in progress.

            Only after the new
government took over did <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> feel a need to suppress the document's
flaws. Their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had failed, and it remained uncertain whether the
fragile new one could withstand challenges to its legitimacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Historians</ENAMEX> began
to rewrite the saga of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s founding, now casting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> as its
inevitable climax rather than as the sharp turn in the road it really
represented. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Farewell Address of 1796</ENAMEX> began the
practice of using religious language to describe the document, as he shared his
wish that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> be sacredly maintained." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Quincy Adams</ENAMEX>'
Inaugural Address <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years later</TIMEX> completed the apotheosis. "Administered
by some of the most eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who contributed to its formation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> said,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alluding</ENAMEX> to his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, "... it has not disappointed the hopes and
aspirations of those illustrious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">benefactors</ENAMEX> of their age and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>." He went
on to deliver a veritable paean to the piece of parchment.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX>' opinions, now widely considered the keystone
to interpreting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, traveled a similar path to legitimacy.
Ironically, the doctrine of original intent was itself not part of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX>' original intent. "As a guide in expounding and applying the provisions
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, the document's primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, "the
debates and incidental decisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Convention</ENAMEX> can have no authoritative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>." Though he had taken extensive notes throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convention</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX> never relied on them to buttress any constitutional
arguments he made, whether as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
(The notes weren't even published until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1840</TIMEX>.) Others shared this aversion to
referring to the convention proceedings because, it was felt, each generation
had to make sense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> for itself. Similar practices favored by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">originalists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, such as appealing to the authority of The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Federalist Papers</ENAMEX> .

            When did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> and other constitutional interpreters began appealing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX>'
original intent? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historian Leonard Levy</ENAMEX> argues that only with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court's notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> decision of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX> was the doctrine of
originalism codified. In that decision--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54 years</TIMEX> to rule an act of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> unconstitutional--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Taney</ENAMEX> wrote that nothing "should
induce the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> to give the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> a more liberal
construction ... than they were intended to bear when the instrument was framed
and adopted." Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dred Scott</ENAMEX> , which ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> or free, couldn't be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, came to be condemned not just as racist
but as a quintessential example of tortured reasoning in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s personal prejudice--precisely the kind of jurisprudence that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">originalism</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> claim it alone can avoid.

            This argument--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> only use originalism to dispute
decisions they don't like--is as compelling a reason to distrust originalism as
any historical reason. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levy</ENAMEX> notes, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> use history, it's typically
after they've made up their minds on how they want to rule. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> resorts
to history for a quick fix, a substantiation, a confirmation, an illustration,
or a grace note," he writes, "it does not really look for the historical
conditions and meanings of a long time gone ... to decide a case in one way
rather than another. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>, moreover, cannot engage in the sort of
sustained historical analysis that takes professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> to
accomplish." It would be nice to believe that originalists really apply their
doctrine without first deciding the case on political grounds. And it would
also be nice to believe that every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> truly thinks censure--and every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat</ENAMEX> thinks a finding of fact--would be that worst of all possible things,
unconstitutional.

         
      
   
