
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Myths of
History
            

            The legendary mass
suicide at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masada</ENAMEX> may be just that--legendary. The story of the mountaintop
where outnumbered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> are said to have committed suicide rather than
give in to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> siege--chronicled by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> Flavius
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Josephus</ENAMEX>--has been a part of popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> history for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>; the site is
now one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s most heavily visited tourist attractions. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">eminent Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archaeologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yigael Yadin</ENAMEX> claimed to have found the bones of
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">960 martyrs</TIMEX> there, thus confirming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Josephus</ENAMEX>' account of their deaths. But the
current issue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblical Archaeology Review</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yadin</ENAMEX>'s conclusions--and
his scholarly procedures--into question. In the cover story, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
Zias, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> of archaeology and anthropology at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel Antiquities</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authority</ENAMEX>, claims that the bones <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yadin</ENAMEX> found belonged to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>--and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yadin</ENAMEX> knew it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zias</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yadin</ENAMEX> misrepresented and suppressed
evidence, including the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig bones</ENAMEX> were found alongside the skeletons
he claimed belonged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> would not have been likely to eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>,
which is not kosher.) Accompanying articles explore other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Masada</ENAMEX>-related
confusions: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Josephus</ENAMEX>' text is ambiguous about where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">martyrs</ENAMEX> actually fell,
and the site itself was probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> rather
than a civilian refuge.

            
               Bad
Timing
            

            Just in time for
millennium celebrations, theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbour</ENAMEX> will publish the results of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 30 years</TIMEX> of reflection,
in which he argues that time as we understand it does not exist. Even before
the book's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, the claim has stirred up controversy among theoretical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbour</ENAMEX> bases his thesis on a highly abstract but oddly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">common-sensical</ENAMEX> application of quantum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> that amounts to taking
literally the implications of the fact that a synonym for "infinite" is
"timeless." The practical implications for things such as train schedules,
magazine deadlines, and the minimum wage have not even begun to be
contemplated.

            
               Unfeathered
Nests
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Turku</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> have established that air pollution can hamper
the sex drive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>. According to an article published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientist</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tapio Eeva</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> report that because pollutants
from a copper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">smelter</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harjavalta</ENAMEX> dull the plumage of local
great tits,
they are unable to perform a courtship dance that relies on the display of
bright feathers. Worse, toxins from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> have greatly reduced the
availability of a staple of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tits</ENAMEX>' diet: green caterpillars. Without
caterpillars, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tits</ENAMEX> cannot produce the bright yellow breast feathers they
need to do the dance and thus cannot attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fifth</NUMEX>
Wheel
            

            Physicists may also be on
the verge of discovering the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
dimension . This dimension's theoretical existence was first posited in
the 1920s by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematicians</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodor Kaluza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oskar Klein</ENAMEX>, who
hypothesized that "each point of normal space is actually a loop in [the] <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>
dimension." They thought the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> dimension also accounted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gravity</ENAMEX> and electromagnetism. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Higher Education</ENAMEX>
Supplement reported that, thanks to advances in supercollider technology
that enable the precise calibration of subatomic quantum energy and computer
programs that are able to model the behavior of this energy with previously
unheard-of speed and precision, we may soon have a glimpse of the real thing.
"Some physicists," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, "have suggested that we might one day
unroll such a dimension [and] travel along it." But others are skeptical.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Traveling</ENAMEX> along [the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> dimension]," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, "wouldn't get you
anywhere."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melville</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Whale</ENAMEX>
            

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Melville</ENAMEX> once
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">famously</ENAMEX> asked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moby</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> , why don't whales collapse under the
pressure of all the water they swim under? According to a law of physics called
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Boyle's law</ENAMEX>, the pressure times the volume of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> is always a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">constant</ENAMEX>--increasing pressure makes volume decrease, and vice versa. In the
fall issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Scholar</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace Marmor Spruch</ENAMEX>
reveals the answer. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melville</ENAMEX> pointed out, if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sperm whale</ENAMEX> can spend more
than an hour swimming at depths of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 6,000 feet</NUMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sperm whale</ENAMEX> is
composed mostly of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> (air-filled lungs and blubber), then <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Boyle's law</ENAMEX> would
dictate that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spruch</ENAMEX> puts it, "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> of regulation size at the surface
should, at the pressures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand</TIMEX> fathoms down, decrease its volume to the
size of a bathtub!"--becoming a "miniwhale." But, in fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>'s gaseous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chambers</ENAMEX> (i.e., his lungs) are not particularly large to begin with. They do
collapse on a long dive, but the viscera move into the space. In short, most of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> is incompressible.

            
               Faster, Pussycats!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Island School of Design</ENAMEX> have unveiled the "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> of the future." The utopian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prototype</ENAMEX>, called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Kitchen</ENAMEX>, is designed for maximum efficiency in
cooking and cleaning: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> steps it now takes to prepare a modest dinner in
an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> would be reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>. Its oven would perform all the
functions of a microwave, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">broiler</ENAMEX>, and a conventional oven, as well as
steam-cooking and steam-cleaning. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Langmuir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
project, "water and heat come together and create a totally new appliance." The
model is currently on display at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooper-Hewitt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. If it's ever built, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> will come in two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sizes</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">min</ENAMEX>" and "max."

            
               Dead Letters
...
            

            The world's oldest and
largest university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>--has just announced that it is canceling its
poetry list. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>, which is, after Faber
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faber</ENAMEX>, the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> of contemporary poetry in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, has cut
loose its living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">poets</ENAMEX>, including such respected figures as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Raine</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.J. Enright</ENAMEX>. The dead poets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX> publishes--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spenser</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Wordsworth</ENAMEX>--will remain in print.

            
               ... and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living</ENAMEX>
Arts
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Language Association</ENAMEX> has commissioned a
documentary on the history of oral performance, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Homer</ENAMEX> to poetry
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slams</ENAMEX>--raucous readings in which the quality of poems is judged by the ferocity
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> response. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find the popularity of the events an
encouraging sign in a media-saturated age. But others--notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Bloom</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Vendler</ENAMEX>--view the rise of the slam with alarm. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloom</ENAMEX>, after reading the
work of some contest winners, declared them "of a badness not to be
believed."

         
      
   
