
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">186</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>; 's cool&quot;

            

               Joining a national trend, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, ordered these turned off during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. What?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 185</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tourist Tsuris ":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Parks Authority</ENAMEX> was uneasy about a
proposed new attraction but, after consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church authorities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning Zeev Margalit</ENAMEX> concluded that it would "not hurt the feelings of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and it would not be too kitchy, so we decided to go with
it." With what? ( This story 
                        courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radosh</ENAMEX>. )
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
large monument honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Diamond</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Silhouette brooches of popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> made from the bones of slain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crusaders</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>-only <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> petting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "An
I've Got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Secret</ENAMEX> style quiz show where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity evangelists</ENAMEX> question
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of male <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> about which is the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
Burchman
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
sound and light show mocking the beliefs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus, Buddhists</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Silow-Carroll</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah Meyerson</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            I'm afraid this is kind
of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> joke question, and the joke is cheap and easy blasphemy. Well, maybe
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jokes if you count <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage USA</ENAMEX>; is that still for sale? Shouldn't someone
inform Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>? Actually, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, if you count <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jew Town</ENAMEX>, but
that's a scary place. You know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Antichrist</ENAMEX> come into direct
physical contact, there'd be, like, a big explosion that would blow stuff up.
Cool! I learned that in religious physics at my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>. Just before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was struck by lightning. OK, not the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, just my
desk.

            
               Simulated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miraculous Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            They're building a sunken
ramp into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Galilee</ENAMEX> to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> simulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' walk on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma Blijdenstein</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13 foot</NUMEX> wide, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> foot
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, crescent-shaped floating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> will be submerged <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 inches</NUMEX> below <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
and can handle <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. To enhance the "walking on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>" effect, the bridge
will be unrailed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lifeguards</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> will be standing by.

            
               You Make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Call</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Can you figure out the
next step in each scenario?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. You Be the
Former Monkee
            

            "They decimated my business; they decimated my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">catalogue</ENAMEX>, by luring me into this kind of complacently by lying to me. I closed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> down in the shambles that it was, swept everything clean, moved to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> and ... "

            What did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Nesmith</ENAMEX>
do then?

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. You Be the
Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Adviser</ENAMEX>
            

            "We used to have a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 a.m.</TIMEX> meeting and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Erskine</ENAMEX>
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowles</ENAMEX>] would sit at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> end of the conference table in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and I would
sit at the other. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every now and then</TIMEX>, when things got a little tense, I would
... "

            What did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rahm Emanuel</ENAMEX> do
then?

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. " ... wrote a novel."

            When a video deal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> went sour, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> sued <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nesmith</ENAMEX> who countersued. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Monday</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> awarded
him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$47 million</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. " ... walk over and give him a little kiss on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forehead</ENAMEX>."

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> now work on Wall
Street.

            
               Race
Results
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kitsch</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
