
   
   
      
         
            Mails of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Species</ENAMEX>

            I'd like to have been on
the set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleepless</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>) when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX> directed the
scene in which a misty-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> as he frolics on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">beach</ENAMEX> with his little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. It felt as if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ephron</ENAMEX> were standing off-camera with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">megaphone</ENAMEX> shouting: "OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>, frolic! More frolic! Now--romp! OK, gambol!" In
life, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ephron</ENAMEX> is evidently incisive, but she doesn't have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> into the minutiae of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interaction</ENAMEX>. She's the opposite of a detail
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. Almost all the scenes she writes and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stages</ENAMEX> are blandly generalized--a
homogeneity that seems part commercial cunning (her movies go down easy, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muzak</ENAMEX>) and part the result of being rich and snobbishly insulated on the Upper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Side</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, that magic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> parade their
liberalism but the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>" is always good for a laugh and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shudder</ENAMEX>.

            
               You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX>
(which she co-wrote with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delia</ENAMEX>) is based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ernst Lubitsch</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samson Raphaelson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shop Around The Corner</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>), one of the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">enchanting</ENAMEX> comedies ever made. It's a classic setup: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> work side by
side and can't stand each other but--unbeknownst to either--are pen pals ("Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friend"</ENAMEX>) who pour out their hearts in prose. When I went online in the early
'90s, the first thing I thought (and posted in a chat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>) was: "Oh, now
someone will remake The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shop Around the Corner with</ENAMEX>
e-mail"--which I mention to spotlight not my prescience but the obviousness of
the idea. It came to me while watching a pretty young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cybercafe</ENAMEX> who seemed to have a wonderful, funny, flirtatious personality online
(I was in a position to read some of what she was typing) but who logged off
and buttoned up her coat without looking left or right and hurried into the
street as if afraid that someone might actually speak to her.

            The story works better when set in a society with a clear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gulf</ENAMEX> between public behavior and private feelings--a society rather unlike our
own, in which the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are increasingly interchangeable. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ephron</ENAMEX> has diluted the
drama even more by making her cyberchums (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX>) friendly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">down-to-earth</ENAMEX>, and adorable, not at all the sorts who'd save their true selves
for their electronic epistles. There is conflict, but it's surface. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the vast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Books</ENAMEX> (read: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>), which
relishes the process of opening "superstores" and driving the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and pop
joints out of business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Kelly</ENAMEX> owns a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bookstore</ENAMEX> called, amusingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shop Around the Corner</ENAMEX>. She and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">snarling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX>, but online (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX>, actually, which has been
flacking this picture for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>) they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shopgirl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NY152</ENAMEX>, and are
constantly shoring each other up. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> even gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX> tips on how to lock
horns with her (unnamed) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversary</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best things
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lubitsch</ENAMEX>'s original is that its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austro-Hungarian</ENAMEX>, kitsch-laden universe
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikolaus Laszlo</ENAMEX>'s original play was set in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Budapest</ENAMEX> perfumery) barely
conceals real economic desperation, and there are serious consequences when the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> clash and one of them gets fired. In the world of You've Got
Mail , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> might lose her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, but she gets to keep her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upper West</ENAMEX>
Side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and to continue to frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zabar's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starbucks</ENAMEX>, and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are happily hired by the competition. The movie, without seeming to
realize it, turns into a romantic parable about the joys of being absorbed by a
conglomerate. Why, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> never even get a busy signal when they dial
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AOL</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> ou've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> gets better as it gets more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relaxed</ENAMEX>, and the famous cafe scene--in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> discovers in horror who
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> really is--remains sure-fire. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ephron</ENAMEX> does well at evoking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> in which e-mail and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX> mail diverge, the former being so much more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impulsive</ENAMEX> and exhibitionist. And I loved how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX> flinched when the screen
displayed an instant message from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">NY152</TIMEX>: He's actually there, in real time! Too
close! But where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shop Around the Corner</ENAMEX> had a matrix of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relationships, Ephron</ENAMEX> reduces You've Got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> to its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leads. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine</ENAMEX> have featherweight significant others (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker Posey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Kinnear</ENAMEX>)
who can be discarded at the narrative's convenience without muss or fuss. The
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to be talked at. (You don't even get a sense
that the rest of the world uses e-mail.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> clearly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adores Ryan</ENAMEX>, but she's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>'s worst <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, goading her into ever more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sickening</ENAMEX> reaches of chin-wagging cuteness--such as her fatuous look of
enchantment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> or the furtive little hip-hops to her laptop after
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Luddite boyfriend</ENAMEX> has left for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> does better. It's nice to
see him playing a self-serving wisenheimer in a light comedy. He looks
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">careworn</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, malfunctioning space <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">capsules</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha Beach</ENAMEX> will do
that to you--but his timing is still amazing. His wisecracks sound as if he's
nervously thinking them up on the spot, and he's better than anyone at saying
something he doesn't mean and then wincing in horror, as if longing to hit the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Delete</ENAMEX>" key.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Cahill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Gleeson</ENAMEX>), the protagonist of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boorman</ENAMEX>'s marvelous almost-comedy The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> , is a gangster in the
flamboyant movie tradition of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobsters</ENAMEX> who smile at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> that end
their lives. They aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> but they have a bullying magnetism that Boorman
calls "pagan." The real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cahill</ENAMEX>, who thrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dublin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> and was
gunned down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, was the most legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history.
He was a "whaddya got?" rebel--someone who could have justified his thieving on
all sorts of grounds, from contempt for the repressive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypocritical</ENAMEX> police
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> to contempt for the repressive, hypocritical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. He might even have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fancied</ENAMEX> himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boorman</ENAMEX> (who also wrote the screenplay)
is careful to show that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cahill</ENAMEX> stole from the rich he gave to no one but
himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and that his thieving put a lot of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of
work. Call him a roguish tribal chieftain or an ornery sociopath, he is what he
is. And, for much of the movie, I had no moral reaction to his sometimes brutal
exploits; I just watched. How radical! There are different kinds of artistic
neutrality: the nihilist kind that signals "Nothing matters, so who cares?
Let's just get off on the spectacle!" and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boorman</ENAMEX>'s kind, which signals "This
subject is too big to reduce to a thesis. Let's lay it out and study it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleeson</ENAMEX> gives you
something to study. Purposefully inexpressive (the real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cahill</ENAMEX> would only be
photographed with his hand blocking his face), he has a thick neck and eyes
that, while small, suggest watchful calculation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> begins with
his murder and the cheers that go up when word reaches the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, then
flashes back: As a boy, he steals <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastries</ENAMEX>, which he gallantly shares with his
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Doyle Kennedy</ENAMEX>). But even his gallantry is suffused
with mulishness. Refusing to budge from a condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing project</ENAMEX>, the adult
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cahill</ENAMEX> doesn't bother to reason, he just sits--past the point where the
building is razed and the trailer he has moved to the spot has been firebombed.
When a city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> marches on his tent and offers to set his family up in a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, the inveterate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">burglar</ENAMEX> asks for a place in a wealthier neighborhood
so that he'll be "closer to work." His capers range from casual break-ins to
armed holdups to intricate jewel heists--the latter capped with an impudent
visit to the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> to establish an alibi.

            W hat works against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cahill</ENAMEX> is his own runaway success. To
monitor his movements, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> appoint an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> (an amusingly sober
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Voight</ENAMEX>, reunited with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boorman</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1972</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deliverance</ENAMEX> ), who soon has the resources to post cops on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cahill</ENAMEX>'s back
fence and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in front of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and to follow him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>
wherever they go. Using only the simplest cinematic means, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boorman</ENAMEX> achieves
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> needed whip-pans and zoom lenses and a cacophonous sound
mix to do at the climax of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GoodFellas</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>): He gives you the jittery
and suffocating sense of the universe closing in. Hunted by both the cops and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>, the snorting, overweight, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diabetic Cahill</ENAMEX> does the
opposite of lie low.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boorman</ENAMEX> pays a price for
his neutrality: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> isn't an emotional grabber. But on its own
terms it's nearly perfect. All I missed was something more than winks and hints
about the nature of the triangle among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cahill</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lush Angeline Ball</ENAMEX>), with whom he fathered several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. (Apparently, it
was a happy arrangement for all.) Some have argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boorman</ENAMEX>, the director
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excalibur</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1981) and Hope</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Glory</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>), doesn't employ his
extravagant visual gifts in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> , which is in black and white and
isn't ostentatious in its mythic resonances. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boorman</ENAMEX>, pickled since youth
in Arthurian legends, has become nearly unemployable thanks to the mythic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resonances</ENAMEX> in such epic turkeys as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zardoz</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exorcist II</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heretic</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where the Heart Is</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>), and the worthy dud
Beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rangoon</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>). It's agreeable to find him grounded in the here
and now--the magic is there but below the surface.

            
The magic is all on the surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> , an animated musical version of the exodus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>
that at times feels as if it might have been called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indiana Moses</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple of Doom</ENAMEX> . Ever on the lookout for a new way to tell an old story--or,
rather, a new old way to tell an old story--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks SKG</ENAMEX> has recast the life
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> as the saga of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> who end up on opposite sides of an issue.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>, his existence endangered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharaoh</ENAMEX>'s edict calling for all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hebrew sons</ENAMEX> to be slain, is set adrift in a basket <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">on the Nile</ENAMEX> before being
discovered--and adopted--by one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharaoh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. Cut to a chariot race
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that out- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Hur</ENAMEX> s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Hur</ENAMEX> , after which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">victor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>, goads his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramses</ENAMEX> on to ever more high-spirited antics:
"Oh, come on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramses</ENAMEX>, where's your sense of fun<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" But then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> bumps into his
real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miriam</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>, and learns the truth about his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origins</ENAMEX>. Ramses, who becomes the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharaoh</ENAMEX>, isn't pleased when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> civil rights instead of the wild and crazy guy
with whom he grew up.

            A ctually, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> in the biblical
tale--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>, the latter directed by God to speak for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> believe had a speech impediment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> might have
been more psychologically compelling if it had set up a rivalry between the
good and bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>--between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramses</ENAMEX>--for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>' soul. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>
hardly figures here and, of course, psychology isn't the point. What wows 'em
whose work has become less tuneful and more pretentious since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the heady days</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godspell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pippin</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>'s rhymes are all of the moon-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
variety, and the big inspirational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX>, in which hope is conceded sometimes
to "fly away, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">silver birds</ENAMEX>," asks: "Who knows what miracles you can
achieve/ When you believe?" The miracle here is the animation and production
design, which has less to do with belief than with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of
dollars.

            This is sensational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> swarming among
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">pyramids</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eye-popping 3-D</TIMEX>, camerawork that's distinctly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spielbergian</ENAMEX> in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluidity</ENAMEX>. Everything we love about biblical-movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kitsch</ENAMEX> is here, only
concentrated and heightened. Best of all is a sequence in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> falls
asleep against the wall of a temple and, in his dream, the two-dimensional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hieroglyphs of</ENAMEX> familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> painting begin to move, enacting the story of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX> in stiff, horizontal processions. The dream exalts the primitive art
that is the movie's visual inspiration in a way that seems truly religious.

         
      
   
