
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks SKG</ENAMEX>). Measured praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks</ENAMEX>'
animated version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> story. Biggest plus: The animation is glorious,
especially the parting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Sea</ENAMEX> and a neat sequence with dancing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hieroglyphics</ENAMEX>. Biggest minus: the clunky musical numbers, which "hang like
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cinder</ENAMEX> blocks" around the neck of the production (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> ). Critics also complain that the movie is short on emotional power,
partly because "it tries to do too much" and be all things to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wilmington</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> says the
film "feels as if it might have been called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indiana Moses</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> of
Doom ." Click to read the rest of his review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  You've Got
Mail
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>/co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX>'s pleasant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trifle</ENAMEX> works because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> in it. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX>
update of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ernst Lubitsch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Shop Around the Corner</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> plays a
"lemony-fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s bookshop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Dreher</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> )
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> to be put out of business by the discount <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">megabookstore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> meet in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">cyberspace</TIMEX>; the rest is thumb twiddling until they "solve their
problems, fall into each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and get down to the old rumpy-pumpy"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). Fun, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, as long as
you can believe that "lurking in the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> might be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> or
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX> and not some drooling <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> with bad skin" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
O'Sullivan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review, in which he
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ephron</ENAMEX>'s movies "go down easy, like Muzak," .)

            
               
                  The
General
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). Raves for this biopic of infamous
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Cahill</ENAMEX> ("The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>"): It "belongs on a long list of
history's best gangster movies" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Boorman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">won Best</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX> for the film. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Voight</ENAMEX> gives a fine understated
performance as a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Gleeson</ENAMEX>'s turn as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cahill</ENAMEX> is a "tour
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">de</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> ... first rate" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreher</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ), and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photography</ENAMEX> is a "seductively beautiful black and white" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX> gives the
film its only pan, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voight</ENAMEX> performs well below his abilities and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boorman</ENAMEX>'s directing is a "disappointment." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX> says the film "isn't
an emotional grabber. But on its own terms it's nearly perfect." Read the rest
of his review . To find out more about the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Cahill</ENAMEX>, click here for links to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blind Man</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bluff: The Untold Story of American Submarine Espionage</ENAMEX>
               , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Sontag</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Drew</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annette Lawrence Drew</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX>). This exposé of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX> espionage is "an evocative and
important look at the cold war," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Naftali</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> . Told with the color and pacing of a spy novel, the book is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of firsthand accounts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who served on the underwater spying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">missions</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>--a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and a current one--are insufficiently skeptical about
inflated claims to heroism. But the book is full of gems, such as the story of
a massive wiretapping device placed on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> underwater communication cable
that, when found by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>, had "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property of the United States</ENAMEX>
Government" printed on it. (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> here, courtesy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> [free registration
required].)

            
               
                  Opened Ground:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selected Poems</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966-1996</TIMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seamus Heaney</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giroux</ENAMEX>). Unanimous praise for this selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heaney</ENAMEX>'s poems, which
"eloquently confirms his status as the most skilful and profound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> writing
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> today" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Mendelson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ).
The book includes excerpts from his translation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sophocles</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lecture</ENAMEX>, but more important, it features a wide selection of his poems,
charting his progress from unknown to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX>. The collection "exhibits
the kind of imaginative eclecticism that characterizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of the first
order" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Driscoll</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> selections from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Opened Ground</ENAMEX> at the New York
Times Web site.)

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unknown</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Matisse</ENAMEX>, The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Early Years, 1869-1908</TIMEX>
               , by Hilary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spurling</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Reviewers hail this biography as "a work of deep research and
intense concentration, full of archive-sweat, legwork and looking" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ), not to mention a great read.
Most notable is the revelation that a financial scandal involving close family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> to quit the experimental phase he was starting and focus
on more salable works: "Spurling brushes aside all our preconceptions about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painter</ENAMEX> to reveal a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>--and a personal history--none of us had guessed
at" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dorment</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> ). Also praised is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> into the role <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amélie</ENAMEX>, played in fostering his talents.
This volume covers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 40 years</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>'s life; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are
eager to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> volume. Sole drawback: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spurling</ENAMEX> is "not an especially
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">penetrating commentator</ENAMEX> on painting" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Baker</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> ). (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, courtesy of the New York
Times .)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Star Trek: Insurrection</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rushmore</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Simple Plan</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Frost</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Television--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tempest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Room</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hare</ENAMEX> (Cort
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Psycho</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Central Station</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Hard Core Logo</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Voice</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McEwan</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Edo: Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1615-1868</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>);

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Electra</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophocles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ethel Barrymore Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>).

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX>
            

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pig</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Fries</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>: Ringmaster ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Very Bad Things</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Town</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Rum Diary: The Long Lost</ENAMEX>
Novel , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX>.

            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 25</TIMEX>:
            

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Enemy of the</ENAMEX>
State;

               
                  Movie -- The Rugrats
Movie ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waking Ned</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devine</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Bug</ENAMEX>'s
Life ;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- I Will Bear Witness: A</ENAMEX>
Diary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years, 1933-1941</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Klemperer</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- American Beach: A Saga</ENAMEX>
of Race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wealth</ENAMEX>, and Memory , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Rymer</ENAMEX>;

               

                  Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winchell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>).

            

         
      
   
