
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Who's the
Greatest?
            

            Your article "" is right
on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, to question the descriptive "greatest" in referring to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> generation. (I have no problem at all with it being used to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">describe Muhammad Ali</ENAMEX>.) I was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX> and have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> since then. I thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX>'s term was cute
until I saw on television the gist of his conclusion--then I thought it was
stupid and packaged for television. (Did he hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> writing a
book then rush to get one out first?) The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won a war (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
wars, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on each side of the world) then felt they had earned riches, comfort,
a homogenous society, everlasting youthful looks, the right to never die, the
right to never being questioned with the corresponding right to never being
wrong, etc. You did a good job of starting the dialogue. There's a ton of good,
commercial stories to be had in mining that way of thinking.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon Smith Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fathers</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Re Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s piece
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GI Envy</ENAMEX>": Perhaps we should also remember that those "heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX>" are the ones
who ensnared their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and sent the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX>" into that superbly
planned and managed conflict without the support of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Zellman Modesto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bravo</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>"!
            

            As a recent subscriber
to 
                  Slate
               , I cannot tell you how much I have enjoyed the exchange
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana Gioia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wood</ENAMEX> as they reviewed contemporary poetry. How
refreshing to have candor in a review instead of the usual (and predictable)
empty praise that passes for criticism. This is a concept--and these are two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>--that you need to repeat often in the future in order for me to change
from a trial to a regular subscription. I want more of this type of intelligent
honesty in the criticism I read. Good show!

            
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Peich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Chester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX>'s
Balls
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 13</TIMEX> "" mentions
the amount of money <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70 th</NUMEX> home run ball sold for and
points out the difference between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> quoted numbers--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.7 million</NUMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $3 million</NUMEX> by the other major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. The
difference is: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is the amount that the lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> is going to get
(prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> inquiries), and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> number is the first number plus
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auctioneer</ENAMEX>'s fee. This is the amount on the check the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> writes. So
how much did it sell for? I'd say it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> number. But if the story
was about the bonanza to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, the first number is accurate.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasser Louisville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
