
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schlock</ENAMEX> and Load

            You know what sort of movie
Message in a Bottle will be from its opening montage. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shimmery</ENAMEX> orange
sunset over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Waves in slow motion, crashing. Rain on the ocean. Floating
on the bubbly: a bottle. Fade to puffy clouds. Then, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright Penn</ENAMEX>), jogs along an empty beach and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> that bottle. She kneels down
and removes it--gingerly, tenderly--from the wet sand. Now here's the clincher,
the holy touch: She pats the sand on the beach back down. Good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>. Blessed
sand.

            She'd probably have said
a prayer, except she's too busy reading the missive in the bottle, which has
been lovingly composed on a manual typewriter. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Catherine</ENAMEX> ," it
begins. "I've lost 
               my bearings. I've never been lost before. " The
fog rolls in. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa</ENAMEX> is hooked. "I'm sorry I didn't hold you with so much
strength that even God couldn't pull you away ." As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theresa</ENAMEX>'s
sums it up, "Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the world wants to be loved like that."

            Who is this supremely sensitive and poetically pining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paramour</ENAMEX>? I trust I'm not spoiling the surprise when I tell you that he's
top-billed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX>, complete with sandy hair and a slightly deeper tan
than the one he sported as a golf pro in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tin Cup</ENAMEX> . He bears the Harlequin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moniker "Garret Blake</ENAMEX>" and works on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outer Banks of North Carolina</ENAMEX>
and speaks with winsome gentleness--but he can throw a punch when he has to.
Not that he has to around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Theresa</ENAMEX>, who traces him through his stationery and
shows up pretending that she's interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>. The one he's shining up now
is a beauty, but it wasn't always that way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garret</ENAMEX>: "She was neglected,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unappreciated</ENAMEX>." Theresa: "I know how she feels." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garret</ENAMEX> (taking her in): "I
doubt it." The last is said in a courtly fashion, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garret</ENAMEX> is no lech.
He's too busy poetically pining for his lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX>, and it's difficult to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lech</ENAMEX> and pine poetically simultaneously.

            These are two
extraordinarily beautiful, literate, soulful, kindly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely people</ENAMEX> of roughly
the same age. The challenge facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald DiPego</ENAMEX> is to create
impediments enough to keep them apart for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> or so. Issues must be left
hanging: Where is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX>, anyhow? Why does a belligerent yokel (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Savage</ENAMEX>)
want to bust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garret</ENAMEX>'s head? Most momentously: When will Theresa tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garret</ENAMEX>
that she first came poking around his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> because she'd found his letter and
already knew the depth of his heart? When he stumbles on the truth, will he
feel violated? Will he storm out into a pouring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>? Will she pursue him,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleading</ENAMEX>, weeping, trying to explain that it was God who threw that bottle out
of the sea and into her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Garret</ENAMEX> manage to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine</ENAMEX> behind him
before he loses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa</ENAMEX> too, or will fate keep them tragically separated?

            Whether you attend Message in a Bottle with a hankie
or a vomit bag depends, of course, on your own predilections. Mine run less
toward schlock romances than schlock thrillers but, hey, I can recognize an
expertly engineered, inspirational soap opera when I see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The movie, based
on a best-selling novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Sparks</ENAMEX>, preys on the unsatisfied longings
in us all; were it to satisfy any of them too quickly its spell would evaporate
in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. It's probably just as well for the film's commercial prospects
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Mandoki</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When a Man Loves a Woman</ENAMEX> ), does not
appear to have a mind with multiple tracks. He and his great cinematographer,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caleb Deschanel</ENAMEX>, focus all their energy and resources on the task of lyrically
withholding your gratification.

            It's no mystery why this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> appealed to
Costner, who also co-produced the picture: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> does all the emoting,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--passive, overly contained--reaps the rewards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Wright Penn</ENAMEX>
emotes well. She's a good, no-nonsense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> who can disappear into a part
and whose beauty needs no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">embellishment</ENAMEX>. But there's nothing
distinctive about her--no funky <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> of personality that signal the
difference between a gorgeous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> and a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. She and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner</ENAMEX> are
meant to be elemental in their attractiveness, but they also demonstrate that
there's a perilously thin line between the elemental and the simple-minded.

            What a waste to use
colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Illeana Douglas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robbie Coltrane</ENAMEX> as blah second
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>. And what could have possessed the movie<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX> to cast the topmost of
top <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Newman</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>--a crotchety, albeit caring, voice
of wisdom? Yes, I'd rather watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman than</ENAMEX>, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilford Brimley</ENAMEX>, but the
real tragedy here is reducing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX> to hovering on the periphery and
delivering old codger lines such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Young lady</ENAMEX>, if I were 150 years younger
..."? If Message in a Bottle is finally about holding onto what's most
dear before it's too late, shouldn't we be chucking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner</ENAMEX> into the briny and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinging</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX>?

            If Message in a Bottle plays like an inflated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlequin</ENAMEX> romance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payback</ENAMEX> plays like an inflated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocket Books</ENAMEX> pulp.
Based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Stark</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Hunter</ENAMEX> , the same novel that provided
narrative fodder for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Boorman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde noir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Point Blank</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payback</ENAMEX> has a syntax much more old-fashioned than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>. In
more or less linear fashion, it tells the story of a violent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX>), who, left for dead after a double-cross, re-emerges with an implacable
determination to avenge himself on his ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Val</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Henry</ENAMEX>), and
reclaim <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $70,000</NUMEX> that is rightfully his--rightfully in the sense that he's
the one who actually stole it.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payback</ENAMEX> sounded
like a good time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Helgeland</ENAMEX>, also co-wrote
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Confidential</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>) and gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> one of his wildest roles ever
in his script for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conspiracy Theory</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>)--which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> hit out of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, striking a note of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">authentic paranoia</ENAMEX> that put him leagues ahead of
most action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX>'s pretty good in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Payback</ENAMEX> , too. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Point Blank</ENAMEX> was an automaton, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX> oscillates between
bug-eyed monomania and hangdog embarrassment. When he realizes, for instance,
that he has no choice but to bust someone's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, he prefaces the brutal act
with a look of weariness, even sorrow, for the blood he's about to draw.

            God help me, I had a decent time at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payback</ENAMEX> . But I
don't offer that admission proudly--it's more in the spirit of "Look how
debased my taste has become after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> of sitting through crap thrillers."
The shambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX> beats <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> in, gets his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> beaten in,
beats some more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> in, and drives away. The end. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helgeland</ENAMEX> has set
the film in a metropolis of uncertain period (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>? the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX>?) and has kept
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX> 's absurdist archetypal lingo--the crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX> goes by
the name of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Outfit"</ENAMEX>--but the film has no mythic resonances, and it has
been photographed in a brackish, blue-tinted monochromatic style that's meant
to be expressive but just looks cheap.

            For some reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX>'s revenge doesn't stop at
Val but continues up the ladder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outfit</ENAMEX> as he clamors to collect his
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX>. None of the movie's distinguished crime honchos--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Devane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coburn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kris Kristofferson</ENAMEX>--can understand why he's risking his and others'
lives in pursuit of such a paltry sum. The problem with the movie is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helgeland</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to understand it either: It's just a line on which to
hang a lot of shootings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-bashings, and explosions. The only moments of
conviction come from an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian-American</ENAMEX> dominatrix called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Liu</ENAMEX>), who
brings far more glee to the task of beating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up than the picture's star
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> could have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as much fun as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX> is having,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payback</ENAMEX> would be a kick.

         
      
   
