
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX>'s Objection

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, as Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX>, was urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to convict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of perjury
and obstruction of justice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Harkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, rose and objected to the
"use of the word 'jurors' when referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> scrambled
for their notebooks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> stirred from their slumber at this deviation
from the trial's script. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judd Gregg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX>'s complaint a
pointless distraction, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> dismissed it as a semantic quibble. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX>'s objection was neither unscripted nor purely semantic. It was an
important strategic maneuver.

            "Regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> cannot
overrule the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>. "Not so here.
Regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> do not decide what evidence should be heard, the standards of
evidence, nor do they decide what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> shall be called. Not so here.
Regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> do not decide when a trial is to be ended. Not so here. ... I
think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> meant us, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, to be something
other than a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX> added, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> decides one thing--facts--and sometimes the law. We have a much broader
responsibility. ... We can't hide behind the curtain of saying, 'Oh, I'm just a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juror</ENAMEX>, I can't take that into account.' We have to take everything into
account."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin proudly</ENAMEX> explained that he wasn't surprised when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> ruled in his favor, because he had read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s book on
impeachment and knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> in an impeachment trial
were "more than just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>." He asserted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s ruling "undermines
their case for bringing any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, because obviously we are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>."
Above all, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> was affirming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> "can take into
account not just the facts and the law, but the public good ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> really means that we can be expansive, that we can decide on a much
broader set of findings than just the findings of fact or law."

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> actually
said, however, was narrower. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is not simply a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. It is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in
this case," he ruled. The word "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>," consisting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>, is
crucial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> was agreeing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> could decide questions such as
"what evidence should be heard" and "when a trial is to be ended," which are
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>, are bound by facts
and law. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX> was distorting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s ruling into an affirmation that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> could reach beyond the facts and the law to consider "the public
good."

            Harkin correctly construed the jury metaphor as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> strategy to frame the debate. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for more analysis of that
strategy.) "I believe that the continual use of the word 'juror' by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> was meant to sort of circumscribe ... what we could do in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>,"
he said. "They were trying to put us in a box" in which "all we could do was to
take the facts and decide" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s guilt or innocence. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX>'s purpose
was equally strategic: to break out of that box, dispense with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, set
aside persuasive facts and inconvenient law, and instead acquit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> based
on the undefined "public good." All the while portraying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s focus on
facts as a cowardly ruse to "hide behind the curtain" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> scruple.

            The "public good" may indeed be a valid reason not
to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> didn't authorize that
consideration, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> metaphor doesn't square with it, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
have yet to define it.

         
      
   
