
   
   
      
         
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 27</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> articles and a photo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> chronicle <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s bleakness. The grimmest piece describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>
in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> survive without money: They skip rent payments, grow <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in
garden plots, and go without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> and meat. (The local shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> employs
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and makes only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> pairs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.) Underlying theme: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> is a
Potemkin village of prosperity, and the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is dying. ... The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> publishes a sublime guide to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s doomsday prophets and other
assorted millennialists. Among the many highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morningland</ENAMEX>, whose high
priestess preaches that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> will land a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX> "the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard W. Noone</ENAMEX>, who says the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s crust will shift on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 2000</TIMEX>, turning oceans into "maelstroms of death"; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meade Ministries</ENAMEX>, which
believes the "world will soon be engulfed in a sticky white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>."
... The cover profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Penn</ENAMEX> gushes over his cowboy independence,
high-paying roles.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28 and Jan. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> fiction issue
includes short stories by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Kesey</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Proulx</ENAMEX>. ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Nabokov</ENAMEX> reviews his own autobiography. (He wrote the review of
his book in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> but never published it.) It is a superb review, though he's a
bit too fulsome in his praise for himself: "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nabokov</ENAMEX> is to be congratulated
for having performed a very capable and very necessary job," writes Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>. ... A fascinating article tells the real story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kid</ENAMEX>. He was not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bonney</ENAMEX>" and was not a killer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX>.
Instead he was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry McCarthy</ENAMEX>," and he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> in a vicious war between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranchers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. A convert from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholicism</ENAMEX> to
Presbyterianism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> took the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> side and murdered fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irishmen</ENAMEX>.
... The annual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> poem closes with the wish "may our inmost
selves aspire/ to higher things, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>!"

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1999</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            A prosperous writer
spends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> in the low-wage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX>, waitressing at a cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>'s bleak
restaurant. She describes how difficult it is to survive on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> an hour and how
nasty working conditions for low-wage service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are and explains why it
costs more to be poor than to be rich (e.g., her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> can't save enough
for a security deposit on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> apartment, so they must rent week-to-week
at exorbitant rates).

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Esquire</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1999</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The much-previewed
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Huffington</ENAMEX> reveals that he is--surprise, surprise--gay. The
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> and ex-husband of conservative glamour-puss Arianna
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huffington</ENAMEX> says he never liked politics and is glad he lost his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race (on
which he dropped <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX>). The article leaves the impression that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huffington</ENAMEX> is quite confused and a bit dull. ... The annual Dubious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Achievement Awards</ENAMEX> celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> as "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the worst year ever</TIMEX>": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> wins
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man of the Year</ENAMEX>" title over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX>, Lucianne
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, and others.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28 and Jan. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 1998, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Men of the Year</ENAMEX>" for their "shared obstinacy."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's view of both is dim: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s loss of control inspired the
other's, and we are no better for anything either of them did." In a long
accompanying profile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> says he is the "tortoise" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "hare." In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s defense, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> notes that he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the results of the
dress DNA tests in advance. On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> let his aggressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deputies</ENAMEX> hijack his investigation. Oddly, there is no profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
himself, but there is a long piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. (She was bumped as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Woman of the Year</ENAMEX>" by the successful impeachment.) "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Better Half</ENAMEX>" says that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> marriage is rocky but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> believes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s infidelities
mean only that he is weak, not that he doesn't love her. ... Slugger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX> is dubbed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hero of the Year</ENAMEX>" for his modesty and generosity.
... An impeachment ticktock recounts the crazy events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28 and Jan. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
impeachment cover chronicles the terrible week. Curious scoop: Despite
claims that they were voting only on evidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> examined documents containing "old,
unsubstantiated allegations unearthed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>." ... A piece says that impeachment won't hurt your stock portfolio: Wall
Street has already taken into account the political disruption. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> contends that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> attack made no sense strategically,
and it won't aid our efforts to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s weapons development.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baseball</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> comeback was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a mere</TIMEX> respite from its overall
decline, argues the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. Salaries are too high, attendance is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spotty</ENAMEX>, and the chasm between rich and poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> is widening. ... The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perspectives</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roundup</ENAMEX> recalls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best cartoons and quotes: "If I ever
want to have an affair with a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> again, especially if he's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
please shoot me," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica to Linda</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28 and Jan. 4</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The highlights of the
impeachment cover package: A piece predicts the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">august</TIMEX>, rule-abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will hold a trial,
and a column argues that "We're all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> now." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, like the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> because they have no choice, and the
alternative is too awful to contemplate. ... The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> package celebrates "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innovators</ENAMEX>," arguing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> produces the best new ideas because it charges little for patents,
doesn't punish business failure, and superbly transfers technology from the
public sector to the private. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">innovators</ENAMEX> saluted include: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of
"talking books" for the blind, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> who designs friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, a
biochemist pushing for-profit science, and incoming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX> "The
Body" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>. (Which of these is not like the others?)

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, which has
been pushing impeachment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, celebrates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Finest Hour</ENAMEX>." The
editorial declares that "History will smile on these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>; they may
never live a nobler moment." ... A piece nominates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man of the Year</ENAMEX>" for refusing
to cave to poll pressure. ... A short profile of probable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hastert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, says little about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> except that he's a quiet
conservative. Mostly it disses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Cox</ENAMEX>--who also considered bidding for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>--as "arrogant and cold."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4 and 11</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The triumphal cover
story marshals an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of statistics to prove that "life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has never
been better." Crime, accidents, fires, drinking, smoking, drugging, air
pollution, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water pollution</ENAMEX>, racism, and divorce are declining. We live longer,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">happier</ENAMEX>, wealthier lives than ever before. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit American</ENAMEX> pragmatism: We
really can fix our problems if we try. ... An article says
impeachment-crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R-Ga.</ENAMEX>, lied about his association with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">racist Council of Concerned Citizens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, despite his claims to the contrary,
spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s conference, never denounced its views, and
knew about its loathsome ideology when he spoke to it. ... The editorial
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> bombing proves <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s strength, not its weakness: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the</ENAMEX>
middle of the greatest political excruciation in its modern history, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is doing the noble and necessary thing."

         
      
   
