
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  She's All
That
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). A clichéd high school Pygmalion
story is enlivened by some witty writing: "not a great movie, but it has its
moments" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prinze Jr.</ENAMEX> plays
a smart, rich, popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> who (on a bet) transforms <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachael Leigh Cook</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">earnest</ENAMEX>, morose art nerd, into prom queen material. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> take note of both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stars</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>, who is likened by many to a young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winona Ryder</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> gives the film a glowing review, saying
it "puts a priority on intelligence" and is a "special delight for anyone for
whom high school was something less than nirvana." (Visit the official site.)

            
               
                  The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> Hour
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woman</ENAMEX>
                (The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shooting Gallery</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie Perez</ENAMEX> fast-talks her way
through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this</TIMEX> drama of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> torn between her career and new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call it flat: "a homey compendium of feminist talking points laced with
awkward satire" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The film's breakneck
speed, mostly showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perez</ENAMEX> being pulled in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> directions at once, is "a
scream--not because it's funny, but because screaming is about all anyone does"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Newsday</ENAMEX> ). A few enjoy the
high-decibel/high-speed film, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Taubin</ENAMEX>,
who says it's "a tour de force of barely controlled hysteria that's as funny as
it's insightful." (Did you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie Perez</ENAMEX> cut a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s throat at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 12</TIMEX>?
Find out more about her at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CelebSite</ENAMEX> .)

            
               
                  Still
Crazy
               (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). Nice but unenthusiastic reviews for
this account of a fictional 1970s rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">present-day</TIMEX> reunion. While
comparisons to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Is Spinal Tap</ENAMEX> are inevitable, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say this is
much more a straightforward feel-good comedy than a satire. Written by The
Commitments ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian La Frenais</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Clement</ENAMEX>, the film isn't about
making fun of aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> as much as it is about rekindling old friendships:
"winsome if entirely predictable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Brace</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ).
(Download the trailer here.)

            
               
                  My Name Is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artisan Entertainment</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Loach</ENAMEX>'s
departure from agitprop filmmaking: "a pleasant surprise--there's no overt
political content" just "a delightful, heartwarming, grown-up love story"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Foreman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ) about a recovering alcoholic in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glasgow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, putting his life back together. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Mullan</ENAMEX> won the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> award <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX> for this "raw, emotionally charged" performance
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Newsday</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Loach</ENAMEX> talks about his previous work in a
RealVideo clip and an interview here.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  What Our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mothers</ENAMEX> Didn't Tell Us: Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happiness Eludes</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Woman</ENAMEX>
               ,by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Crittenden</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). The conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commentator</ENAMEX> offers a solution to the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s problems: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Marry young</ENAMEX>, put
career after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, get comfortable with the idea of being supported by hubby.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> don't buy all of it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> predictably doles
out praise: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This wonderful</ENAMEX>, breezy book reads as easily as all the women's
magazines the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> uses for her evidence. But it bravely faces what those
magazines, steeped in feminist ideology, steadfastly avoid" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Graglia</ENAMEX>).
But others note that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crittenden</ENAMEX>'s claim that "feminism has failed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," it "does not seem to have failed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
who is building her own career based in the subject" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Glieck</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> alike agree that
Crittenden oversimplifies both the nature of the contemporary workplace and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s choices. (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> here, courtesy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> [free registration
required].)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Isabelle</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Strout</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). Raves for this
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> warring with her teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, whose blossoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexuality</ENAMEX> and questionable relationship with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> upset the careful
balance of their existence together. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Truax</ENAMEX> calls it "an excellent novel
about enduring the banalities of ordinary life" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne Berne</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> agrees: "one of those
rare, invigorating books that take an apparently familiar world and peer into
it with ruthless intimacy, revealing a strange and startling place." (Read an excerpt from the book.)

            
               
                  Heavy
Water
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmony Books</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX> is one
of the most talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>; they disagree as to whether
this collection provides fresh evidence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX> marvels at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX>' ability to
write stories that "seem to have been written on a dare, or as entries in a
contest to see who could get the best results from the worst ideas" (the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). But some are unimpressed with these tossed-off
tales. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> seems downright irritated: "The volume is basically a
case of a skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> lazily using his sleight of hand to toss off what
(with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> exceptions) are pure exercises in craft" (the New York
Times ). (Find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amis</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Featured Author</ENAMEX>" page.)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie
                  --
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --
                  Playing by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another Day</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stahl</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Face-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Tarloff</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Miss Nobody , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomek Tryzna</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Varsity Blues</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- At First Sight</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- In Dreams</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duane</ENAMEX>'s Depressed , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry McMurtry</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intuitionist</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colson Whitehead</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Fosse: A Celebration in Song and Dance</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadhurst Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Affliction ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hi-Lo Country</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> Era , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Weinstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Vassiliev</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --Note <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Found in a Bottle: My Life</ENAMEX> as a Drinker , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Cheever</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glamorama</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bret Easton Ellis</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Action</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Thin Red Line</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Down in the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hurlyburly</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Theory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Careless Love: The Unmaking of Elvis</ENAMEX>
Presley , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guralnick</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katchor</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
