
   
   
      
         
             A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Bestiary

            The assumption of bad faith
on the part of one's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> is a hallowed tradition of politics, and Flytrap
has honored it. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have tended to assume that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are pursuing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> simply out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">loathing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have tended to assume that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are defending him simply out of political expediency. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impeaching Clinton</ENAMEX> on a nearly party-line vote, obligingly fulfilled those
expectations.

            But the pregame of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial is already confusing those assumptions. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are
behaving like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Why?

            What follows is a taxonomy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, an attempt to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classify senators</ENAMEX> and explain why they're doing what they're doing.

            The Controller : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX> The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> early conclusions drawn about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s
efforts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> a deal were that the majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is too conservative, too
weak, or both. How else to explain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s weak push of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorton-Lieberman</ENAMEX>
plan to cut short the trial by holding an early test vote on whether the
charges justify removing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office, and his concessions to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX> who wanted an expansive trial?

            But these conclusions don't do justice to his deft
handling of an impossible position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s conservative principles are at odds
with the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> defining elements of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>: political pragmatism
and an almost pathological love of efficiency. Much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s principles tell
him to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and much as he would love to satisfy
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> knows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> won't be convicted and
that a long trial will unhinge his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, disrupt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s business, and
endanger <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> has actually
accomplished more than most expected, a fact that even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> admit privately. He has assuaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> by giving up on
Gorton-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX>. In the process, he has paved the way for a trial that will be
longer--a month, apparently--but still limited. Which is essentially what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>
has wanted all along.

            Blocking that limited trial are the Unbowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> . The most vocal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inhofe</ENAMEX>. Others include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Smith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Smith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownback</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nickles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unbowed</ENAMEX>, who tend to be
quite religious, have never lost their outrage about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s moral failings
and crimes. They sincerely believe he is unfit to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> requires a full trial--damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> be damned!
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unbowed</ENAMEX> can afford their principles because of their other notable quality:
None faces re-election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> . Most also live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where torturing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectator</ENAMEX> sport. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> as a whole may suffer from a
long trial, but they won't.

            The ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unbowed Conservatives</ENAMEX> would be thicker
but for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Campaigning Conservatives</ENAMEX> . By temperament and principle,
they agree with everything the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Unbowed Conservatives</ENAMEX> say. But political
necessity beckons. All face tough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> races in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is quite
popular. They know that a prolonged, cringe-inducing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial could be
disastrous for their prospects. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Campaigning Conservatives</ENAMEX> walk a delicate
line: They want to inflict the maximum possible punishment on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the
minimal possible time. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ashcroft</ENAMEX>, for example, has demanded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s resignation, declared that censure is unconstitutional, and insisted
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hold a trial. But he also says the trial should be quick and no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> should be called. Besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashcroft</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaigning Conservatives</ENAMEX>
include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Grams</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>).

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch McConnell</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> is an honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>. The extremely conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McConnell</ENAMEX> is not
running for re-election. In his heart, he undoubtedly favors a full trial. But
oversees the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> elections for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. So he, too, is backing a quick,
witnessless trial to protect his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.)

            The largest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> may be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tight-Lipped</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> . These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, who include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">old-timers</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Stevens</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thad Cochran</ENAMEX>,
are as annoyed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. But they're sick of the whole
business, want it to end, don't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> or the party damaged by it, and
don't want to talk about it. The most prominent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tight-Lipped</ENAMEX>, oddly, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, who is never tight-lipped. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, who is running
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and has his own shaky marital history, has assiduously ducked
comment. "I'm about as big a media hound as anyone," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>,
but "I've turned down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 500</NUMEX>--maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX>--requests to go on talk
shows on this issue." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tight-Lipped Republicans</ENAMEX> will probably vote for
conviction but will also cooperate with any compromise that shortens the
trial.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tight-Lipped Republicans</ENAMEX> are not to be confused
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Moderates</ENAMEX> , who may not vote for conviction. The mods are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chafee</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olympia Snowe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>. None seems comfortable with the notion of removing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
for sex-related misdeeds. All but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> are running for re-election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>,
and all represent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where the removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is anathema. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s
procedural agreement collapses and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> faces a long, ugly trial, the
Mods are the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> most likely to support a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> motion to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjourn</ENAMEX>.

            Not all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Moderates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>, who is often lumped with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mods</ENAMEX>, really belongs with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> . Led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeWine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>), who are, in fact, ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> view
themselves as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Law</ENAMEX>. They tend to favor a trial
with as much procedural baggage as can be attached. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX>, for example,
pushed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> to drop its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> inquiry but, once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">impeached</ENAMEX>, became an adamant supporter of a trial. He even favors having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> testify. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> reject <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorton-Lieberman</ENAMEX> as a fraud and call
censure unconstitutional. They are also alarmingly prone to say things like
"I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stickler</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disgruntled</ENAMEX>
Pragmatists lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Chief among them is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lieberman</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPs</ENAMEX> can barely open their mouths without savaging the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX> repeats his desire for a "stinging censure" so often that
I am beginning to think he likes whips. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPs</ENAMEX> tend to view <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
failures as moral rather than criminal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPs</ENAMEX> know that a long
trial probably benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, but they are so sick of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> and so
concerned about the comity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> that they will do almost anything to
end this quickly. The other salient characteristic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disgruntled</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pragmatists</ENAMEX> is that they speak out. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have ducked the
spotlight during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> because they don't want to get stuck defending the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s loathsome behavior. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPs</ENAMEX>, who have inoculated themselves by
attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, have filled that void. Those who criticize the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> most are his most effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disgruntled Pragmatists</ENAMEX> provide cover for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tight-Lipped Democrats</ENAMEX> and Anxious 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> .
Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> wants to talk about the scandal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tight-Lipped</ENAMEX>, like their
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>, are sick of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> and will do anything to end the
trial with as little damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> as possible. The Anxious face
re-election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Robb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>) is the most prominent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robb</ENAMEX>, who had
his own sex scandal and represents a generally conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, has made it
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> with barely a public utterance. (When quizzed, his
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> gave me the most innocuous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> sentences I have ever heard.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robb</ENAMEX>, it seems, will do his "duty.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tight-Lipped and Anxious Dems</ENAMEX> will let
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> do the work of negotiating a deal and selling it to the
public, keep their mouths shut, and vote to acquit.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Partisans</ENAMEX> seek
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> political victory. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> believe that a full trial can
serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. A trial would prove, once and for all,
how frivolous the charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> are and warn any future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> not
to use impeachment as a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Harkin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>) is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
who expresses this view publicly, saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should be "exonerated"
with a "definitive vote." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX> also acknowledges the political benefit from a
trial: "I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are reeling from this," he told the New York
Times .

            At the far end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caucus</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partisans</ENAMEX>
are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutionalists</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Byrd</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>). They don't particularly care about saving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> or about the
health of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. They aren't worried about their poll numbers,
since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> is retiring and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX> holds a safe seat. They are most concerned
about protecting their beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> is now pushing censure in
order to "protect the presidency as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>." Impeachment could
"destabilize the presidency" and "degrade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> quickly."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX>, who has joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> in trying to draft a
censure resolution, has made it his mission to guard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s prerogatives.
He has warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> not to lobby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> for their vote. According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX>, everyone--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>--should stop jockeying
and let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
