
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> on the Rack

            Anti-Americanism gripped
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, the press heralded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s visit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> with gloomy assessments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>
relations. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestia</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Abarinov</ENAMEX> wrote that they were going
through "a time of trouble" and that disagreements between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
had been "snowballing." He said that their opinions differed on practically
every issue and that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anti-Americanism</ENAMEX> has become 'in' in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> political
circles."

            An article in
Komsomolskaya
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pravda</ENAMEX> said that "differences over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> that allegedly collaborated with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
plan to withdraw from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ABM Treaty</ENAMEX>, and an old one to enlarge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> have
brought the temperature of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russo-American</ENAMEX> relations to a record low since the
end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s ex-press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Yastrzhembsky</ENAMEX> as saying on television that cooperation between
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> appears to be over. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> press comment after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s
talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Igor Ivanov</ENAMEX> was rather more upbeat, though
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nezavisimaya Gazeta</ENAMEX> again described her visit as having taken place "at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most difficult moments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> relations" and described the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> plan to amend the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">anti-ballistic missile</ENAMEX> treaty as "clearly
unacceptable." It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivanov</ENAMEX> as saying, in reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American ABM</ENAMEX>
initiative, that it is vital that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> "spring no more surprises
on each other."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with a report on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s efforts to
force the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>' chief weapons
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations Sergei</ENAMEX> Lavrov
had described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>'s report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX>, used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to justify the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, as "not
professional," "biased," and "provocative," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX> had
responded by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lavrov</ENAMEX>'s comments "bullshit." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lavrov</ENAMEX> has said he would
continue to insist on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler</ENAMEX>'s resignation because he didn't have the
confidence of a majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. In its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> edition,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> led with a revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>
working as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> had placed and operated spying
devices that were later used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to select targets for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Desert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dawn</ENAMEX> condemned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> air attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, saying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in an editorial that it was
"shocking that not even a whimper has been heard in protest against these
blatant acts of terrorism on the part of the sole superpower in the world. ...
Should the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> be allowed to get away with this sort of bullying and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">banditry?</ENAMEX>"

            A l-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Khaleej</ENAMEX> , a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Arab Emirates</ENAMEX>,
said in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that the attacks demonstrated "the contempt in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> holds its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, even when they do its political
bidding. ... After applauding the statement issued by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> following their 'consultative' meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
proceeded to ignore the most important thing that statement had to say--namely,
its appeal for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to desist from military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and pursue
peaceful diplomacy instead."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> said that the closing statement
issued at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>' meeting had been "woefully inadequate"
and, by failing to condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Desert Fox</ENAMEX>, had made it possible for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> to claim <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> support for further military action.

            However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq al-Awsat</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> had only itself to blame for the
isolation it encountered at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> gathering. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> that had wanted a
meeting of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> held, followed by a summit, in order to get the
embargo against it lifted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "That being the case, one would have
assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> would have done its best to secure the support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, or at least the most important ones, and the goodwill of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX>," it added. "But what happened is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> began by
denouncing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX>, then turned on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, and then on the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>!"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> received
extensive coverage in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most famous sinner meets His Holiness</ENAMEX>" was the
headline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX>), but especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> where the
Corriere della
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in a front-page editorial that although no
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had ever met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> more often, nor made such a public
display of his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> faith than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, "perhaps no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has become
so distant from the Holy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>. ... Beneath the smiles and formal concord of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> there is a widening gulf between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> who represents the voice of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mankind</ENAMEX>'s conscience and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who hasn't failed to deliver on his material
promises, but who has violated his spiritual ones." It added that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> must
also have been saddened not only by "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sexgate</ENAMEX>" but also by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s attacks on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, since "in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, at the time of their first
meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, he probably saw in the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, so socially committed,
a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in the reconstruction of a just and peaceful world after a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> of hot and cold wars."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espectador</ENAMEX> , bitterly lamented the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s unreadiness for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
earthquake disaster. "Just when you think things couldn't be worse, it turns
out that they are," it said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in an editorial, pointing out that only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> earthquake warning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> had been working at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> coastal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> had been completely cut off from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Seismological Network</ENAMEX>, having no money to maintain its equipment. All
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>'s disaster prevention <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> were on the edge of collapse, it
said.

             

         
      
   
