
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">169</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Eats/Wets&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               You chew household
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objects</ENAMEX> and drool copiously, and perhaps you defecate or urinate on the
floor.
            

            

               Who are you, and what should you do next?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 168</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East/East</ENAMEX>":
            

            

               
                  "We've been made the butt of a joke in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>--on television,
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. We take it not as funny but as something very serious." Who
said this about what?
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>, on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. Which is why he's outlawed television
and radio, starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Also, he's dissolved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reichstag</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, is looking like an awfully convenient 'corridor to the sea.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carvell</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene Hellerman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cavanaugh</ENAMEX> had similar
answers.)

            "The
ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX> speaks out, in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> plural, against his
recent bad press. 'Although we may have fired a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> without
congressional approval, we never had sexual relations with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Staples</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of the outer boroughs, about TV shows such as The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> and comic strips such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumb Bastards From</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> ."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sante</ENAMEX>
Kimes, about her odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-rearing techniques."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunkin' Donuts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>, on the termination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rugrats</ENAMEX> product
tie-in negotiations."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cole</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Once, when you were made
the butt of a joke, a recurring punch line on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>, it really was serious:
You were finished as a public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>.) More recently, when you
become a running gag on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave or Jay</ENAMEX>, you're merely humanized. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>.)
Perhaps that's as it should be. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mockability</ENAMEX> is an evanescent quality; it's the
slip-up, the gaffe, the anomalous pratfall. To joke about such things is the
comic equivalent of scandal journalism, focusing on crime rather than policy.
But it's not their missteps that are the problem, it's their steps. Or as a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s once said, it's not what's illegal that's the
crime; it's what's legal.

            
               Deep-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fried</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cream-Filled Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            As everyone knew, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Laudermilk</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunkin' Donuts</ENAMEX>, said it about a photograph in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> of a
mouse nibbling a doughnut in the window of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>'s midtown
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>.

            "Anytime someone laughs at your trademark and what's
going on in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, you've been damaged," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laudermilk</ENAMEX>.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunkin' Donuts</ENAMEX>
filed suit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riese Organization</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">store</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pairs</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duo</ENAMEX> has something in common. What?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shozaburo Nakamura</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steinbrenner</ENAMEX>

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>: The former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joined Akin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gump</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strauss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hauer & Feld</ENAMEX>, the law and lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> works, along with founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Strauss</ENAMEX>. It's bipartisanship at its finest--rich and
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> joining rich and powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to help rich and
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>: Each is honored by a new minting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> on a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 pound</NUMEX> coin, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a series of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
commemorative quarters. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them shows somebody on a horse.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Remorse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mates</ENAMEX>: Each
made a public apology--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nakamura</ENAMEX> for calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>, and
Steinbrenner for the way he fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yogi Berra</ENAMEX>.

            
               Race
Results
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s most frequent
target: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
