
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Drawing upon her rich experience of life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>) responds to questions about manners, personal relations, politics, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Please send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Queries
should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> words in length. Please indicate how you wish your letter
to be signed, preferably including your location.
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> is an exceedingly good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, and when
he comes to my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> on business it's understood that I am delighted to take him
out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, put him up in my guest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, etc. Ditto for when I'm in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. As we're both computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX>, when we happen to be going to the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> show or conference, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> life plans and party invites for me
automatically include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>--and vice versa.
            

            
               Enter The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Problem</ENAMEX> in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moe</ENAMEX>, a common
acquaintance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> who sometimes attends the same conferences.
Moe simply invites himself along to everything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> and I do for the whole
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. If he gets wind of our plans, he'll turn up to meet us. If he hasn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overheard</ENAMEX> anything, he'll simply tag along with one of us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch</TIMEX>
or dinner or whatever. We have attempted to gently give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moe</ENAMEX> the message that
he's not welcome unless invited, but it just bounces off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moe</ENAMEX>'s tact-proof
armor.
            

            
               Prudie, HELP. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moe</ENAMEX>'s
not a jerk, he's just clueless, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> and I are agreed that we'd just like
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freakin</ENAMEX>' option of him not joining us. We'd like to achieve this without
actually being forced to tell him to **** off, but we're nearing our rope's
end.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shemp</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Shemp</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> deplores the density of your cyberclod
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> and sees no reason for you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> to have to be stealth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geeks</ENAMEX>. Since
you've tried tact, you must now be direct with this judgment-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>.
Simply tell him you hate like hell to hurt his feelings, but you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> use
these gatherings to catch up, and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> simply changes the dynamic. (It
is, alas, poor manners to ever tell anyone to **** off.)

            You must be benevolent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">despots</ENAMEX>, lest you find yourself manipulated by someone with the hide of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhinoceros</ENAMEX>. Gird your loins, make your statement, and brook no further
discussion ... roger and out.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, determinedly

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               We are often invited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and dinners at
some really splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> owned by wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquaintances</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> of both
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and me. Should we invite these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthies</ENAMEX> back to our
comparatively humble, small home? They know we are not in their league
financially, but we feel a little sheepish inviting them to view our worn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upholstery</ENAMEX> and carpets. We wonder if they, too, would feel uncomfortable with
our differences made so plainly apparent.
            

            
               Should we just muster
our courage and invite them over, or should we invite them for dinner/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> at
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>? Would this seem impersonal and contrived?
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stuck in the Middle Class</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Stuck</ENAMEX>,

            It has been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>'s experience that, when invited
to a simple home, she has often been impressed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> in such a situation
usually are genuine, confident, and wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>: genuine because they are who
they are, confident because they know where the real values lie, and wise
because they understand that putting on the dog is pointless. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> of quality
do not choose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on the basis of their possessions.

            Restaurant entertaining
is becoming fashionable, however, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> would recommend that for you if
that choice would not come from shame, and if you would have a better evening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yourselves</ENAMEX>.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, entertainingly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               I am a young woman
who has made the unfortunate mistake of falling in love with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. I say
"unfortunate" because he happens to be gay. We both graduated together with the
same major: art history. I have admired his intelligence and sensitivity for a
long time. If it was not for him, I am sure I wouldn't have done nearly as well
in my studies. But I did not expect to become romantically involved! He has
asked me to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> with him, and I do not know what to do about it. If I
tell him how I really feel, I fear he will want to end everything. And yet, the
longer I am with him the worse it gets and the harder it becomes to hide my
true feelings. Should I go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>? I would rather be with him than nothing
at all. Thank you.
            

            

               --Confused
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Con</ENAMEX>,

            Ah yes, the old story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> falling for one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>'s bachelors. If it's any consolation to you, this occurrence is not all
that rare. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> cast her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> in that direction while in college
(when ice covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>). It is a truism that, straight or gay, certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to have electricity for certain other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            Occasionally, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual person</ENAMEX> will experiment
in the other arena. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> can think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> show business examples (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
and dead, the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and living). Both these gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> gave a romantic
whirl to their leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>, though the relationships were short-lived. As a
general rule, sexuality is hard-wired and that's that.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> feels it
important to point out that when you write you are "romantically involved," it
is only you experiencing the romance or the involvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> believes in the
interest of your mental health that you confess your feelings, thereby
relieving yourself of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> and pain of a fantasy love affair. When you
'fess up (and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> may already have figured things out), you might ask
if there is any reciprocal inclination. If not, your cards will be on the table
and together you can decide if the friendship continues, platonically, or if it
seems best to put things on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. You need a resolution, and better sooner than
later.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, resolutely

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> I met--but
never dated--at work left for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five months ago</TIMEX>. When he was
preparing to leave, I wrote him a letter explaining my unease about his
departure, because I felt we had somehow missed our chance at what could have
been a real relationship. I wrote it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, and I still have it. (Never
mailed it.) Without my explaining how or why I feel the "loss" more now than
ever. Can you tell me whether I should mail the letter? I'll spare you the more
complicated question of the mystical power of love.
            

            

               --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">xxxooo</NUMEX>-nyc
            

            Dear xxx,

            Interesting that you
wrote the letter but kept it. Now that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> has past, Prudie
suggests a compromise. Send the object of your affections a letter--but a
different one, a new one. Write to say that you've become aware of missing his
presence and wonder how things are going on the left coast. If he answers, and
if the answer is at all responsive, keep the correspondence going. If things
start to look promising, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you find it suddenly necessary to
visit your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>/college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>/former dog <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX>, anybody in the
city wherein the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> resides.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, plottingly

         
      
   
