
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s payoff has
failed to silence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>. In the first installment of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part "world
exclusive in-depth interview," she told the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> magazine
OK! <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that "because of my beliefs and stuff" she thought she had
been chosen "to bring this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to light." She explained, "I was the strong one
that did not say no." The unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the interview, which was spread
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 14</NUMEX> pages and accompanied by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX> large photographs of Jones
posing variously in black leather, fake leopard skin, and white shirt and
jeans, wrote that, although she was "heavily made up," there wasn't "even the
smallest hint of a smell of perfume about her."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> claimed that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" were still out to get her and that she will feel even less
safe after he leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> "because then he's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, and he may
think 'well, since I'm not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> now, I can do whatever I want--I can
get rid of her or hurt her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.' " But she said that although "something
like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could have helped to expose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for what he really is"
have died since her case started, she feels she is being watched over by God,
"the strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX> of all." Of her famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excelsior Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>,
she said it left her feeling "like he raped me, without physically raping me."
On the dismissal of her case by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Webber Wright</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> said, "I was
just devastated. I can't even describe my feelings. It was almost like I'd lost
somebody."

            In an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cambio of Bogotá</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>, reprinted in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> translation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel García Márquez</ENAMEX> praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for his
"intellectual brilliance" and lamented that "this exceptionally human man
should have his place in history distorted because he couldn't find a secluded
place in which to make love." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">García Márquez</ENAMEX> wrote, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sadder still</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> only wanted to do what the common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has done behind his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s back
since the world began. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stupidity</ENAMEX> didn't only refuse him that, it
withheld his right to deny it. ... Surely it is more dignified to perjure
yourself in defence of carnal desire than to condemn love altogether?"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent of London</ENAMEX> led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with a
warning by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> must take
urgent steps to stimulate domestic demand and bring down trade barriers to
prevent another world economic crisis. In an editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> generally supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> and attacked
protectionism. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">triumphalists</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago School</ENAMEX>, who attribute
any of the world's economic troubles to a falling short of the free-market
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX>, make the mistake of overlooking the cultural and infrastructural
differences between different economies," it said. "But they are more right
than the new protectionists." But an editorial in the Financial Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> criticized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX> for having "little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX> to offer on the great policy issue of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>:
reform of the international financial system." Discussing his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> address
had "little substance" and that that he was effectively "telling emerging
economies that it is up to them to avoid becoming ill and, should they succumb,
to make themselves better."

            Also on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sevodnya</ENAMEX> published an article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX>, under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Recovery</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>," saying that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>,
unfortunately, lived up once again to its reputation as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which has
failed to build capitalism and does not pay its debts." Referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>'s speech urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to keep faith with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> to be tolerant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> wrote that, despite his talks in Davos
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>'s Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Fischer</ENAMEX>, "no one has shown any intention thus far to write off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
debts." (For more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davos</ENAMEX> gathering, see the 
                  Slate
                "" by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie T. Allen</ENAMEX>.)

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> , Elyakim
Haetzni, who speaks for the hard-line right, wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, "On the eve of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, I recommend
that we think again, before it is too late, about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> involvement in
the negotiations." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haetzni</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX> agreement had been a catastrophe
because it had brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> to the goal he had longed for--"instead of
negotiations between him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, there would be negotiations between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> representing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>."
He went on, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wye</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestine</ENAMEX> into an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> protectorate. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
military strike would run into an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> response. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> were to refuse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s demands it would be like refusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>."

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> gave front-page treatment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to a
row over the nomination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman-philanthropist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Lauder</ENAMEX> to
chair the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of Presidents of Major Jewish Organizations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said pressure was mounting to delay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s vote on his
appointment following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s disclosure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauder</ENAMEX> had provided financial
support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wing organizations</ENAMEX> identified with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Noor</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s progress in
getting rid of anti-personnel land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The achievement of
having already destroyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 60,000</NUMEX> land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 220,000</NUMEX>
planted in various areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has been commended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Mine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action Service</ENAMEX>, established under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Ottawa Mine Ban Treaty</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said,
"It is no secret that the [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was divided on whether or not
to go ahead and sign the international treaty. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thanks to Queen Noor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
has not only signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ottawa</ENAMEX> treaty but is closer than ever to ratifying
it."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, an editorial in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asahi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shimbun</ENAMEX> applauded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for planning a new law to prevent
unauthorized access to the Internet. "The proposed legislation would punish
those who connect to the Internet by using other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s codes or by hacking
into the system," it explained. "Official regulation should be kept to a
minimum, but it is natural that improper access--which can lead to criminal
acts, such as shopping with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' accounts or rewriting and destroying
their data--should be prohibited by law."

            Back to the subject of
celebrity interviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> have published a huge number with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Winslet</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> , to promote a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> film
she has made. On the filming of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> , she told <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classic</ENAMEX> FM
magazine that "for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in my life on a film set I was thinking, 'I
wish I wasn't here.' There were even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when I would wake up and think,
'Please God, let me die.' " To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>: she said "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t was so
exciting. For me, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> when I'm working it's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>: you get up, go
see all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and do the thing you love most." At least she does not
repeat herself.

             

         
      
   
