
   
   
      
         
             The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rise of the Front Man</ENAMEX>

            It is universally agreed
that the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker-designate</ENAMEX> and his
replacement by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Hastert</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Thing</ENAMEX>. For starters, the
annunciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who doesn't cast a shadow, exposes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anorexia</ENAMEX> in the top ranks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucus</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
so strapped for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> that they had to recruit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> no one outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> had even heard of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes ago</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are now ex-wrestling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>, ex-college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>
Armey, ex-exterminator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, and ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX>. Who says
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics is dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>?)

            And, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fretting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>'s emergence also reinforces the crisis over "the politics of
personal destruction" (to use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s catch phrase). The sexual puritanism of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s own right wing undid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> cakewalked into the
speakership only because he is--fingers crossed--above reproach. It's uncertain
whether sexual litmus testing will endure, but for the moment <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is
anxious. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> and ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> are predicting that smart, charismatic folks
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> will now shun public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            There is another, less talked about, reason why the
ascension of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> is alarming. Call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Front Man Syndrome</ENAMEX>. Most people
would agree that in a well-run democracy, political power ought to be
transparent. By this I mean that those who hold nominally powerful jobs
ought to exercise correspondingly real power. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> should
be directly related. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should be the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>, the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> the most powerful in
the judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> the most powerful in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>,
etc. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">transparency</ENAMEX> serves democracy, because it enables <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to hold the
politics has not always been transparent. In the golden age of political
machines, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> often occupied ostensibly unimportant jobs and
left the glorious titles to their marionettes.)

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">transparency</ENAMEX> may be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">casualty</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> fear that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> will
be subject to personal attack--and they do--then there is a huge incentive for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to vest nominal power in squeaky-clean nonentities and hide real
power behind the scenes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> astert may be Exhibit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "Coach," as he's fondly known,
has a history of modest service to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and his district, delivering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>,
opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> health-care bills, etc. Mostly he has been a faithful
deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>, helping "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hammer</ENAMEX>" count votes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of the
conservative cause. DeLay mobilized his whip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to ensure his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>'s election as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are already wondering if
Coach will be <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hammer</ENAMEX>'s tool.

            It may be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> will be thoroughly
independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> assure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doubters</ENAMEX> that he is his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--but what if he's not? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will have placed a clean,
good-natured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> at the front of their parade, a bland and acceptable
public face for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> won't cripple the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> with a too-big mouth
and too-big ideas, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> did, and he won't cripple it with an
embarrassing history, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX> did. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> will retain the only
true power base in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucus</ENAMEX>: a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>-odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> whip
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>, the best access to corporate campaign contributions, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fearsome</ENAMEX> personality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX>, who knows he lacks the charm and cooperative
instincts required for speakership, will be able to run his operation quietly,
behind closed doors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s job will be secure, and he himself will remain
(mostly) sheltered from strict public scrutiny.

            This is, of course, pessimistic speculation. It is
far too early to know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s puppet. And even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX>'s puppet, that won't necessarily mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has
entered an era of puppetry. (A sample size of one does not an era make.) Still,
it's yet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more reason--as if we need another--to worry about what happened
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
