
   
   
      
         
            Lives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Painters</ENAMEX>, as a rule, have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">livelier</ENAMEX> lives than novelists do. Where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> basically sits alone at a
desk, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> does his thing amid a supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, and assistants. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> hones his private style, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painter</ENAMEX> joins and repudiates group movements. In the misbehavior category,
there's not even any comparison. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulkner</ENAMEX> nips from a flask in the drawer,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> makes a boozy public spectacle of himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> might have a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX> has scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painter</ENAMEX> has orgies.

            All this has made art
biographies, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giorgio Vasari</ENAMEX> started writing them in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, pretty good entertainment. Yet it's not immediately obvious how such
stories help you to appreciate what's hanging on the wall. If you want to grasp
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Truman</ENAMEX> contributed to civilization, you would do well to pick up a
good bio. You can't exactly go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> to view "containment policy."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX>, by contrast, endeavor to reach us without words. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> or art
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> may direct our attention to things we would otherwise miss. But does
the intimate biographer bring us any closer to the experience of art?

            You might derive very different answers to that question
from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> books I read over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX>. These biographies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego Rivera</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador DalÃ­</ENAMEX>, all of them by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
without backgrounds in art, represent alternative approaches to the problem of
writing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>'s life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Spurling</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> is a careful and tightly
focused attempt to illuminate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>'s development. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Marnham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX>
is a breezy life and times, a raucous and gossipy tale that is only secondarily
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> painting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Gibson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DalÃ</ENAMEX>­ is an overflowing dumpster of a book, which
puts forward an irritating psychological argument about its subject. But though
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these biographies are excellent and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one dreadful,
they all butt up against the same generic problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artists</ENAMEX>' lives are often
diverting but seldom illuminating.

            Let's start with the best
of the bunch. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spurling</ENAMEX>'s biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> volume of a projected
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, is a subtle account of a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>'s unfolding. The obvious question
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> is how a seed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s ugly and smelly
industrial north became both an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX> of modernism and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of
Mediterranean color and light. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unknown Matisse</ENAMEX> gives us his small
steps, setbacks, and radical innovations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spurling</ENAMEX>'s scoop is her explanation
of why, after moving several increments toward his mature style, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>
lapsed into a dark period that lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1902-04</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>, she has
discovered, was drawn into the scandal arising from a huge financial fraud in
which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were implicated. This took up all his time, strained
his meager resources, and gave him a breakdown. Only after his in-laws were
cleared did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> make his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fauvist</ENAMEX> breakthrough in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1905</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spurling</ENAMEX> draws our attention to some of his influences: the ornate textiles
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flanders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where he was raised, paintings by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX> seen on a
honeymoon in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CÃ</ENAMEX>©zanne painting he bought with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s grocery
money.

            The thing that is so admirable about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> is his quiet
integrity. For the better part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>, this reserved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of regular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">habits</ENAMEX> fought poverty, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, incomprehension, and rejection to make
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revolutionary</ENAMEX> painting. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> considered him a shame to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
disinherited him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teachers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> told him he was hopeless. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Contemporaries</ENAMEX>
greeted each of his milestone paintings as more ridiculous than the last. Works
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Nude</ENAMEX> shocked even rival-to-be <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>. "If
he wants to make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, let him make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. If he wants to make a design,
let him make a design. This is between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> said. Soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>
was imitating him.

            But even a biography as
well-wrought as this one does little to elucidate artistic inspiration. What
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">made Matisse</ENAMEX> radically simplify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> and flatten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> dimensions into
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in the way he did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harmony</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Red</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1908</TIMEX>)? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spurling</ENAMEX> informs us that
the pattern on the wallpaper and tablecloth comes from a bolt of blue cotton
cloth that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> glimpsed from a bus and that in the course of revising the
painting he changed the background from blue to red. This is interesting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trivia</ENAMEX>, but it does nothing, really, to enhance enjoyment of this masterpiece
or comprehension of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> could have painted it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego Rivera</ENAMEX> had a wilder life than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> and produced
less important art, a balance wisely reflected in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marnham</ENAMEX>'s entertaining
biography. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> had a lifelong involvement with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> politics,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">countless</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, famous scandals, and a soap opera of a marriage (actually two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marriages</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frida Kahlo</ENAMEX>. He was also a fabulist of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MarquÃ</ENAMEX>©zian proportions,
spinning incredible yarns about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> as a student cannibal or a fighter
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emiliano Zapata</ENAMEX>.

            The true stories are nearly as good as the imagined
ones. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> didn't, as he claimed, try to assassinate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, he may
have got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotsky</ENAMEX> murdered, writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marnham</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera evicted Trotsky</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sanctuary</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> when he found out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotsky</ENAMEX> was having
an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kahlo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kahlo seduced Trotsky</ENAMEX> because of her jealousy over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affair Rivera</ENAMEX> had with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. Without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX>'s protection, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotsky</ENAMEX> was
easier prey for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassins</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marnham</ENAMEX> gives us the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX>-Kahlo
relationship as black comedy. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> confides to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has become so depressed that he can't even cheer her up by telling her
about his latest sexual conquests.

            But in this biography,
too, we learn the salient facts of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s development without really
coming to understand how they happened. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> before and during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde</ENAMEX>, executing competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cubist</ENAMEX> works
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Still Life With Liqueur Bottle</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>). After a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, on
which he saw the frescoes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>, he dropped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubism</ENAMEX> for
what soon became his well-known mural painting. In the public fresco, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX>
saw the chance to express his political ideas to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>. But where did this
style come from? And why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX>'s murals transcend their propagandistic
purpose in a way that works by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> don't? The mystery at the
heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> remains.

            B ritish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX> can usually be counted on to boil
things down for us, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> swamps us with as much boring detail as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>. His book is crammed full of stray data he has disinterred
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DalÃ­'s Catalan</ENAMEX> ancestors, his sexual obsessions, and infighting within
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surrealist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DalÃ­</ENAMEX> was eventually drummed out of for his
pro-fascist sentiments. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> never gets around to telling us is why we
should care. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DalÃ­</ENAMEX> was a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>, which is not a
given, as with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX>'s big theory is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DalÃ</ENAMEX>­'s life was defined
by his feelings of shame. This hardly amounts to a surprising idea about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">creator</ENAMEX> of a painting titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great Masturbator</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>), but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibson</ENAMEX>
treats it as a bolt from the blue. He does not, however, come close to giving
us a sense of what went wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DalÃ</ENAMEX>­'s art. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX>, who
took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of decades</TIMEX> to attain their mature styles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DalÃ</ENAMEX>­'s arrival came
quick and early. Surrealism, a style he borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Ernst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yves</ENAMEX>
Tanguy, gave him a way to express the rancid contents of his own psyche. It's
hard to dispute the virtuosity of a painting such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Birth</ENAMEX> of Liquid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desires</ENAMEX> , painted when he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DalÃ­</ENAMEX> rapidly became slack,
repetitious, corrupt, and in the end completely pathetic. Gibson chronicles his
long degradation but can't begin to explain it.

            After reading these books, I performed an
experiment by going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> and testing my reactions
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> in question. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> had reduced DalÃ­ to a midget. Several
examples of his early works reminded me that he was not completely worthless
after all. A chunk of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivera</ENAMEX> fresco left me wishing I could see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s
great murals in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> again. Finally, I made my way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX>'s big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>
room, my favorite in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. Knowing more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>'s struggles had
certainly deepened my respect for him. I could have delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short</TIMEX> lecture
on his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>. But did the book add anything to my appreciation of his
paintings? I can't say it did.

         
      
   
