
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Dock</ENAMEX>

            Commonly described in
headlines as "the trial of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>," the impeachment proceedings against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> received massive coverage around the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> clearly under strain to find anything new to say about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s troubles. The angles varied widely from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> to paper. An editorial
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
Post compared the impeachment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s
current political turmoil and said that "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]n both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting
frustrated with political systems that have become obsessed with themselves,
and wish that what they see as unseemly distractions will be quickly over."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, the
conservative Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figaro</ENAMEX> repeated the usual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> view that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> is a symptom of
demented <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> puritanism. "Wake up, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tocqueville</ENAMEX>, they've gone mad!" began a
front-page editorial signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz-Olivier Giesbert</ENAMEX>. "When one observes the
depressing spectacle presented by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> imagines that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who talked best about it cannot be feeling very well in his heaven.
There is decidedly something rotten in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> of democracy. The American
obsession with truth and purity has turned morbid and demanding of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychoanalysis</ENAMEX>. It is even endangering the whole political system."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japan Times</ENAMEX> said the impeachment drama had been
"sordid and embarrassing, lending itself to the worst sort of moralistic
posturing and inevitable charges of hypocrisy and opportunism." It went on, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>
has ended or done serious damage to several once-promising political careers.
... For all his accomplishments, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legacy has been permanently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stained</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> broadsheets
strove for originality in their front-page headlines. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> 's was "They
came in, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, to call for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>" over a picture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> arriving in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent 's</ENAMEX> was "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Judge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>' is sworn in for trial of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>," focussing on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s funereal garb. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> 's was weirder
still. "A moment of history to connect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>) with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">96</NUMEX>)," was what
it said.

            Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> was content with a normal headline: "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> goes on trial." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s main editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was not about the
impeachment process but about a new revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s D-Day commander
and military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field Marshal Bernard Montgomery</ENAMEX>, had referred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX>
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> as "a complete savage" whose only hope would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
colonial "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> plan" to carve out giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federations</ENAMEX> and unlock their vast wealth for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s benefit. "Had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monty</ENAMEX> won,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> would have imposed an indefensible, and unsustainable, version of
apartheid," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. But it concluded that "the sobering fact remains
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are poorer than they were" when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery</ENAMEX> unveiled his
plan.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> continental <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> papers indulged their
frequent penchant for interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> on current political
questions. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, interviewed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Schlesinger Jr.</ENAMEX>, who said that even if the impeachment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't succeed, "its effect in weakening the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">presidency</ENAMEX> will continue to be felt for generations." In Le <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">historian Fred Greenstein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton University</ENAMEX> said nobody apart from
"hezbollah <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>" wanted the impeachment trial to continue beyond
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mid-February</ENAMEX> or for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> to be called. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had "generated an
almost paranoiac fury among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wing extremists</ENAMEX> who hate and despise him, and
for whom he personifies the 'permissive' generation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX>."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the new
conservative national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post</ENAMEX> , commented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that, despite its show of "serene confidence a
trial will end in victory for Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and disaster for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> was in reality "on the edge of panic." This was because this
"impeachment trial requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to argue two tough--even
incredible--propositions: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> did not perjure himself and did
not obstruct justice; <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, that even if he did, perjury and obstruction are
not grounds for impeachment if they are committed in the context of sex." The
paper asked, "Can Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, most of whom don't
like him much, to go on repeating these unconvincing lines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week after week</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month after month</TIMEX>?"

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> called it "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s Trial by
Chaos" and said in a commentary by its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> that "beyond
the elaborate facade of formality, the opening of the trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX> was more reminiscent of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football scrum</ENAMEX> in a particularly
vicious game." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> said, "It is like a parody of an
end-of-the-millennium crisis. ... Can the world's greatest power really be
reduced to this--a serious legal argument in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> about such
issues as whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> did indeed touch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s breasts and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">genitals?</ENAMEX>"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> also carried an interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> conceded that intelligence gathered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> by his UNSCOM
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> might have been secretly passed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. "The idea that
somehow products of our work could be diverted to other purposes is
theoretically tenable," he said, "but I have no knowledge of that."

             

         
      
   
