
   
   
      
         
            

            Scroll
down for 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Flytrap</ENAMEX> coverage.

             

            

               2/15/99 The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquits President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55-45</NUMEX> on perjury
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-50</NUMEX> on obstruction of justice, well short of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> vote
required. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> vote unanimously for acquittal, joined by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on
perjury and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> on obstruction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Censure</ENAMEX> fails on a procedural motion, so
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> sign an unofficial censure statement instead.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says he's "profoundly sorry ... for what I said and did to trigger
these events." Reporters sniff for signs of celebration at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> but
come up empty. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> congratulate themselves for conscience, bipartisanship,
and fidelity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> to drop the idea of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indicting Clinton</ENAMEX>. Polls indicate that the public supports the verdict and
wants to move on.

            Chance
of removal from office: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zero</ENAMEX> .

            

               2/12/99 Amid expectations that neither impeachment article
will get majority support in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, both sides gear up for the aftermath.
Everyone agrees censure is doomed. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leak:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is furious at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for impeaching him and is determined to
drive them from office. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> leak: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is furious at the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX>" who leaked that story before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote and is determined to
drive them from office. Zero
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">2/10/99 Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> aims for a final
vote by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The suspense is over how many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will vote no
on the obstruction of justice article. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chafee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffords</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vt.</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>, say they'll vote no. Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> turn against censure, accusing its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">backers</ENAMEX> of "seeking
cover" for voting to acquit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Zero
            

            

               2/9/99 The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> begins final deliberations after voting to
close the deliberations to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>. The idealistic spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kicking</ENAMEX> out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to reach their verdict based on reason and
conscience. The cynical spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> voted to open the deliberations and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> voted to close them because both sides know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are on the
politically popular side of the debate. Facing the certainty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acquittal</ENAMEX>, a few more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> concede they could vote for censure.
Zero
            

            (For
earlier entries and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Clintometer Uncertainty Principle</ENAMEX>, click .)

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Complete Flytrap Coverage</ENAMEX>
               
            

            Direct
links to all recent 
                  Slate
                stories on the scandal.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on
Trial"

            Dispatches by

                  Slate
               's political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>.

            : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> acquits itself.

            : Great expectations.

            : A pecking or a choking?

            : The rush to judgment.

            : A tale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> trials.

            : Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hyenas</ENAMEX>.

            : The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> murder the genie.

            : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> behaves like itself.

            : Notions to dismiss.

            : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>.

            : A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s touch.

            : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union</ENAMEX> speech.

            : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Ruff</ENAMEX> takes the offensive.

            : The sideshow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX>.

            : Is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> time the charm?

            : Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will become more like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX>

            : The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> says, "I do."

            : The gloom and rancor of the debate.

            : The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX>.

            : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Graham</ENAMEX> turns indecision into high
art.

            : All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> arguments, numbered for your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>.

            : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> swoons for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Ruff</ENAMEX>.

            : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilentz</ENAMEX> goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> goes on
record.

            
"": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX> reveals how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> got what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
wanted.

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>"

            "": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Shapiro</ENAMEX> on the
greatness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            
"Readme"

            : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> says: Let's impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, too.

            : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX> finds striking
similarities between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            "Frame
Game"

            "": How the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' star witness
outsmarted them.

            "": The pure spin behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s latest
gambit.

            "": The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> whine about their
"needs."

            "": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> obscures his adultery by reinventing
"family values."

            "": Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Harkin</ENAMEX> killed the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX>" metaphor
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trial.

            "": Should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>?

            "": Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should force a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial.

            "": Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will spare his presidency.

            "": The debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> attack blazes new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">frontiers</ENAMEX> in cynicism.

            "": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> could blow up the impeachment process by crying "coup."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedfellow</ENAMEX>"

            "": The taxonomy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            "": <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dennis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastert</ENAMEX>.

            
"Chatterbox"

            Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scuttlebutt</ENAMEX>,
prepared for you by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Shapiro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Noah</ENAMEX>.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22</TIMEX>: The tortuous impeachment logic of a moderate
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>; "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>."

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> , unlisted; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">punts</NUMEX> the
vote; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> shocker.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 18</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s first shocker.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 17</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial nuttism.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog fantasies</ENAMEX>.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX> at the barricades.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 14</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lying</ENAMEX> is perjury; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> in
error!

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX> pool nettles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blame Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> gets on TV, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WaPo</ENAMEX> gets it done.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Do-it-yourself</ENAMEX> censure.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>: Considerate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>? Maybe. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liar</ENAMEX>? Definitely.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>: How might <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pay a fine?

            Also posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5</TIMEX> (scroll down): The hermeneutics of sexual touching.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s inspiration is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wonderland</ENAMEX> ?

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More Flytrap in verse</ENAMEX>.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> in verse.

            
"Explainer"

            Answers to your Flytrap
questions.

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 18</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s perjury defense. Why not bomb on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX>?

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 10</TIMEX>: Can a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame-duck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?

            Posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Flytrap ruin Hillary</ENAMEX>'s bid for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Person of the Year"</ENAMEX>?

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
Papers"

            

               
                  Slate
                rounds up reactions from around the globe.

            
               ""
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is unfit to serve.

            "Pundit
Central"

            The
opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> holds forth on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s predicament.

            a
Flytrap musical, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Malanowski</ENAMEX>.

            Click for

                  Slate
               's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
