
   
   
      
         
            

            
               Go <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>,
Impeachment!
            

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a book on the politics of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX> affair (especially the congressional hearings), I was pleased to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s "" on impeaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. Clearly the issues then
were of much greater constitutional import.

            Besides quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, you could have
also quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McCollum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>: "I don't
want you prosecuted. I don't. I don't think many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> do. And I
think there's going to be one lot of hell raised if you are." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCollum</ENAMEX> (now one
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, I believe) told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX> that he had "served your country
admirably" and that he was "a dedicated, patriotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>" for whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCollum</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was "grateful." These statements were made, of course, after
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX> (under a grant of immunity) proclaimed that he had previously misled and
lied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. And, as you point out in your piece, these were issues
involving life and death--not only TOWs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> but also aid to the guerrilla
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>, who were regularly implicated in killing peasant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villagers</ENAMEX> and others.

            Keep up the good
work.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Fried</ENAMEX> , author of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muffled Echoes</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX> and the Politics
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Opinion University of Maine</ENAMEX>
Orono, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>

            
               Who's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>?
Who Cares?
            

            As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, I was very pleased to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s review of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> of biographies in "." His conclusion that
the lives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> provide little (or no) illumination of their artistic
production is entirely accurate. To understand the work, look at the work and
understand its aesthetic context. Literary insights are to be found in other
writing--criticism, theory, philosophy, art history, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s own
writing. Visual creativity is driven by a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> (social,
political, cultural, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>, theoretical, aesthetic); an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">physiology</ENAMEX>, by virtue of idiosyncrasies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of vision, has more
effect than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s psychology on his or her work.

            Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s
biography may be interesting, and at times inspiring (as is the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX>), it more often than not distracts from the work and leads to the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inane</ENAMEX> and invalid interpretations. Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> for addressing this issue
and providing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> with an appropriate perspective!

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jo</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Scraba</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultra-Fat Cats</ENAMEX>
            

            Discussing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> prep
industry article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of ""
describes rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> as "overprivileged." "Privilege" itself already suggests to
me the sense of overness, if you will. Privilege is above and beyond the
normal. Either someone is privileged, or he is not. To use "overprivileged"
suggests that while a certain amount of privilege is acceptable, too much
privilege is wrong and should be taken away. This seems to me a wholly
irrational distinction to make.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel D. Smith</ENAMEX>
            

            New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>

            
               Tasty
Spatulas
            

            In "," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Goldberg</ENAMEX> alluded to, but didn't quite
hit on, the ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> toy for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the two month to 18 month</TIMEX> set, i.e., a spatula.
You can buy a darn nice spatula for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $2</NUMEX>--wooden with a rubbery blade--and
it's easy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to grip. It makes no noise when they whack things with it
(unlike a wooden spoon), and the blade gives them something to gnaw on, which
they find very satisfying, and there's no risk of splinters. It's also quiet
when they're in church (hey, I'm from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, OK?) unlike, say, squeaky
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toys</ENAMEX> or a set of car keys. I suppose the only hazard is the noxious chemicals
they use to make the blade rubbery, but if you post this in

                  Slate
                there will undoubtedly be an organic rubber
spatula with black-and-white geometric patterns (in soy ink) on a sustainably
harvested tropical hardwood (grown by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cooperative</ENAMEX>) handle available
soon for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29.95</NUMEX>.

            Good luck with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">squirts</ENAMEX>. The only other valuable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> raising hint I have is to dress the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
in orange shirts when they get mobile, because then they're easy to spot in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> (nobody wears orange voluntarily), although if you put this in

                  Slate
                and everyone does it, it won't work anymore.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cole Saint Paul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trial</ENAMEX>" an
Error
            

            About the trial coverage (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX>"): We need to be clear
about something. The trial of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will not really be a
trial, or at least not a trial that any of us recognize. First, let's set aside
any pondering about what the chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> will or will not do. He can't really
do much of anything. On any ruling by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJ</ENAMEX> as to admissibility,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relevancy</ENAMEX>, or objections to testimony that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> may make, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>) can overrule him by a simple majority of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> votes. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, so getting to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> is not a high hurdle. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, in any
ordinary trial, meetings, conversations, or even deals are not made between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. Here the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is the prosecution <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> have been in constant
contact, making deals and arrangements. That would be considered jury tampering
and would get any other case thrown out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. In any ordinary trial, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> sets the rules and the time frame. In this trial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> can change
the rules from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to day--doing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> what they would not allow on
another. They can decide mid-presentation (if they want to) to permit testimony
that was disallowed during the previous presentation. Or mid-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> if it
comes to that. Remember it takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 51</NUMEX> votes to make any decision, and there
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>.

            I do not have any
confidence that this trial will observe long-established rules of law. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> have made it plain, to anyone who is listening closely to their
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Senatespeak</ENAMEX>," that they will do it their way .

            -- Lois
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erwin Waldwick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
