
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               "My joy is that
we're still in business and we're alive."
            

            

               Who said this about what?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 163</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Initiation":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  
                     
                        
                           
                              As a condition of joining the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuania</ENAMEX> has agreed to ban a practice quite common in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. What?
                           
                        
                     
                  
               
            

            
"Judaism."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deb Stavin</ENAMEX> had an identical
answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supersizing</ENAMEX>. Anything."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> )

            
"Limiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terms and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noah Meyerson</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Bombing the crap out of Third World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> when you
need a quick pick-me-up at the polls."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Snell</ENAMEX> (similarly, Ananda
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gupta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cole</ENAMEX> )

            "Either
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> public gunplay or regular bathing. It depends on the civilization you'd
care to malign."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim O'Grady</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            By far the most popular response was to denigrate
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>. Giving this disdain a richer historical context so appropriate for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday season</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bell</ENAMEX> cites some early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglo-French</ENAMEX> contempt in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Review of Books</ENAMEX> discussion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Hampson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Perfidy of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albion</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Perceptions of England</ENAMEX> During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the French Revolution</ENAMEX> .

            " 'It should flatter us,' wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fougeret de Montbron</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1757</TIMEX>. 'Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> is called a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
Dog".' In sermons, novels, political broadsheets, moralising treatises and
popular engravings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> were portrayed as mangy, corrupt, effeminate,
ignorant, indolent, immoral and lecherous, as well as vain and
superficial."

            And aimed the other way: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertrand Bar√®re</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1794</TIMEX>,
wrote: 'National hatred must sound forth. Young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republicans</ENAMEX> should suck a
hatred of the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX> with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.' "

            Inevitably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> union
will dilute that continent's rich heritage of multinational scorn. You can say
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adieu</ENAMEX> to all those marvelous anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> jokes the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> tell so well. In
another year they'll be as wan and anachronistic as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ohioans</ENAMEX> mocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianans</ENAMEX>.
Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has no more actual places, all that's left is taking cheap
shots at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> from right across the river, on the dubious moral high
ground of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>. You'd think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> would learn from our loss. Of
course, for the truly nostalgic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist</ENAMEX>, there's always the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>.

            
               Powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deterrent</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            Executions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuanian parliament</ENAMEX> voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76-to-3</NUMEX>
to end capital punishment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amnesty International</ENAMEX>
lists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> that have abolished the death penalty either in law or
practice, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX> that retain it, among them <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koreas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, and of course the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX> executions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mathematically</ENAMEX> and morally tidy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>--occurring in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater-Going Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Can you match your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> of television,
movies, music, and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> whose work each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graces</ENAMEX>? Hint: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> tickets generally run around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Danza</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judd Hirsch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wendt</ENAMEX> (together!)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uma Thurman</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Dennehy</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Braxton</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Cathy Rigby

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX>'s
ass

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. J.M. Barrie</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. David Hare</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Arthur Miller</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Moli√</ENAMEX>®re

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Eugene O'Neill</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Linda Wolverton</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Yasmina Raza</ENAMEX>

            
               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-E Tony Danza</ENAMEX>, lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of television's
Taxi and Who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>? has been offered the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rocky the</ENAMEX>
bartender for a revival of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Iceman Cometh</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">G Taxi</ENAMEX> 
               and 
               Cheers --oh,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby!</ENAMEX>--in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> .

            3-D <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uma Thurman</ENAMEX> has joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Misanthrope</ENAMEX> ; previews begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-C <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennehy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of a Salesman</ENAMEX> previews
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 22</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-F Braxton</ENAMEX> stars in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Timeless Classic</ENAMEX>," as
it's billed, Beauty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beast</ENAMEX> .

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-A Rigby straps on the harness <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> times a week
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pan</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-B NK</ENAMEX>'s A can be briefly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glimpsed</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Blue Room</ENAMEX> , of course. Scary thought: What if she caught
a really bad stomach <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> and had to be replaced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Dennehy</ENAMEX>'s ass!
Yipes!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and will be
published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may
publish your name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
