
   
   
      
         
            Standards for Vampires

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plot Holes</ENAMEX>" is an occasional column about logical inconsistencies in
movies.
            

            What happens to a vampire
in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight</TIMEX>? Does he explode into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX>, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampires</ENAMEX> ? Turn into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pompeii</ENAMEX>-like ash sculpture, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interview With</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampire</ENAMEX> ? Feel a little short of energy, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bram Stoker</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> ? Or merely require the use of a good sunblock, as in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blade</ENAMEX> ?

            Behaviorally speaking,
vampires are all over the place. Not only do they differ morphologically from
movie to movie, but they behave with stunning inconsistency even within their
own films. Why, for instance, would a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vampire</ENAMEX> who can hover a good <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 feet</NUMEX>
above the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX> have to scramble frantically over a chain-link fence when
being chased by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Buffy the Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX>? Why can't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master Vampire</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampires</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> who has repeatedly demonstrated
his ability to disembowel and decapitate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> with a single swipe of his
hand, manage to do anything more deadly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Woods</ENAMEX> during their final
epochal confrontation than just cuff him around?

            The vampire is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">undead</ENAMEX>. Like any other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>, it should manifest a certain behavioral logic that moviegoers can rely
upon. What if I wanted to make a movie about, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX>? And what if I found
it more "interesting" creatively if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX> in my movie had fish scales
instead of fur? Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> placidly accept such a frivolous reordering of
nature? I think not! Yet when it comes to vampires, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> feel free to
reinvent the rules with every picture.

            This has become such a
problem in our society that I hereby propose a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Uniform Code</ENAMEX> of Vampire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards and Practices</ENAMEX> . In my opinion, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> major areas that are
in need of immediate clarification.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Mortality and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mortification</ENAMEX>.
Vampires, declares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Kristofferson</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blade</ENAMEX> , are "hard to kill. They
tend to regenerate." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> enough, but it's past time for a meeting of the minds
on this crucial issue. How, exactly, do you kill a vampire? It was easy enough
back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">F.W. Murnau</ENAMEX>'s silent classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nosferatu</ENAMEX> . If a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX> "pure in heart" manages to keep the vampire by her side <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> until
"after the cock has crowed," he is guaranteed to suffer what looks like a
massive coronary and disappear in a puff of smoke. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1931</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> ,
however, which like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nosferatu</ENAMEX> is based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bram Stoker</ENAMEX>'s novel, Bela
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lugosi</ENAMEX> has to be impaled through the heart in his coffin, whereupon he emits a
strange little disappointed groan that remains a benchmark of decorum when
compared with the hissing and writhing deaths of modern screen vampires.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interview With the Vampire</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> informs us
that the stake-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-heart method is "nonsense." Later he suffers a slit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throat</ENAMEX>, is eaten by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">alligator</ENAMEX>, and then what is left of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is consumed
in a fire. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few centuries later</TIMEX> he bounces right back. In
Buffy , vampires are much easier to dispatch: A simple wooden stake will
do it after all--or, in an emergency, a broken guitar neck. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Coppola</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bram Stoker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> dies when he is
impaled by a bowie knife wielded by an improbable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>-based cowboy. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX>, playing the film's mad vampire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX>, seems to put more store
in chopping off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> than impaling hearts. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s
Vampires , a vampire can't get real dead unless he is dragged out into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sunlight</ENAMEX>, though he can be considerably slowed down if his heart is pierced by
a crossbow bolt or a giant crucifix. The vampires in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blade</ENAMEX> , however, can
walk around in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> if they have prudent ultraviolet protection, but
disintegrate on the spot when they are hit in either the head or the heart with
a hollow-pointed bullet filled with garlic. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blade</ENAMEX> , by the way, is one
of the only contemporary vampire movies that bothers to regard garlic as a
serious deterrent. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blade</ENAMEX> , garlic is as dangerous a substance to a
vampire as bad seviche is to a human: It induces instant anaphylactic
shock.)

            
               Proposed
Standard: crucifixes and garlic to be regarded as nonlethal irritants.
Vampire death to be assured by penetration of heart muscle by any foreign
object or by prolonged exposure to sunlight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decapitation</ENAMEX> alone not sufficient
to secure desired death effect. A deceased vampire should not explode,
disintegrate, burst, morph, or molder but should serenely resume countenance
pertaining at the time of its transmogrification. (See No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, below.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transmogrification</ENAMEX>. We face no more
challenging issue than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of "turning," i.e., becoming a vampire. In
less sophisticated movies, everybody who is bitten by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vampire</ENAMEX> turns into one,
usually after an unspecified incubation period. The artsier the film, the more
elaborate the distinction between the merely dead and the truly undead. To the
degree I could follow the tortuous logic of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interview With the Vampire</ENAMEX> ,
it seemed to be that the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> dies a straightforward bloodsucking
death. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every millennium</TIMEX> or so a vampire meets that special someone. In
order to "turn" this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, it is necessary for the vampire to drain the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> and top it off at the crucial moment with a quart or so of his
own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, whereupon the thirsty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> becomes a "new-born vampire weeping
at the beauty of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bram Stoker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> , by contrast, the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruit</ENAMEX> must also drink the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vampire</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, but the transformation is far
pokier, requiring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, and if the vampire happens to get stuck with
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bowie knife</ENAMEX> before the process is completed, it immediately goes into
reverse. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blade</ENAMEX> , like several other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>-conscious vampire movies, treats
vampirism as an infectious blood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. "Look at the polys," a beautiful
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hematologist</ENAMEX> says to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> as she's performing an autopsy on a
vampire cadaver, "they're binucleated!"

            
               Proposed
Standard: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampirization</ENAMEX> to be contingent upon total extraction of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and its subsequent replacement by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> vampire. If
more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> occur between initial suckage and revivification, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> no
longer qualifies for living death designation and will be considered
conventionally deceased.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motility</ENAMEX>. Not to mince words: Can
vampires fly? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of the movies, before special effects, they had
trouble getting off the ground. The bald, pointy-eared vampire in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nosferatu</ENAMEX> is barely ambulatory, in fact. He shuffles arthritically
around his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>, and when he rises from his coffin he's as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stiff</ENAMEX> as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ironing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lugosi</ENAMEX> takes to the air it's in the form of a giant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fruit</ENAMEX> bat. (He also turns into a hyena and an armadillo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> that are
similarly not native to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transylvania</ENAMEX>.)

            In recent vampire movies the miracle of flight is
well established. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruise</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gathers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> into one of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homoerotic</ENAMEX> embraces
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interview With the Vampire</ENAMEX> and soars with him high into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Oldman</ENAMEX> turns himself into some sort of gigantic hominid-bat creature
and flaps about in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampire</ENAMEX> Master in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampires</ENAMEX> can fly down the road fast enough to catch a speeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and can
stick to the ceiling of a motel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. But at crucial moments in these movies
the vampire always seems to forget he has these powers and ends up wrestling
around on the floor of a dusty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX> or abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> with the
earth-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.

            
               Proposed
Standard: vertical flight only, to a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 feet</NUMEX> above the
ground. Sustained flight permissible if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vampire</ENAMEX> takes the form of a bat, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX>,
or other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">authentic nocturnal species</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampire</ENAMEX> is specifically prohibited from
turning into a flying homonculus. Once flight capabilities are established and
demonstrated in a motion picture, they must be used consistently and logically
throughout, without regard to the convenience of the filmmakers.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dentition</ENAMEX>. Are fangs fixed or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retractable</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lugosi</ENAMEX> managed to evade this critical issue--one never sees his
teeth at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nosferatu</ENAMEX> 's vampire is so eccentrically snaggletoothed
that his fangs seem a danger only to himself. In the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX>
novel, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> notices Count <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX>'s "peculiarly sharp white teeth" that
"protruded over the lips" almost at once. In his baroque homage to the book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX> apparently could not muster the will to portray the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> with such
a pronounced overbite, and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dracula</ENAMEX>'s fangs descend only periodically, amid
so much gaping mouth movement that the count looks like he's coughing up a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hairball</ENAMEX>. The vampires in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffy</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX> , in contrast, exist
in a constant state of dental arousal. They're the exception, however. Almost
every other vampire movie accepts the patently unnatural convention that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vampire</ENAMEX>'s fangs are capable of receding into his gums. But since vampires are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unnatural</ENAMEX> to begin with, maybe that's OK.

            
               Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> : retractable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fangs</ENAMEX> as default characteristic. Strongly recommend, when appropriate,
on-screen discussion of physical requirements for said phenomenon--as when a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in Blade observes an "odd muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">canines</ENAMEX>."

            This plea for a code of standards should not
be considered anti-vampire. For the sake of vampires themselves we need a few
simple regulations. With teeth, of course.

         
      
   
