
   
   
      
         
            We Bombed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>

            The coincidence of the
airstrikes on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and the suspension of the impeachment proceedings
preoccupied most of the world's press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, bringing further damage to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s international standing. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were predictably critical of
the bombing raids. In one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Commission</ENAMEX> chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX>, rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, was seen as the villain of the piece. In
Bahrain, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akhbar al-Khaleej</ENAMEX> wrote, for example: "A word from
the spy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX> could have saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> aggression. And
a word from him is sufficient justification for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> to be launched."

            The pan-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> published an article by its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdelbari Atwan</ENAMEX>, saying that "once again <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is using the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scapegoats</ENAMEX> to extricate himself from his domestic crisis. ... What have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> done to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to deserve such disdain
and to be singled out for destruction, death, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">extermination?</ENAMEX>"

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-Dustour</ENAMEX> said the attacks would "only lead to more
devastation and pain to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have suffered a lot as a result of unjust
sanctions." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Rai</ENAMEX> said that "the real aim of this strike is to get rid
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> and, in such a case, the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> is international
legitimacy and law." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan Times</ENAMEX> opined that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s "well-phrased and
logical" justifications of the attack had unfortunately been undermined by the
coincidences of the postponement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment vote and of "the
remarkable window of opportunity that opened up right before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX> [the
Muslim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fasting month</TIMEX>]."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Ben-Ishai</ENAMEX>, the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> , said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had predicted a month
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> air offensive would be launched <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-December</TIMEX>,
during the "narrow window" between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and the
start of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>. "This consideration took precedence, apparently,
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s unwillingness to be portrayed as trying to divert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
public opinion from the impeachment process," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Ishai</ENAMEX> wrote.

            He added that the reason
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> was so calm in advance of the attack was that it had concluded there
were no launchers or ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> to threaten it in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and
that even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> decided to launch the few "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and improved
Scuds he still had, he would need more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> to transfer them from
their hiding places to an area within range of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> intelligence could detect the intention and prevent the
launchings, he said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also devoted much space to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
political crisis and the likelihood of early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knesset</ENAMEX> elections. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margalit</ENAMEX> wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> had made a major
political miscalculation at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye</ENAMEX>, having made the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> state an
established fact in the minds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>--"certainly not the
achievement he planned to be remembered for."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in the attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> was strongly supportive
of them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said they were "a grim necessity" forced on the allies
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>; while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">See It Through</ENAMEX>," ran an
editorial urging them to extend the offensive into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX>. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]o set such a tight limit on bombing will ensure that it is little
more than a pinprick," it said. "[I]t will not seriously dent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s hold
over his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. For that, a prolonged air campaign is the bare minimum."

            The liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> , however, said that the bombing would only be
justified if it led to the self-determination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening Standard</ENAMEX> said that even those who wholeheartedly
supported the offensive were "deeply dismayed by the fact that it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> who has made the decision, who has precipitated this grave step.
...This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s personal position is far too deeply compromised for the
world easily to accept at face value either his judgements or his reasons."

            On the continent of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, there was harsh
condemnation of both the raids and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s general conduct. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> called the pretext for the offensive "dramatically
thin" and linked it to the postponement of the impeachment process. The
conservative Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figaro</ENAMEX> supported <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s policy of detachment not as appeasement but
rather as good sense. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sera</ENAMEX> said it didn't believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to gain time
on impeachment--it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> that wanted to retaliate before
returning to the issue of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. It added: "To us impotent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectators</ENAMEX>,
there is left the sad privilege of realizing how weak in reality our principal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ally</ENAMEX> is, and how deeply shaken it is in its politico-institutional
mechanisms."

         
      
   
