
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Killing Them Softly</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter jets zipped</ENAMEX> into the "no-fly" zone over southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, encountered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> warplanes, and sped away without firing. Rather than pursue the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>, the allied <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> rained bombs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> on
unrelated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> radar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>, and communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. This was the
latest chapter in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven week</TIMEX> assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s air defenses that has earned
scant media coverage and no outcries in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> or at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>,
thanks to an ingenious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> public relations strategy of spontaneity,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX>, and silence.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last December</TIMEX>, when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX>, television networks
covered the onslaught live. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Governments</ENAMEX> around the world cringed, many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protested</ENAMEX>, and the bombing had to be halted. Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> has
repeatedly defied the no-fly zones, using his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>, radar, and anti-aircraft
weapons to provoke allied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>. The conventional wisdom, distilled last week
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> is shrewdly provoking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and that they're taking the bait, engaging in a "war of attrition" that
will "keep world attention focused" on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
"looking like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>."

            But over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past month</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has
learned how to wage war under the guise of ad hoc retaliation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> to attack air defense sites unrelated to those that
have threatened their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Zinni</ENAMEX>, who commands <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, "We have the authority to react and attack any part of the
air defense system any time there's a threat. And it's not particularly geared
to the cause of the threat." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> patrolling the
no-fly zones deliberately pass over predetermined targets, obviously in the
hope that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> will provoke them. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, for example, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> noticed that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> had moved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti</ENAMEX>-ship <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> launchers toward the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>. Only after a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> battery fired on allied patrol <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX> did the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> drop a dozen bombs on the anti-ship <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">launchers</ENAMEX>,
destroying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them.

            In short, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beating Saddam</ENAMEX> at his own game of provocation. "He's provided an opportunity
for us to pick apart his military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> explained to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> alone, allied aircraft patrolling the
no-fly zones dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 60</NUMEX> bombs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">scoring</ENAMEX> more hits than they achieved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four day</TIMEX> campaign. On
background, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> admits that its aim is to destroy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">defenses</ENAMEX>, demoralize his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>, and provoke a coup. He is
losing the war of attrition.

            Meanwhile, the world isn't paying attention. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s
bombing made Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A5</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A33</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> (as a wire story). Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are silent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N. Security Council</ENAMEX> is ignoring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s protests.
That's largely because, in contrast to the overhyped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> bombardment, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are playing down the recent assaults, justifying them in terms of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX> and providing scant information on the damage. "We are responding
in a comprehensive way when [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>] threatens our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.J. Crowley</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . Meanwhile, officials
anonymously concede that the piecemeal retaliatory strategy is designed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">mollify Arab</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. One senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
"It's a way of pursuing an objective in a way that everyone's comfortable with.
You get things done without rocking any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>. If we started a broad bombing
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would say, 'What provoked this?' "

            None of this implies
that the bombing raids are unjustified. There is broad international agreement
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> is a menace and scofflaw. Furthermore, he can always moot the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>' self-defense argument by ceasing his provocations. But evidently he's
too dumb and stubborn to restrain himself. Meanwhile, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> that
couldn't resist staging a pep rally for its impeached <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has remained
scrupulously gloat-free about its military success in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Sometimes the best
spin is no spin at all.

         
      
   
