
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 16</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial speculates on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s post-devaluation
future. Will <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> recover, or will it "descend into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>-style chaos" and
spark a global financial meltdown? The optimistic view: The real was overvalued
anyway, so devaluation could lower the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX> interest rate. Pessimists
counter: The incompetence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' lack of
confidence, and the "souring" of international sentiments toward emerging
markets could bring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> crashing down, dragging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary</ENAMEX>
Fund's name through the mud along with it. ... The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lexington"</ENAMEX> column
celebrates the retirement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>, if only because it provides relief
from the recent battle between the game's "short billionaires and tall
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story traces
the free fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kofi Annan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX>, says the article, is a
career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX> who "succeeds at little things and fails at big things."
Among his most notable botches: His involvement as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> (before his tenure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annan</ENAMEX>'s latest
debacle--he has cuddled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> and squared off against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. ... An article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> "perpetual scorn" as the best
punishment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and another scandal article bangs an old but never dead
theme: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s unquenchable appetite for sex talk ... An article
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disputes Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Paragon</ENAMEX> status. Liddy may be a good,
strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, but she's had her share of professional blunders--and she's
hardly the doting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife conservatives</ENAMEX> want.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s legacy argues that his greatest achievement is making the presidency
smaller while restoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. His welfare reform and balanced
budget not only shrank <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> but also encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to believe that
it could work. He also replaced the heroic presidency with the competent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,
asking to be judged by what he accomplished, not by how he behaved. Even so,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal guarantees that he will be a historical joke.
(
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> wrote the piece.) ... "Whatever
happened to the Class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>?" catches up with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> elected to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican Revolution</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 50</NUMEX> remain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, and most
of those still there are chastened. They have assimilated to the institution
and moderated their conservatism. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel Allende</ENAMEX>
writes that even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusto Pinochet</ENAMEX> is never tried in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, justice has
finally been done to the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> detention has caused
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX>'s moral ruin. Henceforth, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had the gall to pose as his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX> will take his place alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caligula</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idi Amin</ENAMEX>." Allende
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador Allende</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> deposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pinochet</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               
               and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18</TIMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> cover story focuses on alarmists, especially millennialist
Christians stockpiling for the looming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX> disaster. The story visits the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">survivalism</ENAMEX>, who advises suburbanites how to ride out
the chaos in comfort. The dehydrated food industry is booming, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
notes. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s own take is more reassuring: There will be minor
glitches but not wholesale societal collapse.) ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> puts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Imus</ENAMEX> on the cover for a package about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stars of the New News</ENAMEX>." The
lead essay bemoans the replacement of objective,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authoritative</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Cronkite</ENAMEX>-style news by opinionated, entertaining talk.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imus</ENAMEX> is hailed as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> "ringmaster" of the new news: The accompanying
profile --like every profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imus</ENAMEX>--applauds his
sense of the absurd and his ability to bully the famous into speaking
truthfully but worries about his crudeness and his temper. Among the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titans</ENAMEX> of 'tude " are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tavis Smiley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Lamb</ENAMEX>, and 
                  Slate
               's own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Shuger</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> describes "honor killings" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>,
which comprise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s homicides. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>
murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have been raped or have had sexual affairs because their honor
has been sullied. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are punished lightly, if at all.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
reveals some of the drawbacks of the economic boom. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.D.</ENAMEX>, unemployment
is so low (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1 percent</NUMEX>) that fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> pay signing bonuses
to anyone who works <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 days</TIMEX>. And in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, it's impossible to get a
table at fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            Branching out from its
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Colleges</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> describes what makes an outstanding high school and identifies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> should look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> with demanding standards, a rigorous
core curriculum, qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, high attendance rates, small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>, and
lots of parental involvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> examines mostly public and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, because independent private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> refused to participate.
... A short piece says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, are being
killed for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie Bauer</ENAMEX> down parkas.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A story demolishes the
idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Pollard</ENAMEX> didn't harm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence operations while
spying for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollard</ENAMEX> sold critical details about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> signal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> and battle plans that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> probably traded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>.
He also gave away <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX> planning documents that allowed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> to conduct military operations without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detection</ENAMEX>. And contrary to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>' claim, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollard</ENAMEX> spied principally for money, not to help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.
Releasing him from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, even to further <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace, would be a huge
mistake. ... An article describes the effort by an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Icelandic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>
to document his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s gene pool. With its isolated and homogeneous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX> is a perfect laboratory for investigating genetic disease.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> believes that his database, which will be marketed to drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, will be an essential tool for locating and curing genetic disease. A
few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Icelanders</ENAMEX> are worried about losing their privacy, but most want to advance
medicine. ... A "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>" item argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should be
punished by prohibiting him from giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address.
He would enjoy it too much and would take "too much credit for things he had
too little to do with."

            
               
                  The
Nation
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            A piece reviews the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Free Trade Agreement</ENAMEX> on its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> anniversary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> has cost
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of jobs, worsened <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> environmental
problems, and overloaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> with unsafe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>. ...
The cover story
warns that the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>-controlled health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
threatens reproductive choice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> control <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of
nonfederal hospital beds and are the largest nonprofit health care providers.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are being forced into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic HMOs</ENAMEX> that don't perform
abortions or provide contraception.

         
      
   
