
   
   
      
         
            Miracle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>

            The decision of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Carnahan</ENAMEX> to commute the death sentence on triple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darrell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mease</ENAMEX> in response to an appeal by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope John Paul II</ENAMEX> was splashed across the
front pages of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pope Stops the Hangman</ENAMEX>" was
the main headline in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>; and front-page cartoons included one
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> showing the pope sticking his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX> into
the back of a black-hooded executioner with his hands up, and another in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX>
with him unplugging an electric chair while telling the still strapped-in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">murderer</ENAMEX>, "I have commuted the death penalty to life imprisonment, so you will
have all the time you need to repent."

            In a front-page comment
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corriere</ENAMEX> , veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arrigo Levi</ENAMEX> marveled at the power of
something as weak as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s voice to affect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s decision, and he
added that now "perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> still favoring the death
penalty will be induced to reflect on the words and the reasoning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>."
However, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> also carried an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geraldine Ferraro</ENAMEX>,
who said that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Catholics</ENAMEX> believe in the death penalty. She also
criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> for his attitude to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. In a front-page comment by its
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vittorio Zucconi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazarus</ENAMEX> was
alive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s act of clemency was "the flower that
pushes up through the snow, the sign of a new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> after the long <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> of
the gallows."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press was entirely dominated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> by the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever joint appearance before the cameras of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> standing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilla Parker Bowles</ENAMEX>. It lasted for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 seconds</TIMEX>
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> together at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> after
attending a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilla</ENAMEX>'s younger sister
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annabel</ENAMEX>. Their decision to "come out" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> was broadly welcomed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , saying
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camilla</ENAMEX> has been in the shadows for too long" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> saying that the
timing of the photographs was "undoubtedly connected" with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June wedding</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX> and his companion
would not wish to upstage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> and groom, and it is probable that they
will make a number of appearances together, so that by the time of the wedding
they will appear perfectly natural as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said. But, as
several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> observed, they don't look very natural in public yet.

            A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> papers
carried headlines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> saying that a major objective of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> had been to rally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> support for
moves to oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>; but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq al-Awsat</ENAMEX> quoted
unidentified high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as saying that even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s closest
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> "does not believe in or support any foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> undertaking to
change the ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>." It quoted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as saying, "Such
change should come about from within and can only be undertaken by the people
themselves. Such action would not be helpful or worthwhile or have effective
tangible results if it were organized from abroad."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> expressed concern over the
consequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s new health crisis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Ben-Ishai</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yediot Aharanot</ENAMEX> 's military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>, said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> factors are threatening
stability in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>: the trauma in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, the war of
attrition the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is waging against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>, and the lack of
political stability in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. "Any one of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> focal points of tension
could spill over into other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the region," he wrote.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>'s sudden return
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> left behind a "fluid and dangerous situation" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yosef Lapid</ENAMEX> commented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maariv</ENAMEX> . "The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the throne,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX>, is a young, inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who is now supposed to
run the affairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s help," he said. "Now he leaves him
in a state of uncertainty. It seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>, who is known to be a careful
and balanced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, was this time impetuous and hasty." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lapid</ENAMEX> wondered if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> had misled the king when they told him he had
recovered. "The mistake could not only cost the king dearly, but his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>
too," he added.

            But in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mustafa Abu-Libdeh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the business
daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Aswaq</ENAMEX> , said that the prevailing calm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was
testament to the stability of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> had done so much to build.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> had emerged from a truly extraordinary week confident of itself and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, he wrote. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> had rebuked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crown Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX> on a number of counts in the letter excluding him from the succession,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX> had accepted that criticism graciously and loyally. "It is that kind of
openness and adherence to legality that has given the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hashemites</ENAMEX> their leading
role in history," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu-Libdeh</ENAMEX> wrote. "They have nothing to hide because they
have no agenda other than service of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX>."

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in crisis, plagued by terrorist kidnappings, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>'s semi-official
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Ahram</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is at a crossroads and must choose between the rule
of law and the lawlessness of its tribal past. "Certain outside powers" that do
not want to see a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> are using <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yemeni</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist groups</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to sabotage its modernization drive, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

             

         
      
   
