
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Browser Bork Replies</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> seeks to
find a contradiction between the book I wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Antitrust</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paradox</ENAMEX> , and my representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that support the
have become a "disingenuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX>" and have endangered, if not lost, my
scholarly reputation. Though he reveals his own conflict of interest, which
hardly requires confession, since everyone knows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> owns

                  Slate
               , his attack follows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> line. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
minions are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> of the ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hominem</ENAMEX>.

            Let us begin with my
motivation, which Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX> questions. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX> first approached me, I
said I thought I was on the other side. All I knew then came from newspaper
accounts that described the case as an attack on tie-ins. I continue to think
tie-in law mistaken, but this was not a case of extending a monopoly to a
competitive market. Rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, as its own internal documents show, was
trying to stamp out a product, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> browser, that might compete with
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> operating system. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> sent not only the reference to my book,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Antitrust</ENAMEX> Paradox , but an explanation of why predation would work in
this market. At about that time, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> called and, in
conversation and by letter, tried to convince me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s practices
created efficiency. He offered me a retainer. I have no idea how large that
might have been because I did not ask or try to negotiate with him. I said that
if he convinced me, I would simply stay out of the case. He did not persuade
me, and I went with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>, charging the same <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> rate I charge all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, no more, no less. There was no reason why I should make that choice
except that I thought, and continue to think, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> is right. The government
seems to be proving that in the courtroom.

            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s economic analysis fares no better than his
personal attack. The key question is whether predation, including price
predation, can be an effective monopolizing technique. As I recall Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s review of my book, it was one of the less comprehending assessments.
The ensuing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX> have not improved his comprehension, and it is too much to
expect that he will reread the work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. My belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> has the better
of the argument with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> rests on much more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lorain</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> case. To refresh Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s memory, the relevant passage begins
at Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">148</NUMEX>, where I wrote that "The technique of predation, rather than the
question of reserves, is likely to be decisive in the success of the tactic,
and the law should focus upon this issue."

            Price cutting will
usually not be a successful technique, I wrote, because it requires the
predator to expand his rate of output in order to drive prices down. In the
case I posited, an expansion of output imposes increasing costs upon the
predator because his marginal costs will rise and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s will not. That
will be true in almost all industries. It follows from the argument that price
cutting can be a successful predatory tactic if marginal costs are not rising.
I did not make the point explicit because it seemed obvious and a rare
case.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> have made it clear that, after
development costs, the production and distribution of software displays a flat
marginal cost. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX> is at no disadvantage. If his financial reserves
are larger than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s (in proportion to their market shares), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predator</ENAMEX> can destroy the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s business. This is especially true where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predator</ENAMEX> is spending only a small fraction of its monopoly profits while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> has no such profits. Nor will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> put up the capital to resist the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predator</ENAMEX>, for they will know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> is at a disadvantage in the fight.

            That, in essence, is the
case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s attempted destruction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> browser in order
to defend its monopoly in operating systems. I trust the matter is now clear to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
               , and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX>, but it is too much to hope
that any of them will concede.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>
responds:
               
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> for the above
response. Next, a few points in reply:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. I consulted no one at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, outside of

                  Slate
               , in writing my piece. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s "minions" didn't even
know I was writing it until it appeared. I did read a document or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s publicly available antitrust suit propaganda
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, as well as a similar page sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the striking
things about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial, so far, is the extent to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boies</ENAMEX>, have built their case around personal
vilification of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>. This may be justified or not--we like him well
enough around here!--but it does seem unreasonable for a supporter of the DOJ
to suggest that ad hominen attacks are a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> specialty.

            3.In his response, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> fleshes out his earlier
statements about how he came to sign up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>. Until Netscape
approached him, he thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> was right and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX> was wrong--based on
his general view that "predation" (misuse of market power) is largely a myth.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> didn't merely point out a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> page discussion in his book of a single
case that pointed the other way. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> also sent him "an explanation of why
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">predation</ENAMEX> would work in this particular market." If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> supplied Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>
with the argument why his own theories supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s position, what
did Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> supply ?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> says that when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> also tried to
hire him, he gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> a hearing, with the understanding that
"if he convinced me, I would simply stay out of the case." Bizarrely, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>
seems to think this arrangement allowed him to choose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> with complete
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neutrality</ENAMEX>. Let's see: If he chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX>, he got "the same <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> rate I
charge all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, no more, no less." If he chose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, he got ...
nothing. Sure, that sounds perfectly neutral.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. I'm sorry Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>
recalls my review of his book as "one of the less comprehending assessments."
It was, as I said, a favorable review. Maybe that's why.

            6.Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> says his argument against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is based on
"much more" than his book's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> page discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorain Journal</ENAMEX>
case. I guess it depends on what you mean by the word "much." All he cites in
this reply is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> additional passage from the book, which, he concedes, "does
not make the point explicit." Indeed it does not. The discussion of predation
in the pages following Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">148</NUMEX> does not contain a single word suggesting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> believes predatory pricing can ever be a valid antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. In fact,
the only "technique of predation" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>, in his book, expresses any concern
about is "misuse of government process." He writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Misuse</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> is a particularly effective means of delaying or stifling
competition."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "The point" is his current argument that his
earlier argument--that predation by price cutting doesn't work--only applies
where marginal costs are rising. He says his current argument is implied,
though not "explicit," in the book (and therefore, by further implication, he's
not a hypocrite). It's true the book assumes rising marginal costs, but it does
not "follow," as he claims, that predation by cost cutting depends on rising
marginal costs. (If you assume you're holding an apple and conclude from that
you're holding a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>, it doesn't "follow" that if you're holding an orange
you're not holding a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>.) Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>'s current argument may be right or
wrong, but it's certainly not derived from his book.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. The assumption of
rising marginal costs (in any but the shortest of short terms) is widely
regarded as the weak link in the logic of neoclassical economics. Software may
be an extreme example of marginal costs that plunge immediately to near zero
and stay there, but learning curves and economies of scale are more
characteristic of most modern industries than rising marginal costs. Yet in
order to defend his current position, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> now
declares--unnecessarily!--that his whole theory of antitrust rests on this weak
point. His life's great intellectual achievement, he says in effect, doesn't
apply in most real-life situations.

            9.On the merits of his current argument, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> is right
to call me uncomprehending. His original argument that predatory price cutting
can't work (and therefore needn't be illegal) was that it will always cost the
predator more than the intended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX> is selling more
units during the price war in which both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are losing money. I do not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehend</ENAMEX> why that depends on rising marginal costs. It's true that rising
marginal costs increase the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX>'s losses--but even with flat marginal
costs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predator</ENAMEX>'s losses get bigger and bigger until the victim surrenders.
Zero marginal costs, if anything, ought to make it even harder to drive a
competitor from the field with devastating losses. Am I missing something?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. And--to finish the argument--if Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>'s
original argument about relative losses doesn't depend on rising marginal
costs, neither does its corollary that capital markets should be willing to
bankroll a price war that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> could win with an adequate war chest.
(This is actually the very point, in context, of the sentence Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> quotes
from Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">148</NUMEX> of his book.) I therefore do not comprehend why Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> now
thinks it matters that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has more money than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> when he was so
specifically contemptuous of that argument <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. This is not to say that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX>'s old theory
was right or that his new one is necessarily wrong--only that the two theories
are irreconcilable. And if what Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> is arguing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> cannot be honestly
derived from his seminal book <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, this makes the question of what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> is paying him for even more piquant.

         
      
   
