
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">171</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;It Grates Outdoors&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               Fill in the
blank.
            

            

               It first happened outside in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, and now, frets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reba White Williams</ENAMEX>,
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Art Commission</ENAMEX>, "it seems as though wherever
there is a vacant spot, anybody can _______________ without any consideration
of how it looks."
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 170</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aust/Test</ENAMEX>":
            

            
               I give the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headline</ENAMEX>, you give the lead.
            

            

               From the front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Australia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertiser</ENAMEX> : "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1664</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDIOTS</ENAMEX>."
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">testy Alex Trebek</ENAMEX> lashes out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> for not knowing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joydip Kundu</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HYANNIS PORT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MASS.</ENAMEX>--At a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX> gathering, all family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> with
political aspirations ..."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David McShane</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Natural selection takes hold among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire yachters</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ananda Gupta</ENAMEX>
(similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Atkinson</ENAMEX> )

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
recent discovery in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Archives</ENAMEX> has revealed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were
executed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles II</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1664</TIMEX> for inappropriate dress at a royal levee.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> appeared at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> wearing tunics with 'Bring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Oliver Cromwell</ENAMEX>'
embroidered on the front. No <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> were harmed in the incident."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>
Cornog
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s poll results are in. Slightly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,600</NUMEX> of you answered 'yes' to
the question 'I still giggle when I hear the phrase "down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">under</NUMEX>." ' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX>
Hotchkiss
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            The silly accents, the
comical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, the inadequate TV shows--it must be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are
denigrated for a lack of ability to find other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> on a map and a lack of
interest in trying. But here's what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> know about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, based on a count of all submitted answers:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia Reference Tote Board</ENAMEX>
               

               Kangaroos--0

               Koalas--0

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pandas</ENAMEX> (misinformed players only)--0

               Dingoes, eating of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> by--5

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bee Gees</ENAMEX>, eating of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> by--0

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Hogan</ENAMEX>--4

               Attacks by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>--0

               Attacks by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>--0

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Beer--1</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Convict forebears--2</ENAMEX>

               Marginality re larger
world--0

            

            OK, as it turns out, we
don't know all that much. But in a hypothetical reverse version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Quiz run in an imaginary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, most responses refer to a big,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beer-swilling Elvis</ENAMEX> cruising in a big, gas-guzzling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>; insensitively fondling
a big, busty blonde on the seat beside him; and firing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> out the window,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, or what I like to call "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Aussie</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Police</ENAMEX>
have branded as 'impatient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,664</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> caught on speed cameras at
well above the limit. Many of them believed they could drive safely at high
speeds because they were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'an</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>' behind the wheel. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,664</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> paid
around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> in fines, a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$305</NUMEX> each.

            
               Know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showbiz</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            Below, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> recent headlines from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Variety , each followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possible leads. Which is genuine?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELDER POISED FOR</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATIONAL EXPOSURE</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "A chance to gape at a naked old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motorcycle</ENAMEX> lured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waking Ned Devine</ENAMEX> ."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look for Larry Elder</ENAMEX>, the self-described 'sage
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Central</ENAMEX> ,' to break into the national talk radio landscape
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THAILAND SAND TRAP</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "A nude granddad on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> was arrested on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, in an act <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> say was inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'an</ENAMEX> adorable
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irish</ENAMEX> movie about puckish, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>-swilling stereotypes.' "

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> threatened to sue
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">20 th Century Fox</ENAMEX>, claiming <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Beach</ENAMEX> , starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX>
DiCaprio, was responsible for the destruction of a beach in a protected
national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> area."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECHOSTAR</ENAMEX>, PSEUDO
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PACT</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "A foxy grampa was released from custody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>,
after repeated pledges to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to stay off <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX>. He left
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Square</ENAMEX> pants-less on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>, chattering away in a grotesque
caricature of an endearing brogue."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EchoStar Communications</ENAMEX>, one of the leading
direct broadcast satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, has signed a deal with Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">programmer Pseudo Programs</ENAMEX> to add <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pseudo's</ENAMEX> programming to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EchoStar</ENAMEX>'s
interactive channel lineup."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PROVIDENCE PICKS UP</ENAMEX>
PEACOCK

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> "A bare-assed codger was killed near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangkok</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> collided with a low-flying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">game bird</ENAMEX> that police
say was 'hurled in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> by a vengeful god.' "

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> has
intervened on behalf of slumping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, premiering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with a divine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13.1</NUMEX>
rating, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> share, best for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peacock</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that 8-9 p.m.</TIMEX> slot with non-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>
programming since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 6, 1992</TIMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX> )."

            

               Answers
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-B,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-B, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-B, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-B.
            

            
               Race
Results
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime target</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
