
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">185</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;Tourist</ENAMEX> <EM>Tsuris</EM><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Parks Authority</ENAMEX> was uneasy about a proposed new
attraction but, after consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church authorities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of planning Zeev
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Margalit</ENAMEX> concluded that it would "not hurt the feelings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and it would not be too kitchy, so we decided to go with it." With
what? ( This story 
                  courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>. )
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 184</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Post-Game Blame":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Fill in the blank on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcon</ENAMEX>'s analysis of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> loss. "Instead of getting mentally ready for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>, we
were ___________."
               
            

            
"Getting mentally ready for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengals</ENAMEX>. Were we surprised when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> was
introduced!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Building a fort</ENAMEX> with our knee and shoulder pads."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balk</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Anticipating that all-new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Simpsons</ENAMEX> episode."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliot Cohen</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visiting Manuel Noriega</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Pollack</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Praying</ENAMEX>. Which just goes to show you how much power that has, let me
tell you. Thanks a lot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Lawhorn</ENAMEX> had a
similar answer.)

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            What we know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>.
Here's the sketch on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place mat</ENAMEX> in the coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>: Sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> of
a lovely art deco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crockett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tubbs</ENAMEX> read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man in Full aloud to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Estefan</ENAMEX>. This replaces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place mat</ENAMEX>: Leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> of a
tatty deco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> on their way to enjoy an early bird special, my grandparents
are elbowed into the gutter by a coke-sniffing fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> on his way
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next year</TIMEX>'s millennial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX>: A dolphin and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> sit at
the controls of an atomic monorail filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX>
throwing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX> at the ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Gleason</ENAMEX> as he flees inside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fontainbleu Hotel</ENAMEX>. Come on down!

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX>
Answer
            

            "Instead of getting mentally ready for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>,
we were talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> ."

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The night</TIMEX> before the game, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Robinson</ENAMEX>, one of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> north of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, was arrested for
soliciting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>.

            Another distraction some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> blamed for their
lack of concentration--their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> were allowed to travel and stay with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>.

            "Having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in the
hotel became a hassle to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>. "We had to drive all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> north of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hooker</ENAMEX> in peace," he did not
add.

            
               Waiting for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dough Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            An experiment reported in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> shows how waiter or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> behavior affects the
size of the tip. Will the following increase or decrease it?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Introduce yourself.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Draw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smiley</ENAMEX> face on the bill.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Touch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> on the shoulder when asking if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> was all right.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Rub the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> on the thigh and wink when
asking, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anything else?</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Crouch at the table when taking the order.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Crouch under the table
when taking the order.

            

               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Increase

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Increase for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX>; decrease for waiter

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Increase

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Not included in experiment

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Increase

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Not included in
experiment

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, restaurant tips
totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $12 billion</NUMEX>, averaging <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16.7 percent</NUMEX>.

            
               Race
Results
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Man in</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
