
   
   
      
         
             Don't Blame It on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio</ENAMEX> ... or Brasilia Either

            Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, a friend
sent me a postcard showing the famous statue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> that overlooks <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rio de</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Janeiro</ENAMEX>. Underneath the outstretched <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> he had written a caption, "The debt
is this big, and only God can repay it." He was wrong: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazil</ENAMEX> eventually
worked its way out of the debt crisis and even became a favorite of foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">As late as last summer</TIMEX>, things still seemed to be going pretty well.
And then the bottom fell out.

            The economic history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> is one of punctured enthusiasms--of brief episodes of hope followed by
bitter disappointment. From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazonian</ENAMEX> rubber boom to the "Brazilian
miracle" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has repeatedly seemed on the verge of an
economic takeoff, only to slide back again into stagnation. Or as an old local
joke has it, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of the future--and always will be.

            But what has happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six months</TIMEX> is
perhaps the saddest story of all, because this time the punishment seems so
unjustified. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, when the backwash from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s crisis forced
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> to raise interest rates to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 50 percent</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> lamented the
situation: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> has never had such a responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>; the environment
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> has never been so good; why is this happening to us?" Good
question.

            For the fact is that this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time Brazil</ENAMEX> has tried very hard to play by the rules. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX> it
introduced a new currency, the real, and promised to avoid the inflationary
excesses of the past. Thus far it has delivered, with prices basically stable
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. Like other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> also moved to
free up its markets, privatizing inefficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, eliminating import
quotas, lowering tariffs, and so on. While the process of reform has by no
means been completed, the progress is real and substantial.

            Then came <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. What does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> have to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>?
Well, to a certain extent both were attracting money from the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--specifically, hedge funds that were borrowing in dollars or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">yen</NUMEX> and
investing in higher-interest real or ruble bonds. When these funds lost money
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> became nervous and demanded their money back--which
meant the funds had to sell off assets, which meant pulling money out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. But the main reason for "contagion" from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> was
psychological: Seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> default on its debt raised fears that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>,
which also has large budget deficits, might be risky too. And so capital began
fleeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Initially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> tried to support the value of the real by
selling dollars at the official exchange rate; but as its reserves of dollars
declined it supplemented this strategy by raising interest rates to punitive
levels in order to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to keep their money in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. Of course,
these high interest rates also made a recession inevitable.

            Now you might say that
this only shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> should not run big budget deficits, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazil</ENAMEX>
needed to get its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> accounts under control to restore market
confidence. And that has indeed been the thrust of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s policy,
agreed upon with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>. But there is something a bit
funny about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s deficit, if you look at it at all closely. You see, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazil</ENAMEX>
is actually running a substantial "primary surplus"--that is, if you do not
count the interest on outstanding debt, tax receipts are larger than spending.
The primary surplus would be even larger than it is if the economy were not
depressed, depressing tax receipts too.

            So the problem must be all that debt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> ran up in years
past, right? Well, not exactly: It turns out that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> isn't particularly
deep in debt, by the usual measures. The government debt is less than half the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> GDP, no worse than the ratio for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and better than that
of most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. What makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s deficit so large is not the
size of its debt but the very high interest rates it must pay on that
debt--interest rates that are high because of a lack of investor confidence.
And why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> lack confidence? Because of those big deficits.

            In case you somehow
missed the absurdity of the situation, let me say it again: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> lack
confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> because it has a large budget deficit, which is the result
of high interest rates and a depressed economy, which are the result of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' lack of confidence. It's completely circular. If markets were
willing to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> the benefit of the doubt--if, say, they were
willing to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> debt at a real interest rate only twice as high as
that on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bonds--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s budget deficit would not look scary at all.

            So what's the answer? Conventional wisdom, embodied in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> program that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> embarked on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>, was that the way to break the
vicious circle was for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> to demonstrate its resolve. And the way to do
that was to make that primary surplus even larger and defend the value of the
currency at all costs--which meant keeping interest rates high. This was
supposed to convince the market that all was well, so eventually interest rates
could come down. The trouble was that all that austerity was a hard sell
politically--especially because the economy was going into a nasty recession
thanks to those high interest rates. I don't think you can blame Brazilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>: How well would our own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> perform if told that taxes must be
raised and spending slashed in the midst of a recession, with no clear reward
except a possible reduction in speculative pressure, maybe, sometime in the
future?

            What were the
alternatives? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Sachs</ENAMEX>--said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> should
simply let the real fall without raising interest rates, maybe even cutting
them. Others--such as me--worried this would lead to such a massive devaluation
that inflation would surge, and argued (in the wilderness) for temporary
controls on capital flight.

            Which brings us to the story of the latest crisis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
program fell apart, predictably, though earlier than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expected.
Still, on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> when the real was floated things didn't look
too bad. The currency didn't fall as much as some feared, and the stock market
soared. It looked, in other words, as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Sachs</ENAMEX> had been right. Then, over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> to raise interest rates.
When the interest rate increase was announced, panic set in and the currency
plunged. Instead of helping, in other words, the interest rate increase
apparently simply reinforced the vicious circle.

            Maybe it is still possible to push the reset
button--to rewind the tape to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-January</TIMEX> and recapture that initial optimism.
After firing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> central bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> in close succession, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> appointed an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX>--an interesting move, particularly given the market action
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the preceding couple of days</TIMEX>. (For more on the recent turmoil, click .)
And perhaps the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can somehow say the magic words, find the formula that
will turn self-fulfilling pessimism into self-fulfilling optimism. But win or
lose, the story is, let us say, not exactly a wonderful advertisement for
either the competence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> or the virtues of the New World Order.

         
      
   
