
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Stands Naked</ENAMEX>

            The impeachment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> dominated front pages around the world <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
Times called for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s resignation, saying that the spectacle of a
trial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> would subvert "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s responsibilities as the world's
only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">superpower</ENAMEX>." Meanwhile, the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> applauded impeachment because it illustrated "the fact that even
[the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>] is subject to political machinery of rare democratic
perfection."

            Where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
Times suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Livingston</ENAMEX>'s resignation "shows Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
the way," an editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melbourne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, called it "a bizarre
political gift" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s act "instantly blurred the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> argument that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s impeachment is based on the issue of
lies and the law rather than sex. ... Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston</ENAMEX>'s resignation unleashes the
spectre of a political system convulsed by regular revelations of sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX> and demands from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>'s [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX>] religious right for
sexual purity."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> presented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>'s events as "the logical conclusion to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-20 th century</TIMEX> drama which has been quietly corroding the old
certainties of political power throughout the world's mature democracies. ...
That is, when the personal really is political, not merely a feminist
catchcry, and when new technologies and competition are driving the media to
deliver unparalleled, all-news-all-the-time access to the lives of those in
power, we should not be too surprised to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> on the brink of
losing his job for having an affair."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the
Independent on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> , which called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "a shallow, fawning mountebank, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose
serial adultery might be overlooked more easily but for his serial mendacity,"
was just as hard on his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>. It said, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX> seems to have been possessed by a zeal which is less 'republican' or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'conservative</ENAMEX>' than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maoist</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will not be happy until they have
inflicted ritual humiliation on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the spirit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cultural</ENAMEX>
Revolution." An editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> concurred, describing the impeachment
debate as "a disgraceful partisan spectacle, an act of vengeance rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>, a triumph for the fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian Right</ENAMEX> that will haunt
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> holy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX> would be "offensive" drew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> responses. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> said that the "considerate gesture ... is like any
hiatus in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostilities</ENAMEX>, a backhanded concession to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>: a hearty
breakfast for a condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>, an editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Star</ENAMEX> suggested that the strikes would have been
more effective if they had been made after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX> ended and predicted that "it
now seems likely that the strikes will have to be suspended for about a month
while devout <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> take leave of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and drink during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight hours</TIMEX> and Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> continues to take leave of his senses at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all hours</TIMEX>. Having been
supplied with so much notice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> will then be able to make good use of that
month to conceal or destroy whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> failed to eliminate."
(For more on the etiquette of fighting during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramadan</ENAMEX>, see

                  Slate
               's"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX>.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> airstrikes
earned it little more than condemnation and condescension. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> op-ed
column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX>
said that the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> mobilization ... helps <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> more than it helps
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, who contributed a symbolic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tornado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, is only signaling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are not
alone." Writing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s new national newspaper the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Steyn</ENAMEX> observed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> media coverage of the strikes barely
mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s participation: "This is the thanks a chap gets for
providing the most naked of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> with his only international fig
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leaf</ENAMEX>."

            An editorial
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> , headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Slavish Devotion</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>,"
claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s tendency to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> itself so closely with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
reflects the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s inability to reconcile itself with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. Instead the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> have attempted "to stay on the world stage by associating themselves
with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> global supremacy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> finds them useful and is too
polite to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> how little weight it carries in the world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spaniards</ENAMEX>, may say so. But they do not say it in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. So <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> does not hear."

             

         
      
   
