
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blast From</ENAMEX>
the Past
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blah</ENAMEX> reviews for this cutesy comedy
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who emerges from a fallout <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX>. Once above
ground, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Fraser</ENAMEX>, reprising the naif he played in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jungle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Encino Man</ENAMEX> , is smitten with a cynical and standoffish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alicia Silverstone</ENAMEX>. The film relies heavily on both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraser</ENAMEX>'s laughably outdated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">notions</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point he exclaims, "Oh my lucky stars, it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX>!") and his
budding romance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silverstone</ENAMEX>, which make for amusingly fluffy stuff. Sissy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spacek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Walken</ENAMEX>, though, both stand out as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraser</ENAMEX>'s daffy
frozen-in-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to
find out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fraser</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  Message in a
Bottle
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). This screen adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Sparks</ENAMEX>'
novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Wright Penn</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely folks</ENAMEX> destined
for each other. It's just as sappy as expected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> writes that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> has "the warm glow of a hazelnut coffee commercial" (the New York
Times ). Despite the fromage factor, great performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Newman</ENAMEX>--who plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Costner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> "with the relaxed confidence
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> shooting free throws in your driveway" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> )--make the film tolerable. (Find out more about
Costner on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celebsite</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  My Favorite
Martian
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call this film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spinoff</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1960s</ENAMEX> TV show about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martian</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lloyd</ENAMEX>) who falls to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> and
befriends an earthling (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Daniels</ENAMEX>) "loud and labored" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ). The film steamrollers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> with a frenetic pace
and loads of slapsticky special effects. Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX> in the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> : It "swings between chaos and pandemonium, with occasional
eruptions of bathroom humor." (This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> has information on the original television show.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
Testament
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX>). The latest installment in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> legal thriller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> gets good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>: It's "personal, moving
and much deeper" than his previous books, writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre Donahue</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say this one is better because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> goes beyond his usual
dabbling in social causes and injects honest-to-God <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> spirituality, and
with success: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s smart use of the suspense novel to explore questions
of being and faith puts him squarely in the footsteps of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene"</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> ). A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> find the overt Christianity
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preachy</ENAMEX> and self-righteous, but most say it improves an otherwise standard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page-turner</ENAMEX>. (In his of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Street Lawyer in</ENAMEX>

                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Gladwell</ENAMEX> argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s leading moralist.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX> of the
Border, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
               ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haruki Murakami</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). After the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>'s epic <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle</ENAMEX> , this novel of a
middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s attempts to rekindle a romance with an elusive childhood
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend disappoints critics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murakami</ENAMEX>'s aim is to "capture illegitimate
passion's elusive madness," but he "falls short" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Ward</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). This book lacks the scope of his earlier works, and at
times the language dips into cliché, but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> attribute this to a
poor translation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Hawthorne</ENAMEX> comes to his rescue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> , calling the novel a "wise and beautiful book ... full of
hidden truths." (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, courtesy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
[requires free registration].)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  Death of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Salesman</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene O'Neill Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Strong reviews
and boffo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.O.</ENAMEX> for this <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary production of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> perennial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Dennehy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy Loman</ENAMEX> is "played with majestic,
unnerving transparency" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Loman</ENAMEX>) draws equally ecstatic reviews. The production is said
to re-establish <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Salesman</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s finest play and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Gamerman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , who
says it's dated (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Salesman</ENAMEX> is showing its age") and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>, who praises this production but calls the play itself "unrelieved and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unchallenging</ENAMEX>." (Read the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s review .)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            :

            

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Payback</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simply Irresistible</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Rushmore ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dry Cleaning</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werewolves</ENAMEX> in Their Youth , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chabon</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- You're a Good Man</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Brown</ENAMEX> .

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  She's All That ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">24 Hour Woman</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Still <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crazy</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- My Name Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Mothers Didn't Tell Us: Why Happiness</ENAMEX>
Eludes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Woman</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Crittenden</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabelle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Strout</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heavy Water</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie
                  --
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --
                  Playing by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Another Day</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stahl</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Face-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Tarloff</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  Miss Nobody , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomek Tryzna</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Varsity Blues</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- At First Sight</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- In Dreams</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duane</ENAMEX>'s Depressed , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry McMurtry</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intuitionist</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colson Whitehead</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Fosse: A Celebration in Song and Dance</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadhurst Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

         
      
   
