
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squabbling Over Saddam</ENAMEX>

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> tug of war
continues over the rehabilitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX>
differing over whether to blame <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>'s rhetoric or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>'s
intransigence for the lack of a common <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> policy toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>.
According to leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riad Najib el-Rayyes</ENAMEX>, writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX> daily an-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nahar</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s reiteration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s historical claim to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> is intended as a signal to his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> that, if they continue
trying to block his rehabilitation, he will make life hard for them by
reopening a number of troublesome "files."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rayyes</ENAMEX> sees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s
pronouncement as a response to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> efforts to exclude him from the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> summit meeting on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, which is to be discussed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>
when they meet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> wants the summit to condemn
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military action against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and to support the lifting of sanctions,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> insisted that neither the summit nor the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>'
meeting should "bestow legitimacy" on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> , there may
be a compromise deal under which there will be no talk of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> summit until
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> elections in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, while the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 24</TIMEX> meeting will issue a
"balanced" statement opposing fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and also coming
out against assistance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> in its goal of bringing down
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> said it expects <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> to use her forthcoming visit to the region to try to
persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morocco</ENAMEX>, both of which are on her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">itinerary</ENAMEX>, to support the hard-line <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> position on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> want to bombard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, deprive it of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of its
only seaport and finance its dissident <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, but get angry when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> cannot contain their outrage and let fly with a few statements
condemning those who collude in aggression against their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Quds</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Arabi</ENAMEX> added. "What do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riyadh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> expect? For <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
to anoint them with rose-petal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">perfume</ENAMEX>, and organize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carnivals</ENAMEX> in celebration of their policies?"

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petra</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Hussein</ENAMEX>'s return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> of cancer treatment in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> was celebrated with the slaughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> and camels along
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roadsides</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>'s return was also welcomed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yosef</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lapid</ENAMEX> wrote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maariv</ENAMEX> : "He is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>, a brave king, a wise king, a
friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>. We hope his recovery will put paid to the struggle for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throne</ENAMEX>. As long as he governs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, we have real peace with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerusalem Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Newman</ENAMEX> wrote
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> was seen "not only as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who made
peace, but also as one who believes in that peace and, who is prepared to come
and visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> killed by his border <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>, as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who has really had enough of war and bloodshed."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Makovsky</ENAMEX>,
diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> , wrote
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown Prince</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX>, to remain next in line to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> throne, despite speculation
that the king, under pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Noor</ENAMEX>, might name their 19-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamza</ENAMEX>, as the next monarch. He quoted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> as saying that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> hopes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hassan</ENAMEX> will succeed because he is not only deeply committed to the
peace process but is also "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> of vast experience."

            Under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Russian Ambassador To Play It Tough</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segodnya</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuri Ushakov</ENAMEX>, who
flew to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to take up his post, had been given instructions
"reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> documents" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>. It also
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ushakov</ENAMEX>'s reputation for toughness might be one of the main reasons
for his appointment.

            "Given his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, one can deduce that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
doesn't intend to surrender its international standing for the sake of its
friendship with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, in spite of serious economic setbacks and the fact
that it is dependent on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> benevolence for overcoming them," the paper
said. It added that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> seems determined to fight to make the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> become the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guarantor</ENAMEX> of international stability and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> needs "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> victory," regardless of the price, it said.

            According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copenhagen Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, new statistics show that one in every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
births in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX> now occurs with the help of artificial insemination
techniques. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> percent of births in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> took place with the help of either
"test-tube <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>" techniques or in vitro fertilization, it said. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years</TIMEX>
earlier the figure stood at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 2.5 percent</NUMEX>.

             

         
      
   
