
   
   
      
         
             He Has To Go

            The preliminaries are over.
It is time to decide. Should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and expel him
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>? My answer, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of indecision, is a strong "Yes!"

            I had formerly been
impressed by the argument that ousting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would set a precedent for any
party having a sufficient majority in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to get rid of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
which would convert us into a parliamentary democracy. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time I had
thought our problem might be solved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">25 th Amendment</ENAMEX>, which
provides for the removal of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> found unable to perform the duties of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. But that required the concurrence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, which
would surely not be forthcoming. I had also thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might save us
a lot of soul-searching by resigning, but apparently he will not. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some</NUMEX> times
I thought that censure or rebuke might do as punishment and expression of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indignation</ENAMEX>.

            I can say exactly when I came to the conclusion that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had to be removed. It was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 15, 1998</TIMEX>. That was two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> was to start action on impeaching him.
It was also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> before he gave orders to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. I got out of bed that
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, took in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, and scanned the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> page. Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> I
was decided, and not only decided, but decided with a heat that I rarely feel
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> public affairs. What sparked this heat was the picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX>, and the reminder of the picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous day</TIMEX>, wearing a
yarmulke at the grave of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yitzhak Rabin</ENAMEX>. And I suddenly thought, "Is this the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I want representing the righteousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in a land sacred to
billions of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moslems</ENAMEX>?" Then I asked whether I wanted him
to represent us anywhere. Do we want him laying the wreath at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tomb of the</ENAMEX>
Unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldier</ENAMEX>, comforting our mourners, saluting our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>? Do I want to see
his "sincere" face on television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>? No, decidedly no!

            No, even more decidedly
no, after the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. I don't know whether he decided to bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in
order to divert us from the forthcoming impeachment debate. That is the point:
I don't know, and most of the world doesn't know. He has generated the belief
that he is capable of taking such grave action to save his own skin.
Terminating the action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> without any conclusive results <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few hours</TIMEX>
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted for impeachment strengthened that belief. He had started
the bombing just in time to give his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> the refuge of arguing that to
impeach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX> while our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> were in harm's way would be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unpatriotic</ENAMEX>. He had stopped the bombing as soon as that argument became
useless. That is an abuse of power! The whole episode shows how unfit he is to
be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He has polluted the atmosphere within which policy decisions are
made.

            L ike almost everyone else, I want to get "this thing" over
with. But to me "this thing" is not only the process; it is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
presidency. I don't want to punish him or have a national catharsis. I want
something more practical. I want him off our screen.

            I admit that I never
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wanted Clinton</ENAMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and never voted for him. But I was always "cool"
about it. I have not been a deep-dyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hater. Except for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> health
care plan, and his vacillation toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, his policy has not been terrible,
in my opinion. The performance of the economy during his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has
been good, and although I don't attribute very much of that to him, at least he
has not been an obstacle. I don't expect any improvement, or any change, in
public policy as a result of his departure.

            
In an article I wrote during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> campaign
(pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>) I said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>:

            
               But he has one
serious deficiency as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. He is prone to foolish mistakes. Every
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, like everyone else, makes mistakes. Foolish mistakes are ones that
could reliably have been known in advance to be mistakes. There is something in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>--some odd combination of naivete and conceit--that makes him
liable to such mistakes.
            

            He has gone too far in
his foolish mistakes, and beyond foolish mistakes, and I am no longer "cool"
about him as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who are legally fastidious say it's not the sex,
it's the perjury. For me it is partly the sex. If he had lied under oath about
parking illegally I wouldn't be so disgusted. But for a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to have
oral sex with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman employee</ENAMEX> less than half his age in the Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> --I can't claim not to be offended by that. I have been told that is
an old-fashioned, puritanical attitude. But even old-fashioned puritans have
the right as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to protest the behavior of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. And it is not
only the perjury. It is the sophomoric deviousness of the perjury that is an
insult to our intelligence.

            The constitutional
question remains. Does his behavior add up to grounds for removal from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>?
The words in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>, "high crimes and misdemeanors," give us much
latitude. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">framers</ENAMEX> had wanted to limit us more they could have been more
specific. Essentially, they left the judgment to us--not to an opinion poll or
even to our political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> who are closest to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but to our
most senior political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. My opinion is that not every
perjury is a "high" crime, as grounds for removing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> from office. But
I believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s performance, before and after his perjuries, has
universally generated such a response of disapproval, ranging from cynicism to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgust</ENAMEX>, as to degrade the ability of the presidency to serve its function.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has said that it is his goal to degrade the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
to threaten <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has degraded the ability of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and the world. That is a high
crime.

            I am still concerned about the risk of setting a precedent
for opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> for purely political
reasons. Future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> will have to deal with that. For now we have to set
the precedent that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> should so behave themselves
as to merit the confidence of the world. This is a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and surely we
can find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in it who are as capable of being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is and who are also able to commit themselves to good behavior.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> requires a vote of at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to convict and expel a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will
not have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> majority, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cannot be convicted on the votes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> alone. That is a good thing. The precedent-setting risk would be
greater if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> were convicted by a strictly party-line vote. The case
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should be strong enough to justify some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his
own party voting against him. In the case of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, it is.

         
      
   
