
   
   
      
         
            Demon

            To hear
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demon</ENAMEX>," click .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Cars</ENAMEX>
stalled, the light gone
hazy under leafless sycamores--
                                                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>'s
diction, as casual as you asking
for a last glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, whispers in my ear
words cotton-mouthed and sere as sloughing bark
littering the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roadway</ENAMEX>,
                                 <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush hour</TIMEX> traffic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">halting</ENAMEX>, faltering like my hand
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> I signed away your flesh
to the crematory fire ...

            Now,
the white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lines</ENAMEX>' dot and dash
makes my hand less steady on the wheel,
the stoplight glimmers a shade too red--
the faith I've never felt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> to day
haunts me like some imp-winged demon
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosch</ENAMEX> painting, its infantile, red-bawling face
staring accusingly into my eyes
as if it dared to fly beyond the gilt frame,
hectoring, hovering, sluggish wings buzzing
like the winter-hatched fly stumbling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spastic</ENAMEX> against the dashboard dials,
its frail internal compass somehow gone haywire
overridden by spurts and shocks.

            Beneath
the roadside <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sycamores</ENAMEX>,
as if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">newsreel unspooled</ENAMEX> in my head,
I see a squirrel, gaunt, great-eyed
as a prisoner <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-starved, its face dissolving
into the demon's face
                                 ... so like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s face
quizzical, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-angry, pinched by death;
and then, at the end, grown grave, calm ...
                                                                
mendicant
as a fly, its legs bent as if to pray,
the great swivelling head a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friar</ENAMEX>'s
black hood, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mephistophilis</ENAMEX> disguised

            

               --Why, this is hell, nor am I out of it ...
            

            Among the quivering needles
the fly
smashes, its imp-wings
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glimmering</ENAMEX> in the cooling light, its demon eyes
shattered into broken mirrors
replicating ad infinitum <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car car car</ENAMEX> car
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree tree tree</ENAMEX> ... now it lands on the steering wheel
and faces me:
                     What do I look like
in the eyes of a fly?
                              Shattered into nose lips eyes
do my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jittering</ENAMEX> faces swarm like harbingers of
the demon in my own last act
who takes off his hood and shows me my signature
signed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> ... ?
                               but it's you, isn't it?
you staring out from those bulging eyes
asking frankly for my sympathy, yet timid,
apologetic, only doing your job--
my familiar flying through rising fumes
to drag me from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
