
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Wear and Tear&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year ago</TIMEX> she wore an orange <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jumpsuit</ENAMEX> and brandished a torch, now she
wears a look of remorse. Who is she, and what went wrong?
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 171</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Grates Outdoors":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Fill in the
blank.
            

            

               It first happened outside in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, and now, frets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reba White Williams</ENAMEX>,
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Art Commission</ENAMEX>, "it seems as though wherever
there is a vacant spot, anybody can _______________ without any consideration
of how it looks."
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daven</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Cornog</ENAMEX>
            

            "Put
words in my mouth."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fran Stearns</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stand</ENAMEX>
around unself-consciously."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Miller</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Paddle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bess Meyerson</ENAMEX>'s naked fanny."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
their own personal ad on a penguin at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park Zoo</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
Franzen
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            The most irritating sight
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> (excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s naked swing dancing with the
ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss Tweed</ENAMEX>) is anyone jabbering into a cell phone. But why is it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">annoying</ENAMEX>? True loathing requires real understanding. So what underlies this
mobile hatred?

            

               It's just showing off? That can't be it. That would be like saying 60 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ooh</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fancy Pants</ENAMEX> and his home phone! Too good to make your calls at
the general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> like the rest of us?"

               It's rude to perform a private act in public? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nope</ENAMEX>. I'm just relieved that
the prattler isn't cutting his nails or worse. And I don't mind seeing someone
at a pay phone.

               Who wants to hear that inane chitchat? Nobody. But would I prefer those
conversations to occur in person? This way, I only hear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. And how
sophisticated is my own conversation? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Aristotle</ENAMEX> seldom comes into it.

               This heedless yammering adds to the clamor and prevents me from thinking my
own thoughts? In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or on a commuter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, perhaps. But how quiet
are the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>? That can't be it.

            

            I sadly conclude that my
anti-cellularism is merely my being a stick in the mud. I'll try to overcome
it. Unless, of course, someone can give me a reason to hate with a clear
conscience. Please.

            
               Please <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deposit</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
Cents for the Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reba White Williams</ENAMEX> said, "It seems as though
wherever there is a vacant spot, anybody can put up a telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX>
without any consideration of how it looks."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called Telebeam
has erected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 200</NUMEX> new phone enclosures designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Fabiano</ENAMEX>, and many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hate them. Made of stainless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>, they are much bigger than the Adco
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX>, the most common model. Applications are pending for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,965</NUMEX> new phones in
addition to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32,239</NUMEX> already on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Archive</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington University</ENAMEX> released a book of previously
top secret transcripts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Below, part of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 21, 1975</TIMEX>, conversation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tse-tung</ENAMEX>:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KISSINGER</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> has
had a certain position for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, and it has an unparalleled record for
being wrong.
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAO</ENAMEX>: It is said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is controlled by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>
family.
            

            

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KISSINGER</ENAMEX>: That is true.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAO</ENAMEX>:
And also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .

               
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KISSINGER</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> --it is no longer true. (He then
conferred with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> who pointed out that Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX>.) You are right.

            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAO</ENAMEX>: The proprietress is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>.
            

            To learn more about the
hell-bound former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of State</ENAMEX>, read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Kissinger Transcripts</ENAMEX> ,
edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Burr</ENAMEX>, or visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Archive</ENAMEX> Web site at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX>seas.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gwu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">edu/nsarchive/.</ENAMEX>

            
               Race
Results
            

            Win: Excretion

            Place: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parking</ENAMEX>

            Show: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
