
   
   
      
         
            Free <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times of London</ENAMEX>, which
never tires of publishing judicious editorials about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, drew its
conclusions about the impeachment trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. While the trial was
"technically legal," it had failed the crucial test set by the founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>
that such a process must inspire public confidence. This is because the
vehemence with which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> pursued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is now "seen by many
as an unacceptable constraint on executive power." The obvious lesson was that
the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> law should be "redesigned" when it comes up for review
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of June</TIMEX> so that the choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> "be made in a way
both independent of party politics and yet seen to be democratic." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said, "Selection by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX> would be an
option."

            Another lesson of the impeachment was that the
"limit to partisanship" implied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">U.S. Constitution</ENAMEX> was breached in this
case when "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> sent Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to trial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
at the same time as some of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> suggested that censure, rather than
impeachment, was the aim. ... It is incumbent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> to recognise that an
impeachment trial should be a way of protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, not
punishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> added, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has certainly been shamed by
the process. But the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> could be the pursuers, not the pursued.
That surely was not the founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>' aim." An op-ed article in the
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> by its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronwen Maddox</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the waste and misery generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flytrap</ENAMEX> left "a sour taste,"
but it may have prompted "a neat political reversal, helping to put <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
back in control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>--and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>."

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrose Evans-Pritchard</ENAMEX>, the most determined anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, said in an op-ed that it was "time to admit defeat." He blamed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "off the hook" by the "bêtise " of
indicting him on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> charges instead of on "the politicisation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> that forms the core scandal pervading the
abuses of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>." He concluded, "So the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> caught red-handed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perjury</ENAMEX>, obstruction of justice and ungallantly smearing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> as a
demented stalker is hailed as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. The world knows that he is guilty,
but he is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> enjoying a victory cigar. What a way to end the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>."

            The stories dominating the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> were:
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the opening of the manslaughter trial of three prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>'s sweep to power in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hesse</ENAMEX> using an
anti-immigrant election strategy; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s decision to
regularize <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 250,000</NUMEX> illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>; and
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, no particular story, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> led its front
page with the opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever war crimes trial--that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Sawoniuk</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77-year-old</TIMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Belorussian</ENAMEX> accused of leading "search
and kill" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squads</ENAMEX> to hunt down <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who had escaped a massacre during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">wartime</ENAMEX> occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belarus</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the Paris
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Libération</ENAMEX> broke ranks by splashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> concession to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> on its front page under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Daring</ENAMEX>." It pointed
out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a period of 18 months</TIMEX>, had given
permission for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 80,000</NUMEX> illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> to stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
Corriere
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, in a front-page editorial, compared favorably the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s well-prepared and well-argued proposal (although rejected
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hesse</ENAMEX>) to grant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident foreigners</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s sudden immigration
decree which, it said, could generate xenophobia and racism. "Such a crucial
problem as immigration can only be confronted in a spirit of bipartisanship, in
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the opposition undertake not to treat it as an
ideological question or to use it as a political weapon," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere</ENAMEX> said.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of center-left persuasion like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s
coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, praised the "open-door policy" as being beneficial to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a declining birth rate and an aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.

            L a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica</ENAMEX> also prominently reported that,
following the collapse of negotiations for a joint venture with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> has decided to pull out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, which he had intended
to be the base for his planned expansion into digital television across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
Instead, he made a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yalta Agreement</ENAMEX>" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> to
divide <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> pay-television between them. In an editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> antitrust legislation for his
departure, but in reality he was alarmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canal Plus</ENAMEX>' acquisition of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
percent stake in his highly profitable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sky</ENAMEX>.

            The position of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX>, made vacant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> by the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>, has still not
been filled but, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph of London</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Harrison</ENAMEX>, one of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX>, excluded himself as a candidate
with a poem published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>:

            

               I'd
sooner be a free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with no butts.
Free not to have to puff some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>'s wedding,
Free to say up yours to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>,
To write an ode on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles I</ENAMEX>'s beheading
And regret the restoration of his heir.

            

             

         
      
   
