
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cold Comforts</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years ago</TIMEX>, when he was
still a film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Schrader</ENAMEX> wrote an evocative study of the directors
Ozu, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bresson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dreyer</ENAMEX> that he called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Transcendental Style in Cinema</ENAMEX> .
How odd that the style of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrader</ENAMEX>'s new movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affliction</ENAMEX> , is as
torturously untranscendent as a work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> can get. Maybe that's the point:
The tragedy is the protagonist's inability to transcend his terrible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upbringing</ENAMEX>. Based on a grim novel by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Baron</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bleak, Russell Banks</ENAMEX>, and set
in a frigid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affliction</ENAMEX> tells the story
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Whitehouse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nick Nolte</ENAMEX>), a part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police officer</ENAMEX> and full-time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flunky</ENAMEX>, who's constitutionally unequipped to survive a succession of personal
and professional crises. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX> can't get on his preadolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wavelength</ENAMEX> and compensates by suing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Beth Hurt</ENAMEX>) for custody.
Then his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> dies (he finds her in bed, semi-frozen), and he ends up caring
for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly father</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Coburn</ENAMEX>), a stuporous and abusive drunk. Grainy,
home-movielike flashbacks show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coburn</ENAMEX> taunting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> for being a sissy and
then beating him senseless when he tries to fight back.

            When a wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is killed in an apparent hunting accident, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX> has a hunch that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was murdered. Who done it? Either the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim True</ENAMEX>), or a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>--perhaps at the behest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s capitalist
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overlord</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes Osborne</ENAMEX>). Late at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> and holds forth on his
suspicions in a low rasp over the phone to his younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolfe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willem</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dafoe</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> who subtly feeds the flames of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX>'s alienation. "I
get to feeling like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whipped dog</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX>. "Someday I'm gonna bite
back."

            A ffliction is an affectless piece of moviemaking. It
features frozen landscapes, gray skies, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX>-spattered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, and long,
protracted shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walking in and out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that seem to have
turned themselves inward to escape the cold. Nothing expresses anything. For
much of the film, you can't decide whether the murder plot is a product of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX>'s escalating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> or if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrader</ENAMEX> is just inept at shaping a whodunit.
As it turns out, the vagueness and even the infelicities are part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrader</ENAMEX>'s
design. The film is uncompromising, all of a piece, its desolateness unleavened
by incidental pleasures. Not a whodunnit at all, it's more like a postmodern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">western</ENAMEX>, the parable of an unruly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> driven to madness by a long line of
unruly patriarchs before him; an impotent vigilante in search of
something--anything--to shoot.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX> lives on the edge of
his emotions--he has no perspective to retreat to even in a crisis. OK, I can't
take credit for that line. It's from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolfe</ENAMEX>'s literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narration</ENAMEX>, which is
helpful in clarifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s motives but ultimately annoying, since only an
inexpert storyteller needs that much pompous clarification. It doesn't help
that the waxen, bug-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dafoe</ENAMEX> inhabits a different universe from the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, an effect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schrader</ENAMEX> intended but that would have worked better with
someone else--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dafoe</ENAMEX> always acts as if he has beamed down from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Martian</ENAMEX> theater
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">troupe</ENAMEX>. He ends up embodying only the movie's numbing obviousness.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nolte</ENAMEX> embodies its volcanic undercurrents, and he keeps
Affliction off life support. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX>, he's a heavyweight too big and
too unstable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The sagging flesh on that square <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> encases small,
babyish features, and the belching sounds that come out of that barrel chest
are like an infant's squalls after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times
that many cigarettes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nolte</ENAMEX>'s eyes are slits in dough, and his huge gestures
might be an attempt to compensate for their tininess. Part of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolte</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conveys</ENAMEX> is the struggle of a clay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to convey a lot of elusive thoughts--a
hopeless prospect that only leads to rage and despair. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, he grabs
and twists his face into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munchian</ENAMEX> scream. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX>, it turns out, has a
horrendous toothache, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolte</ENAMEX> isn't playing the physical pain. He's playing
the metaphor--the toothache as existential agony.

            Not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> could have embodied this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">titan</ENAMEX>'s dominating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coburn</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Saturn</ENAMEX>-like in his awfulness. At once
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lethargic</ENAMEX> and vicious, he is roused from his decrepitude only by the prospect
of inflicting discomfort or pain. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sissy Spacek</ENAMEX>)
confronts him about a crude remark, he fixes her with a leer while licking salt
off the back of his hand--a gesture more wolfishly obscene than anything he
could say. We know why she packs her bags after that and could have done
without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dafoe</ENAMEX>'s concluding lines about the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> beaten by
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> whose capacity for love and hope has been destroyed at birth.

            Perhaps I'd have
responded more fully to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affliction</ENAMEX> if it had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX>. In movies
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winter Light</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>), we give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingmar Bergman</ENAMEX> the benefit of the
doubt because he grew up with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 hour nights</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herring</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strindberg</ENAMEX>.
Dyspeptic storytelling is in his blood. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affliction</ENAMEX> ,
it struck me as both arid and pretentious; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, arriving with no
narrative expectations, I found myself more tolerant of the pacing and more
drawn in by the performances. If you don't have the luxury of seeing the movie
twice, you'd do well to leave your hopes for a good thriller at the
door--unless the thrill you seek is that of a great, gutsy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> on the high
wire.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Peckinpah</ENAMEX> might have been fortunate in croaking before
he could realize his dream of bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Evans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX> western
novel The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hi-Lo Country</ENAMEX> to the screen. This is another of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> sagas, with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rancher-narrator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>, falling under the
spell of an embodiment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old West</ENAMEX>, here a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Big Boy</ENAMEX>. He
also falls in love with a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX>, the embodiment of Sex--the kind
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who sends <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> into spasms of uncontrollable lust, such that they'd
kill their good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> or drink themselves into an early grave. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Boy</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX> start doing the wild thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX> finds himself pulled in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directions</ENAMEX>, neither especially interesting. Mixed in with this is a lot of
elegiac folderol about herding the old-fashioned way, on horseback, rather than
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> or boxcars.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peckinpah</ENAMEX> had made this movie it might have had
some of the ingratiating rowdiness of his The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballad of Cable</ENAMEX> Hogue
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junior Bonner</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Stephen Frears</ENAMEX> directs in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distanced</ENAMEX> and self-consciously classical style. He keeps the horizon line at
the center of the frame, so that the movie's point of view seems static even
when the images are gorgeously evocative. It's pretty, but it's all at arm's
length, with an aura of doom that palls our enjoyment of even the picture's
well-staged fisticuffs and bronco busting.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Big Boy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrelson</ENAMEX> is a pop-eyed cartoon, but I admit to finding his hamminess--and his
pronunciation of such phrases as "You <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scum-suckin</ENAMEX>' dawgs"--hugely entertaining.
Less companionable is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crudup</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>, whose high-arched cheekbones are
emblems of the movie's frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">classicism</ENAMEX>. But what sinks The Hi-Lo
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Country</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Arquette</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona</ENAMEX>, who's supposed to convey sleepy
sensuality but seems merely to be on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaaludes</ENAMEX>. Whatever surprises Arquette
might once have had are long gone; the only thing mysterious about her is those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, distracting fangs.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette Bening</ENAMEX>, on the verge of becoming a major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>
before she got sucked into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>'s orbit, burned up on entry. But she's
astonishingly vivid in her new film, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Dreams</ENAMEX> . It's a poetic but
ultimately disappointing stab at expressionistic horror, courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Crying Game</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bening</ENAMEX> plays a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s book author
plagued by dreams of little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> being lured away by a big, bad wolf in human
form. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of the genre will be surprised to learn that she's established
some kind of psychic link to a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Downey Jr.</ENAMEX>). Besides
Bening, the film's chief interest is the unmatched intensity that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> brings
to her visions, which are both lyrical and ghastly, and so frightening that
it's hard to imagine how the movie can deliver a demon worthy of them. It
can't, of course, which is the problem with mainstream horror pictures: The
more deliriously abstract and unhinged their imagery, the more of a clunk there
is when the evil actually materializes and the genre conventions kick in.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bening</ENAMEX> has one amazing
scene. In despair, she slashes her wrists and ends up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, where she
attempts to explain her bond with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Rea</ENAMEX>,
with an incongruous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> accent). Both haggard and elfin, she moves in and
out of sanity, now distraught with grief, now giddy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior insight</ENAMEX>.
Someone else made her trash her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and scrawl imprecations on the walls, but
cutting her wrists, she says, giggling, was all her own work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bening</ENAMEX> plays the
scene on a cascade of emotion, so that she really seems to be speaking from a
different world. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dreams</ENAMEX> betrays her supernatural brilliance. The last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">half-hour</ENAMEX> is like a séance after the ghost has left. Everyone's at the table
still trying to get worked up, but the spell has been irreparably broken.

            I want to thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sragow</ENAMEX> for encouraging me to
catch the commercial flop <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Babe: Pig in the City</ENAMEX> before the movie ended
its nightmarishly brief run in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>. (Sragow unfashionably named it the
best film of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> .) You could wait for video, but if
you can find <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pig in the City</ENAMEX> playing anywhere on a big screen--an hour
away, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip mall</ENAMEX>, only at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>, in the middle of a blizzard--see it,
because you'd have to go back to the silents to find its like visually, and no
silent picture could have had this kind of soundtrack. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directed</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>, the movie is in a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> from its unassuming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>. The
talking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and discombobulated cityscapes are so exquisite that I started
to snivel <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 minutes</TIMEX> in and more or less kept it up for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next hour and</TIMEX>
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. This is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for the most overlooked big budget film of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, maybe of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>. Pearls before <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">swine</ENAMEX>, indeed.

         
      
   
