
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s Most Wanted

            The fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most
wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>, was much discussed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> press this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s ruling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>, was tightening the noose around him but would not yield
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> pressure to hand him over or banish him to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> country. On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> announced that bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> had been stripped of all means
of communication, including a satellite phone, and that restrictions had been
placed on the meetings he could hold. His status as a "guest" of the Taliban
would be reconsidered if he breached the restrictions, the statement added.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> cited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> conceded that there had been an argument between bin
advocacy of a "fatwa" against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, calling for attacks on them
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worldwide</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> quit <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> lands. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar</ENAMEX> argued against the
indiscriminate killing of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, given that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>,
others who sympathized with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>, and still others who were "peaceable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. He also said that shari'a (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> law) did not
permit the indiscriminate targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> insisted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> would not hand
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX> over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, however much it came under pressure to do
so. They noted that when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turki</ENAMEX> al-Faisal asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar</ENAMEX> to do this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taliban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> retorted sharply, "You should
show respect for your religion. How can you demand the extradition of a Moslem
to an infidel <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, even if he's a killer<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al-Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX>
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> stronghold of Qandahar
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> were less interested in securing the extradition of bin Laden than in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">thwarting Chinese</ENAMEX> attempts to gain influence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> not to sell to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
the unexploded Tomahawk cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> that had landed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> airstrikes on bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>, keen to lay its
hands on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>' technology, had offered to buy them "at a huge price,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> had warned they would
step up financial and military assistance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> "went too far" in its relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            A l-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quds al-Arabi</ENAMEX> also reported that bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> flew into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Qandahar</ENAMEX> aboard a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> with a message from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, threatening bin Laden that he would be putting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>'
lives at risk if he targeted any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>,
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is one of the wealthiest and most prominent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>, was
stripped of his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> because of suspected involvement in two
attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX>, in
which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> were killed.

            Presumably writing
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> announced its new restrictions on bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Samaha</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al-Hayat</ENAMEX> described him in an editorial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> as one of the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-sponsored
"communications revolution," which enabled him to transfer money undetected
around the world and to reach every corner of the "information <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>."

            Pending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> votes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, there was little comment
around the world on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>. But writing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Jenkins</ENAMEX> said that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trial had been painful, it
had "toned up the muscles of democracy." He wrote, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britons</ENAMEX> cannot scoff. They
are suffering an accountability famine. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> can hardly muster
more than a pip or a squeak at present. The can hardly cast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s escape was on several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> front pages. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> off
the hook without even a rebuke" was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s headline in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> .

            But the main story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press, leading
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s editions of both the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> and the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , was a
food scandal about the effects of genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> on human health. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> at a government-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aberdeen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, who
had been forced to retire early after publishing research showing that rats fed
on genetically modified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> suffered a weakened immune system and damage
to vital organs, has been supported in "an unprecedented memorandum" by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> calling for his rehabilitation, the reports said.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> also revealed that the rats' brain size had decreased. The
government promised an urgent investigation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also
gave front-page billing to a row in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> over a ruling by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supreme</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> cannot be raped if she is wearing tight denim jeans.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Il Messagero</ENAMEX> described the ruling, which
overturned the conviction of a driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> for raping one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupils</ENAMEX>,
as "a manual for aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapists</ENAMEX>." Another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Repubblica</ENAMEX> , took the
same line. In a front-page comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furio Colombo</ENAMEX> said it
was "simply not true that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> consenting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are needed to take off a pair
of jeans" and that he couldn't imagine how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> had reached such a
conclusion. "Perhaps it is inexperience, which may be understandable since
jeans have been around in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">little more than 30 years</TIMEX>," he wrote.

             

         
      
   
