
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">178</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&quot;W</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-O-M-A-N&quot</ENAMEX>;

            

               "She was quite a talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, and she was cute as a button too. And
being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, she did give it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s touch." Who said this, about whom,
for doing what?
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 177</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Them</ENAMEX>!":
            

            

               
                  
                     In his inaugural address <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said, "We should celebrate them in festivals, we should enjoy their
traditions in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, we should share them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>."
What?
                  
               
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlboros</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
poor."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rakoff</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Davidians</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Lyle</ENAMEX>
            

            "Graven
images. Now he'll really never win over the religious right."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Radosh
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pornographers</ENAMEX> in wheelchairs. And if that doesn't sound like kissing up to
someone who's got something on you, I don't know what does."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

             

             

            Click for more
responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            Why is it hard to swallow a plea for tolerance from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>?

            Is it the fondness for executions--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, the border patrol, the oxymoronic phrase
"compassionate conservatism," the sweaty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> memories of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>
administration, that paunch on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo</ENAMEX> ? Is it just
metropolitan prejudice, the Southern thing but with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX> explained
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Ruby</ENAMEX>'s actions as essentially lone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, they're really concerned
with balls. Got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> biting rattle <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX>' heads off, and shooting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. And a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> is a tailor there. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX>, he figured: If I kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that
killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>'ll go wheeeew! What balls he had! See, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> at the end saved everybody. And they'll kiss him and hug him and lift him
on high." But I just can't believe they'll enjoy his traditions in their homes
or share him with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mesquite Melting</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> embraced the
well-known cultural diversity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. "We should be proud of our various
heritages," he said.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stars</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX> Extra
            

            Eager to counter their mean-spirited geriatric
image, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> wanted its response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX>
to be delivered by bright, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party stalwarts</ENAMEX>, but instead ... well, make up
your own joke. And while you're at it, let's meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> rating.

               Made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">50 Most Beautiful People</ENAMEX>" list.

               Has seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braveheart</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unembarrassed</ENAMEX> to hold goofy historical views. "As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Largent</ENAMEX>
reminded us during the Congressional debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOMA</ENAMEX> [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense of Marriage</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>], no society that embraces homosexuality has ever survived."-- Breakpoint With
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Colson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Perspective</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> and Trends
               

               Has a proud heritage of union busting. "As a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>,
he'd been physically threatened by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> for refusing to join a
strike."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Rees</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX>
               

               Once faced down a pudgy, middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. "In a firm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>, he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, 'I've been in smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> with bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and I
can't be intimidated.' "--lovesick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Rees</ENAMEX>, ibid.

               Is pleased with traditional male incompetence. "Shares a dingy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>
townhouse with (fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wamp</ENAMEX> and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coburn</ENAMEX>. 'We haven't cooked a single meal in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>,' says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Largent</ENAMEX>."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fields-Meyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX>
               

               Believes God plans <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> rosters. "In a speech following his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> induction
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pro Football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>, he thanked 'my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savior</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>.' "--ibid.

               Is not a wild-eyed, right-wing, radical conservative fruitcake. " 'They
would love to tag me as a wild-eyed, right-wing, radical conservative
fruitcake,' he says, smiling. 'But that's not me. I'm not weird; I'm normal.'
"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Henneberger</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
               

            

            
               Race
Results
            

            Top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>: The little
brown ones. (And yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX>'s editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> persists in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obstinacy</ENAMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
