
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintometer</ENAMEX>:
            

            

               1/22/99 Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Bumpers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, wows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> with
his closing argument in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> groan at anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">televangelist Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>'s admission that the battle to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
"over." Buoyed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impressive poll numbers following his widely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acclaimed State of the Union</ENAMEX> address, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> press <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
to scrap their plans for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. Chance of removal from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> .

            

               For the complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintometer</ENAMEX> and links to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's Flytrap
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">coverage,</ENAMEX> click .
            

            
A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Salinas</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX>, of ordering a murder and sentenced him to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> in jail. It's the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has punished a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> of a powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> for a major crime. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) This proves <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s judicial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is finally becoming honest and independent. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Honest? There was no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>, no interrogation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> in court, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> admitted there was
no "direct proof." The supposed evidence was hearsay from biased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX> had been held in harsh confinement without conviction for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> previously assigned to the case had tried to plant a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX>' property to frame him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) That's OK, they framed a guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/22/99</NUMEX>)
            

            

               C
               onservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> ridiculed "compassionate conservative" rhetoric, "mushy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX>,"
"mealy-mouthed rhetoric and poll-tested clichés." Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "compassionate conservatism" was full of "weasel words."
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> called himself a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>," unlike
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> derby's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> also noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bushes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doles</ENAMEX> had lost
the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> presidential elections. The rebuttals from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) He's not mushy, he's conservative. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The attacks show he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to beat.
(For more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPAC</ENAMEX> meeting, click .) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/22/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
Basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> opened a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>-trading session . Having lost
nearly half the season to a labor standoff, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> is compressing the trading
and signing period in order to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> quickly. This has produced a
mad scramble for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> over a period of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> rather than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, with stars
hopping from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to the next. The big stories: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retirement</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> are dissolving. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scottie Pippen</ENAMEX> has jumped to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX> threatened to retire, then said he would play only for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Knicks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Lakers</ENAMEX>, both of which said they didn't want
him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star forward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio McDyess</ENAMEX>, who had been traded from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, decided to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, then got cold feet amid rumors that he
might go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golden State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latrell Sprewell</ENAMEX>, who had
choked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, was traded to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. The cynical spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knicks</ENAMEX> won't
tolerate a violent old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>), but a violent young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprewell</ENAMEX>)
is OK. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/22/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> delivered his 
                  State of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> message . His proposals
included using the federal surplus to bolster <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, raising the
minimum wage, and suing tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> noted congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' tepid reactions and carried obligatory references to the "surreal"
juxtaposition of the widely acclaimed speech with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s embarrassing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
trial earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> oohed and aahed over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s rhetorical
prowess. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> played up remarks from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">televangelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>, who said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "hit a home run" and "won" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> contest and that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> "might as well dismiss this impeachment hearing and get on with
something else, because it's over as far as I'm concerned." Political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>
praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech because it offered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX> to everyone. Policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> criticized it for the same reason. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/21/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> proposed big changes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> . He proposed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) to
devote <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> of the federal surplus to shore up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) to
invest up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of the transferred funds in stocks; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) to spend
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">another 11 percent</NUMEX> of the surplus to set up voluntary 401(k)-style "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Universal</ENAMEX>
Savings Accounts." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> applauded the first idea but
shot down the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, on the grounds that making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> a shareholder
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would create dangerous conflicts of interest both ways. Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">criticisms: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is using the surplus to avoid proposing benefit cuts,
which will eventually be necessary. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The stock investment idea is
nationalization in disguise. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>,
should get to choose their investments. Pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rebuttals: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers</ENAMEX> would
squander their money if they chose the investments. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) By devoting the surplus
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is keeping congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
from squandering the money on tax cuts and spending, respectively.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/21/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX> for the leading challenger to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> were broken into twice in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burglars</ENAMEX> targeted disks and files relating to the campaign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> reported break-ins at their homes, in addition to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> previous such
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">break-ins.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> press is calling it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barakgate</ENAMEX>, a play on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. In
this analogy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud Party</ENAMEX> have denied involvement, condemned the break-ins, and
threatened to sue those who imply that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud</ENAMEX> is responsible.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/21/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
A new study
indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> doesn't prevent colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> . The study followed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) There goes the latest faddish cancer
prevention theory. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The study is flawed because it didn't include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The
study is flawed because it assumes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> correctly recalled their
dietary habits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Even if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> doesn't prevent colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, it does prevent
other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/21/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
crisis erupted again. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> massacred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> who supervises the
international peace monitors in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> of the massacre, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> denied responsibility (claiming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
were rebel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>) and ordered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> refused to let a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to
investigate the massacre. Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, in defiance of a cease-fire and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> warnings, shelled the area around the massacre site. When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">generals</ENAMEX> tried to schedule a meeting to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to stop the assaults, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> was too busy
to see them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editorialists</ENAMEX> agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is a treacherous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butcher</ENAMEX>, but
nobody knows how to stop him without a major bombing campaign, for which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> lack the stomach. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> will meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Broncos</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> upset
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-27</TIMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>' kicker, who hadn't missed a
kick in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">122</NUMEX> consecutive attempts, botched a field goal with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX>
remaining; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> drove back down the field for the tying touchdown in
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">closing seconds</TIMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX> drove for the winning field goal in
sudden-death overtime. In the other bracket, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> beat the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>. The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> will be a grudge match between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Elway</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Reeves</ENAMEX>, who now coaches the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) No, it'll be a grudge match between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reeves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
Shanahan, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reeves</ENAMEX> fired as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>' offensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> for
"insubordination." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcons</ENAMEX>, who have stunk perennially, are football's
best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella</ENAMEX> story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
The American
Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> fired the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> for publishing a study
about oral sex. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> study says <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59 percent</NUMEX> of a sample of college
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> think oral sex doesn't constitute "having sex." This coincides
conveniently with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s view. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who fired the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> accused him of "interjecting [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>] into a major political
debate" by "publishing that article in the middle of the congressional
proceedings" in order "to extract political leverage." The spins: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
published the study to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX> fired the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> to mollify
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who control legislation on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> payments
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Publishing an oral sex article during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trial is
sensationalism. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Actually, it's standard journalistic practice.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware</ENAMEX> lawyer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Capano</ENAMEX> was convicted of murdering his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> . He is a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief counsel</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>; she was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>. The trial had
transfixed the state and attracted national attention for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. Capano
claimed he had dumped the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> after his other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> accidentally
shot her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> didn't buy it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capano</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> called the case "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Jr.</ENAMEX>,
but with the opposite verdict." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/19/99</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
