
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI Envy</ENAMEX>

            The No. 1 best seller in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Greatest Generation</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> news anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX>. The most acclaimed and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> highest grossing film of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> (just
behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> ) was Saving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> . Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s film is fiction and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX>'s book is something akin to oral
history, they have in common a fashionable theme: the nobility of those who
served in the armed forces during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> and, by extension, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of
that age in general.

            You might describe this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> envy. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brokaw</ENAMEX> (born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> (born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>)
evince a powerful sense of nostalgia for the world of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>. As his
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> suggests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX> makes an explicit case for the superiority of the World
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War II</ENAMEX> generation. In an introduction to the interview-profiles that make up
his book, he repeats a claim he first made on television when he was swept up
by the emotion of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-Day in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>: "This is
the greatest generation any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> has produced."

            The corollary of this reverence is an often
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underarticulated</ENAMEX> feeling of generational self-loathing. Echoing through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX>'s book, and to a lesser extent through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s movie, is an implicit
comparison to the softer and more selfish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> that followed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX>,
another boomer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>, often drew this contrast during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>, which he described as "a choice between
experience and callowness, between sacrifice and self-indulgence, between the
most heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX> and the most coddled." Boomer
self-disgust has also been making itself felt in the impeachment battle. Many
of those who want to remove the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> are conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> who believe
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> symbolizes a generation raised amid postwar prosperity
according to the principles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX>, one that lacks the moral fiber of
those who experienced the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX> and fought in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            Were they the greatest
generation that ever lived? Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s generational neuroses don't
necessarily prove Brokaw wrong. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX> position is badly flawed, not
because of the instinct that motivates it but because of a romanticizing
tendency that eclipses all logic and evidence. The notion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX> were
somehow better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than those born after them remains, like most facile
generalizations about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, a matter of prejudice, not analysis.

            Let's look at a few of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX>'s overreaching assertions. In
his introduction, he writes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX>, "They stayed true to their values of
personal responsibility, duty, honor, and faith." That sounds plausible--where
have you gone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe DiMaggio</ENAMEX>? But consider just one of those attributes:
"faith." Putting aside the question of whether more faith is a good thing, was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI generation</ENAMEX> really more religious than others? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX> doesn't offer any
support for this claim, and one might well make the opposite case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> has probably become more religious as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> have become the dominant
demographic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 10 percent</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now say they belong to churches
than did so in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX> predominated.

            Almost all the traits
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brokaw</ENAMEX> attributes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX> are subject to similar demurrals. "That's another
legacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> generation, the strong commitment to family values
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brokaw</ENAMEX> writes in another characteristic passage. It's true that
returning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> didn't get divorced in large numbers. But that doesn't prove
that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had a deeper commitment to family values. It
simply testifies to the legal and social reality they inherited--it was hard to
get divorced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s and '50s</TIMEX>. Who changed that reality? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX> did,
because they found the virtual prohibition on divorce an intolerable
restriction on their freedom. As divorces became more readily available, GIs
had them too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> who inherited the divorce laws the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
generation loosened have in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> begun to contemplate tightening them
again.

            I don't mean to imply that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX>'s book is all drivel. It
includes a number of moving stories about wartime heroism that can be
appreciated without reference to its argument, which is pretty much
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superfluous</ENAMEX>. But what's missing from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX>'s book--as from most oral
history--is any hint of analytical rigor. Aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life that Brokaw
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deplores</ENAMEX>, such as segregation and McCarthyism, are viewed as part of the
wallpaper. It was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI generation</ENAMEX> that rounded up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese Americans</ENAMEX> and
put them into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. That was merely "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> racism." But when it came to the
good that happened on their watch, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX> gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX> themselves full credit.
"They came to understand the need for federal civil rights legislation," he
writes. "They gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Medicare</ENAMEX>." Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> did give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. But others, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, voted against it. Let's not forget that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe McCarthy</ENAMEX> also served in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.

            Brokaw repeats most of
the other familiar clichés: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> know the value of a dollar,
they never boast, and they're reluctant to talk about their wartime
experiences. I'm tempted to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brokaw</ENAMEX> never met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Stanley</ENAMEX>. Of
course, it's true that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II-</ENAMEX>era <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vets</ENAMEX> who aren't
inclined to relive the battlefield horrors they experienced. But this may have
less to do with the unique stoicism of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> than with the natural
inclination everyone has to repress traumatic experiences. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vets</ENAMEX> have
been tempted to make more of a meal of their experiences, it's partly due to
the fact that those experiences weren't widely shared. The therapeutic culture
of the present era also probably plays a role, teaching us that it's not
healthy to keep one's pain bottled up inside. But who created that therapeutic
culture? You could argue, once again, that it was a bequest from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI generation</ENAMEX>, who introduced psychiatry and psychoanalysis into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
life.

            What many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs Brokaw</ENAMEX> interviews say explicitly is
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> lack the moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> they themselves had. "They faced
great odds and a late start, but they did not protest ," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brokaw</ENAMEX> writes of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX>, casting another aspersion at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX> generation (italics <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>).
But at the risk of stating the obvious, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> was not like <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The
question <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of draft age faced after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> was whether they would serve
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in an unambiguously good cause. The challenge faced by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> was morally more complex: How do you serve your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> when
it is engaged in a morally dubious cause (a cause the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as a whole--not
just a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>--came to conclude was a mistake)? The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>
generation also had little choice. Everyone was needed in the war effort, and
there were few opportunities to dodge the draft. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>, the
military needed only a small percentage of those who were eligible, and there
were many options for evasion, legal and illegal. Some served and didn't
protest. Others protested and didn't serve. Some, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>, served and then protested. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, there is no obvious answer to who
answered this quandary in the best way. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> envy felt by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> seems in part a longing for the clearer moral imperative of
another time.

            There are, to be sure,
pivotal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generational</ENAMEX> experiences. No one would deny that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> molded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> shaped another. But
attempts to explain history in terms of common traits already possessed by the
peer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that confronted these events are seldom illuminating. Just as we
cannot know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> would have responded to the moral challenge of
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, we cannot know how the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> generation would have
responded to the different moral challenge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. For that matter, we
can't compare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIs</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athenians of Pericles</ENAMEX>' time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florentines of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michelangelo's</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s. To call one generation
the "greatest" doesn't say anything meaningful about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>. It does,
however, reveal something of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> finds lacking in his own.

         
      
   
