
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Entertainment</ENAMEX>). Pans for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Lumet</ENAMEX>'s remake of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cassavetes</ENAMEX> film about a tough
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moll</ENAMEX> whose heart gets melted by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngster</ENAMEX> who falls into her charge: "Easily
qualifies as the most tired, unexciting mob movie in recent history" (Godfrey
Cheshire, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Variety</ENAMEX> ). Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> as the title character, played
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gena Rowlands</ENAMEX> in the original, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX> says: "It's not so much a bad
performance as an unnecessary <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Anyone who has seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassavetes</ENAMEX>' film can
imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lumet's</ENAMEX> and save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> bucks" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawrence Van</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gelder</ENAMEX> is alone in support, calling it "smoother, funnier, more suspenseful and
more endearing" than the first film ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (Compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowlands</ENAMEX>'
almost tasteful suit in the poster for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> film with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>'s racy bustier in the current
version.)

            
               
                  Playing by
Heart
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
calls this "a likably sappy romantic comedy that suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Altman</ENAMEX>'s
Short Cuts dipped in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX>." The huge, star-studded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> (Gena
Rowlands, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Burstyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Stewart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX>) pairs off into happy and
unhappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>. The surfeit of mildly interesting plots surrounding each duo
results in a film that is "the cinematic answer to one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> where
you pig out on canapés" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). The highlight of
the film: a wonderful performance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelina Jolie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Voight</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>) as
a tough club <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who falls in love with a blue-haired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Phillippe</ENAMEX>. (Find out
more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connery</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CelebSite</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  Another Day
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimark Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie Griffith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Woods</ENAMEX>
play a drug-addled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> who adopt a pair of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>-in-training while on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>-trip-cum-crime-spree in a sort of '90s version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> like this better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Clark</ENAMEX>'s first film, the
teen shocker <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX>' performance is called "scene stealing"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Overall, though, reviews are so-so. On the
negative side, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say it "rolls in sleaze and squalor like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mangy dog</ENAMEX> on
steaming roadkill" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Dreher</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ). On the positive
side, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> for the way he manages to create "bad times
with a wicked way of looking good" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> site is packed with video stills from the film; find out more
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Clark</ENAMEX> at alt.culture.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  Reporting
Live
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley Stahl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stahl</ENAMEX>'s account of the backroom scrapping and hard work it took for her to get
taken seriously in the old boys' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> of network news in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s and '80s</TIMEX>.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Yardley</ENAMEX>, complain
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stahl "</ENAMEX>pulls her punches" and spends too much time on anecdotes about past
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> and too little on exactly what it took for her to get where she is.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Cloud</ENAMEX> writes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Journalism Review</ENAMEX> that the book
lacks deep analysis: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stahl</ENAMEX> "never even seems to wonder if perhaps the
celebrityhood, egos, careerism, and inflated salaries of on-air journalists
such as herself might have contributed to the decline" of network news, which
she bemoans. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Toner</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> is less
critical: "What shines through this memoir is how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stahl</ENAMEX> loved the work."
(Check out this photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stahl</ENAMEX>, which aptly illustrates the trouble she details
in finding the right hairstyle.)

            

               
                  Face-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Tarloff</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX>). This book gets a
few nice reviews--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn See</ENAMEX> calls it an "excellent <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel" in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> --but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are interested in only in terms of the
insider scoop it promises. This Primary Colors -type story of a president
who has an affair with a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> was written by a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">speechwriter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarloff</ENAMEX>'s rendering of political power dynamics:
"What makes the novel riveting is its almost anthropological description of the
ebb and flow of power and status in official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Overall, though, the dish is more appealing than the prose. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX>
an excerpt here.)

            
               
                  Miss
Nobody
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomek Tryzna</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> agree that this is a
"fearlessly ambitious debut novel" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Hall</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ), but some find that stylistically it doesn't live up to its own
best intentions. The glimpse it gives into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">manic</TIMEX> highs and lows of female
adolescent friendship as seen through a tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the
twilight of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> is remarkably vivid--full of symbolism, magic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">realism</ENAMEX>, and fairy-tale qualities--but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> call the book as a whole
a near miss. Some blame a shaky translation from the original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>; others
say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s use of so many varying literary devices and styles squelches
the heart of the novel: "Only a spark of life survives its mannerisms" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Eder, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> here.)

            

               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Varsity Blues</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- At First Sight</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- In Dreams</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duane</ENAMEX>'s Depressed , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry McMurtry</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intuitionist</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colson Whitehead</ENAMEX>;

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- Fosse: A Celebration in Song and Dance</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadhurst Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  Affliction ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hi-Lo Country</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Haunted Wood: Soviet Espionage in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> Era , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Weinstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Vassiliev</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --Note <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Found in a Bottle: My Life</ENAMEX> as a Drinker , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Cheever</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glamorama</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bret Easton Ellis</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Action</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Thin Red Line</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Down in the 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hurlyburly</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie -- Theory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flight</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Careless Love: The Unmaking of Elvis</ENAMEX>
Presley , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Guralnick</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katchor</ENAMEX>.

            

             

            

               
                  Movie--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patch Adams</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Faculty</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Movie
                  --Stepmom ;

               
                  Movie
                  --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mighty Joe Young</ENAMEX> ;

               
                  Book--
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hundred Dollar Holiday</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKibben</ENAMEX>;

               
                  Book
                  --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vintner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luck</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Knox</ENAMEX>.

            

         
      
   
