
   
   
      
         
             Win, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Place, and No</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Loosemore</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS SportsLine</ENAMEX>'s figure skating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> , has a mission.
She wants to overturn the sport's new scoring system.

            The traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> came under fire after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Flip-Flop</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> Championships. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s
free-skating event, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> had skated, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> places
were held by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexei Urmanov</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viacheslav Zagorodniuk</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philippe Candeloro</ENAMEX>, in
that order. The final <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrejs Vlascenko</ENAMEX>, placed dead last--but in
the process he managed to bump Candeloro up to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place, denying
Zagorodniuk a silver medal.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Loosemore</ENAMEX>'s
explanation of how the old scoring system worked, and how it caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Flip-Flop,</ENAMEX> click here .)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Skating Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottavio Cinquanta</ENAMEX>
decreed after the championship that the scoring system must be revised to
prevent flip-flops. When the new system was announced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1998</TIMEX>, Cinquanta
rejoiced that the problem was solved, so that henceforth "if you are in front
of me, you will remain in front of me."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loosemore</ENAMEX> has raised
several cogent objections to the new system. First, it is more complicated than
the old system. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinquanta</ENAMEX>, it won't stop flip-flops. In
fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loosemore</ENAMEX>'s computer simulations suggest that it will make flip-flops
more common, not less.

            What should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISU</ENAMEX> do? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist Kenneth Arrow</ENAMEX> hacked this
problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five decades ago</TIMEX> with his "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow Impossibility Theorem</ENAMEX>," which proves
that no reasonable scoring system can preclude flip-flops. (The word
"reasonable" incorporates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISU</ENAMEX>'s commitment to basing final outcomes only on
the order in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have ranked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> rather than on their
explicit numerical scores.)

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX> was laying
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> for his future <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX>, he was concerned not with ranking
figure skaters but with ranking social priorities. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Stob</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin College</ENAMEX> points out that the problems are identical. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> may
disagree about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zagorodniuk</ENAMEX> is better than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candeloro</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX> may
disagree about whether a Star Wars defense system is better than a tax cut. In
order to name winners, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISU</ENAMEX> needs a scoring system to amalgamate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>'
opinions into a single ranking. In order to take political action, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> needs a social choice mechanism to amalgamate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' many preferences
into a single list of priorities.

            It might appear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> can afford more
ambiguity than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISU</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can get away with cheerfully
endorsing multiple conflicting goals and declaring them all "top priorities,"
whereas at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISU</ENAMEX> must declare who gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, who gets
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>, and who gets the bronze. But the fact is that at the end of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, political decisions do get made, as surely as skating medalists get
chosen. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> either cuts taxes or it doesn't. Although the political
process is far more complex than anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISU</ENAMEX> might devise, the decisions
it arrives at are just as unambiguous.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX> set forth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> desiderata for any social choice
mechanism. First, unanimity, when it occurs, should be respected. If all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> rate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zagorodniuk</ENAMEX> ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candeloro</ENAMEX>, then Zagorodniuk should come in
ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candeloro</ENAMEX>. If <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, then
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> should not be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. This criterion is the easy one. I doubt that any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sport</ENAMEX>, or any polity, has ever violated it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> dictum is
that there should be no flip-flops. If A ranks ahead of B, then the entry of a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, C, should not overturn that ranking. Simple majority voting,
for example, notoriously violates the no-flip-flop criterion. It's easy to
imagine an election where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is initially ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, but a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> party
entry by, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>, pushes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. This can happen
even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> runs a distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, as long as he takes more votes from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> than from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX>'s goal was to eliminate such anomalies with a
more sophisticated voting system.

            With a bit of elementary mathematics and a lot of keen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX> was forced to a sobering conclusion: If a "reasonable" voting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is one that respects unanimity and precludes flip-flops, then there
are no reasonable voting systems, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exception--the system that
picks <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> and makes him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>.

            In figure skating, that
means the only system that could satisfy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinquanta</ENAMEX> is a system with only one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. (Actually, you could have as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> as you wanted, as long as you
ignored all but one of them.) In politics, it means that if you can't tolerate
flip-flops, you'd better start getting comfortable with absolute
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictatorship</ENAMEX>.

            Is there any way around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX>'s dire conclusion? Well, his
proof does leave one loophole. If the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> is literally infinite,
then the conclusion can be overturned. In that case, there are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nondictatorial</ENAMEX> voting systems that both respect unanimity and eliminate
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">flip-flops.</ENAMEX> However (and this can be proved mathematically), although such
systems exist, none of them can be explicitly described. This observation seems
unlikely to be applicable either to figure skating or to constitutional
government.

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenue</ENAMEX> is to
observe that although every reasonable system allows flip-flops, some allow
more flip-flops than others--and we can try to design a system that allows as
few as possible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loosemore</ENAMEX> argues that the old scoring system is superior in
this respect, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinquanta</ENAMEX> asserts the opposite. I haven't studied the issue
closely enough to take a firm stand but, based on what I've seen, my money is
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loosemore</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> approach is to accept flip-flops as part of life
and get on with designing a voting system that meets other reasonable
criteria. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get excited about this kind of project tend to get
carried away. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Mathematical Society</ENAMEX> wanted to elect a
slate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> from a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. The rules for counting
ballots filled--in the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>--"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pages of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">definitions</ENAMEX>, rules, interpretations, and examples." Having supplied members
with a summary of those rules, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> felt compelled to append this
note: "Please do NOT correspond with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> about the ambiguities that are
unresolved in the above abbreviated description. Instead, refer to Appendices
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV and V</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> pages of rules appear to leave no ambiguities."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loosemore</ENAMEX> might not like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinquanta</ENAMEX>'s new scoring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, but she can be thankful that it wasn't designed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mathematical Society</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
