
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">174</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">&quot;Odd Lott&quot</ENAMEX>;

            
               You be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decorator</ENAMEX>.
            

            

               In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> keynote speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> said: "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> stand for the right principles and the right philosophy.
Let's take it in the right direction and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>." Describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
            

             

            by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to e-mail your answer to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 173</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Woon River":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woonasquatucket River</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>, moved into the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> slot, behind
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic River</ENAMEX>, signs went up along its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> reading: "Peligro!
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Los Peces</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Este Rio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">No Se Deben Comer</ENAMEX>."
            

            

               Loosely translated, what would that be in idiomatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>?
            

            "Ice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cube</ENAMEX>! Get back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> because a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-eating snake lurks in these
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rogers</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Danger</ENAMEX>! Vaguely racist jokes based on a limited knowledge of high-school
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> ahead."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cass</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Pellegrino! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pescis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Williams</ENAMEX> won't come unless they get
some!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Migrating <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>! You're going the wrong way."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Pelicans! The feces in this river are not safe to eat."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
Levy
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Danger</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fish</ENAMEX> are not working up to their full potential."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Attention! If you can read this, you're too <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>. Paid for by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Singer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer.)

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Welcome</ENAMEX>! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> invites you to enjoy fishing and swimming here!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
Bitterman
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alas</ENAMEX>!
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> in this river are impotent."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Smith</ENAMEX>
            

            "Drink
this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, but we can't promise that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX> will represent you in
court."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Garfunkel</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> responses.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up
            

            When someone makes a
movie about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woonasquatucket</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX>, call my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>), he'll have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> riverine tradition to draw on. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart of Darkness</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The African</ENAMEX>
Queen , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deliverance</ENAMEX> --each is a kind of flooded road movie. There are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of them, if memory serves, and I can assure you that it doesn't. In
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sissy Spacek</ENAMEX> struggle to save their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> from
flooding caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild River</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX> rats out
his hillbilly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Valley Authority</ENAMEX>. River of No
Return is the one where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Mitchum</ENAMEX> escapes savage cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> by
floating down a river on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX>. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rivers of Death, Grass</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tears</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Return</ENAMEX>. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rios Bravo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conchos, Grande</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lobo</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita</ENAMEX>--this last featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costello</ENAMEX>, and singing cowboy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX>. That's a
memory I'm sure of. What I'm less sure of is this: When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX> turned
down the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> clearly wanted, why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">would Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>
risk her life to row him through the rapids?

            
               Aquatic
Answer
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Danger</ENAMEX>! River <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fish Are Not Safe To Eat</ENAMEX>!"

            The Woonasquatucket
trails only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Passaic</ENAMEX> for dioxin in its sediment. Informed of the problem,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Vanderslice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health</ENAMEX>, swiftly
ordered an interagency urban rivers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to post the bilingual signs, put on a
slide show, and hand out brochures. The source of the dioxin is unclear. Legal
action is pending. Swimming is discouraged.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Division</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            A few more thoughts on
why we hate what we hate.

            
               The
Problem
            

            "I detect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things. First, a mild feeling of envy
along with irritation, as if someone had noticed something one can get away
with that I hadn't thought of. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cellulites</ENAMEX> seem to be waving some part
of their good fortune in my face.

            "Add these two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impressions</ENAMEX> together and you find the missing element that explains my own
irritation: the public display of advantage. Maybe that's why listening to a
cellulite strikes me as identical to watching the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
commercials as they breeze through the world in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX>, or endlessly amuse
each other in the back seat of a convertible on their way to THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIFE</ENAMEX> YOU WILL
NEVER HAVE. All this shall pass when there are so many cell phones that no one
is remotely likely to confuse their use with a ticket to heaven. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veblen</ENAMEX> remains
a prophet, no?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Potter</ENAMEX>
            

            
               The Solution
            

            For nature's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darwinian</ENAMEX>
response to the mobile phone blight, try <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smn</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">co.jp/keyword/0158k01e.</ENAMEX>html, courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kate Wing</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submissions</ENAMEX> will become the property of 
               
                  Slate
               

               and will be published at 
               
                  Slate
               
               's
discretion. 
               
                  Slate
                
               may publish your name on its
site in connection with your submission .

         
      
   
