
   
   
      
         
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Economist</ENAMEX>
                
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 30</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover editorial predicts the imminent collapse
of--guess what?--massively overvalued Internet stocks. That crash, if it
doesn't drag the whole stock market down, could be useful for the economy
because it will "restore sanity" to the venture capital industry. Some of the
big Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> such as Yahoo! and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX> may survive, but the
Dollar.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coms</ENAMEX> and Buy.coms of the world are surely doomed. ... An article
identifies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> reasons that company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are rich yet miserable: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
They're working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer hours</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Flatter management structures diminish the
sweet sense of victory that used to come from reaching the top. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Job</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paranoia: Execs</ENAMEX> get fired more often <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outside</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> are
increasingly siphoning power from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>' "fiefdoms." ... An article
finds "feminism" in an unexpected place: primitive, forest-dwelling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are deliberately promiscuous in order to win more male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protectors</ENAMEX> for
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>, not knowing if they're the biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or not, assume
that they are.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>
                
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>
            

            ( posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29, 1999</TIMEX> )

            The cover story argues
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> and evangelicals are to blame for the increasingly blurry line
between private morality and public life. Both these newly enfranchised groups
emphasize conversion and consciousness-raising, and insist that the personal is
political. ... The editorial deplores the resignation of a white
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, mayoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> for uttering the word "niggardly" in a financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> meeting. The word has no etymological connection to the racial slur,
but new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Williams</ENAMEX> yielded to the mere appearance of bias instead
of defending his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>. ... A piece accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
DeLay of tap-dancing around the truth in a now-settled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> lawsuit. Accused of
using a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to carry his campaign loans, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> had trouble
affirming or denying his connection to the business, answering with
Clintonesque equivocations.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Magazine
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The cover story examines
the decline and fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gambino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in
particular. The wiser of the wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have gone legit; the dumber ones (such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gotti Jr.</ENAMEX>) preside over sagging profits and faltering allegiances.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gotti</ENAMEX> has even tarnished the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppolaesque</ENAMEX> grandeur. The piece mocks his
car (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a minivan</NUMEX>), his attire (mock turtlenecks), and choice of repast
(country-fried steak). ... A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> finds great disparities among the
different bilingual education <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> public school. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> programs provide a fluid, supportive transition to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, for whom bilingual education was originally designed,
languish in a "well-upholstered trap."... A newbie foreign correspondent
describes his training at "hostile environment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>," where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> learn
to dodge <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> and placate their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kidnappers</ENAMEX>. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> gives
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Murray</ENAMEX> its now-standard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> profile treatment: He's not just a funny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> who makes funny movies. No, he's a fiercely independent artiste with a
secret cerebral side who takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> trips in beat-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>. Just like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Penn</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do the
math on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story details the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s soaring poll numbers and
the various boosts they've given to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>' confidence, his relationships
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and even to donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
calculates the bottom line on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s plan to save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>: It
promises away <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a full 151 percent</NUMEX> of the projected budget surplus, and would
create a shortfall of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.3 trillion</NUMEX>. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> calls Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s nascent presidential campaign strategy "charming" and "insane." In
contrast to the well-oiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> machine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, message, money,
or following. The piece features what is sure to be a major element of any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley run</ENAMEX>: a surfeit of tired sports metaphors. ... 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
cover story says the labor shortage is emboldening and transforming the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Company Man</ENAMEX> has been replaced by a fiercely
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> of "free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>," "new nomads," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">globalists</ENAMEX>," who write
their own job descriptions, schedules, and rules. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 
               suggests that even these bold quasientrepreneurs need to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commiserate</ENAMEX> around the water cooler. It profiles a new kind of office
superstore-cum-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> that sells generic office space to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely telecommuters</ENAMEX>.
... A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> piece describes (and amply illustrates) how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim</ENAMEX> is stimulating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ization</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Competitors</ENAMEX> disdain its lowbrow tone but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> a bad case of circulation
envy.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX>
               
               
                  , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutual</ENAMEX>
Funds issue congratulates the aggressive and chastises those cowed by
short-term fluctuations. Index funds top the lists, while money market accounts
lag behind. ... A piece argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are replacing the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as the primary engine of domestic policy. In contrast to
trial-blinded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are using their newly bulging coffers to
reform education, health care, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. ... The magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recounts Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>'s epistolary romance with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> socialite: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imprisoned</ENAMEX>
after his failed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX> coup, he sent her fervent letters that mixed political
invective with sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nothings</ENAMEX> ("there is a type of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX> that never
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satiates</ENAMEX>").

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            An article says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mongolia</ENAMEX> is clogged with a "glut of raw cashmere": Fresh-off-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">goat</ENAMEX> cashmere
fetches a rock-bottom price worldwide, as supply has skyrocketed (thanks to
capitalism, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mongolia</ENAMEX> has doubled since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>). Since raw
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cashmere</ENAMEX> is sold by weight, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> turn to dirty tricks, like plugging
factory-bound cashmere tufts with heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>. So choose carefully among those
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">thousand</ENAMEX> dollar sweaters dangling in upscale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoHo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. ... A gripping
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> describes why the potential for surgical error is so high. Surgeons are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX>, forced to make split<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-second</TIMEX> choices about conditions they may never have
seen before, and operating on the human body is not a machine-reliant science
such as flying an airplane. Demonizing errors, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> argues, dangerously
hinders constructive discussion about those errors.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
Standard
               
               , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 1999</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> offer their
own diagnosis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. It must be awful, they
argue, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have succeeded in feeding a dubious and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">duplicitous</ENAMEX> defense to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, and the press. ... Two
other stories, however, are premised on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s general success and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contentedness</ENAMEX>. The cover story explains that morality is no longer about a
pre-formed set of abstract values. Instead, moral standards fluctuate like
stocks, rising and falling according to the practical results they yield.
Examples: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> value chastity because it prevents <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, temperance because
it's healthy, and marriage because it produces well-adjusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
... A piece gleefully imagines what will happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
popularity in a future economic downturn. A slump will expose his "disgusting
betrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> principles" and finally cause his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> to jump
ship.

         
      
   
