
   
   
      
         
            How Copper Came a Cropper

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the world was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">astonished</ENAMEX> to hear that a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> of the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barings</ENAMEX>
had lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than a billion dollars</NUMEX> in speculative trading, quite literally
breaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. But when an even bigger financial disaster was revealed last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>--the loss of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $1.8 billion</NUMEX> (the true number is rumored to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion or more</NUMEX>) in the copper market by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo Corp.</ENAMEX>--the
story quickly faded from the front pages. "Oh well, just another rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>,"
was the general reaction.

            Thanks largely to
investigative reporting by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> , however, it has become
clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasuo Hamanaka</ENAMEX>, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Leeson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barings</ENAMEX>, was not a poorly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supervised</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> using his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s money to gamble on unpredictable
markets. On the contrary, there is little question that he was, in fact,
implementing a deliberate corporate strategy of "cornering" the world copper
market--a strategy that worked, yielding huge profits, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hubris</ENAMEX> brought him down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>; but it is his initial success, not his
eventual failure, that is the really disturbing part of the tale.

            To
understand what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX> was up to, you don't need to know many details about
the copper market. The essential facts about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> (and many other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commodities</ENAMEX>) are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) It is subject to wide fluctuations in the balance between
supply and demand, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) It can be stored, so that production need not be
consumed at once. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> facts mean that a certain amount of speculation is
a normal and necessary part of the way the market works: It is inevitable and
desirable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should try to buy low and sell high, building up
inventories when the price is perceived to be unusually low and running those
inventories down when the price seems to be especially high.

            So far so good. But a long time ago somebody--I wouldn't be
surprised if it were a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenician</ENAMEX> tin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">merchant</ENAMEX> in the first millennium
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B.C.</ENAMEX>--realized that a clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with sufficiently deep pockets could basically
hold such a market up for ransom. The details are often mind-numbingly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>,
but the principle is simple. Buy up a large part of the supply of whatever
commodity you are trying to corner--it doesn't really matter whether you
actually take claim to the stuff itself or buy up "futures," which are nothing
but promises to deliver the stuff on a specified date--then deliberately keep
some--not all--of what you have bought off the market, to sell later. What you
have now done, if you have pulled it off, is created an artificial shortage
that sends prices soaring, allowing you to make big profits on the stuff you do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX>. You may be obliged to take some loss on the supplies you have withheld
from the market, selling them later at lower prices, but if you do it right,
this loss will be far smaller than your gain from higher current prices.

            It's nice
work if you can get it; there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> important hitches. First, you must
be able to operate on a sufficiently large scale. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the strategy only
works if not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize what is going on--otherwise nobody will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> to you in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place unless you offer a price so high that the game
no longer pays. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, this kind of thing is, for obvious reasons, quite
illegal. (The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Phoenician</ENAMEX> who tried it probably got very rich; the second
got sacrificed to Moloch.)

            
The amazing thing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX> managed to
overcome all these hitches. The world copper market is immense; nonetheless, a
single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>, apparently, was able and willing to dominate that market. You
might have thought that the kind of secrecy required for such a massive market
manipulation was impossible in the modern information age--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamanaka</ENAMEX> pulled
it off, partly by working through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediaries</ENAMEX>, but mainly through a
covert alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> (some of them state-owned). And as for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> ... well, what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>?

            For that
is the disturbing part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX> story. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamanaka</ENAMEX> had really been
nothing more than an employee run wild, one could not really fault regulators
for failing to rein him in; that would have been his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s job. But he
wasn't; he was, in effect, engaged in a price-fixing conspiracy on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">employer</ENAMEX>'s behalf. And while it may not have been obvious what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX> was up
to early in the game, the role of "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copper</ENAMEX>" and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in manipulating
prices has apparently been common knowledge for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> among everyone familiar
with the copper market. Indeed, copper futures have been the object of massive
speculative selling by the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX>, precisely because informed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamanaka</ENAMEX> was keeping the price at artificially high
levels, and that it would eventually plunge. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX>, however, gave up a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> too soon, apparently intimidated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX>'s seemingly limitless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>.) So why was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamanaka</ENAMEX> allowed to continue?

            The answer may in part be that the global nature of his
activities made it unclear who had responsibility. Should it have been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX> is based there? Should it have been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, home of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Metal Exchange</ENAMEX>? Should it have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, where much of the
copper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX> ended up owning is warehoused? Beyond this confusion over
responsibility, however, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> were inhibited by the
uncritically pro-market ideology of our times. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> nowadays take it as
an article of faith that free markets always take care of themselves--that
there is no need to police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamanaka</ENAMEX>, because the market will
automatically punish their presumption.

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX>'s strategy did
indeed eventually come to grief--but only because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamanaka</ENAMEX> apparently could not
bring himself to face the fact that even the most successful market manipulator
must accept an occasional down along with the ups. Rather than sell some of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> at a loss, he chose to play double or nothing, trying to repeat his
initial success by driving prices ever higher; since a market corner is
necessarily a sometime thing, his unwillingness to let go led to disaster. But
had Hamanaka been a bit more flexible and realistic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX> could have walked
away from the copper market with modest losses offset by enormous, ill-gotten
gains.

            The funny thing about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX> affair is that if you ignore the exotic trimmings--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> names,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> connection--it's a story right out of the robber-baron era, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Gould</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Fisk</ENAMEX>. There has been a worldwide rush to deregulate
financial markets, to bring back the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">good old days of the 19th century</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> were free to make money however they saw fit. Maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sumitomo</ENAMEX>
affair will remind us that not all the profitable things unfettered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
can do with their money are socially productive; maybe it will even remind us
why we regulated financial markets in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

         
      
   
