
   
   
      
         
            Size Does Matter

            If you use the term
"microeconomics" in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> document, the spelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">checker</ENAMEX> will flag it
and suggest "macroeconomics" instead. The spelling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">checker</ENAMEX> has a point. You
see, macroeconomics has gone out of fashion. Not only academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> but
also some of our most influential economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> seem to regard it as bad
manners to talk about recessions and recoveries and how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> might
alleviate the former and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> the latter. Ordinarily reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now
argue that the business cycle is a trivial matter, unworthy of attention when
compared with microeconomic issues like the incentive effects of taxes and
regulation. Trying to do anything about recessions is bad for growth, they say,
and even thinking about the business cycle is a bad thing, because it
distracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from what really matters.

            What is
so peculiar about this attitude, which seems to become more prevalent each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, is that we live in a world in which those old-fashioned macroeconomic
concerns are more pressing than they have been for generations. Not since the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX> have his questions (if not necessarily his answers)
been so relevant. So an occasional reminder that the big things do matter, that
getting microeconomic policy right is no help if you stumble into a depression,
is welcome from any source--even a deficient dictionary.

            To see what I'm talking about, consider a recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> column by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Samuelson</ENAMEX>, in which he seems to dismiss all
macroeconomic analysis--all attempts to understand the behavior of aggregates
such as gross domestic product and the price level--as useless, even malign.
"What we've learned," declares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuelson</ENAMEX>, "is that the little picture is the
big picture." Economic success, he argues, is simply a matter of getting the
incentives right. And he goes on to deride macroeconomics for its "illusion
that it could make the whole system run smoothly almost regardless of how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>'s underlying sectors functioned. ... It's as if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> could run at
breakneck speed even if the engine was corroded and missing some parts."

            One
wonders why the usually judicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuelson</ENAMEX> found it necessary to invent this
straw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Who is supposed to have had that illusion? Even when Keynesian
macroeconomists were at their most hubristic, none of them claimed that
macroeconomic "fine-tuning" could make an economic jalopy into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX>. But
they did claim that even a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX> won't perform very well if you don't give it
enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>--that using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> very efficiently is not much help if the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> is unemployed because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> don't spend enough. And this is not an
abstract point: Just look at the economic storms ravaging quite a lot of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s world.

            
For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s economy has been shrinking
at an alarming pace <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few quarters</TIMEX>. Is this because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> workers
have become lazy or because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> have fallen into disrepair?
Or to take a more extreme case, has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> become a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> less
productive society than it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>? Of course not: Whatever the ultimate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of the crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, the immediate cause of these slumps is a
collapse in that good old-fashioned macroeconomic variable, aggregate
demand.

            I don't
know what provoked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuelson</ENAMEX>'s outburst. But if one of our most well informed
economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> has come to disdain macroeconomics, this may be because he
has been listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> themselves. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macroeconomics</ENAMEX>--and especially that part of macroeconomics that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> itself
with recessions and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depressions</ENAMEX>, in which the economy as a whole is less than
the sum of its parts--has fallen steadily into disfavor within the economics
profession. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">As late as the mid-1970s</TIMEX>, many textbooks still followed the lead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> (no relation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert) Samuelson</ENAMEX>'s classic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX> ,
beginning with the macroeconomics of booms and slumps and turning to
microeconomics only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their second half</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, however, every textbook
(yes, even the one I'm writing) relegates macro to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX>. Even within
the macroeconomics <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, more and more books (like the much-hyped new text by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">N. Gregory Mankiw</ENAMEX>) dwell on "safe" issues like growth and inflation
as long as possible, introducing the question of recessions and what to do
about them almost as a footnote.

            In graduate education the situation has become even more
extreme. While most Ph.D. programs continue to require that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> take a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of macroeconomics, more and more of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> is devoted to long-run
issues, less and less to that part of the subject that might tell you who <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> is and why he might matter. (When I gave an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">honorific</ENAMEX> lecture at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> there told me that their macroeconomics course
did not even mention money until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two weeks</TIMEX>, and never so much as
suggested that monetary policy might have anything to do with business
cycles.)

            The
reasons for this aversion to macroeconomics are a little hard to explain to a
lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. It's not that the business cycle has become less relevant--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> has lately had a smooth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">few years</TIMEX>, but macroeconomics was already in
retreat during the anything but tranquil <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'70s and '80s</TIMEX>. (I remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> famous
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Keynesian</ENAMEX>, challenged during an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '80s</TIMEX> conference to explain how his
model could be reconciled with the savage recession then gripping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, snapping "I'm not interested in the latest residual"--i.e., the latest
statistical blip.) Nor did macroeconomics fail the test of empirical relevance.
Though it is widely believed that events such as the combination of inflation
and unemployment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, or the noninflationary growth from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982 to 1989</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">baffled</ENAMEX> and astounded macroeconomists, this turns out to be another of those
oddly popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> legends--similar to the legend that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
refused to believe in increasing returns. The truth is that stagflation was
predicted as a possibility long before it emerged as a reality and that the
disinflation of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> played out just the way the (old) textbooks said it
should.

            
The real problem with macroeconomics, from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s point of view, is the shakiness of its "microfoundations." Most
economic theorizing is based on the assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> behave
rationally--that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> set prices to maximize their profits, that workers
choose to accept or reject jobs based on a rational calculation of their
interests, and so on. You don't have to believe in the literal truth of this
assumption to recognize how powerful it is as a working hypothesis. But while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macroeconomists</ENAMEX> generally try to put as much rationality into their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> as
they can, --the kind in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> does matter--always depend crucially on
the ad hoc assumption of "sticky prices." In other words, they assume that at
least in the short run, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> do not immediately reduce their prices when
they cannot sell all their production, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> do not immediately accept
lower wages even when they have trouble finding jobs. This assumption
works ; that is, it transforms the otherwise incomprehensible reality of
the business cycle into something that is not only understandable but, to some
extent, controllable. But it makes many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> uncomfortable; it is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic</ENAMEX> case of something that works in practice but not in theory.

            And so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have, more and more, simply avoided the subject; and being human,
have tended to rationalize that avoidance by asserting that the subject isn't
really important anyway.

            The trouble with this evasion is, of course, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macroeconomics</ENAMEX> is important. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Samuelson</ENAMEX> had good reasons for
beginning his textbook with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Keynesian</ENAMEX> analysis. He knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> would not
find microeconomics, with its emphasis on efficiency, interesting unless they
were first convinced that the economy could achieve more or less full
employment, that it need not relapse into depression. He also knew what too
many latter-day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have forgotten: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macroeconomics</ENAMEX> is crucial to the
public credibility of economics as a whole. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analytical</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>-oriented thinking
came to dominate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economics mainly because supernerds like Samuelson
had something useful to say about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>, and their pompous,
windy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> did not. By abandoning macroeconomics the profession not only
leaves the world without guidance it desperately needs; it also risks letting
the fuzzy-minded literati reclaim the ground they so deservedly lost 60 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.

            Of course the little things
matter. But the big things matter too, and if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> try to pretend that
they don't, one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> they are going to get stomped on.

            
               If you didn't stop to
find out why useful business cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> still need to incorporate
"sticky prices," click . And if you missed the article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Samuelson</ENAMEX> on
macroeconomic analysis, click here.
            

         
      
   
