
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Legend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>

            "In a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>'s current troubles with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> grew out of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> seminar that took place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen years ago</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy School of Government</ENAMEX>." So begins an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cassidy</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , titled "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> of an Idea." The idea that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cassidy</ENAMEX> refers to is that of "increasing returns"--which says that goods become
cheaper the more of them you produce (and the closely related idea of "network
externalities," which says that some products, like fax machines, become more
useful the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use them). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassidy</ENAMEX>'s article tells the story of how
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Arthur</ENAMEX> came up with the idea of increasing returns,
held fast to that idea despite the obstinate opposition of mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> and, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> as an academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pariah</ENAMEX>, finally managed to
change the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think about the economy. That story has been told before,
most notably in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Mitchell Waldrop</ENAMEX>'s popular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Complexity: The</ENAMEX>
Emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edge of Order</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chaos</ENAMEX> , and a good story it
certainly is.

            It is also pure fiction. Increasing returns wasn't a new
idea, it wasn't obstinately opposed--and if increasing returns play a larger
role in mainstream economic theory now than they did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
didn't have much to do with that change. Indeed, the spread of the Arthurian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">legend</ENAMEX> is a better story than the legend itself: an object lesson in
journalistic gullibility.

            So what,
you may ask. What could be less interesting than squabbling among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>
over who deserves the credit for some theory? Well, I could say that this bogus
version of intellectual history has metastasized to the point where it may
begin to do real harm--to discredit good economics and to promote dubious
policies. But the real truth is that I'm just pissed off.

            
Let's start with the legend. Here's how it all
began, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldrop</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5, 1979</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Arthur</ENAMEX> wrote in his
notebook a manifesto describing his project to develop a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economics</ENAMEX> based on
increasing returns. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>, he tried to explain it to a
"distinguished international trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX>" from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>, who was baffled. So
were other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">establishment economists</ENAMEX>. Thus began <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the
wilderness. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, he completed his seminal paper, but not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, after
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14 rewrites</TIMEX>, was he able to publish it. "Gradually," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassidy</ENAMEX>, "a number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>"--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Salop</ENAMEX>--"began to take
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>'s conclusions seriously."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
story. Now let's do a reality check, starting with that walk in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. It
is, indeed, truly astonishing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Norman</ENAMEX>, did not
understand what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> was driving at. After all, there is a long tradition of
increasing returns in international trade theory. If nothing else, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
should have been familiar with his own co-authored book, Theory of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Trade</ENAMEX> , which was in galleys at the time. It contained a whole
chapter devoted to increasing returns, based largely on a paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> himself
had written <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years before</TIMEX>. Is it possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> misinterpreted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>'s bafflement--that what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> really couldn't understand was why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
thought he was saying anything new?

            When I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>'s work, probably sometime in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mid-to-late 1980s</ENAMEX>, I thought it didn't tell me anything . His mathematical
models were basically similar to those developed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> by the game
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorist Thomas Schelling</ENAMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> seemed unaware of the conceptual
difficulties that had led <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> not to ignore but to . His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> simply
ignored them. During the course of the 1980s those conceptual difficulties were
partly resolved, leading to a burst of theorizing about increasing returns. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>'s work played no role in that resolution.

            I wasn't
at that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> seminar that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassidy</ENAMEX> describes. I was down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>, finishing with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> a book titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Market Structure</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Increasing Returns, Imperfect Competition</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Economy</ENAMEX> . But it would surprise me if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> were unwilling to
accept the notion of increasing returns, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassidy</ENAMEX> says. After all, at the
time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> economics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Michael Spence</ENAMEX>, who had won
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Medal</ENAMEX> (the highest award of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Economic Association</ENAMEX>)
largely for his work on--you guessed it--increasing returns.

            
EconLit, the database of professional
literature since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, reveals that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>--the moment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waldrop</ENAMEX>'s book claims
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>'s theories about increasing returns began to be
accepted--mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> had published <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 140</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> on the subject.
Salop, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassidy</ENAMEX> presents as an early convert to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>'s ideas, was early indeed. He wrote one of his own best-known papers on
increasing returns in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>, by his own account, even
began to think about the subject.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> is a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, who I think sincerely believes that it happened the way
he tells it. But how can an experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassidy</ENAMEX> be so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credulous</ENAMEX>? Perhaps a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> cannot be expected to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on the ins
and outs of an academic discipline--although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassidy</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>. But even if we accept that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassidy</ENAMEX> doesn't know much
about the discipline he currently covers, what happened to basic journalistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instincts</ENAMEX>?

            Suppose that someone tells you that, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, he made a
fundamental discovery that an entire profession, out of sheer
narrow-mindedness, refused to listen to and prevented him from publishing.
Wouldn't you have at least a slight suspicion that this version of events might
be a bit, well, self-serving--a suspicion strong enough to send you to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> to see whether the facts check out?

            And what
about what we might call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch-Reich</ENAMEX> test (so named for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>'s

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> exposing fabricated quotes in the memoirs of
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>)? Throughout the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Arthur</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">travails</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make the kind of dramatic, pithy remarks that almost never get
uttered in real life. "To admit that increasing returns exist would destroy
economic theory." <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">""</ENAMEX> "We know increasing returns can't exist. Besides, if they
did, we'd have to outlaw them." "Your theory may be theoretically valid, but
there's no evidence of it in the real world." These sound like the kind of
thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> might put at the bottom of a page, under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pronouncements We Doubt Really Got Pronounced</ENAMEX>." And as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>
taught us, when someone tells us that his world is populated by remarkably
eloquent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who always happen to say exactly what makes the storyteller
look good, we are well advised to ask whether that world exists only in his,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">er</ENAMEX>, perceptions.

            
What could have caused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassidy</ENAMEX> to suspend his
critical faculties? Perhaps he has an ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX> to grind--after all, a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months back</TIMEX> he proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> of the future." He argues that the
theory of increasing returns is crucial to the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--which is
true, although even so it is unclear why he couldn't just present the theory
without the dubious intellectual history. Anyway, increasing returns are
equally crucial to the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--as a reason why trying to
break it up would be a bad thing. Perhaps more to the point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassidy</ENAMEX> has made
it clear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> writing that he does not like mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, and he
may have been overly eager to accept a story that puts them in a bad light.

            But this may be looking too
hard for a motive. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waldrop</ENAMEX>'s book came out, I wrote him as politely as I
could, asking exactly how he had managed to come up with his version of events.
He did, to his credit, write back. He explained that while he had become aware
of some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working on increasing returns, trying to put them in would
have pulled his story line out of shape. My guess is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassidy</ENAMEX> reached the
same conclusion. So what we really learn from the legend of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX> is that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> like a good story too much to find out whether it is really
true.

         
      
   
