
   
   
      
         
            Speed Trap

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A couple of years ago</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> had a problem with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>: Whenever he went too
fast--whenever the needle on his speedometer went above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> developed a
dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shimmy</ENAMEX>. So he carefully drove to the repair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, never letting the
needle go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 39</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, after looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, the mechanic declared that
he couldn't fix the shimmy. Moreover, he had found another problem: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">speedometer</ENAMEX> was defective. In fact, when the needle was pointing to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>, the car
was actually going <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX>. And he couldn't fix that problem, either.

            To the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX>'s surprise,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> was pleased with this news. "So what you're telling me is that the
car doesn't shimmy until I go <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">55 miles per hour</NUMEX>. That means I can drive home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles an hour</NUMEX> faster than I drove here!"

            OK, OK, I
made that story up. I have never met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Shepard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in chief of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> , but I'm sure that he would never make that kind of
mistake in ordinary life. It would not be necessary for the mechanic to explain
pedantically that, while it was true that the news about the speedometer
implied that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> could go faster than previously thought, it did not change
the speedometer reading at which the car shimmied.

            But he is apparently not so clearheaded when it comes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the whole "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Economy</ENAMEX>" doctrine--a doctrine relentlessly
espoused by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vociferously</ENAMEX> defended in a
recent signed essay by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> himself--is based on a misunderstanding of the
relationship between measurement and reality that is conceptually identical to
the garbled thinking of the imaginary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> retrieving his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX> doctrine,
sometimes called the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New Economic Paradigm</ENAMEX>, may be summarized as the view that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalization</ENAMEX> and information technology have led to a surge in the
productivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. This, in turn, has produced a sharp increase in
the rate of growth that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy can achieve without running up against
capacity limits. "Forget <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> real growth," urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>. "We're talking <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>, or
even <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>." This increase in the potential growth rate, in turn, is supposed to
explain why the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has managed to drive unemployment to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year</TIMEX>
low without inflation.

            The
conventional view that the economy has a "speed limit" of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 2</NUMEX>-percent to
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5-percent</NUMEX> growth does not come out of thin air. It is based on the real-life
observation that when the output of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy--as measured by real gross
domestic product--is growing rapidly, the unemployment rate falls; when the
output is growing slowly or is shrinking, the unemployment rate rises. Over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 20 years</TIMEX>, the break point--the growth rate at which unemployment neither
rises nor falls--has been <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 2 percent and 2.5 percent</NUMEX>. And this break
point does not seem to have changed much in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>: Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1994</TIMEX>, GDP
has grown at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a 2.7</NUMEX>-percent annual rate, while unemployment has fallen at
a steady rate, implying that the no-change-in-unemployment growth rate is
closer to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent than to 3 percent</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to see a chart that illustrates
the break point.)

            
So what? Don't we want unemployment to
fall? Yes, of course, but the unemployment rate can fall only so far. Obviously
it can't go <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">below zero</NUMEX>; and in reality, the limits to growth are reached long
before the economy gets to that point. Both logic and history tell us that when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are very scarce and jobs very abundant, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> will start bidding
against each other to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, wages will begin rising rapidly, and
real growth will give way to inflation. That means that while the economy can
grow faster than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-point-whatever percent for a while if it starts from a high
rate of unemployment (like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>-percent unemployment rate that prevailed in
late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>), in the long run, that growth rate cannot remain higher than the
rate that keeps unemployment constant. And that is where the infamous "speed
limit" comes from.

            Behind
that speed limit, in turn, lies another bit of arithmetic: The rate of growth
of output, by definition, is the sum of the rate of growth of employment (which
is limited by the size of the potential labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>) and that of productivity,
a k a output per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>.

            Aha! say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>--that's exactly our
point. Productivity growth has accelerated, which means that the old speed
limit has been repealed. It's true, they concede, that official productivity
statistics do not show any dramatic acceleration--in fact, measured
productivity growth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> has been <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1 percent</NUMEX> per year, an
unimpressive performance similar to that of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two previous decades</TIMEX>. (It has
gone up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 2 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>, but this is probably just a
statistical blip.) But they insist that the official statistics miss the
reality, understating true productivity growth because, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> insists, "we
don't know how to measure output in a high-tech service economy."

            He's
probably right about that. What he may not realize is that we really didn't
know how to measure output in a medium-tech industrial economy, either. How
could productivity indexes--which basically measure the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to
produce a given set of goods--properly take account of such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolutionary</ENAMEX> innovations as automobiles, antibiotics, air conditioning, and
long-playing records? Just about every economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> who has looked at the
issue believes that standard measures of productivity have consistently
understated the true improvement in living standards for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least the past 140</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. It's anybody's guess whether unmeasured productivity growth in the last
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> is greater or less than in the past. (My personal guess is that the
hidden improvements are less important than they were in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> and
1960s: For example, direct-dial long-distance calling and television made more
real difference to our lives than the Internet and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DVD</ENAMEX>.)

            
But anyway, that is all beside the point. After
all, what is this number we call "productivity"? It is measured real GDP per
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> --nothing more, nothing less. Suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> is right that we are
understating productivity growth by, say, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>. Since nobody thinks we are
overstating employment growth, he must believe that the official statistics
understate true output growth by exactly the same amount. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> is quite
right that if true productivity growth is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-percent</ENAMEX> measured
rate, and if the labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> is growing at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>, then the economy's true
speed limit is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>. But when the economy is
actually growing at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX>, the statistics will say that it is
growing at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX>--and yet it cannot grow any faster.

            Still,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> thinks that it can. "Perhaps the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> rate of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 12 months</TIMEX> is too
high. ... But the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">to-2</NUMEX> Â<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">½%</NUMEX> speed limit is probably obsolete. In an era of
stronger productivity growth, which may just now be showing up in statistics,
the speed limit is probably <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3% to 3 Â½%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>." In short, now that he knows
(or, anyway, prefers to believe) that the speedometer has been understating his
speed, and that the shimmy therefore doesn't start until he is really
going <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX>, he thinks that he can drive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> as measured using that same
speedometer . Uh-uh.

            But doesn't the happy combination of low unemployment and
low inflation show the payoff from hidden productivity growth? Well, higher
productivity growth would mean lower inflation for any given rate of wage
increase. And if official productivity statistics understate the real rate of
progress by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>, official price statistics also overstate
inflation by exactly the same amount. This is a cheerful thought, but it also
means that invoking covert productivity increases doesn't help explain why even
measured inflation remains quiescent. The low rate of inflation in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy is indeed a surprise: But the puzzle is why wages have not risen
more rapidly despite very tight labor markets, not why prices have remained
stable given very moderate wage increases. And productivity us with that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s essay was pretty
obviously intended as a response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blinder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan Stanley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roach</ENAMEX>, and me--who have recently been critical
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX> doctrine, among other things pointing out (though apparently
to little effect) the dependence of that doctrine on the speedometer fallacy.
It seems clear that he is baffled by the reluctance of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Economists</ENAMEX>" to join
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, and that he can only explain it by their unwillingness to accept the
idea that the world has changed and that their pet theories are no longer
valid. Well, I can't speak for the others, but I have no particular aversion to
admitting that the economy can change and that old rules sometimes don't apply.
In fact, as anyone who makes much of his income from book royalties and
speeches can tell you, the incentives are all the other way: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> would much
rather hear about how everything has changed than about why most of the usual
rules still apply. (And feel-good optimism sells much better than dismal
realism.)

            No, the reason I can't buy
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX> is actually very simple: Despite all the incentives, I
can't bring myself to endorse a doctrine that I know to be just plain dumb.

         
      
   
