
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost Fig Leaf</ENAMEX>

            "You now work from the first
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January to May</TIMEX> just to pay your taxes so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can
satisfy its priorities with the sweat of your brow because they think that what
you would do with your own money would be morally and practically less
admirable than what they would do with it. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Somewhere</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>
couldn't afford to call her granddaughter, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> went without a book, or a
family couldn't afford that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> home because there was just not enough money.
... Why? Because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> took the money to
fund yet another theory, yet another program, and yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>." The
words are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s (actually, they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Halperin</ENAMEX>'s, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> said them in
his acceptance speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>). They are the key to understanding why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolution</ENAMEX>, which seemed so unstoppable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a year ago</TIMEX>, has
stopped.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s speech tried to put
over, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time, the fiction that the federal government takes away your
hard-earned money and spends most of it on things that only social workers
want. Supply-side economics, with its promise that tax cuts would pay for
themselves, may have given <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> the courage to be irresponsible. But
what sold the public on conservatism was the images of vast armies of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> and of welfare queens driving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillacs</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> were able to get away with such stories for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> main reason: They
could always blame their failure to slay Big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who
controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Then they suddenly found themselves in control--and the
fig leaf was gone. Spinmeisters of the right are already saying that this
election was all about tactics--that if only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> were a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campaigner</ENAMEX>, if
only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hadn't shamelessly veered right, if only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> hadn't thrown a
tantrum on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force One</ENAMEX>, the conservative wave would have rolled on. And they
insist that this looming defeat is only a temporary setback. But the truth is
that the political appeal of radical conservatism has always been based on a
fundamentally untrue vision of what the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is and does.

            To get an idea of the gap between conservative mythology
and reality, let's look at the best book published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. It's called
get into the habit of checking it, our politics would be utterly
transformed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX>

               Abstract makes it quite easy to get a realistic picture of where your
tax dollar goes. For example, here is a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> major federal programs. The
number after the colon indicates each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>'s percentage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 1994</TIMEX>
spending:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>:
21.6

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18.9</NUMEX>

            
               Interest on the debt:
13.7

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.7</NUMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.8</NUMEX>

            
               Pensions for federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans</ENAMEX>' benefits:
2.6

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> (mainly
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>, air traffic, etc.) : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6</NUMEX>

            
               Unemployment
insurance: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>

            

               Administration of justice (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, law enforcement, etc.) :
1.1

            
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> important things to say about
this list. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that it encompasses the bulk of government
spending--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82.2 percent</NUMEX>, to be precise. Anyone who proposes a radical downsizing
of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must mean to slash this list.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is that with one
possible exception, these are programs that the public likes--they are not at
all what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> object to when they rail against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Government</ENAMEX>. We believe in
honoring our debts. We like our strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>; indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> wants it
stronger. We like our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>. We want strong law enforcement. The only
possibly unpopular item on the list is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, which is the only "poverty"
program. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> is increasingly a program of aid not for the poor per se,
but rather, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX>. More and more of it pays for nursing-home care--and
many of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            And that
brings us to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> point: Aside from defense and interest payments, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is now mainly--yes, mainly--in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of taxing the young
and giving money to the old. Look at that list, and consider how utterly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shameless Dole</ENAMEX> was in imagining a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> who couldn't afford to call her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">granddaughter</ENAMEX> because she pays too much in taxes. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> almost
surely lives better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of her age ever lived before, supported by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> checks that will greatly exceed the value of the contributions
she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> paid into the system. And her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> could easily have
sent her the money for phone calls, except that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> contributions
had to cover her hip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX>.

            There is a good case to be made that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s gerontocracy
has gone too far, that we are too generous to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>, especially to those
who could afford to do without some of those benefits. But that is not a case
the right has ever made. An honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would
campaign not against elitist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> but against nice middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>
in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominiums</ENAMEX>. Somehow, that wasn't in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s speech.

            It isn't as easy to summarize
federal regulation as it is to summarize federal spending, but the basic point
is similar: Most of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does is actually serving, not opposing,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>'s will. Lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> snicker at <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX>-darter jokes, but only a
small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> wants to see a repeal of the clean-air or clean-water laws. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are prepared to punish those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> whom they suspect of
belonging to that minority.

            Of course, the federal
government wastes a lot of money; so does the private sector (have you read
Dilbert lately?). But the kind of oppressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, run by meddling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">elitists</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> tried to tell us about in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> exists only in the
conservative imagination. And that is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> did not snatch
defeat from the jaws of victory. Their reversal of fortune was preordained,
because their doctrine could not withstand the responsibility that came with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
