
   
   
      
         
            Setting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>

            In an early-'90s
Dilbert , an excessively trendy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> exhorted his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to "search for
excellence in the total quality chaos, or whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> are doing this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only a few years ago</TIMEX>, the business sections of airport <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> were
largely given over to tracts revealing the supposed secrets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
management and the menace <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> posed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Then it turned out
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> were human, after all, and everyone lost interest. Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX>, having once placed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> on a pedestal, now either prefer not to
discuss the subject or see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s failures mainly as an occasion for smug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-congratulation</ENAMEX>.

            But the
new story is much more interesting than the old one. How could a wealthy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">productive</ENAMEX>, sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have gone from enviable growth in the 1980s
to stagnation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, and now be slipping into a downward spiral of
recession and deflation? True, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on the edge of chaos--as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is--but that only adds to the mystery. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> isn't a place
where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is weak, unable to collect taxes or convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> that
their property rights are secure. Nor is it a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> at the mercy of skittish
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who must be persuaded to roll over its debt: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is still
the world's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditor</ENAMEX>. So what's the explanation?

            Inefficiency? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> has many inefficiencies that limit its
productive capacity--too many mom-and-pop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, not enough computerization in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and so on--but inefficiency per se is not the immediate problem.
What <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> lacks right now is not supply but demand: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> just aren't spending enough to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>
busy.

            And the
usual remedies for inadequate demand aren't working. Interest rates have been
pushed down almost as far as they can go. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Japan</ENAMEX>
normally targets the interest rate on overnight loans that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> make to each
other. The difference is that this rate is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 5 percent</NUMEX> here, but
basically zero there. The big public spending projects the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> government
launches every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then do create some jobs, but they never seem to yield
enough bang for the yen: The economy keeps relapsing, while government debt
keeps mounting.

            
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> common explanations for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
plight.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Explanation 1</ENAMEX> is that it is
mainly a financial problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are too burdened with debt,
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> too burdened with bad loans that have never been acknowledged. On
this view, what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> needs is a long, painful financial housecleaning.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Explanation 2</ENAMEX> is that the problem is mainly psychological. When the "bubble
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> (remember when the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">square mile</NUMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Palace</ENAMEX>
was supposedly worth more than all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>?) burst, goes the story,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> went into a funk that has depressed the economy, and
the depressed economy has perpetuated the funk. On this view, what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> needs
is a jump-start--say, a massive but temporary round of tax cuts and public
spending programs that will restore confidence and get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spending again.
(Although it is tactless to say this, the model everyone privately has in mind
is the way wartime spending jolted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX>. Thank you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yamamoto</ENAMEX>!)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explanation 1</ENAMEX> doesn't make sense to me. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s problem
is demand, not supply, how do corporate debt and bad loans cause that problem?
You might say that the answer is obvious: Overindebted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can't borrow
more, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are in no position to lend anyway. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s investment
economies. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> have been lending, too--after all, where do you think
those excessive debts and bad loans came from? The problem is that even these
high rates of investment aren't enough to absorb the huge sums that consumers
apparently want to save.

            Until
recently I was more sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explanation 2</ENAMEX>. But lately I have started to
wonder whether the stubborn unwillingness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s economic engine to catch
is, as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> seem to think, merely because the jump-start hasn't been
big enough or sustained enough. And so (like a small but growing number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> ) I have started paying attention to Explanation
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s troubles really stem from a subtle but deadly interaction
between demography and ideology.

            
Here's the story: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
only much more so, is an aging society. Thanks to a declining birth rate and
negligible immigration, it faces a steady decline in its working-age population
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least the next several decades</TIMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> increase. Given this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> should save heavily to make provision for the
future--and lacking the kind of pay-as-you-go <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> system that
allows <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to ignore such realities, it does. But investment
opportunities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> are limited, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> will not invest all
those savings even at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> interest rate. And as anyone who has read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX> can tell you, when desired savings consistently exceed willing
investment, the result is a permanent recession.

            If this
is the problem, there is in principle a simple, if unsettling, solution: What
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> needs to do is promise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> that there will be inflation in the
future! If it can do that, then the effective "real" interest rate on borrowing
will be negative: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Borrowers</ENAMEX> will expect to repay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less</NUMEX> in real terms than the
amount they borrow. As a result they will be willing to spend more, which is
what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> needs. In short, this explanation suggests that inflation--or more
precisely the promise of future inflation--is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> that will cure
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s ills. The trouble--the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> trap--is that while
the conclusion that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> needs inflation emerges from what looks like
impeccable economic logic, we live in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> in which central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> believe
(and are believed to believe) in price stability as an overriding goal. The
peculiar result of the credibility of modern central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> as inflation hawks
is that no matter how much money the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Japan</ENAMEX> prints now , it
doesn't matter: It can't lower the nominal interest rate, because that
rate is already <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>, and because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't believe that it will allow
inflation to break out any time in the future, it can't lower the real
interest rate either.

            This theory is offensive to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Deep economic
problems are supposed to be a punishment for deep economic sins, not an
accidental byproduct of swings in the birth rate. Inflation is supposed to be a
deadly poison, not a useful medicine. Above all, it seems implausible that the
proposed solution to such severe difficulties could involve so little pain. And
while I think logic and evidence are on my side--that demography, not crony
capitalism, is the villain, and inflation is the answer--it is certainly
possible that I am wrong.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> worries me. It's
not just that we are talking about a huge economy here, an economy whose woes
can drag down a lot of smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with it. What really disturbs me is
this: If we don't really understand what has gone wrong in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, who's to say
the same thing can't happen to us?

            
               If you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">missed Krugman</ENAMEX>'s assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kazuo Ueda</ENAMEX>, click .
            

         
      
   
