
   
   
      
         
            Entertainment Values

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Galbraith</ENAMEX> published The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Industrial State</ENAMEX> , he was sure he
knew where the modern economy was going and was contemptuous of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> who
clung to their old ideas about the primacy of markets. Clearly giant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, driven by the imperatives of technology, were replacing the chaos
of the market with bureaucratic order. The age of business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> was over:
"With the rise of the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>, the emergence of the organization
required by modern technology and planning and the divorce of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of
capital from control of the enterprise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> no longer exists as an
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the mature industrial enterprise." The economy of the
future would be run by faceless organization <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, whose ability to manipulate
pliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> would eliminate the traditional uncertainties associated with
market competition. In effect, capitalism was evolving spontaneously into
socialism without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>.

            Instead,
of course, only the paranoid survived, or something like that. And yet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>'s mistake--believing that one can discern the shape of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> by extrapolating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s iconic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>--is one that each
generation seems to repeat. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> every industry was going to look like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">automobiles</ENAMEX>, and every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> every industry is
going to look like software, and every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>, the prophets of what is variously called
the "business revolution," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Knowledge Economy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Network Economy</ENAMEX>, and the
"new economy" (not to be confused with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX> I wrote about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>) are likely to
be disappointed. Even though information technology may well be the main
driving force behind future economic growth, it's very unlikely that the
information-technology industry is ever going to be more than a fairly
small share of the economy. In its day electricity changed everything, too, but
there was never a time when most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> worked for electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> or even
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> who looked anything like electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX>. Still, even if every
industry isn't about to look like software, it is worth asking what is
special about those industries that do.

            It's
important to get past the obvious, but mainly irrelevant, surfaces of things.
Of course information technology is nifty; but the latest technology
always seems nifty (At the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1876 Philadelphia Centennial Exposition</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triumphant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banners</ENAMEX> proclaimed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All By Steam</ENAMEX>!"). The real question is whether
there really are, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired 's</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Kelly</ENAMEX> put it in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> of a widely read recent article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Rules</ENAMEX>
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> manages to come up with no less than 12
such rules, ranging from the more or less incomprehensible ("Embrace dumb
power") to the basically silly ("Follow the free"), all wrapped in trendy
rhetoric about living "on the edge of chaos" and all that. But most of his
rules amount to variations on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> themes: In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Network Economy</ENAMEX> supply curves
slope down instead of up, and demand curves slope up instead of down. At least,
that's what I think he's saying. To the extent that he is, he is actually on to
something--though not something new.

            True,
traditional economic theory--the stuff that occupies <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 10 or so</TIMEX>
chapters of most introductory textbooks--does assume "diminishing returns" in
both production and consumption. That is, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> units of something the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> is already producing, the harder it is to produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unit more; the
more units of something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are already consuming, the less they are willing
to pay to consume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unit more. That is why the conventional supply curve,
which shows how much will be produced at any given price, slopes up; and the
demand curve, which shows how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will buy at any given price, slopes
down.

            But even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Marshall</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> who
invented supply and demand as we know it--was well aware that while diminishing
returns are a good assumption for agriculture (The more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> you try to grow,
the worse the land on which the marginal bushel is grown), elsewhere in the
economy it is quite possible to have increasing returns, in which the
more you produce, the easier it gets. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX> he explained that
concentrations of industry (yes, they existed before <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>--his prime
example was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sheffield</ENAMEX> cutlery district) can create a virtuous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> in
which the availability of skilled labor, the presence of specialized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>,
and the diffusion of knowledge . Increasing returns to consumption are probably
less common, but can result among other things from "network externalities"--a
bit of useful jargon for what happens when the usefulness of a product depends
on how many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> possess something similar. A telephone is a toy when
only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>; it is a necessity when everyone has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            The
old-fashioned examples are deliberate: Increasing returns have been around for
a long time. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> may historically have downplayed their
importance, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> are long past. In fact, by now, increasing returns are
rather old hat. Everybody knows that sufficiently strong increasing returns can
cause discontinuous change, with markets exploding when they reach a "critical
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX>," that small events can have big effects when a market is near a "tipping
point," that economic choices (like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VHS</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betamax</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Route 128</ENAMEX>) can be subject to "lock-in" by past accidents, and so on. Everybody
also knows that while it is easy to tell good stories along these lines, it's a
lot harder when you get down to real cases: It's amazingly hard to identify a
critical mass or a tipping point for an actual industry, even after the
fact.

            
So what's new about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Rules</ENAMEX>? Well,
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, they may be new to him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cybercritic Paulina Borsook</ENAMEX> has pointed
out to me that technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> are prone to "Luke Skywalker
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fantasies</ENAMEX>," imagining themselves heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>.
(The quintessential example of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Skywalker Syndrome</ENAMEX> is the story of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Arthur</ENAMEX>, as described in my column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.) They are so
sure that boring conventional thinkers could not have anticipated their radical
ideas that it would never occur to them to check.

            Or maybe
what's new about the rules is the claim that now, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, they
apply to a large part of the economy. However, technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX>, who won't
stop thinking about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, often forget to think about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: It's not
at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all</TIMEX> clear that increasing returns are any more important in software than
they were in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX>, electricity, telephones, radio, even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">automobiles</ENAMEX> (What good is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> without gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>? Why open a gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> if
nobody has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>?). And it's very unlikely that in the future everything will
look like software--indeed, it's much more likely that eventually the
information <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> itself will turn into a boring mature industry.

            If there is something new in the writings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> and
other cyberprophets, it is the fact that they don't just predict a
future in which the curves slope the wrong way, they endorse it. That
is, along with the gee-whiz pronouncements about how the economy supposedly
works goes a pronounced libertarian bent, a belief that the new economy is too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynamic</ENAMEX>, organic, or whatever to be regulated from above.

            What is
odd about these libertarian conclusions is that they do not at all follow from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX>. On the contrary: A world in which increasing returns are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevalent</ENAMEX> is one in which markets are likely to get it wrong. Products that
should be developed never get off the ground, or do so much later than they
should, because everyone is waiting for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to move. (I'll buy a fax
machine only when enough other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have them to make it worthwhile.)
Industries can get locked into the wrong technology (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> is better than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX>, but everyone uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX> because everyone else uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOS</ENAMEX>). Waste occurs
because of coordination failures (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX> each line had
a different gauge). Indeed, increasing returns have traditionally been used as
arguments against free markets, for government intervention. You
may not believe that such intervention will work in practice, but that's a
judgment about the rules of politics, not economics.

            
Of course the information-technology sector has
been wonderfully successful--but that is because it has been in a position to
exploit the extraordinary possibilities offered by photolithography, not
because of any special virtue in the way it operates. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> in which
increasing returns to both production and consumption prevail--and there are
quite a few outside what is normally thought of as high technology--do not seem
especially admirable.

            Consider, in particular, an
industry few would regard as a role model: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. It is obviously
characterized by increasing returns to production: Once you've made a movie,
showing it to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> costs virtually nothing. It is also characterized
by increasing returns to consumption: Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to see a movie because
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have seen it. In fact, by my reckoning, the movie business handily
fits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> rules. It even fits "Follow the free," which I think
means "Sell your signature product cheap, and make money off accessories";
major blockbusters make much of their money off product placements and toy
sales, and even theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> depend on sodas and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> to turn a profit. The
only rule I can't apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is "Embrace dumb power"--but then again,
some of those studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> ...

            So think of it this way:
While the prophets of the "new economy" may seem to be telling us that we're
heading for a future in which every industry looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>, what
they are really saying is that we are on our way to an era in which there's no
business that isn't like show business. Let's hope they're wrong.

         
      
   
