
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rashomon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>

            Rarely in the course of
human events have so few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lost so much money so quickly. There is no
mystery about how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term Capital Management</ENAMEX> managed to make
billions of dollars disappear. Essentially, the hedge fund took huge bets with
borrowed money--although its capital base was only a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX>,
we now know that it had placed wagers directly or indirectly on the prices of
more than a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion dollars</NUMEX>' worth of assets. When it turned out to have bet
in the wrong direction, poof!--all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' money, and probably quite a
lot more besides, was gone.

            But the
really interesting questions are all about why. Why did such smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> are smart, even if some of them have <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prizes</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>--take such seemingly foolish risks? Why did the world give them so
much money to play with? As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akira Kurosawa</ENAMEX> could have told us, the beginning
and end of the story are not enough: We need to know the motivations and
behavior in between.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> was secretive about how it made money, but the basic
idea went something like this. Imagine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> assets--say, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and German
government bonds--whose prices usually move together. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> bonds pay
higher interest. So someone who "shorts" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> bonds--receives money now, in
return for a promise to deliver those bonds at a later date--then invests the
proceeds in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> bonds, can earn money for nothing.

            Of course,
it's not that simple. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who provide money now in return for future
bonds are aware that if the prices of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> bonds happen not to
move in sync, you might not be able to deliver on your promise. So they will
demand evidence that you have enough capital to make up any likely losses, plus
extra compensation for the remaining risk. But if the required compensation and
the capital you need to put up aren't too large, there may still be an
opportunity for an exceptionally favorable trade-off between risk and
return.

            
OK, it's still not that simple. Any opportunity
that straightforward would probably have been snapped up already. What LTCM
did, or at least claimed to do, was find less obvious opportunities along the
same lines, by engaging in complicated transactions involving many assets. For
example, suppose that historically, increases in the spread between the price
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> as compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> bonds were correlated with declines in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> stock market. Then the riskiness of the bet on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>-German
interest differential could be reduced by taking out a side bet, shorting
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> stocks--and so on. In principle, at least, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX>'s computers--programmed
by those <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureates</ENAMEX>--allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to search for complex trading
strategies that took advantage of even subtle market mispricings, providing
high returns with very little risk.

            But in
the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX>, somehow it all went bad. What happened?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> version of events makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
of circumstance. Their trading strategy, goes this story, was basically sound.
But there is no such thing as an absolutely risk-free investment strategy. If
the gods are sufficiently against you, if a peculiar, nay, unprecedented
combination of events--debacle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, stalemate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, market crash in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>--comes to pass, even the best strategy comes to grief.
According to this version, there is no particular moral to the story, except
that **** happens.

            Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the investment world, however, are not that forgiving of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX>. Their
version of events does not accuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> of evil intent, but it does
accuse them of myopia. The magic word is "kurtosis," a k a "fat tails." The
story goes like this: Everyone knows that there are potential events that are
not likely to happen but will have very big effects on financial markets if
they do. A realistic assessment of risk should take into account the
possibility of these large, low-probability events--in effect, should allow for
the reality that now and then **** does indeed happen. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizards</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX>,
so the story goes, forgot about reality. They treated the statistical
distributions found by their computers, based on data from a period when ****
didn't happen, as if they represented the entire universe of possibilities. As
a result, they greatly understated the risk to which they were exposing both
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> and those who lent them money.

            
However, knowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ran <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX>--who,
to repeat, are as smart as they were supposed to be--it is kind of hard to
believe that they were really that naive. These were experienced hands (not
your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">typical 29-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, who don't remember anything before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>).
Anyone who has lived through energy crisis and debt crisis, inflation and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disinflation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganomics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintonomics</ENAMEX>, has to know that big surprises are
part of life. Which brings us to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, more sinister version of events:
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> knew exactly what it was doing.

            Here's
the way <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> investment industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>--who prefers to be nameless--put
it to me. Suppose, he says, that someone was willing to lend you a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">trillion</NUMEX>
dollars to invest as you like. What that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lender</ENAMEX> has done is in effect to give
you a "put option" on whatever you buy with that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillion dollars</NUMEX>. That is,
because you can always declare bankruptcy and walk away, it is as if you owned
the right to sell those assets at a fixed price, whatever might happen in the
market. And because the value of an option depends positively on
"volatility"--the uncertainty about the future value of the underlying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asset</ENAMEX>--the rational way to maximize the value of that option is to invest the
money in the riskiest, most volatile assets you can find. After all, it's heads
you become wealthy beyond the dreams of avarice, tails you get some bad press
(and lose the money you yourself put in--but when you are allowed to make a
trillion-dollar gamble with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $2.3 billion</NUMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' capital, that
hardly matters). And as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> reminds us, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ran LTCM
understood all about this sort of thing--indeed, those <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureates</ENAMEX> got
their prizes for, guess what, developing the modern theory of option
pricing.

            This "moral hazard" version of the story may seem a bit too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stark</ENAMEX> to be believed. Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> really sit around saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, let's
gamble with the money those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> have lent us"? Actually, it's a
possibility: I don't know any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> personally, but some of the
hedge fund types I do know are, as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> puts it, "about as moral as
great white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sharks</ENAMEX>." But anyway, never underestimate the power of hypocrisy. It
is entirely possible for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to act in a crudely cynical way without
admitting it even to himself. Given their enormous incentive to take improper
risks, it would actually be amazing if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> didn't respond in
the normal way.

            But we are
still not quite there. For the remaining puzzle is why the world provided LTCM
with so much money to lose. All those clever strategies depended on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>--on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> who would provide cash now in return
for the promise of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> bonds, or whatever, later. Why were those
counterparts so willing to play along? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX>, as a matter of principle, refused
to divulge its assets or strategy--so anyone who entered a contract with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> was accepting an unknown risk.) Were these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>--mainly big banks
and other institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--simply naive?

            
Some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> say no. They think
the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> knew the risks but believed that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> came to grief its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">creditors</ENAMEX> would be protected from loss by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In effect, they
believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX> story is mainly an updated version of what happened to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> and loans, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> guarantees underwrote an era of
high-rolling risk-taking. True, there is no formal guarantee. But they believe
that there was an implicit understanding that any major financial institution
is simply "too big to fail."

            But I don't buy it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> often make the working assumption that the private sector always
knows what it is doing, that markets do stupid things only when the government
gives them distorted incentives. It's a useful working assumption, but it is no
more than that. In fact, everything I can see suggests that the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> really
were naive--that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> struck by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTCM</ENAMEX>'s charismatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and his prestigious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>, they failed to ask even the simplest questions (such as, "How much money
have you borrowed from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?")

            Of course, if you believe
that big, supposedly sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> can be that foolish--or, for that
matter, if you believe that they are not foolish but do foolish things because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will always bail them out--you start to wonder whether our whole
financial structure is as sound as we like to imagine. Did somebody say "crony
capitalism"?

         
      
   
