
   
   
      
         
            Down-sizing Downsizing

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
isn't particularly mendacious on economic matters--in fact, economic analysis
and reporting under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have been unusually scrupulous. But the president
has changed his mind about economic policy so often that now his officials
sound insincere even when they speak the plain truth.

            And so I
feel a bit sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Stiglitz</ENAMEX>, the eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> who chairs
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of Economic Advisers</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stiglitz</ENAMEX> released a report on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, more or less confirming what most independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> had already concluded: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers</ENAMEX> are not doing as badly as recent
headlines might suggest. In particular, the impact of corporate downsizing has
been greatly exaggerated.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stiglitz</ENAMEX>'s report was, to all appearances, a sincere
attempt to produce a realistic picture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> labor market. Yet it was
treated by nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> as a purely political document--an
election<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year</TIMEX> effort to accentuate the positive.

            But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> had reason for their skepticism. After all, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
administration--especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>--have been insistently
pushing a very different view. In the world according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>, even well-paid
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have now joined the "anxious classes." They are liable any day
to find themselves downsized out of the middle class. And even if they keep
their jobs, the fear of being fired has forced them to accept stagnant or
declining wages while productivity and profits soar.

            
Like much of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> says, this story is
clear, compelling, brilliantly packaged, and mostly wrong. Stiglitz, by
contrast, is telling the complicated truth rather than an emotionally
satisfying fiction.

            To understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> is
wrong (about this and most other things), think about the strange case of the
missing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, sensationalist journalism, combining
true-crime stories with garbled statistics, convinced much of the public that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> where vast numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are snatched from their
happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> by mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. TV shows about "stranger
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abductions</ENAMEX>" are a media staple to this day. In reality, however, such crimes
are rare: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 300</NUMEX> per year in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">260 million</NUMEX>.

            It's not
that abductions never happen. They do, and they are terrible things. Nor is the
point that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are all right: For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, life is sheer hell. Almost always, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who victimize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>. For every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> kidnapped by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>, at least a
thousand are sexually abused by family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> abductions made
good copy, and therefore became a public concern out of all proportion to their
real importance.

            Corporate downsizing is neither as terrible nor as rare as
stranger abduction, but the two phenomena share some characteristics. Like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger abductions</ENAMEX>, downsizing is a camera-ready tragedy, perfect for media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploitation</ENAMEX>, that is only a minor part of the real problem.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stiglitz</ENAMEX>'s report is full of
dense statistical analysis making this point, but here's a quick do-it-yourself
version. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> cover story entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corporate Killers</ENAMEX>"
listed just about every large layoff by a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> over the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. The number of jobs eliminated by each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> appeared in large type
next to a photo of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> responsible. The article implied that it was
describing a national catastrophe. But if you add up all the numbers, the total
comes to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">370,000</NUMEX>. That is less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">300</TIMEX>--a tiny blip in the
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who lose or change jobs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, even in the healthiest
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. And the great majority of downsized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> do find new jobs. Although
most end up making less in their new jobs than they did before, only a fraction
experience the much-publicized plunge from comfortable middle class to working
poor. No wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stiglitz</ENAMEX> found that the destruction of good jobs by greedy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> is just not an important part of what is happening to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>.

            The point
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s style of economics--which relies on anecdotes rather than
statistics, slogans rather than serious analysis--cannot do justice to the
diversity and sheer size of this vast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> anything that can
happen, does: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Strangers</ENAMEX> kidnap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; mathematicians become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> find themselves flipping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX>. The important question is not
whether these stories are true; it is whether they are typical. How do they fit
into the big picture?

            
Well, the big picture looks like this: Both the
number of "good jobs" and the pay that goes with those jobs are steadily
rising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who have the skill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, and luck to get these jobs
generally do very well. Only a relative handful of "good job" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> (which is
to say <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only a few hundred thousand</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>) experience serious reverses.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s middle class may be anxious, but objectively, it is doing fine.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are really
doing badly are those who do not have good jobs and never did. Those with lousy
jobs have seen their already-low wages slowly but steadily sink. In other
words, the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of (to use another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s phrases) the "new
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>" are not the few <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> who have become hamburger flippers
but the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions of</NUMEX> hamburger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">flippers</ENAMEX>, janitors, and so on whose real
wages have been declining 1or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> per year for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two decades</TIMEX>.

            Does this distinction
matter? It does if you are trying to set any sort of policy priorities. Should
we, as some in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> want, focus our attention on preserving the
jobs of well-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> at big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>? Should we pressure those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to stop announcing layoffs? Should we use the tax system to penalize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and reward those that do not? Or, instead, should
we fight tooth and nail to preserve and extend programs like the Earned Income
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Credit</ENAMEX> that help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX>? It is disingenuous to say we should do
both: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Money</ENAMEX> is scarce and so is political capital. If we focus on small
problems that make headlines, we will ignore bigger problems that don't.

            So let's give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Stiglitz</ENAMEX>
some credit. No doubt his political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> allowed him to downsize the issue
of downsizing at least partly because they believed that good news re-elects
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>. Sometimes, however, an economic analysis that is politically
convenient also happens to be the honest truth.

         
      
   
