
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vulgar Keynesians</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX>, like all
intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, is subject to the law of diminishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX>. A
great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innovator</ENAMEX> is entitled to some poetic license. If his ideas are at first
somewhat rough, if he exaggerates the discontinuity between his vision and what
came before, no matter: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> and perspective can come in due course. But
inevitably there are those who follow the letter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innovator</ENAMEX>'s ideas but
misunderstand their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, who are more dogmatic in their radicalism than the
orthodox were in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>. And as ideas spread, they become increasingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">simplistic</ENAMEX>--until what eventually becomes part of the public consciousness,
part of what "everyone knows," is no more than a crude caricature of the
original.

            Such has been the fate of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Keynesian</ENAMEX> economics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX> himself was a magnificently subtle and
innovative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>. Yet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his unfortunate if unintentional legacies was a
style of thought--call it vulgar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keynesianism</ENAMEX>--that confuses and befogs
economic debate to this day.

            Before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX> publication
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> had developed a rich and insightful theory of microeconomics ,
of the behavior of individual markets and the allocation of resources among
them. But macroeconomics --the study of economy-wide events like
inflation and deflation, booms and slumps--was in a state of arrested
development that left it utterly incapable of making sense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX>.

            So-called "classical"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">macroeconomics</ENAMEX> asserted that the economy had a long-run tendency to return to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> employment, and focused only on that long run. Its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main tenets were
the quantity theory of money--the assertion that the overall level of prices
was proportional to the quantity of money in circulation--and the "loanable
funds" theory of interest, which asserted that interest rates would rise or
fall to equate total savings with total investment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> was willing to
concede that in some sufficiently long run, these theories might indeed be
valid; but, as he memorably pointed out, "In the long run we are all dead." In
the short run, he asserted, interest rates were determined not by the balance
between savings and investment at full employment but by "liquidity
preference"--the public's desire to hold cash unless offered a sufficient
incentive to invest in less safe and convenient assets. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savings</ENAMEX> and investment
were still necessarily equal; but if desired savings at full employment turned
out to exceed desired investment, what would fall would be not interest rates
but the level of employment and output. In particular, if investment demand
should fall for whatever reason--such as, say, a stock-market crash--the result
would be an economy-wide slump.

            It was a brilliant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-imagining of the way the economy worked, one that received quick acceptance
from the brightest young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> of the time. True, some realized very early
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX>' picture was oversimplified; in particular, that the level of
employment and output would normally feed back to interest rates, and that this
might make a lot of difference. Still, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> after the
publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The General Theory</ENAMEX> , many economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> were
fascinated by the implications of that picture, which seemed to take us into a
looking-glass world in which virtue was punished and self-indulgence
rewarded.

            Consider, for example, the
"paradox of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX>." Suppose that for some reason the savings rate--the
fraction of income not spent--goes up. According to the early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Keynesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>,
this will actually lead to a decline in total savings and investment.
Why? Because higher desired savings will lead to an economic slump, which will
reduce income and also reduce investment demand; since in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> savings and
investment are always equal, the total volume of savings must actually
fall!

            Or
consider the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>'s cruse" theory of wages and employment (named after an old
folk tale). You might think that raising wages would reduce the demand for
labor; but some early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Keynesians</ENAMEX> argued that redistributing income from profits
to wages would raise consumption demand, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> save less than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capitalists</ENAMEX> (actually they don't, but that's another story), and therefore
increase output and employment.

            Such paradoxes are still fun to contemplate; they still
appear in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> textbooks. Nonetheless, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> take them
seriously <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. There are a number of reasons, but the most important can
be stated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>.

            After all,
the simple Keynesian story is one in which interest rates are independent of
the level of employment and output. But in reality the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX>
actively manages interest rates, pushing them down when it thinks employment is
too low and raising them when it thinks the economy is overheating. You may
quarrel with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s judgment--you may think that he should keep the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> on a looser rein--but you can hardly dispute his power. Indeed, if you
want a simple model for predicting the unemployment rate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>, here it is: It will be what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> wants it to be,
plus or minus a random error reflecting the fact that he is not quite God.

            
But putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> (or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>) into
the picture restores much of the classical vision of the macroeconomy. Instead
of an invisible hand pushing the economy toward full employment in some
unspecified long run, we have the visible hand of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> pushing us toward its
estimate of the noninflationary unemployment rate over the course of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>. To accomplish this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> must raise or lower interest rates
to bring savings and investment at that target unemployment rate in line with
each other. And so all the paradoxes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>'s cruses, and so on
become irrelevant. In particular, an increase in the savings rate will
translate into higher investment after all, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> will make sure that
it does.

            To me, at
least, the idea that changes in demand will normally be offset by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>
policy--so that they will, on average, have no effect on employment--seems both
simple and entirely reasonable. Yet it is clear that very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> outside
the world of academic economics think about things that way. For example, the
debate over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Free Trade Agreement</ENAMEX> was conducted almost
entirely in terms of supposed job creation or destruction. The obvious (to me)
point that the average unemployment rate over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 10 years</TIMEX> will be what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> wants it to be, regardless of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> trade balance, never made
it into the public consciousness. (In fact, when I made that argument at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
panel discussion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>, as it
happens--exploded in rage: "It's remarks like that that make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>!")

            What has made it into the public
consciousness--including, alas, that of many policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> who imagine
themselves well informed--is a sort of caricature <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynesianism</ENAMEX>, the hallmark of
which is an uncritical acceptance of the idea that reduced consumer spending is
always a bad thing. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, where inflation and the budget
deficit have receded for the time being, vulgar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keynesianism</ENAMEX> has recently
staged an impressive comeback. The paradox of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>'s cruse are
both major themes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Greider</ENAMEX>'s latest book, which I discussed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>.
(Although it is doubtful whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greider</ENAMEX> is aware of the source of his
ideas--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keynes</ENAMEX> wrote, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Practical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, who believe themselves quite exempt
from any intellectual influence, are usually the slaves of some defunct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>.") It is perhaps not surprising that the same ideas are echoed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John B. Judis</ENAMEX> in the ; but when you see the idea that higher savings will
actually reduce growth treated seriously in ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Looking for Growth in All the</ENAMEX>
Wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Places</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>), you realize that there is a real cultural phenomenon
developing.

            To justify
the claim that savings are actually bad for growth (as opposed to the quite
different, more reasonable position that they are not as crucial as some would
claim), you must convincingly argue that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> is impotent--that it cannot,
by lowering interest rates, ensure that an increase in desired savings gets
translated into higher investment.

            
It is not enough to argue that interest
rates are only one of several influences on investment. That is like saying
that my pressure on the gas pedal is only one of many influences on the speed
of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. So what? I am able to adjust that pressure, and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s speed is
normally determined by how fast I think I can safely drive. Similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> is able to change interest rates freely (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> can double the money
supply in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>, if it wants to), and so the level of employment is normally
determined by how high he thinks it can safely go--end of story.

            No, to make sense of the
claim that savings are bad you must argue either that interest rates have
no effect on spending (try telling that to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homebuilders</ENAMEX>) or that potential savings are so high compared with investment
opportunities that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> cannot bring the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in line even at a near-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>
interest rate. The latter was a reasonable position during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, when the
rate on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bills was less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-tenth</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>; it is an arguable
claim right now for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, where interest rates are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1 percent</NUMEX>. (Actually,
I think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of Japan</ENAMEX> could still pull that economy out of its funk,
and that its passivity is a case of gross malfeasance. That, however, is a
subject for another column.) But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that holds a mortgage on my house
sends me a little notice each month assuring me that the interest rate in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is still quite positive, thank you.

            Anyway,
this is a moot point, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who insist that savings are bad do not
think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> is impotent. On the contrary, they are generally the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who insist that the disappointing performance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy over
the past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> is all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s fault, and that we could grow our way out
of our troubles if only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> would let us.

            Let's quote the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX> 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX>
commentary:

            
               Some contrarian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> argue that forcing up savings is likely to slow the economy,
depressing investment rather than sparking it. "You need to stimulate the
investment decision," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James K. Galbraith</ENAMEX>, a
Keynesian. He would rather stimulate growth by cutting interest rates.
            

            So, increasing savings will
slow the economy--presumably because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> cannot induce an increase in
investment by cutting interest rates. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> should stimulate growth
by cutting interest rates, which will work because lower interest rates will
induce an increase in investment.

            Am I
missing something?

            
               To read the reply of
"Vulgar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Keynesian</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James K. Galbraith</ENAMEX>, in which he explains green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Keynes,</ENAMEX> click here.
            

         
      
   
