
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Loury</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Round Trip</ENAMEX>

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Loury</ENAMEX> and I
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overlapped</ENAMEX> in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>--I arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> and he left in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>--I
have never known him well. But I do remember the joke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> told about
him--that his thesis began: "This dissertation is concerned with the economics
of racism. I define racism as a single-valued, continuous mapping ..." The
story isn't true, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> of that thesis, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"A Dynamic Theory of</ENAMEX>
Racial Income Differences," does have an appendix that begins "Each agent
begins life with a random innate endowment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX> is the endowment set, taken to be
a subset of an arbitrary, finite dimensional <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Euclidean</ENAMEX> space."

            Loury, in
other words, was and is a first-rate technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> with a mathematical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bent</ENAMEX> who has ended up writing and speaking not about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euclidean</ENAMEX> spaces but about
the political economy of race. This is partly because he is as good with words
as he is with equations. It is partly because he cares deeply about social
issues. But inevitably, it is also partly because he is one of only a handful
of well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> in his field. In the process he has become
what, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Koestler</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Orwell</ENAMEX> was in another time and place: one
of those emblematic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> whose career illustrates in microcosm the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dilemmas</ENAMEX>, temptations, and betrayals of an era.

            When he was young, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX>'s disillusionment with the civil
rights movement drove him into neoconservatism. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, he has
been exiled once again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> out by the right essentially because he still
cares about what happens to the poor. The dogmatic rigidity, left and right,
that has left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX> without an ideological <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is also why this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> has
such a hard time talking honestly about race.

            Reading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX>'s dissertation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 years</TIMEX> after he wrote it, is a depressing
experience--precisely because the essays were so good and remain so relevant.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first few</TIMEX> pages, he stated the central dilemma of race policy in modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. He was willing to give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society the benefit of the doubt, to
assume that in the future, racism--direct economic discrimination--would no
longer be a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> holding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> back. But he argued that this
probably would not be enough, and therein lay the dilemma.

            
On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, we all believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
deserve to be judged on their own merits, not by who their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were or what
group they belong to. On the other hand, anyone who imagines that a child
growing up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Bronx</ENAMEX> has the same chance to make it as an equally
talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarsdale</ENAMEX> is living in a fantasy world. So merely
eliminating current racial discrimination might very well fail to
eliminate the effects of past discrimination. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loury</ENAMEX> argued persuasively
that even a world of "equal opportunity" might "perpetuate into the indefinite
future the consequences of ethically unacceptable historical practices." If you
find that prospect unacceptable, you must support some form of social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX>--which ultimately, no matter how you package it, means giving some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> special consideration based on the color of their skin as well as on the
content of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            In a
better world, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX> would have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 22 years</TIMEX> devising
policies--working with other well-intentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come as close as
possible to squaring this circle, finding ways to eliminate the legacy of past
racism with as little intrusion as possible on the colorblind ideal. But he has
basically never been able to get off square <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>--because at no point over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two decades</TIMEX> has he been able to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> who are even willing to accept
the reality of the dilemma.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX>'s problems began with the left. Although his
dissertation was written <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a dozen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights</ENAMEX>
Act, he saw clearly that the problems facing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> had changed. The
biggest barrier to progress was no longer active racism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> but internal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> problems of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. But black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and to a lesser
extent liberalism as a whole, flatly refused even to contemplate that
possibility. He also found powerful pressures--"loyalty tests"--operating
against any black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who tried to challenge the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX>.

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX>, he did not give in to these pressures. He said what he thought. In so
doing, he found himself labeled a "black conservative"--and thereby exposed to
new and dangerous seductions. Let's face it: Any articulate minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who reliably espouses conservative positions is automatically
offered a ticket to a very nice lifestyle. No <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> rejections from picky
academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> or grubbing for sabbatical time. Instead there are cushy
fellowships at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> editorials in the Wall 
               Street

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , and invited articles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Commentary</ENAMEX> --maybe even a regular
column in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> --and a steady stream of invitations to plush
conferences in nice places. All this and more lay before a bona fide academic
star such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX>. Until personal problems temporarily derailed him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>,
he was well on his way to high political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and all the rewards that brings
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> life.

            
But at some point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loury</ENAMEX> made the discovery that
eventually confronts every honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who gets drawn into the
political arena: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> are not necessarily your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Loury</ENAMEX> who wrote that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> thesis was not a conservative. He
criticized the simplistic anti-racism of the liberal establishment because he
wanted society to tackle the real problems, not because he wanted it to stand
aside. His seeming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> on the right, however, turned out to be interested
only in the critique, not in the next step. (According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loury</ENAMEX>, "When I told
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gathering of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> that their seeming hostility to every social
program smacks of indifference to the poor, I was told that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> cannot
properly be said to have no concern for a terminally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> simply because
he had moved on to the next case.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX> found out that the apparent regard
for his ideas by conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> was entirely conditional. Any
questioning of conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthodoxy</ENAMEX> was viewed as an act of betrayal, giving
aid and comfort to the liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. It was the loyalty test all over
again.

            The final straw was surely
the grotesque affair of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell</ENAMEX>
Curve: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Class Structure in American Life</ENAMEX> . This book came
close to claiming that, given your genes, it makes no difference to your
economic success whether you grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarsdale</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Bronx</ENAMEX>. The
implied subtext was that this absolves society from any responsibility to do
something for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> growing up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Bronx</ENAMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell</ENAMEX>
Curve was published, it has become clear that almost everything about it
was inexcusably wrong: suspect data, mistakes in statistical procedures that
would have flunked a sophomore (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> is deceased--clearly does
not understand what a correlation coefficient means), deliberate suppression of
contrary evidence, you name it. Yet conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> such as
Commentary , which was always happy to publish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX> when he criticized
liberal evasions, would not grant him space to critique <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell</ENAMEX>
Curve .

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loury</ENAMEX> is now on his own
(or rather, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> of like-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, centered on
his new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> on Race and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Division</ENAMEX>): rejected by the black political
elite, which still wants to blame everything on white racism, and equally
rejected by a conservatism that wants to do precisely nothing about continuing
racial inequality. And the dilemma <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loury</ENAMEX> identified so clearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 years ago</TIMEX>
remains not only unresolved but also unconfronted.

         
      
   
