
   
   
      
         
            Who's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Buying Whom</ENAMEX>?

            Whenever I put in a good
word for the global economy--pointing out that international trade is not the
source of all misfortunes, or that low-wage exporting benefits many poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--I can count on receiving a pile of hate mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of
these letters rarely offer interesting reasons for their anger or, indeed,
reasoned arguments of any kind: They know that globalization is evil,
and that's that.

            However,
the letters written in response to my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> Slate column on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> trade
turned out to contain something new. Instead of merely telling me that I was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fool</ENAMEX>, some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> accused me of personal venality, of actually being
paid to defend the interests of multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX>.
("Why don't you get off the gravy train<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.) To the letter-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> it
seems perfectly clear: All honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> can see the obvious truth that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalization</ENAMEX> is a terrible thing, and only a capitalist hireling would deny
it. I guess I already knew that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believed this, but the latest
letters suggested that it might be useful if I told their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> something
about the facts of life.

            In case you were wondering: I am not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX>. I am not on
any corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>; do not get paid to defend capitalism; and have not, to my
knowledge, ever received money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (although I was a
bit surprised by the generosity of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> monks).

            And yet my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> are not entirely wrong about the way the world works. Wealthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> do seek to buy the appearance of
intellectual legitimacy for economic doctrines that serve their interests. It
is possible for economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> who might otherwise have limited job
prospects to make a comfortable living by professing certain views on the
global economy. It just so happens that support for free trade is not one of
those views.

            
Why doesn't advocating free trade pay? Too much
supply, too little demand. Unfortunately, there is so much logic and evidence
behind the case for free trade that many smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are willing to make that
case for nothing; they spoil the market for anyone who might want to make money
at it. And anyway, there isn't that much of a market. The benefits of free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>, though substantial, are thinly spread, so it isn't in the interest of
any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> to spend a lot of money promoting that cause. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protectionism</ENAMEX>, by
contrast, tends to impose widely spread costs but to confer benefits on
concentrated interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, who therefore have a strong incentive to lobby
for it--and to provide financial support for those who help make it seem
intellectually respectable.

            This is
not an abstract speculation: In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, at least, it is easy to be
specific about who pays whom to say what about globalization. Presumably,
everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is familiar with that picture; but since my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> obviously weren't, let me trace out the basics.

            At the center of the picture stands an imposing
figure--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Milliken</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> textile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baron</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>. He
is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moriarty</ENAMEX> of protectionism: He does not orchestrate everything (there
is, in particular, a parallel but mostly distinct anti-globalization network
funded by labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">industrialists</ENAMEX>), and even those who benefit
from his largess do not always do his bidding. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milliken</ENAMEX> is the biggest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in this game, and following the money <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> that lead back to him is a
pretty good way to understand how this particular piece of the world really
works.

            On most
issues <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX> is an unabashed hard-line right-winger, with a reputation as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kingmaker</ENAMEX>. (His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have boasted that without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> would not have become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.) Among other things, he gave
several <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOPAC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> pretending to be an educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX> has decided,
however, that free-market principles . He hosts dinners of the so-called No
Name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, a group of right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Free Trade</ENAMEX>
Agreement--dinners enlivened, according to press reports, by uproarious
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> jokes. And he has supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of trade liberalization on a
truly impressive scale--giving, for example, some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in soft money to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Buchanan</ENAMEX> to fund anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> advertisements.

            
But all that is money politics as usual. More
interesting is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milliken</ENAMEX>'s role in supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> that help create an
appearance of intellectual legitimacy for his cause.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX> supplied crucial seed money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Strategy Institute</ENAMEX>, a
think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tank</ENAMEX> headed by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde Prestowitz</ENAMEX>;
thereafter, he contributed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 10 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESI</ENAMEX>'s budget. (Other major
contributions came from the auto and steel industries.) He also supplied
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of the budget of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturing Policy Program</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Choate</ENAMEX>, who
ended up as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>'s running mate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> but first became famous for his
book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agents of Influence</ENAMEX> , about the alleged influence-buying practices
of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX> is the most important
contributor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Business</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Council</ENAMEX>, a lobbying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> that was originally formed to oppose the New Deal but which in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> has devoted its energies to opposing free trade. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> was
described in some reports as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s "brains <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX>.")

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX>'s direct lobbying efforts have been relatively
unsuccessful: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> never got anywhere near the presidency, and both NAFTA
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> passed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. However, his longer-run efforts to influence the
climate of opinion have had considerable effect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> he supports--call them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken Men</ENAMEX>--have helped legitimize a point
of view that still commands virtually no support among professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>,
and which was regarded, even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>, as politically beyond the pale.
Particularly impressive is the way that the influence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken Men</ENAMEX> cuts
across the usual political lines. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> of honor at the party
held to celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESI</ENAMEX>'s founding included not only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milliken</ENAMEX> himself but also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Tonelson</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Business and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industrial Council</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Foundation</ENAMEX>, is simultaneously
writing position papers on foreign policy for the harshly conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> and supplying factoids for presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>'s speeches
on trade policy.

            It's a
classic example of what crusading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Greider</ENAMEX>, in his book
Who Will Tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>? , called "deep lobbying": Rather than simply
using their money to buy influence directly, special interests pursue the
longer-term strategy of funding plausible-sounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and institutions that
supply intellectual rationales for the policies they want. We're not talking
conspiracy theory here: It's all quite legal, and more or less aboveboard.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milliken</ENAMEX> himself shuns publicity, his role in backing these institutions
has been fairly well reported. It is strange, however, that when Greider
himself turned his attention from money politics to the global economy, he
ended up relying for technical advice mainly on--you guessed it--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milliken</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protégé Prestowitz</ENAMEX>.

            
Since everyone who matters presumably knows all
about who backs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken Men</ENAMEX> and why, why does their advice still get
taken? The answer, I believe, is an odd but very <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtonian</ENAMEX> combination of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cynicism</ENAMEX> and credulity. Of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> get funded because their
views happen to be convenient for certain interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>--but doesn't
everyone? And regardless of who supports them, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have a lot of
expertise to offer, don't they?

            Both the cynicism and the
credulity reflect ignorance about the world beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
do not get paid to express particular views. Try to get a job at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, or even at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>, merely by singing the praises of
free markets; you will learn the hard way that the currency of academic success
is creativity, not ideological correctness. (It might actually be a good thing
if academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> spent more time educating the world about familiar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">truths</ENAMEX> and less time chasing the latest intellectual trend.) And the Milliken
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> do not, in fact, have a lot of expertise to offer. On the contrary, looking
closely at their work--or confronting them over some issue--quickly reveals
these particular hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gang That Couldn't Think Straight</ENAMEX>. After
all, a policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of whatever persuasion ought to be able to make a case
for his position without relying on calculations that count the same benefits
twice, or forgetting that foreign exchange must either be spent on imports or
invested abroad, that it can't just disappear. And he should be able to look up
standard statistics without reading from the wrong column. Yet the Milliken
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>--even the classy-looking operation at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESI</ENAMEX>--have repeatedly . A Milliken
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>, in short, isn't a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>; he just plays <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on television.

            I don't
think that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> realizes how bad a bargain it gets when it takes advice
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and institutions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milliken</ENAMEX> has supported. Still, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> will
be shocked to hear that supposed progressives receive much of their funding
from wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reactionaries</ENAMEX>, or even that supposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> are actually making
it up as they go along. But who will tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?

            
               Still
think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milliken</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Click</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
