
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> Is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>

            Want an easy way to
eliminate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> trade deficit? Just declare <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> a separate
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>," with its own balance-of-payments statistics. I can almost guarantee
you that the trade deficit of the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--call it "mainland
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>"--will disappear.

            After
all, if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s numbers were counted separately, we would no longer treat
goods imported into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> as debit items in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> balance of payments.
Furthermore, all of the goods that mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
would be considered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports. True, the goods that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> to the
rest of the world would be struck off the export tally, while the goods the
city <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> to the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would henceforth count as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
imports. But these would be minor adjustments: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> is basically not
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of producing physical objects. So we can be sure that the city
runs a huge trade deficit--probably bigger than that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as a
whole, which is why splitting it off from the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would give
the mainland a surplus.

            Of course, most if not all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s deficit in
goods trade is made up for by exports (to mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and the world
at large) of intangibles such as financial services and tickets to see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cats</ENAMEX> ; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> also has a disproportionate number of wealthy
residents, who receive lots of income from the property they own elsewhere. It
would not be surprising to find that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> actually runs a surplus on its
"current account," a measure that includes trade in services and investment
income as well as the merchandise trade balance. But if it's the trade deficit
you worry about, splitting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> off from mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will take care of
the problem. Nothing real would have changed, but maybe it would make some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel better.

            What
inspires this idea is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s assumption of political control over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>,
which removes the last faint excuse for treating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> as
separate economies--and therefore offers a way to make some of the same people
feel better about another trade issue, the supposed threat posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> surplus. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-sans-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>--what we used to call
"mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>"--has been running large and growing surpluses in its
merchandise trade (although its balance on current account has fluctuated
around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-plus-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> does not run big trade surpluses.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year ending in April</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> ran a trade surplus of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $24</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion</ENAMEX>--but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, as one would expect for a mainly service-producing
city-state, ran an offsetting deficit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 billion</NUMEX>, reducing the total to a
fairly unimpressive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.6 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s trade surpluses, in other words, are
largely a statistical illusion produced by the fact that so much of the
management and ownership of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s industry is located on the other side
of an essentially arbitrary line.

            
Pointing this out doesn't change anything real,
but perhaps it may help calm some of the fears being fostered by underemployed
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>-bashers who, like old cold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX>, have lately gone searching for new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>.

            
Professional trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alarmist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Tonelson</ENAMEX> gave a particularly clear statement
of the new fears in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> review of The Big Ten: The Big
Emerging Markets and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How They Will Change Our Lives</ENAMEX> , a book by former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Undersecretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Garten</ENAMEX>. (The review caught my eye because some
of it matched word for word a recent speech by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> and
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gephardt</ENAMEX>.) After praising <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garten</ENAMEX> for taking
seriously the possibility that "the growing ability of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> to produce
sophisticated goods and services at rock-bottom prices could drag down the
standard of living of even affluent, well-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonelson</ENAMEX> chided
him for imagining that developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> included, would provide
important new markets for advanced-country exports: "[C]onsumer markets in
these emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are likely to stay small for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> ... if they don't
keep wages and purchasing power low, they will have trouble attracting the
foreign investment they require, both to service debt and to finance
growth."

            Iam always grateful when influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> make such
statements, especially in prominent places, for in so doing they protect us
from the ever-present temptation to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seriously simply because they
are influential, to imagine that widely held views must actually make at least
some sense.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonelson</ENAMEX>'s claim is that as
emerging economies grow--that is, produce and sell greatly increased quantities
of goods and services--their spending will not grow by a comparable amount;
equivalently, he is claiming that they will run massive trade surpluses. But
when a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> grows, its total income must, by definition, rise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-for-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
with the value of its production. Maybe you don't think that income will get
paid out in higher wages, but it has to show up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX> . And why
should we imagine that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in advanced
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX>, cannot find things to spend their money on?

            In fact,
one might well expect that emerging economies would typically run trade (or at
least current account) deficits . After all, such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> will
presumably attract inflows of foreign investment, allowing them to invest more
than they save--which is to say, spend more than they earn. To put it
another way, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that attracts enough foreign investment "both to service
debt and to finance growth" must, by definition, buy more goods and services
than it sells--that is, run a trade deficit. The point, again, is that the
money has to show up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX> .

            
How can a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> run a trade deficit when it
has the huge cost advantage that comes from combining First World productivity
with Third World wages? The answer is that the premise must be wrong: When
productivity in emerging economies rises, so must wages--that is, the supposed
situation in which these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are able to "produce sophisticated goods and
services at rock-bottom prices" never materializes.

            I am sure that, despite its
logic, my position sounds unrealistic to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. After all, in reality
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> World <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> do run massive trade surpluses, and their wages
don't rise with productivity--right?

            Well,
let's do some abstruse statistical research--by, say, buying a copy of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> and opening it to the last page, which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> conveniently
offers tables summarizing economic data for a number of emerging economies. We
immediately learn something interesting: Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garten</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Ten</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six</NUMEX> run trade
deficits (as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as a whole); <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> run current account deficits. Of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> economies listed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> run trade deficits and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> run current account
deficits. Wage numbers are a little harder to come by, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Bureau of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Statistics</ENAMEX> makes such data available on its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Labor Statistics</ENAMEX>
Web site. There we find that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>
received <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 6 percent</NUMEX> as much <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per hour</NUMEX> as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>; by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, the numbers were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent and 43 percent</NUMEX>, respectively.

            Surprise! The facts fit the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panglossian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>'s vision
quite nicely: Emerging economies do typically run trade deficits, wages do rise
with productivity, and actual experience offers no support at all for grimmer
visions.

            But those grim visions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persist</ENAMEX> nonetheless. For smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonelson</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>), this cannot
be a matter of simple ignorance: It must involve ignorance with intent. After
all, it must require real effort for a full-time trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX>, who not
only writes frequently about the Third World threat but also decorates his
writings with many statistics, not to notice that most of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> run
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> deficits rather than surpluses, or that wages have in fact increased
dramatically in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that used to have cheap labor. It is, I imagine,
equally difficult to pursue such a career without ever becoming aware of the
arithmetical necessity that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> attracting big inflows of capital must
run trade deficits.

            But
perhaps the uncanny ability not to notice these things is acquired by focusing
mainly on , which does appear to run a huge trade surplus even while attracting
lots of foreign capital. Most of that trade surplus, as we've seen, is a
statistical illusion. But it is still, at first sight, hard to understand how
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> can attract so much foreign investment without running a large current
account deficit. Where does the money go?

            
Auseful clue comes if we look again at the last
page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> and ask which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> runs the biggest trade
surplus of all. And the answer is ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> . Obviously this isn't
because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economy is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-</ENAMEX>competitive. What that trade surplus actually
reflects is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s sorry <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, in which nervous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> and corrupt
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> siphon off a large fraction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s foreign exchange
earnings, parking it in safe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">havens</ENAMEX> abroad rather than making it available to
pay for imports.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, if you think about
it, suffers from a milder form of the same ailment. The reason those inflows of
foreign capital don't finance a trade deficit is that they are offset by
outflows of domestic capital. In particular, huge sums are being invested
abroad to establish overseas nest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> for honest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> just in
case <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> ends up looking like the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, and no doubt to
establish similar nest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> for corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> just in case the rest
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> ends up looking like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. To the extent that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> does run a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> surplus, in other words, that surplus is a sign of weakness rather than
strength.

            None of this should be taken
as an apology for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s thoroughly nasty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. I fear the worst in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>, and worry as much as anyone about the effects of growing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> power on
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s political and military stability. One thing I don't worry about,
however, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s trade surplus. Neither should you.

         
      
   
