
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby-</ENAMEX>Sitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economy</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years ago</TIMEX> I read a
story that changed my life. I think about that story often; it helps me to stay
calm in the face of crisis, to remain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> in times of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, and to
resist the pull of fatalism and pessimism. At this gloomy moment, when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s
woes seem to threaten the world economy as a whole, the lessons of that
inspirational tale are more important than ever.

            The story
is told in an article titled "Monetary Theory and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby-Sitting Co-op Crisis</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Sweeney</ENAMEX> published it in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Money</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banking</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. I've used their story in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my books, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peddling Prosperity and The Accidental Theorist</ENAMEX> ,
but it bears retelling, this time with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> twist.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeneys</ENAMEX> tell the story of--you guessed it--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby-</ENAMEX>sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to which they belonged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1970s</TIMEX>. Such co-ops
are quite common: A group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (in this case <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 150</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> with
congressional connections) agrees to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sit for one another, obviating the
need for cash payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX>. It's a mutually beneficial arrangement:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> that already has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> around may find that watching another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> is not that much of an additional burden,
certainly compared with the benefit of receiving the same service some other
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. But there must be a system for making sure each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> does its fair
share.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> fairly natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX>. It issued scrip--pieces
of paper equivalent to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sitting time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitters</ENAMEX> would
receive the appropriate number of coupons directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sittees</ENAMEX>. This
made the system self-enforcing: Over time, each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> would automatically do
as much baby-sitting as it received in return. As long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were
reliable--and these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> certainly were--what could go
wrong?

            
Well, it turned out that there was a small
technical problem. Think about the coupon holdings of a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. During
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods</TIMEX> when it had few occasions to go out, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> would probably try to
build up a reserve--then run that reserve down when the occasions arose. There
would be an averaging out of these demands. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> would be going out when
another was staying at home. But since many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> would be holding reserves
of coupons at any given time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> needed to have a fairly large amount of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scrip</ENAMEX> in circulation.

            Now what
happened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeneys</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> was that, for complicated reasons involving the
collection and use of dues (paid in scrip), the number of coupons in
circulation became quite low. As a result, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> were anxious to add to
their reserves by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sitting, reluctant to run them down by going out. But
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s decision to go out was another's chance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sit; so it became
difficult to earn coupons. Knowing this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> became even more reluctant to
use their reserves except on special occasions, reducing baby-sitting
opportunities still further.

            In short, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> had fallen into a recession.

            Since most
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, it was difficult to convince them the
problem was monetary. They tried to legislate recovery--passing a rule
requiring each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> to go out at least twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>. But eventually the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> prevailed. More coupons were issued, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> became more willing to
go out, opportunities to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sit multiplied, and everyone was happy.
Eventually, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> issued too much scrip, leading to
different problems ...

            
If you think this is a silly story, a waste of
your time, shame on you. What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill Baby-Sitting Co-op</ENAMEX> experienced
was a real recession. Its story tells you more about what economic slumps are
and why they happen than you will get from reading <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Greider</ENAMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorials. And if you are
willing to really wrap your mind around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX>'s story, to play with it and
draw out its implications, it will change the way you think about the
world.

            For
example, suppose that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stock market was to crash, threatening to
undermine consumer confidence. Would this inevitably mean a disastrous
recession? Think of it this way: When consumer confidence declines, it is as
if, for some reason, the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> had become less willing to
go out, more anxious to accumulate coupons for a rainy day. This could indeed
lead to a slump--but need not if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> were alert and responded by
simply issuing more coupons. That is exactly what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> coupon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">issuer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>--and what I believe he would do again. So as I said at
the beginning, the story of the baby-sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> helps me to remain calm in
the face of crisis.

            Or suppose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> did not respond quickly enough and
that the economy did indeed fall into a slump. Don't panic. Even if the head
coupon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">issuer</ENAMEX> has fallen temporarily behind the curve, he can still ordinarily
turn the situation around by issuing more coupons--that is, with a vigorous
monetary expansion like the ones that ended the recessions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981-82</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-91</TIMEX>. So as I said, the story of the baby-sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> helps me remain
hopeful in times of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>.

            Above all,
the story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> tells you that economic slumps are not punishments for
our sins, pains that we are fated to suffer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> did not get
into trouble because its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were bad, inefficient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX>; its
troubles did not reveal the fundamental flaws of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> values" or
"crony baby-sittingism." It had a technical problem--too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> chasing
too little scrip--which could be, and was, solved with a little clear thinking.
And so, as I said, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX>'s story helps me to resist the pull of fatalism
and pessimism.

            
But if it's all so easy, how can a large part
of the world be in the mess it's in? How, for example, can <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> be stuck in a
seemingly intractable slump--one that it does not seem able to get out of
simply by printing coupons? Well, if we extend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX>'s story a little bit,
it is not hard to generate something that looks a lot like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
problems--and to see the outline of a solution.

            First, we
have to imagine a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of which realized there was an unnecessary
inconvenience in their system. There would be occasions when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> found
itself needing to go out several times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>, which would cause it to run
out of coupons--and therefore be unable to get its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> sat--even though it
was entirely willing to do lots of compensatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sitting at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later date</TIMEX>.
To resolve this problem, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to borrow extra
coupons from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in times of need--repaying with the coupons
received from . To prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> from abusing this privilege, however, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> would probably need to impose some penalty--requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> to
repay more coupons than they borrowed.

            Under this new system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> would hold smaller reserves
of coupons than before, knowing they could borrow more if necessary. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co-op</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> would, however, have acquired a new tool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> reported it was easy to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX> and hard to find
opportunities to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sit, the terms under which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> could borrow coupons
could be made more favorable, encouraging more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go out. If baby
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitters</ENAMEX> were scarce, those terms could be worsened, encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go
out less.

            In other
words, this more sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> would have a central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that could
stimulate a depressed economy by reducing the interest rate and cool off an
overheated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by raising it.

            
But what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>--where the economy slumps
despite interest rates having fallen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost to zero</NUMEX>? Has the baby-sitting
metaphor finally found a situation it cannot handle?

            Well,
imagine there is a seasonality in the demand and supply for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sitting.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>, when it's cold and dark, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> don't want to go out much
but are quite willing to stay home and look after other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--thereby accumulating points they can use on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">balmy summer evenings.</TIMEX> If
this seasonality isn't too pronounced, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> could still keep the supply
and demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sitting in balance by charging low interest rates in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter months</TIMEX>, higher rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>. But suppose that the seasonality is
very strong indeed. Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>, even at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> interest rate, there
will be more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> seeking opportunities to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sit than there are couples
going out, which will mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sitting opportunities will be hard to
find, which means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> seeking to build up reserves for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> fun will
be even less willing to use those points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>, meaning even fewer
opportunities to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-sit ... and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> will slide into a recession even at
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> interest rate.

            And this is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s discontent. Perhaps
because of its aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, perhaps also because of a general nervousness
about the future, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> does not appear willing to spend enough
to use the economy's capacity, even at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> interest rate. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, say the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, has fallen into the dread "liquidity trap." Well, what you have
just read is an infantile explanation of what a liquidity trap is and how it
can happen. And once you understand that this is what has gone wrong, the
answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s problems is, of course, .

            So the story of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby-</ENAMEX>sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">co-op</ENAMEX> is not a mere amusement. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would only take it
seriously--if they could only understand that when great economic issues are at
stake, whimsical parables are not a waste of time but the key to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enlightenment</ENAMEX>--it is a story that could save the world.

         
      
   
