
   
   
      
         
            Bahtulism

            I often run
into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who assert confidently that massive speculative attacks on
currencies like the ones on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> pound in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> peso in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994-1995</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">baht</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, prove that we are in a new world in which
computerized trading, satellite hookups, and all that mean that old economic
rules, and conventional economic theory, no longer apply. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One physicist</ENAMEX>
insisted that the economy has "gone nonlinear," and is now governed by chaos
theory.) But the truth is that currency crises are old hat. The travails of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> franc in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '20s</TIMEX> were thoroughly modern, and the speculative attacks
that brought down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bretton Woods</ENAMEX> system of exchange rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>
were almost as big, compared with the size of the economies involved, as the
biggest recent blowouts. Currency crises have been a favorite topic of
international financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> ever since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. In fact, they are
among my favorite topics--after all, I helped found the field.

            The
standard economic model of currency crises had its genesis in a brilliant
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'70s</TIMEX> analysis of the gold market by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Henderson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Salant</ENAMEX>, two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>. They showed that abrupt speculative attacks,
which would almost instantly wipe out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s stockpile, were a
natural consequence of typical price-stabilization schemes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> I was an
intern at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>, and realized that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Henderson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salant</ENAMEX>'s story could, with
some reinterpretation, be applied to currency crises that suddenly wipe out the
government's foreign exchange reserves. A bit later <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Flood</ENAMEX>, now at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Garber</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, produced the canonical
version of that conventional story.

            The key
lesson from that conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is that abrupt runs on a currency, which
move <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in a very short time, are not necessarily the result
of either irrational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> stampedes or evil financial manipulation. On the
contrary, they are the normal result when rational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> contemplate the
implications of unsustainable policies.

            Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, however--notably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Obstfeld</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichengreen</ENAMEX>--argue that the standard model is too mechanical in its
representation of government policy, and that the more complex motives of
actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> make speculation a more uncertain and perhaps more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pernicious</ENAMEX> affair. Self-fulfilling crises, in which a currency that could have
survived is nonetheless brought down, are a hot topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. But everyone
agrees that a sufficiently credible currency will never be attacked, and a
sufficiently incredible one will always come under fire.

         
      
   
