
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soft Microeconomics</ENAMEX>

            I wrote this piece in
WordPerfect, not Word, mainly because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Word</ENAMEX>'s equation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> is awful (are you
listening, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myhrvold</ENAMEX>?), and I may as well use the same software for plain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English</ENAMEX> articles and professional gobbledygook. I surf with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX>
and check e-mail in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eudora</ENAMEX>. So, I am not a fan of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s products.
Moreover, for reasons explained below, it is in the public interest to have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> always running a bit scared of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless,
the more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-MS</ENAMEX> propaganda I read, the more pro-MS I get. There is a
case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, but it is not the one you hear, and I would hate to see
crude misunderstandings posing as sophisticated analysis prevail.

            Probably the first thing one
ought to say is that the public has no interest in helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' rivals
for their own sake. It's easy to think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who run software companies
other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as underdogs fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bad Bill</ENAMEX>. But those "little"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are no more in need of extra money than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is, and if allowing him to
get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an extra billion</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Ellison</ENAMEX>'s--or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Andreesen</ENAMEX>'s--expense is
good for the rest of us, so be it. Those of us who do not get paid in software
stock options should not allow ourselves to become pawns, either way, in
struggles among those who do.

            So what
is the public interest?

            The case for leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> alone does not rest on some
naive faith in the perfection of free markets. Software is an industry
characterized by powerful increasing returns in both production and
consumption: The more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units Netscape ships</ENAMEX>, the lower its per unit cost; the
more copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Navigator</ENAMEX> in use, the more attractive it is to the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>.
These increasing returns make the kind of atomistic, "perfect" competition that
prevails in the market for, say, wheat impossible in the market for browsers or
word processors. Necessarily, each type of product will in the end be produced
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a few</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>.

            But how
does this concentration of production take place? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the depressing things
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> public discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case, even among supposedly
well-informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, is that much of it has come to be dominated by a
basically primitive view about what increasing returns do to markets--namely,
that they convey monopoly power purely randomly, on whoever happens to be in
the right place at the right time--and that this "path dependence" allows
clearly inferior technologies to become "locked in." Now path dependence has
its place--but when applied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case it misses the point. After
all, high-technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are themselves quite aware of increasing
returns, and their strategies--above all the prices they charge when they are
trying to establish themselves in a market--are very much affected by that
awareness.

            
Consider, for example, one particular form of
increasing returns: The so-called "learning curve," which says the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> units
of something you have already produced, the lower the cost of producing the
next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. You might think this means that whoever gets into a market first will
simply have a snowballing advantage. But as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Spence</ENAMEX> pointed
out in a classic, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> on this subject, profit-maximizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that know they face a learning curve will compete fiercely to move
down it more rapidly, selling cheaply in the early stages of a product cycle
(and therefore losing money) in the hope of making the money back later.

            The same
logic applies to increasing returns on the demand side: As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, if I
know that a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>'s choice of browser depends both on the price and
on the number of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> using that browser, I will initially make my own
browser cheap--maybe even free--so as to build market share. In either case I
must incur initial losses that are, in effect, part of the price of entry into
the market--an add-on to the cost of developing a product in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.
And because nobody will want to pay this entry fee without a reasonable hope of
earning it back, only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will enter a market subject to strong
increasing returns. The point is that the eventual domination of an industry by
a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--and a high rate of profit on sales for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the
later stages of the cycle--doesn't happen because these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> just happened
to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> start. On the contrary, it is precisely because it isn't
purely a matter of luck--because everyone competes so fiercely on prices in an
effort to get some of those nice increasing returns--that only a few dare
enter.

            Of course, there is also an element of luck. It's
not true that whoever gets a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> start always dominates the market--if a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> start but offers a clearly inferior product or has
clearly higher costs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> can and will overtake it. But nobody can be sure
just what an as-yet undeveloped product will cost to produce, or how it will go
over with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. Thus, competition in a market characterized by increasing
returns is--as it must be--a sort of demolition derby in which only some of
those who enter cross the finish line. Those who do make it across the finish
line will typically make big profits. But this profitability is necessary to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX>. Who will enter a demolition derby without the ?

            So this is
the case for leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> alone: High-tech competition is, necessarily, a
competition that ends up being won by a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. Those who make vast
fortunes may not always be the most deserving--but so what? For the rest of us,
what matters is not who wins or loses, but how they play the game. And if they
know or suspect that too much success will be punished--that anyone who does
too well will become a target of envy-driven litigation--they will have that
much less incentive to play hard.

            
Now there is, of course, also a case against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. Never mind the crude complaint that it is too big, or too
profitable, or that nerdy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> tend to dislike its products. The real concern
is that because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s victory in an earlier derby happens to have given
it control over a particularly strategic part of the industry--because it
supplies operating systems--it is in a position to squeeze out rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>
of other software. And that is a real concern: If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> had, for example,
written Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> in a way that made it hard or even impossible for me to use
WordPerfect, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> would have been absolutely justified in
calling out the arsonists.

            But the
fact is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> has been very careful not to use its undoubted power to
practice any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, obvious version of what is known in the trade as "vertical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreclosure</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> work just fine on my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Windows</ENAMEX>-based
machine. This restraint may partly reflect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s market strategy--after
all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> partly because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> did practice vertical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreclosure</ENAMEX>, and as a result inhibited the development of complementary
software (although the main problem was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s persistent belief, despite all
the evidence to the contrary, that everyone would be willing to pay a premium
price for a niftier machine). For sure, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has mainly been
restrained by the knowledge that any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX> use of its power would indeed land
it in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            And yet, despite all that restraint, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is in court
anyway. Any nontechnologist ventures into the browser wars at his peril, but
here is how I understand it: After initially missing the significance of the
Internet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has gone to the other extreme, designing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 95</ENAMEX> so that
it uses an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internetlike</ENAMEX> metaphor for everything. It makes sense, then, for a
browser that can find both internal and external documents to be an integral
part of the system--unless, that is, you regard browsers and operating systems
as still basically different things, and view <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as practicing vertical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreclosure</ENAMEX> under the guise of product enhancement. Well, maybe--but it's a
pretty subtle point. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> isn't preventing anyone from using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> or
charging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> for the right of access; it's providing Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>
free, but then that would be normal practice in this kind of industry even if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> wasn't allegedly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">an integral part of Windows</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>. You can argue that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has stepped across the line on this one--but surely by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few</TIMEX>
inches.

            Here's what worries me: Given
the subtlety of the real issues here, what is the chance that this stuff will
be decided on its merits? When you hear that despite the fact that he has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> who know better, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Klein</ENAMEX> apparently
either believes or chooses to claim that this case is about path
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dependence</ENAMEX>, you start to wonder. And when you hear that the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> side
has retained the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of that economic and technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, you
start to despair.

         
      
   
