
   
   
      
         
            Paradigms of Panic

            There were warning signs
aplenty. Anyone could have told you about the epic corruption--about tycoons
whose empires depended on their political connections and about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
growing rich in ways best not discussed. Speculation, often ill informed, was
rampant. Besides, how could <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> hope to know what they were buying, when
few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> kept scrupulous accounts? Yet most brushed off these well-known
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vices</ENAMEX> as incidental to the real story, which was about economic growth that was
the wonder of the world. Indeed, many regarded the cronyism as a virtue rather
than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>, the signature of an economic system that was more concerned with
getting results than with the niceties of the process. And for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the faint
voices of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> were drowned out by the roar of an economic engine
fueled by ever larger infusions of foreign capital.

            The
crisis began small, with the failure of a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">financial institutions</ENAMEX> that had
bet too heavily that the boom would continue, and the bankruptcy of a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that had taken on too much debt. These failures frightened
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, whose attempts to pull their money out led to more bank failures;
the desperate attempts of surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to raise cash caused both a credit
crunch (pushing many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that had seemed financially sound only months
before over the brink) and plunging stock prices, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankrupting</ENAMEX> still more
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, the panic had reduced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
sudden destitution. Moreover, the financial disaster soon took its toll on the
real economy, too: As industrial production skidded and unemployment soared,
there was a surge in crime and worker unrest.

            But why am I telling you what happened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125 years ago</TIMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Panic of 1873</ENAMEX>?

            Anyone who claims to fully
understand the economic disaster that has overtaken <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> proves, by that very
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">certainty</ENAMEX>, that he . The truth is that we have never seen anything quite like
this, and that everyone--from the country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary</ENAMEX>
Fund and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX> who must prescribe economic medicine to those
of us who have the luxury of irresponsibility--is groping frantically for
models and metaphors to make sense of this thing. The usual round of academic
and quasiacademic conferences and round tables has turned into a sort of
rolling rap session, in which the usual suspects meet again and again to trade
theories and, occasionally, accusations. Much of the discussion has focused on
the hidden weaknesses of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies and how they produced fertile
ground for a financial crisis; the role of runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> that exploited
political connections to gamble with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s money has emerged as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime suspect</ENAMEX>. But amid the tales of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">rupiah</NUMEX> and ringgit one also hears
surprisingly old-fashioned references--to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Kindleberger</ENAMEX>'s classic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>
book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manias, Panics, and Crashes</ENAMEX> , and even to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Bagehot</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lombard Street</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1873</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s debacle, a growing number of us now think,
is at least in part a souped-up modern version of a traditional, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1873</TIMEX>-style
financial panic.

            The logic
of financial panic is fairly well understood in principle, thanks both to the
old literary classics and to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> mathematical formalization by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Douglas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Dybvig</ENAMEX>. The starting point for panic theory is the
observation that there is a tension between the desire of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> for
flexibility--the ability to spend whenever they feel like it--and the economic
payoff to commitment, to sticking with long-term projects until they are
finished. In a primitive economy there is no way to avoid this tradeoff--if you
want to be able to leave for the desert on short notice, you settle for matzo
instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, and if you want ready cash, you keep <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> coins under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mattress</ENAMEX>. But in a more sophisticated economy this dilemma can be finessed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BankBoston</ENAMEX> is largely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of lending money at long term--say,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> mortgages--yet it offers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depositors</ENAMEX> such as me, who supply that money,
the right to withdraw it any time we like.

            
What a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">intermediary</ENAMEX> (a bank or
something more or less like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>) does is pool the money of a large number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and put most of that money into long-term investments that are
"illiquid"--that is, hard to turn quickly into cash. Only a fairly small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reserve</ENAMEX> is held in cash and other "liquid" assets. The reason this works is the
law of averages: On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any given day</TIMEX>, deposits and withdrawals more or less
balance out, and there is enough cash on hand to take care of any difference.
The individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depositor</ENAMEX> is free to pull his money out whenever he wants; yet
that money can be used to finance projects that require long-term commitment.
It is a sort of magic trick that is fundamental to making a complex economy
work.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>, however, has its
risks. Normally , financial intermediation is a wonderful thing; but now
and then, disaster strikes. Suppose that for some reason--maybe a groundless
rumor--many of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depositors</ENAMEX> begin to worry that their money isn't safe.
They rush to pull their money out. But there isn't enough cash to satisfy all
of them, and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s other assets are illiquid, it cannot sell them
quickly to raise more cash (or can do so only at fire-sale prices). So the bank
goes bust, and the slowest-moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depositors</ENAMEX> lose their money. And those who
rushed to pull their money out are proved right--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> wasn't safe,
after all. In short, financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">intermediation</ENAMEX> carries with it the risk of bank
runs, of self-fulfilling panic.

            A panic,
when it occurs, can do far more than destroy a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>. Like the Panic of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1873</TIMEX>--or the similar panics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1893</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1920</TIMEX>; and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of all
bank runs (which, much more than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX> stock crash, caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX>)--it can spread to engulf the whole economy. Nor is strong long-term
economic performance any guarantee against such crises. As the list suggests,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was not only subject to panics but also unusually
crisis-prone compared with other advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very years</TIMEX> that
it was establishing its economic and technological dominance.

            Why, then, did the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis catch everyone by surprise?
Because there was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half-century</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, when they just
didn't seem to make panics the way they used to. In fact, we--by which I mean
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and everyone else I can think
of--had pretty much forgotten what a good old-fashioned panic was like. Well,
now we remember.

            I'm not
saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s economies were "fundamentally sound," that this was a
completely unnecessary crisis. There are some smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--most notably
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Sachs</ENAMEX>--who believe that, but my view is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies
had gone seriously off the rails well before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>, and that some kind of
unpleasant comeuppance was inevitable. That said, it is also true that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s
experience is not unique; it follows the quite similar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> "tequila"
crisis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX> at least some resemblance to the earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> debt crisis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. In each case there were some serious policy
mistakes made that helped make the economies vulnerable. Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are no
more stupid or irresponsible now than they used to be; how come the punishment
has become so much more severe?

            
Part of the answer may be that our financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> has become dangerously efficient. In response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and just about everyone else imposed elaborate regulations on
their banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>. Like most regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regimes</ENAMEX>, this one ended up working
largely for the benefit of the regulatees--restricting competition and making
ownership of a bank a more or less guaranteed sinecure. But while the
regulations may have made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> fat and sluggish, it also made them safe.
Nowadays <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are by no means guaranteed to make money: To turn a profit they
must work hard, innovate--and take big risks.

            Another part of the
answer--one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kindleberger</ENAMEX> suggested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX>--is that to introduce
global financial markets into a world of merely national monetary authorities
is, in a very real sense, to walk a tightrope without a net. As long as finance
is a mainly domestic affair, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> run is local
money--and, guess what, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is able to print as much as it wants.
But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indonesians</ENAMEX> started running from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX>, what
they wanted was dollars--and neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> can
give them enough of what they want.

            I am not
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who believes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis will or even can cause a
world depression. In fact, I think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is still, despite
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, more at risk from inflation than deflation. But what worries me--aside
from the small matter that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, with a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, seems at
the time of writing to be sliding toward the abyss--is the thought that we may
have to get used to such crises. Welcome to the New World Order.

            If you
missed our previous link to the sidebar, click .

         
      
   
