
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gold Bug Variations</ENAMEX>

            The legend of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midas</ENAMEX> has
been generally misunderstood. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> that turned
everything the old miser touched into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, leaving him unable to eat or drink,
was a lesson in the perils of avarice. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midas</ENAMEX>' true sin was his failure to
understand monetary economics. What the gods were really telling him is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> is just a metal. If it sometimes seems to be more, that is only because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> has found it convenient to use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> as a medium of exchange--a bridge
between other, truly desirable, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>. There are other possible mediums of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exchange</ENAMEX>, and it is silly to imagine that this pretty, but only moderately
useful, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> has some irreplaceable significance.

            But there
are many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--nearly all of them ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>--who reject that
lesson. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bartley</ENAMEX> are best known for their promotion of supply-side economics,
they are equally dedicated to the belief that the key to prosperity is a return
to the gold standard, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Keynes</ENAMEX> pronounced a "barbarous relic"
more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years ago</TIMEX>. With any luck, these latter-day <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midases</ENAMEX> will never lay
a finger on actual monetary policy. Nonetheless, these are influential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--they are one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> now struggling for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>'s
soul--and the passionate arguments they make for a gold standard are a useful
window on how they think.

            There is a case to be made for a return to the gold
standard. It is not a very good case, and most sensible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> reject it,
but the idea is not completely crazy. On the other hand, the ideas of our
modern gold bugs are completely crazy. Their belief in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> is, it turns
out, not pragmatic but mystical.

            The
current world monetary system assigns no special role to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>; indeed, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> is not obliged to tie the dollar to anything. It can print as
much or as little money as it deems appropriate. There are powerful advantages
to such an unconstrained system. Above all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> is free to respond to
actual or threatened recessions by pumping in money. To take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> example,
that flexibility is the reason the stock market crash of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>--which started
out every bit as frightening as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that of 1929</TIMEX>--did not cause a slump in the real
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>.

            
While a freely floating national money has
advantages, however, it also has risks. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, it can create
uncertainties for international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the dollar has been worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as 120 yen and as little as 80</NUMEX>. The
costs of this volatility are hard to measure (partly because sophisticated
financial markets allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> to hedge much of that risk), but they must
be significant. Furthermore, a system that leaves monetary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> free to do
good also leaves them free to be irresponsible--and, in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, they
have been quick to take the opportunity. That is why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with a history
of runaway inflation, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>, often come to the conclusion that
monetary independence is a poisoned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chalice</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Argentine</ENAMEX> law now requires that
one peso be worth exactly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one U.S. dollar</NUMEX>, and that every peso in circulation
be backed by a dollar in reserves.)

            So, there
is no obvious answer to the question of whether or not to tie a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
currency to some external standard. By establishing a fixed rate of exchange
between currencies--or even adopting a common currency--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> can eliminate
the uncertainties of fluctuating exchange rates; and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a history
of irresponsible policies may be able to gain credibility by association. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wants to join a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Monetary Union</ENAMEX> largely because it
hopes to refinance its massive debts at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> interest rates.) On the other
hand, what happens if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have joined their currencies, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> finds
itself experiencing an inflationary boom while the other is in a deflationary
recession? (This is exactly what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, when
western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> boomed while the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> slid into double-digit
unemployment.) Then the monetary policy that is appropriate for one is exactly
wrong for the other. These ambiguities explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> are divided over
the wisdom of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s attempt to create a common currency. I personally think
that it will lead, on average, to somewhat higher <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> unemployment rates;
but many sensible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> disagree.

            So where does gold enter the picture?

            While some
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have chosen, with reasonable justification, to renounce their
monetary autonomy in favor of some external standard, the standard they choose
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is always the currency of another, presumably more responsible,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> seeks salvation from the dollar; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> from the deutsche
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mark</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>, and even those who run the German
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bundesbank</ENAMEX>, are mere mortals, who may yet succumb to the temptations of the
printing press. Why not ensure monetary virtue by trusting not in the wisdom of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but in an objective standard? Why not emulate our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfathers</ENAMEX> and
tie our currencies to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>?

            Very few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> think this would be a good idea. The argument against it is one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pragmatism</ENAMEX>, not principle. First, a gold standard would have all the
disadvantages of any system of rigidly fixed exchange rates--and even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> who are enthusiastic about a common <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency generally
think that fixing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency to the dollar or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">yen</NUMEX> would be going too
far. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, and crucially, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> is not a stable standard when measured
in terms of other goods and services. On the contrary, it is a commodity whose
price is constantly buffeted by shifts in supply and demand that have nothing
to do with the needs of the world economy--by changes, for example, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dentistry</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> abandoned its policy of
stabilizing gold prices back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. Since then the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> has
increased roughly tenfold, while consumer prices have increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 250</NUMEX>
percent. If we had tried to keep the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> from rising, this would have
required a massive decline in the prices of practically everything
else--deflation on a scale not seen since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>. This doesn't sound
like a particularly good idea.

            So why
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>, the Wall 
               Street 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , and so on so
fixated on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>? I did not fully understand their position until I read a
recent letter to, of all places, the left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jude Wanniski</ENAMEX>--one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> of supply-side economics
and its reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the many comic-opera touches in the late
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unlamented Dole</ENAMEX> campaign was the constant struggle between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>, who tried
incessantly to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanniski</ENAMEX> a key role, and the sensible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> who tried
to keep him out.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanniski</ENAMEX>'s main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> was to deny that the rich have gotten
richer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent decades</TIMEX>; his letter is posted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> Web site, and makes interesting reading.

            But, particularly noteworthy was the following passage:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> let us get our
accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> squared away. To measure anything in the floating paper dollar
will get us nowhere. We must convert all wealth into the measure employed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6,000 years</TIMEX>, i.e., <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ounces</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. On this measure, the Dow Jones
industrial average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 60 percent</NUMEX> of the DJIA of 30 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, when it hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>. Back then, gold was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> per ounce. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$380</NUMEX>-plus. This is another way of saying that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 30 years</TIMEX>, the people
who owned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> have lost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of their wealth held in the form of
equity. ... If you owned no part of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX>, because you
were poor, you lost nothing. If you owned lots of it, you lost your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> in
the general inflation.
            

            Never mind the question of
whether the Dow Jones industrial average is the proper measure of how well the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> are doing. What is fascinating about this passage is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanniski</ENAMEX> regards
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> as the appropriate measure of wealth, regardless of the quantity of other
goods and services that it can buy. Since the dollar was de-linked from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> has risen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 700 percent</NUMEX>, while the prices of the goods we
ordinarily associate with the pursuit of happiness--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, clothes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>--have gone up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 250 percent</NUMEX>. In terms of the ability to
buy almost anything except gold, the purchasing power of the rich has soared;
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanniski</ENAMEX> insists that this is irrelevant, because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, and only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, is
the true standard of value. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanniski</ENAMEX>, in other words, has committed the sin of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Midas</ENAMEX>: He has forgotten that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> is only a metal, and that its value
comes only from the truly useful goods for which it can be exchanged.

            I wonder whether the gods
read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>. If so, they know what to do.

         
      
   
