
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX> of Biobabble

            The
invitation came, rather disappointingly, by conventional mail. Still, it
sounded enticing: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato Institute</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bionomics Institute</ENAMEX> invite you to
Now What? Living <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With Perpetual Evolution</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> Bionomics
Conference." Leading the list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13-15</TIMEX> conference was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Benford</ENAMEX>, one of my favorite science-fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. And at the top of
the card was a stirring quotation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bionomics Institute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX>:

            Like a deep-sea volcano
bursting to the surface, spewing out vast new lands soon to be inhabited by a
complex ecosystem, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is creating a virtual landscape that will soon be
occupied by an awesome array of economic organisms. ... It's evolution at warp
speed. Strap yourself in.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libertarian think tank</ENAMEX> noted mostly for its adamant opposition
to government regulation. But what on earth (or in cyberspace) is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bionomics</ENAMEX>--and why is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASAP</ENAMEX> , which is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-sponsor</ENAMEX> of the conference) promoting it?

            Although you have to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothschild</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> book,
Bionomics: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economy</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ecosystem</ENAMEX> , to get the full flavor, the essential
tenets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> are spelled out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bionomics Institute</ENAMEX> home page,
which offers a primer called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Bionomics 101</ENAMEX>." The primer explains:

            [A]ll traditional schools
of economics are based on the concepts of classical physics, while bionomics is
based on the principles of evolutionary biology. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>]rthodox economics
describes the "economy as a machine." ... Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bionomics</ENAMEX> says that an
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> is like an "evolving ecosystem." A modern market economy is like a
tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rainforest</ENAMEX>.

            Sounds
good, doesn't it? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bionomics</ENAMEX> has won converts not only at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato Institute</ENAMEX> but
also among a wide variety of influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde Prestowitz</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> has described it as "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policymakers</ENAMEX>' version
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Celestine Prophecy</ENAMEX> .") And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> is certainly a bright,
energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>. There are, however, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big weaknesses in his thinking: He
doesn't know much about economics, and he doesn't know much about evolution.
When I say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> doesn't know much about economics, I don't mean that
conventional economics is right and his ideas are wrong--although where they
differ that is generally true. I mean that his description of what conventional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> is all about bears no relation to what actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> believe or
say.

            
Take, for starters, his assertion that
"orthodox economics describes the 'economy as a machine.' " You might presume
from his use of quotation marks that this is something an actual economist
said, or at least that it was the sort of thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> routinely say.
But no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> I know thinks of the economy as being anything like a
machine--or believes, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> asserts a bit later, that because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> is like a machine, it is possible to make precise predictions. (In
fact, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> who came up with the famed "random walk" hypothesis
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> stock prices, which says that they are inherently
unpredictable.)

            It gets
better. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> tells us, "I know this is hard for non-economists to
believe, but orthodox economics essentially ignores technological change." That
is even harder for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> to believe. In fact, I don't know how I'm going
to break the news to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. You see, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Solow</ENAMEX> is
under the impression that he got the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> for his work on technological
change, in particular for his demonstration that technology, not capital
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX>, historically has been the main driving force in economic growth.
On a different subject, it's going to be a shock to environmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>--who have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> arguing that one good way to control
pollution is to create a market in emission permits--to learn that this is an
idea unique to bionomics and totally at odds with orthodox economic thinking.
And I'm not feeling too good myself: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> insists that conventional
economics depends on the assumption of diminishing returns and that, as a
result, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> have completely ignored the possibility of increasing
returns. Does this mean I have to give back that medal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Economic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> gave me for my work on increasing returns and international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>?

            Well, all this is more or less the usual. Whenever a
manifesto about economics contains a sentence that begins, "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> economics
assumes that ..." it almost always completes that sentence with something
strange and unfamiliar. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just the last two years</TIMEX>, I've learned that I believe
that gross domestic product is the sole measure of economic welfare, that
growth at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 2.5 percent</NUMEX> always causes inflation, and that sudden
speculative attacks on currencies can't happen. I've also learned that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Memorial Prize</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Sciences</ENAMEX> keeps going to supply-siders--or
should that be Marxists?

            What is
surprising, however, is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who proposes to replace what he imagines to
be the mechanistic worldview of conventional economics with a new view based on
evolutionary biology should know so little about the discipline that supposedly
inspires him.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX>'s lack of familiarity with
evolutionary theory may not be obvious to uninformed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>--his book bristles
with ostentatious footnotes and seemingly learned references. It happens,
however, that I am an evolution groupie. I started as a fan of great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">popularizers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dawkins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>, and I have since graduated
not only to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> worship of the leading evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> but also to
reading textbooks and even journal articles. And so when I picked up a copy of
Bionomics , the first thing I did was check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s treatment of
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> and of what I knew to have been the important . His record was
perfect: Not one of the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> was mentioned, not one of the key
developments discussed. The bionomics version of what evolutionary theory is
about has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as little</NUMEX> to do with the real thing as its version of what economics
is about does.

            What the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bionomics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> apparently think evolution is about is constant,
breathless change--strap yourself in!--change so rapid that everything is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unpredictable</ENAMEX>, that the rules themselves are constantly changing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothschild</ENAMEX>
seems, in particular, to view evolutionary thinking as the antithesis of
"equilibrium economics." Apparently nobody told him that equilibrium
thinking--the idea that in order to understand how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> interact, it is
often useful to ask what would happen if each individual was doing the best he
or she could given what everyone else is doing--is almost as prevalent in . In
fact, the really funny thing is that for the most part the bionomics program
has already been implemented: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX> already is very similar to
evolutionary theory, and vice versa. However, neither field looks anything like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bionomics</ENAMEX>.

            OK, enough already. The really interesting question is why
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato Institute</ENAMEX> and other free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> should be willing to
squander their intellectual credibility by associating their names with this
sort of thing. After all, conventional economics already has lots of nice
things to say about free markets. Why not stick with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX>?

            Part of
the answer, I suspect, is sociological. Traditional conservative causes like
the gold standard tend to have a musty, old-fashioned feel. They sound like the
sort of thing that appeals mainly to rich old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (and conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX>
are, of course, mainly funded by rich old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>). Young, vigorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>
are therefore always looking for ways to seem more fashion-forward. Some of
them parade their knowledge of pop culture, some make a point of being
photographed wearing miniskirts, and some go for what we might call the
Wired style of economic rhetoric--the continual assertion that things
are changing! so fast! that we have to use lots! of exclamation points!!!

            
But there is also a more serious reason that
bionomics appeals to the free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>: They find the conventional case
for laissez-faire too modest, too conditional, for their tastes. Standard
economic theory offers reasons to believe that markets are a good way to
organize economic activity. But it does not deify the market system, and it
even offers a number of fairly well-defined ways in which markets can fail, or
at least could be helped with government intervention. And that, for some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, is just not good enough.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bionomics</ENAMEX> doesn't actually
provide any coherent argument in favor of free markets. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX>'s
original book seems to hedge its bets: It spends a full chapter ("<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Secret Weapon"</ENAMEX>) explaining how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government-business</ENAMEX> cooperation makes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy invincible (remember, the book was published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>). But
what the doctrine lacks in serious argument it makes up for in rhetoric. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> is an ecosystem, like a tropical rain forest! And what could be worse
than trying to control a tropical rain forest from the top down? You wouldn't
try to control an ecosystem, wiping out species you didn't like and
promoting ones you did, would you?

            Well,
actually, you probably would. I think it's called "agriculture."

            What do we learn from the willingness of extreme
free-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> to associate themselves with crank doctrines like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bionomics</ENAMEX>? I think the main lesson is that their faith in free markets is just
that: a faith, which does not rest on either logic or evidence. Belief comes
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>; then they look for arguments to justify that belief. And they are
therefore not too scrupulous about the quality of those arguments, or of those
who produce them.

            Anyway, I guess I won't
attend the conference. I would have liked to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Benford</ENAMEX>; but I couldn't stand
to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> 
               River demeaning himself
by consorting with such disreputable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
