
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unmitigated Gauls</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, just
after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">François Mitterrand</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, I attended my first
conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. I can't remember a thing about the conference itself,
although my impressions of the food and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>--this was my first adult visit to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>--remain vivid. The only thing I do remember is a conversation over
dinner ( canard aux olives ) with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, who
explained its plan to stimulate the economy with public spending while raising
wages and maintaining a strong <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">franc</NUMEX>.

            To the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> present this program sounded a bit, well, inconsistent. Wouldn't it,
we asked him, be a recipe for a balance of payments crisis (which duly
materialized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months later</TIMEX>)? "That's the trouble with you Anglo-Saxon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>--you're too wrapped up in your theories. You need to adopt a
historical point of view." Some of us did, in fact, know a little history.
Wasn't the plan eerily reminiscent of the failed program of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Blum</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>
government? "Oh no, what we are doing is completely unprecedented."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> have no monopoly on intellectual pretensions or
on muddled thinking. They may not even be more likely than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
combine the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. There is, however, something special about the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> discusses economics. In no other advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is the elite
so willing to let fine phrases overrule hard thinking, to reject the lessons of
experience in favor of delusions of grandeur.

            To an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s current problems do not seem particularly
mysterious. Jobs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> are like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>: Those who
provide them are subject to detailed regulation by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that is very
solicitous of their occupants. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> must pay his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> well and
provide generous benefits, and it is almost as hard to fire those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> as it
is to evict a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> policies have produced
very good deals for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but they have also made it very hard for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> to find a place to live. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s policies have produced nice work if
you can get it. But many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, especially the young, can't get it. And, given
the generosity of unemployment benefits, many don't even try.

            
True, some problems are easy to diagnose but
hard to deal with. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> can't end rent control, why should we
expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Chirac</ENAMEX> to be able to cure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eurosclerosis</ENAMEX>? But what is mysterious
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is that as far as one can tell, absolutely nobody of consequence
accepts the obvious diagnosis. On the contrary, there seems to be an emerging
consensus that what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> needs is--guess what?--more regulation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lionel Jospin</ENAMEX>'s idea of a pro-employment policy is to require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> the same money for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fewer hours</TIMEX>--an idea that was popular with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, the recent election results would suggest. Even conservative Phillipe
Seguin, regarded as an iconoclast by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> standards because he has questioned
the sacred goal of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> monetary union, thinks that one way to add jobs is
to ban self-service pumps at gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>.

            Beyond
more of the same, what does the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> see as the answer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
problems? For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX> its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have sought salvation in the idea
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>--that is, a unified <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> economy (under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, of
course), with common regulations and a common currency. In such a continental
market, they imagine, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> can once again prosper.

            Now a unified <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> market is a pretty good idea. There
is even a reasonable case for unifying <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s currencies--although there is
also a good case for doing no such thing. (There is a whole industry of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eurologists</ENAMEX>?--who make a living by debating that issue.) But to
acknowledge the potential virtues of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> economic integration risks
missing the essential fatuousness of the whole project. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s problem is
unemployment (currently <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 13 percent</NUMEX>). Nothing else is even remotely as
important. And whatever a unified market and a common currency may or may not
achieve, they will do almost nothing to create jobs.

            Think of
it this way: Imagine that several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, all suffering housing shortages
because of rent control, agree to make it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to
own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> in another. This is not a bad idea. It might even slightly
increase the supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>. But it is not going to get at the heart of
the problem. Yet all the grand schemes for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> integration amount to no
more than that.

            
Indeed, in practice the dream of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> unity
has actually made things worse. If you are going to have a common currency,
everything we know suggests you should follow what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Eichengreen</ENAMEX>
calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> strategy. But instead of just doing it, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> agreed
to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> transition period during which they would be required to meet a
complex set of criteria--mainly to reduce their budget deficits while keeping
their currencies strong.

            There is
nothing wrong with balancing your budget. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> need to do
some serious fiscal housecleaning. And as the happy experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has shown, it is quite possible to reduce the deficit and increase
employment at the same time. All you need to do is cut interest rates, so that
private spending takes up the slack. But you can't cut interest rates if you
are obliged to keep your currency strong. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Maastricht Treaty</ENAMEX> (the
blueprint for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency union) ensured that the budget-cutting it
required would be all pain and no gain. Nobody can make a precise estimate, but
a guess is that without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maastricht</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> might have an unemployment rate of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX>. Not great, but a couple of points better than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.

            While some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have been willing to say nice
things about budget deficits, nobody seems willing to challenge the dogma that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> integration is the answer. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seguin</ENAMEX> the iconoclast declares that
"the fight against unemployment is inseparable from the realization of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand European</ENAMEX> design."

            But let us
not blame <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. Their inanities only reflect the broader tone of
economic debate in a nation prepared to blame its problems on everything but
the obvious causes. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, say its best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and most popular
talking heads, is the victim of globalization--although adroit use of red tape
has held imports from low-wage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to a level far below that in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where the unemployment rate is now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> that of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, they say, is the victim of savage, unrestrained
capitalism--although it has the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the smallest private
sector of any large advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, they say, is the victim of
currency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speculators</ENAMEX>, whose ravages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX> once likened to those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.

            
The refusal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> to face up to
what looks like reality to the rest of us may doom the very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> dreams
that have sustained the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s illusions. After this last election it is
clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> will not be willing to submit to serious fiscal
discipline. Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> still be willing to give up their beloved deutsche
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mark</ENAMEX> in favor of a currency partly managed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>? It is equally clear that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> will not give up its taste for regulation--indeed, it will surely try to
impose that taste on its more market-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>.
That will give those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>--yes, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>--plenty of reason to
hesitate before forming a closer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>.

            But if it turns out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chirac</ENAMEX>'s political debacle is the beginning of a much larger disaster--the
collapse of the whole vision of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> glory that has obsessed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> for so
long--we can be sure of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> will blame it all on someone
else.

         
      
   
