
   
   
      
         
            Algorithms

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, for some
reason that now escapes me, I began to wonder what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
would make. Never mind his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> or his private life--I leave such matters
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. What I'm interested in is his mind. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--is an unusually bookish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>, one who reads serious tomes on
serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> and even tries to be a bit of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
pre-presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> tastes played a big role in determining the shape
of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years</TIMEX>. The same might be true of his
loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant</ENAMEX>. And so I picked up a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> environmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manifesto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Balance: Ecology and the Human Spirit</ENAMEX> . I can't
pass judgment on the scientific merits of the book's environmental analysis,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> touches on areas where I do know something and, in so doing, he gives
me some important clues to his intellectual style.

            Perhaps
the best way to think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> is to contrast him with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are deeply wonkish, clearly enjoying nothing (well, almost
nothing) more than long discussions on how to save the world with a simple
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>-point program. But the objects of their affections differ. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is most
attracted by matters social and economic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> by matters environmental and
scientific. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who attends panel discussions at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance Weekend</ENAMEX> and pores over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
pays personal calls on physicists and curls up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American</ENAMEX> .
And while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Rubin</ENAMEX> took him in hand, was a rather credulous
consumer of pop economics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s corresponding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> seems to be pop
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>.

            Which is not to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> in the Balance is
entirely free from pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">econ</ENAMEX>. The book contains a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, lamentably titled
"Eco-nomics," that perpetuates the oddly popular myth that conventional
economic theory is constitutionally incapable of dealing with environmental
problems. "Many popular textbooks on economic theory fail even to address
subjects as basic to our economic choices as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> or the depletion of
natural resources," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> declares. Actually, I have all the leading
introductory texts on my shelf (I'm writing one myself and am trying to steal
my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' ideas), and every one has an extensive section on environmental
issues. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> looks in vain in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s book for even a mention of the fundamentals
of standard environmental economics: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> as the prime example of an
"externality" (a social cost that the market does not properly value), and the
standard recommendation that externalities be corrected with pollution taxes or
tradable emission permits. (I wrote about the economics of environmentalism in

                  Slate
                <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Earth in the Balance Sheet</ENAMEX>.") Since these concepts have
actually made their way from theory into practice, one wonders how he missed
them. The introduction of tradable permits was an important feature of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>
revision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>, for example, and both fees and permits have been
crucial in efforts to protect the ozone layer.

            But for
me, at least, the really revealing part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> in the Balance was the
book's conclusion, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> talks about sandpiles and how they changed his
life.

            
Sandpiles, for those unfamiliar with pop
science trends, are the motivating example for a concept known as
"self-organized criticality," which, in turn, is one of the Big Ideas of
so-called "complexity theory." Imagine allowing sand to slowly trickle onto an
existing pile. Bit by bit the pile's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> will become steeper. When they
become too steep--when they exceed some "critical" slope--there will be an
avalanche. In simplified computer models of sandpiles (though not, apparently,
in all real sandpiles), a curious pattern emerges. Because the slope of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sandpile</ENAMEX> is always close to its critical value, dropping a single grain of sand
on the pile can produce anything from no effect to a massive sand slide.
Specifically, the distribution of avalanche sizes follows a particular
mathematical form known as a "power law" that is found in many natural and some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> phenomena, such as the sizes of earthquakes and the sizes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.
(For an example of the power law applied to city size, click .)

            What Per
Bak, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> who came up with the sandpile metaphor, has argued is
that because sandpile-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> produce power laws, and because there are
lots of power laws out there in the real world, such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> hold the key to
understanding, well, everything. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bak</ENAMEX>'s book explaining this idea is modestly
titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Nature Works</ENAMEX> . The reaction of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, as best I can
tell, is that the sandpile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is interesting, as is the prevalence of power
laws, but that his claims of having developed a universal theory are a bit
premature. (For more on power laws, click .)

            If you are wondering what all this has to do with saving
the planet, congratulations. But here is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, who made a pilgrimage to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bak</ENAMEX>, has to say:

            The sandpile
theory--self-organized criticality--is irresistible as a metaphor; one can
begin by applying it to the developmental stages of a human life. The formation
of identity is akin to the formation of the sandpile, with each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> being
unique and thus affected by events differently. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> reaches the
critical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> once the basic contours of its distinctive shape are revealed;
then the impact of each new experience reverberates throughout the whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, both directly, at the time it occurs, and indirectly, by setting the
stage for future change. Having reached this mature configuration, a person
continues to pile up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX> of experience, building on the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>. But
sometimes, at midlife, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX> start to stack up as if the entire pile is
still pushing upward, still searching for its mature shape. The unstable
configuration that results makes one vulnerable to a cascade of change. In
psychological terms, this phenomenon is sometimes called a midlife change.

            This may
sound silly, and it is. But it is a time-honored kind of silliness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is in
the grand tradition of those who thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX>'s theory of relativity
refuted not only classical physics but also conventional morality; or those who
imagined that because quantum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> showed that the apparent solidity of
the material world is an illusion, it vindicated the thoughts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mystics</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, these particular confusions don't seem to have done the
world any harm. So why not let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> find solace in sandpiles?

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> answer is that the speed with which
sexy-sounding scientific ideas get picked up by popular culture is getting
alarmingly high: from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physical Review Letters</ENAMEX> to the latest best seller
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Peters</ENAMEX> almost before you know it. This is arguably starting to distort
the practice of science itself. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Winslow</ENAMEX> puts it in a gently
skeptical review on self-organized criticality, "A theory can, once in the pop
science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, acquire a level of acceptance and momentum that may or may not
be warranted by its actual scientific credibility." And the track record of pop
science enthusiasms is uniformly dismal. Does anyone remember cybernetics or
catastrophe theory? Does anyone know what happened to chaos? It would be
unfortunate if the already worrying faddishness of science were to receive a
presidential seal of approval.

            I also have a more specific
worry: that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would give undue credence to the views of his
favorite pop science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Occasionally, I have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nightmarish</ENAMEX> vision in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe Institute</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX> of "complexity
theory" (whose heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hitters</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Kauffman</ENAMEX> and, yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>) actually starts having direct input into major policy decisions.
Now that would be scary.

            But I
guess I shouldn't take that nightmare seriously. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> in the
Balance was written a long time ago, and we may suppose that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> has
learned a lot since then. And anyway <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, if and when he becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, is
no more likely to give his personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gurus</ENAMEX> any real influence than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
would have been to place important policy decisions in the hands of, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magaziner</ENAMEX>.

            Missed our links to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) on
power laws and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an</NUMEX> of how the power law applies to city size? Here they are
again.

         
      
   
