
   
   
      
         
            Economic Culture Wars

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kuttner</ENAMEX> devotes an
essay
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Prospect</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> he edits, to an attack on my writings
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and elsewhere. Don't worry, I won't respond here to that attack. If
you're interested, you can read my response in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November-December</TIMEX> issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>. What I would like to discuss is what I think is the true
reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like myself and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX>--who also writes columns for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> --have so much trouble getting along. We
are both, after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>. I have even written for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospect</ENAMEX> . It is not, I claim, really a political issue in the normal sense.
What we are really fighting about is a matter of epistemology, of how one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perceives</ENAMEX> and understands the world.

            If you
try to follow arguments about economics among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> whose politics are
more or less left-of-center, you gradually become aware that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
in these arguments are divided not only by particular issues--deficit
reduction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>, and so on--but by the whole way that they think about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side there are those whose views are informed by academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>, the kind of stuff that is taught in textbooks. On the other there
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kuttner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Faux</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Policy Institute</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> have held university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointments</ENAMEX>. But most of them
lack academic credentials and, more important, they are basically hostile to
the kind of economics on which such credentials are based.

            If the anti-academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> does not draw its ideas from
textbook economics, however, where does its worldview come from? Well, here's a
story that may sound trivial but which I regard as revealing. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, I
supplied the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Prospect</ENAMEX> with an article on the problem of growing
income inequality. In the published piece, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuttner</ENAMEX>, improved on
my drab title, but also added a dreadful subtitle: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rich, the Right</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Facts: Deconstructing the Income Distribution Controversy</ENAMEX>."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deconstructing</ENAMEX> ? Why on earth would anyone not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Language Association</ENAMEX> want to use an academic buzzword that has been the butt of
so many jokes? (What do you get when you cross a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafioso</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deconstructionist</ENAMEX>? Someone who makes you an offer you can't understand.) How
could the cause of liberal revival be served by making me sound like a
character out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lodge</ENAMEX> satire?

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astrong</ENAMEX> desire to make economics less like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> and more like literary criticism is a surprisingly common attribute of
anti-academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> on the subject. For example, in a recent collection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essays</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundations of Research</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX>: How do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX>? , edited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven G. Medema</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Samuels</ENAMEX>),

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James K.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>, a constant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of the profession (and a frequent contributor to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Prospect</ENAMEX> ), urges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> to emulate "vibrant humanities
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">faculties</ENAMEX>" in which "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> develop viciously opinionated, inbred,
sometimes bitter and tyrannical but definitely exciting intellectual climates."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economics</ENAMEX>, in short, would be a better <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> economics department
were more like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> during its deconstructionist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heyday</ENAMEX>.

            Academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>, the stuff that is in the textbooks, is largely based on mathematical
reasoning. I hope you think that I am an acceptable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, but when it comes
to economics I speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>: I think in equations and
diagrams, then translate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of mainstream economics dislike people
like me not so much for our conclusions as for our style: They want economics
to be what it once was, a field that was comfortable for the basically literary
intellectual.

            This should sound familiar. More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years ago</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.P. Snow</ENAMEX> wrote his famous essay about the war
between the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cultures," between the essentially literary sensibility that
we expect of a card-carrying intellectual and the scientific/mathematical
outlook that is arguably the true glory of our civilization. That war goes on;
and economics is on the front line. Or to be more precise, it is territory that
the literati definitively lost to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only about 30 years ago</TIMEX>--and they
want it back.

            That is
what explains the lit-crit style so oddly favored by the leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of
mainstream economics. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> know that the quantitative,
algebraic reasoning that lies behind modern economics is very difficult to
challenge on its own ground. To oppose it they must invoke alternative
standards of intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> and legitimacy. In effect, they are saying,
"You have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Samuelson</ENAMEX> on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>? Well, we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Derrida</ENAMEX> on
ours."

            
A similar situation exists in other fields.
Consider, for example, evolutionary biology. Like most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>,
I first learned about this subject from the writings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Jay Gould</ENAMEX>. But
I eventually came to realize that working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> regard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX> much the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> regard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>: talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, too bad he never gets
anything right. Serious evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Maynard Smith</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hamilton</ENAMEX>, like serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, think largely in terms of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mathematical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the introduction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard Smith</ENAMEX>'s classic tract
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evolutionary Genetics</ENAMEX> flatly declares, "If you can't stand algebra, stay
away from evolutionary biology." There is a core set of crucial ideas in his
subject that, because they involve the interaction of several different
factors, can only be clearly understood by someone willing to sit still for a
bit of math. (Try to give a purely verbal description of the reactions among
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> mutually catalytic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>.)

            But many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> who
can't stand algebra are not willing to stay away from the subject. They are
thus deeply attracted to a graceful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX>, who frequently
misrepresents the field (perhaps because he does not fully understand its
essentially mathematical logic), but who wraps his misrepresentations in so
many layers of impressive, if irrelevant, historical and literary erudition
that they seem profound.

            Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard Smith</ENAMEX>
is right, both about evolution and about economics. There are important ideas
in both fields that can be expressed in plain <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and there are plenty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> doing fancy mathematical models. But there are also important ideas that
are crystal clear if you can stand algebra, and very difficult to grasp if you
can't. International trade in particular happens to be a subject in which a
page or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of algebra and diagrams is worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> volumes of mere words. That is
why it is the particular subfield of economics in which the views of those who
understand the subject and those who do not diverge most sharply.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, there is probably no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to resolve this conflict peacefully. It is possible for a very skillful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to convey in plain <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> a sense of what serious economics is about,
to hide the algebraic skeleton behind a more appealing facade. But that won't
appease the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>; they don't want economics with a literary facade, they
want economics with a literary core. And so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuttner</ENAMEX> will never be able to make peace, because we are engaged in a zero-sum
conflict--not over policy, but over intellectual boundaries.

            The literati truly cannot be
satisfied unless they get economics back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX>. But they can't have
it, because we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> have the better claim.

         
      
   
