
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raspberry for Free Trade</ENAMEX>

            Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have
suffered his humiliating rebuff over fast-track trade legislation if the
administration had not wasted crucial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> failing to take the issue
seriously? I don't know. Will that rebuff severely damage the world trading
system? I don't know. Is this the beginning of a more fundamental backlash
against globalization? I don't know that, either.

            What I do
know is that the arguments advanced by fast track's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual opponents</ENAMEX> are
stunningly specious. Consider the tale of the tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">berries</ENAMEX>.

            Here's the story: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last spring</TIMEX>, there was an outbreak of a
nasty disease known as cyclosporiasis, which was eventually traced to
Guatemalan raspberries. Together with some other incidents, this led to a
demand for tougher controls on imported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">produce</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> asked
for legislation that would allow him to ban <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> imports from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that do
not follow adequate sanitary standards in agriculture. Intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>
of globalization gleefully noted a double standard: We're willing to seize
shipments of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">berries</ENAMEX> to protect yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> (the sort of people
who eat raspberries out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>) from inadequate foreign sanitary standards,
so why aren't we willing to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> from inadequate foreign labor
standards? Isn't it the same thing?

            It isn't
the same thing, as the example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee Gifford</ENAMEX> will now demonstrate. A
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> back, you may remember, the infernally perky <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX> got some bad
press when it turned out that some of her clothing line was produced in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sweatshops employing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor. Since then she has had other
problems, which are more up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Wright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> than mine. But it is useful, as a thought
experiment, to ask how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of imports would have reacted had the story
been slightly different.

            
Imagine that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> imported a lot
of clothing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedonia</ENAMEX>. Without question, the growth of these
imports had cost some jobs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, and possibly exerted some
downward pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> wages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> might point out, in their
tiresome way, that the jobs lost in the clothing industry were more than
matched by jobs gained elsewhere. They might point out that trade, by allowing
each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to specialize in doing what it does relatively well, normally
raises productivity and incomes in both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. But these arguments would
not be much consolation to the displaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of the
affected clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>, and we would surely see a campaign against
Freedonian products--a campaign that would make the most of stories about the
low wages and terrible working conditions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freedonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>.

            Now
suppose that an investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Freedonia</ENAMEX> and discovered that
it was all a sham. In reality, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freedonia</ENAMEX> was a high-tech, high-wage economy:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Freedonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had been faking poverty in order to avoid paying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dues</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Freedonian</ENAMEX> clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> were able to undersell their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> not because of low wages but because robots and computers made them
highly efficient.

            Here's the question: Would the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> demanding limits on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedonian</ENAMEX> exports say, "Oh well, I guess that's OK, then"? Whom are we
kidding? The demands for protection would not abate because for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
industry competing against imports, it doesn't matter how the clothing was
produced . When the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> consumer is offered cheaper shirts from abroad, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> loses the same number of shirt-making jobs regardless of whether
the shirts were produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 cents</NUMEX> an hour or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> an hour.

            Now I come
to berry seizures--not to praise them (sorry, I couldn't help myself) but to
point out how different the case is. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">berries</ENAMEX>, it does
matter how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">berry</ENAMEX> was produced: If it was watered with sewage, eating it
will make you sick. And for now the only practical way to enforce health
standards on the product is to enforce sanitary standards on its production.
But if we impose the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inverted Kathie Lee Gifford</ENAMEX> test--asking how our attitude
would change if it turned out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX> were actually much
cleaner than rumor had it--we immediately see that our concern about foreign
sanitary standards, unlike our alleged concern about foreign labor standards,
is genuine.

            
Are those who want to impose import
restrictions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with low labor standards willing to lift those
restrictions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that start to pay decent wages? Circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
was still a low-wage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, accused of keeping its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in "rabbit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hutches</ENAMEX>" in order to pursue its relentless export drive. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> wages were actually higher than those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Did the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>-bashers relent? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> wages were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5 percent</NUMEX> of those
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>; by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> they had risen to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX>. Did opposition to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> exports dissipate?

            The real
complaint against developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> is not that their exports are based on
low wages and sweatshops. The complaint is that they export at all. And so the
supposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> abroad are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at all. If they got
their way the result for the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedonian</ENAMEX> would not just be no sweatshop--it
would be no job. And manufactured exports, initially based on low wages, are
the only route we know for rapid economic development.

            As I pointed out in an earlier column in

                  Slate
               , the growth of labor-intensive exports from Third World
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, a development possible only because those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are able to
offset their disadvantages by competing on the basis of cheap labor, has
brought about a huge improvement in the human condition, even if the wages look
miserably low by our standards.

            It is hard to believe that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, writing about economics are really
so fuzzy-minded that they cannot see the difference between protecting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> from tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">produce</ENAMEX> and protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> from competing products.
On the other hand, I doubt that they are purely cynical. It is more likely that
some kind of double-think, some convenient ability to stop thinking clearly
when the situation demands it, is at work. But the truth is that I don't
know--and I don't think it matters.

         
      
   
