
   
   
      
         
            Confessions of a Cybershaman

            The dramatic growth of the
Internet has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> extrapolating wildly. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX> we see something new and
amazing. Surely, given what we have seen so far, the future is bright! Don't
believe me? Need more details? Just ask your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> visionary.

            Predicting the future of
technology has gone from a minor sideline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX>
actively <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that future to a discipline of its own. No technology company
worth its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> lacks a full-time visionary on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. And every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marketer</ENAMEX> and
spinmeister must be a junior visionary. The higher-placed your visionary, the
more visionary your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will seem--so, by all means, promote <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Even so, make sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> does the "vision thing" as well.

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Visionary</ENAMEX>" has even become a profession. (As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX> once wrote:
When the going gets weird, the weird turn pro.) Their business cards don't have
"visionary" on them, but these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not hard to spot. They may be
"fellows" at some impressive-sounding institute you've never heard of before.
Or they might write a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> column and have recently published a
best-selling book. If you need more vision than that you can subscribe to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">newsletters</ENAMEX>, attend their elite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> conferences of industry big shots, or
invite them to speak or consult for astronomical fees.

            Being a visionary is a new profession, but it is really
just a variant on fortunetelling, which may be the world's oldest. And its
marketing appeal is similar--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will pay for reassurance about the unknown.
The fortunetellers of old had many techniques. Yet the crystal balls and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> are just apparatus. All fortunetelling, in fact, rests on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
pillars.

            First, you must tell people
more or less what you think they want to hear. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, you must spice your
predictions with drama. Nobody wants a prediction that the future will be more
or less like the present, even if that is, statistically speaking, an excellent
prediction. Predictions must involve either acquiring or losing love, wealth,
or life itself--ideally a combination of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>,
your predictions must somehow avoid measurement of their accuracy. Many tricks
have been invented to serve this end. Predictions can be vague, for example, or
couched in complicated gibberish. Either way, there is a loophole. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> generally don't mind: Seeking advice about the future is more about
relieving insecurity or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX> than about achieving statistical accuracy.

            
But being a fortuneteller is harder <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.
Chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">entrails</ENAMEX> aren't enough--you need to channel the spirit of an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>. Or you become a technological visionary for the
Internet. The techniques of being an Internet visionary are just like those of
lower-tech fortunetellers through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX>. A technological visionary must tell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what they want to hear, because your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock won't rise if you
spout an unpopular vision to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. Big shots won't speak at your conference
if you piss them off. Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> also use standard soap-opera themes.
A popular one: life and death--not of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or, even better,
entire industries. Tell 'em that "old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>" are going to die. There seems to
be an infinite appetite for this, despite precious little evidence. If you
hurry, you can tell them that "push" will conquer all, but that one's got a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> left at best. Talk like an action hero
so you seem tough and important. And be bold: It is better to predict dramatic
things that don't happen than boring things that do.

            Most of
all, being a technological visionary is not about predicting what will actually
happen. This astounded me when I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> realized it, and even now I am not
really comfortable with the thought. Technology and engineering are all about
testing hypotheses against reality--aren't they? Yet there is no evidence that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> or the press holds any technological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> accountable. In
fact, many latter-day Internet fortunetellers don't even bother with vagueness
or complicated loopholes. They just baldly spout predictions, certain that
nobody will care if these predictions are true.

            Aconfession: I have been accused of being a visionary
myself. And, in all candor, I fit the profile. What can I say in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX>? I
say this: The problem does not rest with us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX>. Sure, there are a few
bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> in every crate, and a few legitimate deep thinkers who sometimes get
carried away. But most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> are smart and honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sincerely</ENAMEX> interested in the future. The problem is the need that drives people
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            Technology
is driving our lives at a torrid pace. That generates many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>.
Will my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> come through this richer or poorer? Will my job be safe? What
does it all mean? The technology that shapes the modern world is as
incomprehensible to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of nature were to a society of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hunter-gatherers</ENAMEX>. So we turn to technological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> as we once turned to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shamans</ENAMEX>.

            
This call to play fortuneteller is not easily
refused. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> from a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> cornered me recently, and said:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan</ENAMEX>, I only have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of minutes</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quick</ENAMEX>, what is your vision?"
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-fifteen</NUMEX>," I riposted, "but only with my glasses on." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ho ho</ENAMEX>. But he
didn't want a joke. Nor did he want a carefully constructed set of arguments
projecting current trends, or a well-reasoned strategy. He wanted a sound
bite--something pithy to take out of context.

            What does
it matter that you have the whole truth if you can't understand it? In this
context, it is understandable that nobody really cares about a visionary's
track record. If <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s vision is exactly the opposite of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s,
don't hesitate to tell that one, too. Among modern occupations, only cult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and TV weathermen rival the technological visionary's ability to retain
credibility despite all evidence to the contrary.

            There is an antidote to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">visionary disease</ENAMEX>. We as a society
have to learn more about the technology that is shaping our lives, and become
more comfortable with it. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> believe that evil spirits cause
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, that the rain god causes rain, or that electric-light bulbs are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mystical</ENAMEX>. We do not fear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of nature as much as our species once did,
because we understand those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> better. Even if most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't actually
understand, say, where hurricanes come from, there is widespread comfort with
the notion that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> do. At the same time, there is widespread
appreciation that even weather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have their limits, which empowers people
to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> as mortals rather than as gods.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX>, the technology that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> creates a market for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> will be as mundane as light bulbs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who have grown up with that technology will be as comfortable with it as
we are with light bulbs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. They will not be as dependent on cybershamans.
There is a name for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who will accomplish this daunting task and put
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> like me out of business. We call them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But
they'll have their own fears about the future, and so--my last prediction--the
future of the fortunetelling industry is secure.

         
      
   
