











<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erlenborn Commission Members</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hon. John N. Erlenborn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Professor T. Alexander</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleinikoff Hon. Gilbert F. Casellas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah H. Cleveland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy H. Rogers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enid F. Trucios-Haynes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reporter Hon. Romano L. Mazzoli</ENAMEX>, A dvisory Member
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Directors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas S. Eakeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hon. John N. Erlenborn</ENAMEX>, V
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ice-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulett H. Askew LaVeeda M. Battle Hon. John T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broderick, Jr. Edna Fairbanks-Williams F.Wm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCalpin Maria Luisa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy H. Rogers Thomas F. Smegal, Jr.</ENAMEX> Ernestine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. Watlington</ENAMEX>
Management and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McKay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danilo A. Cardona</ENAMEX>, A cting V ice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of Compliance and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nforcement</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor M.</ENAMEX>
Fortuno, V ice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX> A ffairs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX> and
Corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James J. Hogan</ENAMEX>, V ice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> for A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dministration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX>, V ice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmental</ENAMEX>
Relations and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ffairs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John A. Hartingh</ENAMEX>, Special A ssistant
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of A dministration and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David L. Richardson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Treasurer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward H. Faris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Management</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Q.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Technology</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Genz</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Performance</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EXECUTIVE SUMMARY</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> is a private, nonmembership,
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> of the Corporation is composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who
are appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with the advice
and consent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. By law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> is bipartisan: no more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> can be of the same political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erlenborn Commission</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erlenborn Commission</ENAMEX> was authorized by
a resolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1998</TIMEX>, to study the presence requirement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s
statutory restriction on the representation of eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s appropriations act and its regulation
on the representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> have required that an alien be
"present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>" to be eligible for legal assistance
from an LSC grantee. Neither the appropriations act nor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s regulations define the term "present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> solicited written comments from the public
and held <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> public hearings duly noticed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> is based on a thorough analysis of the
applicable statutory provisions, the extensive record compiled from
the comments and testimony regarding the circumstances under which
representation of eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> occurs and the practices of legal
services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> relating to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>.
Scope of alien representation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporation grantees</ENAMEX> are
permitted to represent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, including lawful
permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> granted asylum, and temporary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> admitted under the "H-2A" program. With the
sole exception of H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees may provide
representation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> on the same subjects as is provided to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. (The report refers to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> as "unrestricted
categories.") The representation of H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, however, is
limited to "matters which arise under the provisions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worker</ENAMEX>'s specific employment contract" in the areas of wages,
housing, transportation and other employment rights under the
contract. The "present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>" requirement applies to
both the unrestricted categories and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
Of particular interest to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> was the situation of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, a category that includes both aliens
from the unrestricted categories (such as permanent resident
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aliens</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seasonal</TIMEX> agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> frequently
leave and re-enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>; thus the "presence"
requirement would have a substantial and direct impact on their
ability to receive legal representation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees.
The record reveals that it has been a long-standing practice for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees to provide legal assistance to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who
have left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> at some point during representation.
This practice has been followed without objection from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> when conducting audits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees, or from
agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> involved in legal
disputes. In addition, there has been no formal regulation or
opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> regarding the specific
scope of the presence requirement. A recent complaint to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> about the activities of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub-grantee</ENAMEX> relating to alien
representation raised the issue presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statutory Analysis.</ENAMEX> Applying the principles of law governing
statutory analysis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> considered the presence
requirement in light of its plain and ordinary meaning, its context
in a statutory scheme and the purpose and design of the statute as
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX>. See Part III(A). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s appropriations act
requires that an alien must be "present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>" in
order to be eligible for legal assistance. Construing the term
"present" according to its ordinary meaning, it is clear that the
statute requires the alien to be physically present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> at some point. This conclusion does not end the inquiry,
however, because the relevant question is not whether an alien must
be physically present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, but when the alien must
be present in order to be entitled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> representation. Here, the
language provides no express statement on when an alien must be
present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Indeed, no single interpretation is
clearly compelled by the statutory language. For example, nothing
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> authorization language keys representation to when the
cause of action arises or specifically requires that the alien be
present when the representation commences. In particular, the
statute does not expressly require that an alien be continuously
physically present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> throughout the period of
representation in order to be eligible for legal assistance.
The factual record and the statutory scheme in which the
language arises, on the other hand, provide an important context
for consideration of the legal question of when an alien must be
"present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." Consideration of the immediate
context in which the language appears raises further questions
regarding the meaning of the presence requirement. The statute's
application of the presence requirement to legal permanent
residents, for example, is in some tension with the fact that those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> are legally entitled to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> temporarily
without affecting their immigration status. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Part II</ENAMEX>(C)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>).
Furthermore, H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> by definition are physically present in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> only temporarily. Reading "presence" in the
statute to require uninterrupted, continuous physical presence
would mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, without using such language, intended to
deny LSC representation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who engaged in
federally-authorized travel that did not affect their immigration
status. In the case of H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the reading would require the
conclusion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> intended to provide H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> with
legal services representation on claims arising from their
employment contracts only for the very brief periods that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> -- potentially rendering the
promise of legal representation largely meaningless. In short, an
examination of the language of the presence requirement and the
statutory context in which it arises raises a number of
interpretive problems and fails to resolve the question of when an
alien must be present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in order to be entitled
to legal services representation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> concludes that the
statutory language is ambiguous on this point. These difficulties
support further inquiry into relevant legislative history to help
determine the meaning of the presence requirement.
Legislative History. The legislative history of the presence
requirement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s appropriations and the applicable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> provisions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Immigration Reform and Control Act</ENAMEX> confirm
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> intended to provide meaningful representation to
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> on claims arising from
their employment contract; and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did not understand the
presence requirement to severely alter or restrict this
representation. See Part III(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> Act was adopted
to provide effective legal representation to low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>.
The presence language appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> appropriations act as
part of an effort to expand LSC representation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> other than
lawful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, and does not appear to have been intended to
limit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> representation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who were continuously physically
present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Similarly, the express purpose of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 305</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRCA</ENAMEX> was to "secure the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H-2</ENAMEX> agricultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> under the specific contract under which they were admitted
to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." Such representation was intended to prevent the
exploitation of foreign H2A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and to ensure that the wages
and working conditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> would not be undermined.
Findings of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fact and Application of Law</ENAMEX>. The record compiled by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> supports, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">inter alia</ENAMEX>, the following findings of
fact. See Part II. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Aliens</ENAMEX> in the unrestricted categories often
legally leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> during the course of their
representation. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Part II</ENAMEX>(C)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>). Most H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> for brief periods of time and do not seek legal
representation until they have completed their contract, often
because of fear of retaliation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Part II</ENAMEX> (C)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
and (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>). Most claims made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to resolve. See
Part <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>). Requiring legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to monitor their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' movements and formally withdraw whenever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> leaves
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would create extraordinary burdens for the LSC
grantees, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. See Part
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>). Finally, the private bar and other nonprofit legal services
providers are neither available, willing, nor able to take over the
representation of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Part II</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>).
This factual record provided an important context for
consideration of the legal question of the meaning of the presence
requirement. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> possible interpretations of the presence
language were listed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> notice:
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) an alien must be physically present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> when
the cause of action for which the recipient provides legal
assistance arises; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) an alien must be physically present only
when legal representation is commenced; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) an alien must be
physically present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> any time the alien is
provided legal assistance from an LSC grantee. Upon careful
consideration of the findings of fact, the language and purposes of
the statute and the legislative history, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has
determined that none of these formulations fully responds to the
purposes of the statute or the intent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, the
record demonstrates that the interpretations initially offered by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> notice would contradict
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' clear purpose of providing meaningful legal
representation to indigent lawful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> and lead to absurd
results. See Part III(C).
For example, as applied to the unrestricted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, such
interpretations would preclude representation for permanent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident aliens</ENAMEX> who are evicted from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> or against
whom divorce proceedings were commenced while the alien is legally
out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for brief periods to attend a family emergency
or funeral. These interpretations would also invite exploitation by
allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> to simply wait until an alien temporarily
departed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> before cutting off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> compensation
benefits, or initiating eviction, repossession, or divorce or
custody proceedings.
In regard to H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, the record demonstrates that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' purpose of providing meaningful representation to these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> cannot be accomplished under the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> interpretations in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. Many of the contract rights of such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>--
such as reimbursement for return transportation, workers
compensation, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/4</NUMEX> guarantee, and claims that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grower</ENAMEX> failed to
mail the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s final paycheck-- often do not arise until after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> has returned home. In addition, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> is
required to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> throughout the course of the
representation, the right to legal assistance would be lost
altogether. By law, H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> must leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> at the end
of their contract period and most such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two to five months</TIMEX>. The factual record before the
Commission demonstrates that the vast majority of the claims of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> cannot be completed while the alien is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> recognizes that representation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> was a central element in the legislative
crafting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> program. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> concludes that this
reading of the statute would essentially bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> representation of
this class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> and leave H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> without meaningful
representation on their employment contract claims, directly
contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' express purpose. We decline to sanction such
a result.
Conclusion. Together, the language, purpose, and legislative
history of the applicable statutes, and the factual record before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, suggest an interpretation of the statute that would
authorize the following representation:
For an alien in one of the unrestricted categories
representation would be authorized so long as the eligible alien is
present sufficient to maintain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> or lawful immigration
status. Under this interpretation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> who have begun
representation of a permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> alien may continue that
representation should the alien be temporarily outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Grantees may also initiate representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> in the
unrestricted categories who are temporarily outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, provided that they have been present sufficient to maintain
and have not abandoned their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">INA</ENAMEX> status. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees
may not represent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> in this category who have never entered or
been present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
For H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, representation is authorized if the workers
have been admitted to and have been present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
pursuant to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> contract, and the representation arises under
their H<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-2A</TIMEX> contract. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees are authorized to litigate this
narrow range of claims to completion, despite the fact that the
alien may be required to depart the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> prior to or
during the course of the representation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees may not
represent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> in this category who have never entered or been
present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. INTRODUCTION</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erlenborn Commission</ENAMEX> was established to evaluate the scope
of permissible representation for eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s appropriations act and its regulation
on the representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> have required that an alien be
"present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>" to be eligible for legal assistance
from an LSC grantee. Neither the appropriations act nor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s regulations defines the term "present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> adopted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resolution</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-011</NUMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 16, 1998</TIMEX>, providing authority to
establish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> with the express purpose of studying the
presence requirement for the representation of eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees are permitted to represent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> classes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aliens</ENAMEX>, including lawful permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>
granted asylum, and temporary agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> admitted under
the "H-2A" program.1 With the sole exception of H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, LSC
grantees may provide general representation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> on all the
same subjects as is provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>. (These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> will be
referred to as "unrestricted categories.") The representation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, however, is limited to matters which arise under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worker</ENAMEX>'s specific employment contract in the areas of wages,
housing, transportation and other employment rights. The "present
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>" requirement applies to both the unrestricted
categories and to H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has gathered an extensive factual record. The
Commission solicited comments from the public through a notice duly
published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8140</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). The
Commission sought public comments on the facts and circumstances
surrounding the representation of all eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who are
affected by the presence requirement. It placed particular emphasis
on seasonal
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> --which includes temporary H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> as
well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> from the unrestricted
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
categories such as permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident aliens</ENAMEX> and special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> (SAWS). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> notice asked that
comments be directed to the following questions:
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) How long are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> typically in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>?
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>'s name is derived from the subparagraph of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nationality Act</ENAMEX> (INA) that defines the status, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1101</TIMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)(a) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>) (an alien "having residence
in a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> which he has no intention of abandoning who is
coming temporarily to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to perform agricultural
labor or services . . . of a temporary or seasonal nature").
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1160</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seasonal</TIMEX> agricultural work is
defined in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INA</ENAMEX> as: "the performance of field work related to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">planting</ENAMEX>, cultural practices, cultivating, growing and harvesting
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> of every kind and other perishable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commodities</ENAMEX>, as defined in regulations by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1160</TIMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). An alien is eligible for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classification</ENAMEX> as a special agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> if he or she has
resided in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> agricultural
work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 90</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-days during the
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> period ending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1, 1986</TIMEX>.
-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
When does the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> normally seek
legal representation?


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
What are the common claims of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> agricultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> seeking legal representation?


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
When do the claims of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> agricultural workers
generally ripen?


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)
How long does it typically take to resolve seasonal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' legal claims?


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)
What is the established practice of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> in
representing seasonal agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>?


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)
What is the likelihood that private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> is available
to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> under temporary
visas or who may temporarily leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>?



(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>)
Under what circumstances do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> agricultural workers
commonly leave the

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>?


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>)
What are the implications of the presence requirement on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient attorneys</ENAMEX>' professional obligations to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>?<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> notice identified a number of possible
interpretations of the presence requirement: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) an alien must be
physically present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> when the cause of action
for which the recipient provides legal assistance arises; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) an
alien must be physically present when legal representation is
commenced; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) an alien must be physically present in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> any time the alien is provided legal assistance from
an LSC grantee<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> This Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> identifies the
current interpretation used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees and the impact of
alternative interpretations on all categories of eligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> held hearings at: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University Law School</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 27, 1999</TIMEX>; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 10, 1999</TIMEX>. All requests to
provide live testimony at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> public hearings were
granted.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 64</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8140, 8141</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Id.
II. FACTUAL FINDINGS
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has compiled factual findings that address the
questions identified in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> notice described
above.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Categories of Aliens Eligible</ENAMEX> for LSC-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Current Law
LSC representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> is limited to certain classes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who broadly may be described as lawful permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>,
prospective lawful permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
temporary, nonimmigrants<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lawful</ENAMEX> permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX>" is a term of
art under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Nationality Act</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> Under current law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> may provide legal assistance
to an alien if the alien is present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and falls
within one of several designated categories:


(A)
Act (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>C. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1101</TIMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX>));


(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)
an alien who - (i) is married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> citizen
or is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> or an unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> under the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> of such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) has filed an application to adjust the status of
the alien to the status of a lawful permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nationality Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. 1101 et</ENAMEX> seq.), which
application has not been rejected;


(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX>)
an alien who is lawfully present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
pursuant to an admission under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 207</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nationality Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. 1157)</ENAMEX> (relating to refugee admission) or
who has been granted asylum by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> under such
Act;


(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>)
an alien who is lawfully present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as
a result of withholding of deportation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attorney General</ENAMEX>
pursuant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 243</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and Nationality Act</ENAMEX>
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>C. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1253</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>)); [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 1253</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>) was redesignated as section
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1231</TIMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Restriction</ENAMEX> on Removal, and amended by the Illegal
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIRAIRA</ENAMEX>)]


(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>)
an alien to whom <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 305</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration Reform</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Control Act of 1986</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>C. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1101</TIMEX> note) applies, but only to
the extent that the legal assistance provided is the legal
assistance described in such section; or


(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INA</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1101-1504</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1994 & Supp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), and is
defined in the statute as "the status of having been lawfully
accorded the privilege of residing permanently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
as an immigrant in accordance with the immigration laws." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX>
ยง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1101</TIMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of prospective lawful permanent
residents includes both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> for permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> status
and likely prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> based on their current status in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> fleeing persecution (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>,
asylees, conditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> granted relief from
removal by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> There is one category of
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> under the H-2A Program, who
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> only temporarily in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. As noted above,
representation of H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> is limited to specific subject
matters arising under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> employment contract. Because of the
special representational issues regarding this category of eligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aliens</ENAMEX>, we will examine it in detail.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temporary Agricultural Workers</ENAMEX> under the H-2A Program
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-2A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, as the only category of eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> who reside
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> temporarily, are particularly affected by the
issue before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> because of their necessarily short
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods</TIMEX> of time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-2A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> are
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, who reside in a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but come to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> temporarily to perform agricultural labor or services
for a specified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1101</TIMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>)(a)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). Their term of stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is dependent upon the agricultural needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>,
but by law cannot exceed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">214.2</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
The H-2A Program for temporary agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> is a complex
regulatory scheme devised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to meet competing concerns:
the need of agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and the need
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>) an alien who is lawfully present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as the
result of being granted conditional entry to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Nationality Act</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>C. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1153</TIMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)), as in effect
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31, 1980</TIMEX>, because of persecution or fear of persecution on
account of race, religion, or political calamity.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omnibus Consolidated Recissions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Appropriations Act of 1996</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tit</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">V, ยง 101, Pub.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L. No. 104134, 110 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1321, 1321-55</TIMEX>, as
incorporated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Colombia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Convention Center Revenues</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">112 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1515</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), implemented by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R.</ENAMEX> pt. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1626</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
7Further, current law allows the representation of any alien who
herself or whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has beensubject to domestic violence.
However, the representation is limited to preventing or obtaining
relief from the violence. The representation may occur only with
non-LSC funds. Eligibility for legal assistance for this category
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> is not dependent upon the alien being "present in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>." See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments of Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Related Agencies Appropriations</ENAMEX> Act, ยง
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">502</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(C), (b), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">111 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2440</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), as
incorporated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Colombia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Convention Center Revenues</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">112 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1515</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), implemented by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R.</ENAMEX> pt. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1626.2</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1626.4</NUMEX>(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
to protect agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laborers</ENAMEX>, both foreign and domestic. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> has facilitated the importation of foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in response to alleged shortages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> under various programs<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>
Agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> have consistently asserted that many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> did not want to work in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> agriculture or live in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> areas, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> would rot in the fields without foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Organized labor and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> for farm workers
historically have disputed these assertions based on the general
high employment rate among domestic farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and the alleged
desire of agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to preserve a cheap labor force
with limited legal rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Gordon et al.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration Law</ENAMEX>
and Procedure, ยง 20.09[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
The H-2A Program was established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration Reform</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> (IRCA), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-603</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3359</TIMEX>. In
adopting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> sought "a balanced program that
would ensure an adequate source of labor, but would not exploit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> or provide an added incentive to hire foreign rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident workers</ENAMEX>." See H.R. REP. NO. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX>-682(I), at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">106</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>),
reprinted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.C.A.N.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5649, 5710</TIMEX>. Accordingly, the
legislation requires that agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> first, and that the terms of work offered foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>,
when
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are unavailable, must notadversely affect the wages
and working conditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ย</ENAMEX>ง1188(a) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> designated a specific set of rights and guarantees for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> compensation, housing, and other
benefits to ensure that these statutory goals were met. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX>ง
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1188</TIMEX>(b)-(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Labor</ENAMEX> (USDOL) has also
promulgated regulations mandating the minimum benefits that must be
provided to H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">20 C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ง655.102</NUMEX>(a) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). In general,
the wages, benefits and working conditions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> intends to
offer to H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> must also be offered to recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, which includes lawful permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident aliens</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration Law</ENAMEX> and Procedure, supra at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ย</NUMEX>ง 20.09[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Growers</ENAMEX> must
replace H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> with any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> who applies for the job
before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half of the season</TIMEX> is over. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">20 C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">655.103</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
The process for the admission of H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> requires that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grower</ENAMEX> submit an application for certification to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX> setting
forth all the material terms and conditions of work that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employer</ENAMEX> intends to offer its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX> determines that a
labor shortage exists and that the job offer satisfies the federal
requirements, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX> approves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s application for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">certification</ENAMEX>. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ย</ENAMEX>ง1188(a)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of</ENAMEX>
then approves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> visa petition to bring in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of State</ENAMEX> issues nonimmigrant
visas. See id. The approved <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> visa petition and the
corresponding H-2A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> The controversial "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bracero</ENAMEX>" Program operated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1942</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> and permitted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> to work temporarily in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agriculture</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1964 to 1986</TIMEX>, entry of foreign agricultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> was permitted under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H-2</ENAMEX> Program which many agricultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> found inadequate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration Law</ENAMEX> and Procedure, supra at
ยง 20.09[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]; see also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erlenborn Commission</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comments on</ENAMEX> "Presence
Requirement" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplement</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1999</TIMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">56</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>) [hereinafter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Comments]
(describing prior programs as "quite controversial for many
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>").
visa permit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> to stay for the duration of the certified
period of employment, but in no event may the visa exceed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ง214.2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9</NUMEX> (comment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Michael Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX>). Further, the visa is terminated at any
time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s employment relationship ends, whether
through voluntary departure or involuntary termination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> must depart the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and is subject to deportation
for failing to do so. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>. Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> is only admitted to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to perform work for a designated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, and must leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> when that employment
terminates for any reason.
In crafting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> was acutely aware of the
vulnerability of temporary agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and of problems
that had arisen under other such programs, particularly the Bracero
Program. See discussion infra Part III(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> further
recognized that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> provisions
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
required enforcement mechanisms lest they become mere paper
guarantees. Thus, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 305</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRCA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> specifically
authorized LSC-funded representation for H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> on matters
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pertaining</ENAMEX> to their employment contract. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1101</TIMEX> note
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). LSC-funded representation was a core element in the
legislative design of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> program. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONG</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>. H9866-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erlenborn Commission</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comments on</ENAMEX> "The Presence
Requirement," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 1999</TIMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29-43</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Beardall</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX>) [hereinafter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments]; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Comments
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53-58</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Berman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>); see also
discussion infra Part III(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>).
The statutory protections set forth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> program, and the
provision of legal representation to H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to enforce these
rights, thus were intended to accomplish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> purposes: to protect
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> from exploitation, and to ensure that the
employment of such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> would not depress the wages and working
conditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. These considerations explain why H-2A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are the only category of nonimmigrants eligible for
LSC-funded representation. They also point to the differences
between the representation authorized for the unrestricted
categories and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>: for the former, grantees may represent
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> on all matters; for the latter, representation is
restricted to matters arising under the employment contract.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> constitute a small but growing portion of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>' agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. During <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FY 1998</ENAMEX>, the most
recent year for which statistics are available, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX> certified
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34,898</NUMEX> job openings and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>. The FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-2A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Labor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division of Foreign Labor</ENAMEX>
Certifications, Revised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1999</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">hereinafter FY 1998 H-</ENAMEX>2A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>]. This is a dramatic increase from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23,352</NUMEX> job
openings were certified and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 2,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Michael Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX>). The USDOL
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9 H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are exempt from other federal laws protecting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">farmworkers</ENAMEX>. Of particular significance is their exemption from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Migrant</ENAMEX> and Seasonal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agricultural Worker Protection</ENAMEX> Act (MSWPA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง 1801 et</ENAMEX> seq.(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>), the primary federal statute protecting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>, Erlenborn
Commission <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hearing Transcript</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apr.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 1999</TIMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">122</NUMEX> (testimony of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Schacht</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Rural Legal Assistance Foundation</ENAMEX>)
[hereinafter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Testimony].
believes that the upward trend will continue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>.; see also
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">128</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Shelley Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmworkers Legal Assistance Project</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grower associations</ENAMEX>
organized to obtain approval to bring in H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are now
appearing in a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erlenborn Commission Hearing Transcripts, Mar.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 1999</TIMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX>
(testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Javier Riojas, Texas Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX>) [hereinafter
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Testimony]; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">222</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melissa A.</ENAMEX>
Pershing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> eight
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> accounted for over seventy-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent of all H-2A
activities. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1998 H-2A</ENAMEX> Report. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia -</ENAMEX> totaled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27,150</NUMEX> positions in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>.
The leading H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> commodities were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,984</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4,428</NUMEX>), vegetable harvesting (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4,822</NUMEX>), and fruit harvesting
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,483</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX> reports that the vast majority of H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> come
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Michael Hancock</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for which country statistics are
available, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,353</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 4,231</NUMEX>
came from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>. This is sharply
at odds with the relative proportions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, when the majority of
temporary foreign agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12,609</NUMEX>)
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 2,499</NUMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>. The only other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> with a
significant presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> program -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX> -- sends about
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> as sheepherders to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX> and
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">B. Matters of Representation for Eligible Aliens</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aliens in Unrestricted Categories</ENAMEX>
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> seek legal assistance on a variety of
matters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Aliens</ENAMEX> may be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence, need
assistance with divorce and custody matters, find themselves having
to file bankruptcy, or require help applying for social security
and unemployment benefits. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">246</NUMEX> (comment of
Marci <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Gate University School of Law</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
Testimony at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX> (testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Rice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Rural Legal</ENAMEX>
Assistance). Housing issues arise over eviction actions,
substandard housing, eligibility for public housing, mobile home
purchases, housing discrimination, and mortgage foreclosures. See
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">68</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McIntyre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Project</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn J.</ENAMEX>
Endriss, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">82</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Friends Service Committee</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">141</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Michael Dale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Law Center</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Morgan</ENAMEX>,
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Services of Oregon</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">172</NUMEX> (comment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel G. Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colombia Legal Services</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">206</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Padilla</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia L. Rice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Rural</ENAMEX>
Legal Assistance); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">269</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Butler</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Rural Legal Services</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LSC</ENAMEX> eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> may also seek
assistance on immigration and consumer matters. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Testimony
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">89</NUMEX> (testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Iwasaki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> of Los
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>). Because of their limited English ability and isolation
within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">communities</ENAMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> are particularly vulnerable to
exploitation by unscrupulous sales and marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">246</NUMEX> (Comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marci Seville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Gate University School of</ENAMEX>
Law). They are particularly susceptible to workplace exploitation
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> such as agriculture, landscaping, janitorial and
restaurant work, and day labor. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Testimony at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
(testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Rice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Rural Legal Assistance</ENAMEX>).
Alien agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, who are not temporary H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>,
are protected in their employment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant</ENAMEX> and Seasonal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agricultural Worker Protection</ENAMEX> Act (MSWPA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง 1801 et</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seq</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), which governs recruitment, wages, housing, health and
safety, vehicle safety standards, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>' licensure and minimum
vehicle insurance levels. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX>). Their claims include violations of
recruitment promises and disputes over wages, working conditions,
wrongful terminations, and the job contract. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McIntyre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Justice Project</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn J. Endriss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>);
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">82</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Friends</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Committee</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99</NUMEX> (comment of Nan Schivone
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Holmen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal Services Program</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">141</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Michael Dale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Law Center</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Services of Oregon</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel G. Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colombia Legal Services</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">269</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Butler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Rural Legal Services</ENAMEX>). Legal
assistance is also sought for job injuries, and other health and
safety issues. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">68</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrick</ENAMEX>
McIntyre, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Justice Project</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80</NUMEX> (comment
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn J. Endriss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Friends Service Committee</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">141</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Michael Dale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Law Center</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Morgan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Services of Oregon</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Butler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Rural Legal Services</ENAMEX>). Health and
safety issues include improper use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">172</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel G. Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">207</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Padilla</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia L. Rice</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Rural Legal Assistance</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">225</NUMEX> (comment
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa A. Pershing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX>
are also represented in civil rights and retaliation claims. See
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">141</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Michael Dale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> Law
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Morgan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Services of Oregon</ENAMEX>).


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-2A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aliens</ENAMEX>
Current law limits the representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> to matters
"relating to wages, housing, transportation, and other employment
rights as provided in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s specific contract under which
the nonimmigrant was admitted." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1101</TIMEX> note (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s contract must include certain minimum benefits,
wages, and working conditions that are mandated by federal law. 20
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">655.102</NUMEX>(a) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-2A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> seek legal assistance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">inter alia</ENAMEX>, in the following
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">a.</ENAMEX> Housing: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> of H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> must provide
adequate housing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who travel further than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 miles</NUMEX> to the
job site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">20 C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">655.102</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX> from programs
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> mentioned
housing as an issue for which H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> sought legal assistance.
See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">22</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Willis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at
Law); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">63</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James F. Schmidt</ENAMEX>, Farmworker
Legal Services of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99</NUMEX> (comment of Nan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schivone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Holmen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal Services Program</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">108</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Salzman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte Sibley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia C. Kakalec</ENAMEX>, Farmworker
Law Project); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">125</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Shelley Latin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Farmworkers Legal Assistance Project</ENAMEX>).


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">b.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> Compensation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> of H-2A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are required to enroll in state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> compensation
programs or to provide equivalent insurance coverage for both
domestic and foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">655.102</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
Job injuries are common in agriculture. Aliens commonly seek legal
assistance on issues related to job injuries. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Soucy</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX> (comment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Carlin</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">22</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Willis</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">28</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">31</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
Beardall, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">46</NUMEX> (comments of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Corrie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99</NUMEX> (comment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nan Schivone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Holmen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal Services Program</ENAMEX>);
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">107</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Salzman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte Sibley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia C. Kakalec</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmworkers Law Project</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">125</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shelley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Farmworkers Legal Assistance Project</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">159</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wyatt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olga Pedroza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern New Mexico Legal Services</ENAMEX>);
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">269</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Butler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Rural Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">225</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa A. Pershing</ENAMEX>,
Legal Services of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">103</NUMEX> (comment
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry G. Geffert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> Plan); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Testimony at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33-37</NUMEX> (testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry G. Geffert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>
Legal Services Plan); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Testimony at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">145</NUMEX> (testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Legal Services</ENAMEX>).


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">c.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundtrip Transportation</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> of H-2A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are required to reimburse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> for transportation to the
workplace if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> completes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half of the season</TIMEX>, and for
return transportation from the workplace if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> completes
the contract. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">20 C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">655.102</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). It is not uncommon
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> to seek legal assistance because the employer
failed to reimburse them for transportation expenses. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">32</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Beardall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX>);
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan Schivone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Holmen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal Services Program</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">107</NUMEX> (comment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Salzman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Mid</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> Sibley
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia C. Kakalec</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmworker Law Project</ENAMEX>).


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">d.</ENAMEX>
Wage Rate: H-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> must pay an adverse effect wage
rate, which is a minimum wage rate set by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of</ENAMEX>
Labor reflecting the prevailing wages in the particular
agricultural sector. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">20 C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">655.102</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX> aliens
commonly seek legal assistance for unpaid wages. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Soucy</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX> (comment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Carlin</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comment at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Willis</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">27</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Wiggins</ENAMEX>,
Student Action With Farmworkers); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
(comment


of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Beardall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Corrie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James F. Schmidt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmworker Legal Services of New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan Schivone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis</ENAMEX>
Holmen, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal Services Program</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">107</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Salzman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Mid</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte Sibley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia C. Kakalec</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmworker Law Project</ENAMEX>);
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">126</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Shelley Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmworkers Legal Assistance Project</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">225</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa A. Pershing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services of North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>).


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">e.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3/4 Guarantee</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agricultural</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are required to
offer their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> either work or wages for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 3/4</NUMEX> of the
contract period. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">20 C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">655.102</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-2A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> have
sought legal assistance for violations of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/4</NUMEX> guarantee right.
See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Willis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at
Law); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">32</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Beardall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural</ENAMEX>
Legal Aid); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">99</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan Schivone</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Holmen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal Services Program</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comment at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">107</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Salzman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Mid</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte Sibley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia C. Kakalec</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmworker Law Project</ENAMEX>);
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">127</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Shelley Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmworkers Legal Assistance Project</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">159</NUMEX>
(comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wyatt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rural Legal Aid, et</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">228</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa A. Pershing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">270</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Butler</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Rural Legal Services</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">92</NUMEX> (comment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry G. Geffert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> Plan); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">103</NUMEX> (comments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry G. Geffert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services Plan); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Testimony at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">147</NUMEX> (testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Williams</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Legal Services</ENAMEX>).


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">f.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Non-waiver/Anti-</ENAMEX>retaliation <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rights</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDOL</ENAMEX> regulations
prohibit the waiver of any rights provided by law. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">29 C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">501.4</NUMEX>(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). They also prohibit anyone from blacklisting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intimidating</ENAMEX>, or retaliating against any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> for "consulting
with a legal assistance program" or otherwise asserting her rights
under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H-2A</ENAMEX> program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">29 C.F.R. ย</ENAMEX>ง <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">501.3</NUMEX>(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). State laws also
prohibit blacklisting. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Testimony at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66-67</NUMEX> (testimony of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Lee Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-2A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> have
sought legal assistance for violations of these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>retaliation
rights. See <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Soucy</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert J. Willis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>);
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">98</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan Schivone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Holmen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal Services Program</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">108</NUMEX> (comment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Salzman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Mid</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> Sibley
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia C. Kakalec</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmworker Law Project</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">128</NUMEX> (comment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Shelley Latin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Farmworkers Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assistance Project</ENAMEX>); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> Comments at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">226</NUMEX> (comment of
Melissa

