



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION BOARD OF DIRECTORS</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COMMENTS</ENAMEX> ON THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OFFICE OF INSPECTOR GENERAL'S SEMIANNUAL REPORT</ENAMEX>
TO THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONGRESS</ENAMEX> FOR <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">THE</TIMEX> PERIOD
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">OCTOBER 1, 2000 - MARCH 31, 2001</TIMEX>


<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MAY 31, 2001</TIMEX>

FOREWORD
I am pleased to transmit the comments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LSC" or "Corporation"</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>")
regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Semiannual Report</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Inspector</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OIG</ENAMEX>") for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six-month period of October 1, 2000</TIMEX> through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31, 2001</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> recognizes the value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX>
function and remains committed to working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIG</ENAMEX> to achieve
our goal of providing high quality legal assistance to the poor of
our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. We note, in particular, our support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIG</ENAMEX>'s work
to strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>' compliance efforts and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Service</ENAMEX>
Reporting, which has resulted in increased accuracy in the
documentation of the performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas S. Eakeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>



MESSAGE OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOARD OF DIRECTORS</ENAMEX>
During the reporting period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> made continued progress in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX>. Building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Justice Communities</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Report</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>, issued
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2001</TIMEX>, highlights the state planning successes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> states
in developing coordinated plans to increase resources and services
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> statewide<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> The report shows the variety of ways in
which these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have strengthened their equal justice systems,
providing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and inspiration for others. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> improved
access to justice for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, strengthened the quality
of legal services delivered by programs<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,2</NUMEX> and forged new and deeper
bonds among stakeholder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s civil justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has restructured legal services programs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> has decreased from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997, to 167</TIMEX> anticipated grantees (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Field</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> grants) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">calendar year 2002</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX> is premised on the belief that
LSC-funded programs must:
?? function as a concerted, coherent, closely coordinated legal
assistance delivery system;
?? include other equal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in the creation and
implementation of this coordinated delivery system;
?? develop additional resources to expand legal services;
?? incorporate the views of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in making
major decisions about
how to design and implement a comprehensive system of high
quality legal services;
and
?? target legal services resources to achieve the greatest
measure of equal justice for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and economically disadvantaged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s ultimate goal in this regard is to help grantees create
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of justice - integrated and coordinated legal
services delivery systems which
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> 'Programs', <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'recipients'</ENAMEX>, and 'grantees' are used
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interchangeably</ENAMEX> in this report to refer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX>.
comprehensively improve grantees' delivery of services to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has made significant progress in this effort and
continues to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> in improving the quality of legal
services nationwide.
To further its goal of expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>' use of technology,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is proceeding with its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Initiative</ENAMEX>
Grants, it has consulted with grantees on the selection of case
management software which will accommodate merger-related
technology needs, and it has provided continued technology training
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>.


BACKGROUND
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> is a private, non-profit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX> established in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Services Corporation <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1974</ENAMEX>, as amended ("the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>"), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> to
provide financial support for legal assistance in civil proceedings
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> unable to afford legal services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is governed by an
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>-member bipartisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> appointed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with the advice and consent of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> appoints <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, who serves as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive officer</ENAMEX>, subject to general policies
established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1988 Amendments to the Inspector General Act of 1978</ENAMEX> ("<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>
Act") required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to establish an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX>
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OIG</ENAMEX>") and extended specific provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1978 Act</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>.
Accordingly, such an office was established by and for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> is appointed by, reports to and serves under the
general supervision of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funding</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant-Making Activities</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> received a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> appropriation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$330 million</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, with which it made grants to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX> programs to provide free
legal services to indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Of the funds
received for FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7-million</NUMEX> will be used for client self help
and information technology.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C.</ENAMEX> ? ? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2996-2996l</TIMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANAGEMENT INITIATIVES</ENAMEX>
During this reporting period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> continued its efforts to
improve the efficiency of its competitive grant award system and
the effectiveness of the delivery of legal assistance by its
initiative for statewide planning and coordination of legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> continued to demonstrate its ability to
ensure both compliance with program rules and regulations, and the
maintenance of high quality legal assistance to eligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> continues to implement its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) year Strategic Direction
Plan ("the Plan"). Adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 28</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, the Plan commits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to dramatically enhance the impact of
legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> by improving access
to legal services while enhancing their quality. The Plan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emphasizes LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX>, as well as the
increased use of technology, as significant strategies for
expanding access to, and availability of, civil legal services
throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is developing performance
measures to assess the ongoing effectiveness of its strategic plan,
and will undertake pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to five</NUMEX> programs in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.


Competition and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s primary goals for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the calendar year 2002</TIMEX> grants
competition are to refine the Request for Proposal ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">RFP</ENAMEX>"),
simplify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> process for competing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grants, and
obtain applicant information essential to maintaining a quality
legal services delivery system.
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refinements</ENAMEX> have been incorporated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX>, including: questions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant staff</ENAMEX> diversity; staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recruitment</ENAMEX> and retention strategies; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> training; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>
strategic planning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX> inquiries on technology are streamlined and
incorporated into the RFP form for technology, which allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to
assess the technological capacities of the delivery system. The RFP
was also modified to obtain more comprehensive information on
sub-grantees that receive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> percent (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX>) or more of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grant award, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub-grantees</ENAMEX> that deliver a full range of
services to a specific geographic area within the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>'s
service area. Evaluation weights assigned to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX> topics have been
restructured to correspond with the modifications made to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> continues to make the most use of available technology. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX> is fully electronic and is available from the Internet at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ain</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lsc</ENAMEX>.gov. The technology used to capture and evaluate
information in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">RFP</ENAMEX> permits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to compile and
assess key information about the delivery system at the program,
state, regional, and national level.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> continues to provide technical assistance to grantees in
many areas of state planning including, but not limited to,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> and implementation of state plans, resource
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, and mergers. During this reporting period, LSC
retained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> to assist planning efforts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>.
Technical assistance contracts supported resource development
activities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> organized and sponsored a national <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-day</TIMEX>
training on mergers attended by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>.
These efforts have resulted in the development of additional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> for civil legal services, new and more efficient ways of
providing legal information and advice to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, and
more effective and economical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> to assure equal justice to
greater numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.


Technology Efforts
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is in the process of reviewing and awarding its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round
of Technology Initiative Grants ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TIGs</ENAMEX>"). It has received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>
applications with total grant requests of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $19-million</NUMEX>, for
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36 million</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-three</NUMEX> of these requests are
for implementation of statewide web site templates developed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> grant competition. If funded, these projects would provide
the potential for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> with legal
information and pro se resources on a statewide basis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> continues to provide assistance to former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGs</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000 and March 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> hosted meetings of TIG
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to discuss the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of the grants.
Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has created a web site for the collaboration of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>.
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Conference</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EJC</ENAMEX>") held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2001</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project</ENAMEX> for the Future of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice</ENAMEX> held
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Management Software</ENAMEX> pre-conference. The primary
goal of this gathering was to address issues generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX> and resulting mergers. At the meeting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> discussed the creation
of central databases for a program, region, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, using various
applications such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WAN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SQL</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citrix</ENAMEX>.
During the reporting period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> provided technology training at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southeast Projects</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> meeting; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee On Regional</ENAMEX>
Training for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Access</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Conference</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EJC</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Aid and Defender</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Information Exchange</ENAMEX>. It also
provided assistance to several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with the development of
statewide technology plans. Finally, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, in
conjunction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courts</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Institute</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Society Institute</ENAMEX>, convened a
conference of representatives from legal services, state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>,
bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community partners</ENAMEX> to forge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collaborations</ENAMEX> to advance pro se efforts in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.


Program Visits
To assure the provision of high quality legal assistance to
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Program Performance</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OPP</ENAMEX>")
instituted a written protocol for conducting program reviews. LSC
published a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Review Guide</ENAMEX> to aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> while
conducting on site recipient reviews. All program reviews are
conducted to enhance the purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s Strategic
Direction Plan. The on site visits are conducted for the purpose of
program monitoring and development, to solve problems, and to
develop new strategies for expanding access and enhancing quality
of services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> programs were chosen for visits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> visit was
conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>; one is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are scheduled for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>; and one is scheduled for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. Dates for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> additional visits will be selected in
the near future.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'The Results Project</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'The Results Project</ENAMEX>' is aimed at gauging, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time,
the type and volume of work, other than the handling of cases, in
which LSC-funded programs engage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has long noted that its
programs provide referrals and community legal education, engage in
outreach, and work cooperatively with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to address the
needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> client <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> recognizes that this work
entails great effort and produces significant results. 'The Results
Project' will enable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to describe and quantify that work. LSC
has endeavored to minimize the burden on programs in the collection
of this information through the design of a carefully developed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> collection instrument, the collection of information only once
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and through efforts to modify existing case management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> to allow for collection of this information.
The project attempts to identify the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> served by
the following types of work, and obtain descriptions of programs'
efforts and of successes.
?? Referrals; ?? Community legal education presentations<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">; ?</ENAMEX>?
Community legal education materials, articles and web <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>; ?? Pro
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">se clinics</ENAMEX>, distribution of pro se materials including the
technologically enhanced
approaches; ?? Indirect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> such as training to other (lay)
service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and collaborative
service delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>; and ?? Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> such as mediation
and alternative dispute resolution work.
The draft of the instrument to collect this information was
tested by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is in the process of reviewing the test
results in order to make appropriate improvements. Regular data
collection is scheduled to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 2001</TIMEX>.


Diversity
To better serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and strengthen program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
leadership sensitivity to client <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has convened a
series of conferences on diversity. These conferences will enable
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to examine the degree to which gender, race,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ethnicity</ENAMEX> and age have adversely affected the ability of some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to obtain critical legal services from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> conference was held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31, 2001</TIMEX> in conjunction with the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Conference</ENAMEX>, and others are planned later in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Client Conference</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX>, just beyond the reporting period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> held a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day</TIMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, entitled "Creating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Client-Centered State Communities of Justice</ENAMEX>". The conference
provided a forum for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of ideas about methods by which
the legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> can better empower, strengthen and
enhance the lives of legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. It convened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community advocates</ENAMEX>, as well as legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> who embrace
the concept of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>-centered legal services.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sixteen</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) conference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> were written by legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on topics that enhanced and enlightened
the conference discussions. The conference was attended by a
diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than seventy</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, comprised of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client advocates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the bench and the academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>.
Conference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> reflected a true cross section of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> attending from more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty-eight</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">28</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. As part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> solicitation
process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> were asked to commit to lead and participate in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> statewide activity that will promote positive, lasting
change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client community</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will publish a report on the conference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> will capture the ideas, recommendations, and strategies from
the conference and serve as a possible guide to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates facilitate client</ENAMEX>-centered legal services delivery in
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Characteristics of Model Intake Systems</ENAMEX>
As a part of its effort to encourage and promote innovative
procedures, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is producing a listing of draft characteristics of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> telephone intake, advice, and referral systems. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIG</ENAMEX> have, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, been committed to promoting these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>. In arriving at the draft characteristics, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> staff
considered a variety of documents describing standards for intake
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>, including those published by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> also
solicited input from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the area of intake systems and
presented the draft characteristics during a workshop on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best</ENAMEX>
Practices" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">March ABA/NLADA Equal Justice Conference</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early May 2001</TIMEX>, shortly beyond the reporting period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Performance</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OPP</ENAMEX>") notified programs that it was
accepting comments to draft characteristics of a telephone intake
advice and referral system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Draft Characteristics</ENAMEX> were posted
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Recipient Information Network</ENAMEX> and were sent to all
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> via electronic mail. After considering comments
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> intends to publish the
characteristics in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Letter</ENAMEX> and use them as the best
practice standard when evaluating programs' intake systems.


Program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mergers/Consolidations</ENAMEX>
In anticipation of many program mergers or consolidations due to
the reconfiguration of service areas for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, along with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Aid and Defender Association</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Exchange</ENAMEX> sponsored a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making Mergers Work</ENAMEX>" workshop
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">March ABA/NLADA Equal Justice Conference</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> examined the practicalities of mergers and
consolidations; considered ways in which new service area
configurations can better serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>; prepared for the
challenges of joining different program cultures and emerging with
an effective larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>; and talked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> about the
specific opportunities and problems they face. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> presented
a session on LSC program requirements for mergers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consolidations</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Program Performance</ENAMEX> has revised internal
procedures for handling program mergers/consolidations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grant
conditions require that programs obtain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> approval of a merger or
consolidation before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will allow the transfer of the grant from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> program to another. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s internal procedures for clearing
mergers and consolidations involve the work of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Office</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Inspector</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Compliance and Enforcement</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Affairs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Information Management</ENAMEX>, with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of Program Performance having primary responsibility for the
clearance process.
Shortly beyond the reporting period in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
Program Performance held a special telephonic conference for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>
grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> involved in mergers/consolidations. This session
focused on how programs should complete grant applications, and the
new grant application requirements for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> which anticipate
sub-granting part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grant during the grant year.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rulemaking Activities</ENAMEX>
During the reporting period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> issued a revised final rule on
recipient fund balances, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFR</ENAMEX> Part <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1628</TIMEX>. Under the final rule,
published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 7, 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> will be permitted to
carry over fund balances of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> or less; will be able to seek LSC
approval for carryover balances of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 10% and 25%</NUMEX>; and will be
generally prohibited from retaining fund balances of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 25%</NUMEX>,
except in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> very limited and especially compelling
circumstances. The exceptions would be where the fund balance
overage results from the receipt of insurance proceeds; real estate
sale proceeds; or proceeds received as a result of a lawsuit in
which the recipient was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. The new rule became effective on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 7, 2000</TIMEX>.
In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has begun conducting a thorough review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
regulations. This project is consistent with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX>
strategic plan, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Strategic Directions 2000 -2005</ENAMEX>" which, among
other things, requires reviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s regulatory compliance
requirements for efficiency, unnecessary duplication and burden,
and implications for the delivery of high quality, appropriate
legal services. As part of this project, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> solicited public
comment via notices published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> and on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Website</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX>. The review effort is still underway
and a final report is expected to be presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> for
consideration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">TABLE 1</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Report</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audits</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grantees Issued With Questioned Costs For the Six Month Period</ENAMEX>
Ending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31, 2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TABLE 2</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Report</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Audit Reports Issued During The Six Month</ENAMEX>
Period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ending March 31, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With Recommendations That Funds Be</ENAMEX>
Put to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX> Use By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Agreed</ENAMEX> to in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management</ENAMEX>
Decision





