



A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONFERENCE OF STATEWIDE PROGRAMS</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 8 - 9, 2002</TIMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
Introduction
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Team</ENAMEX> determined that
there is a critical need to communicate clearly the key elements of
planning related to statewide legal services programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team</ENAMEX>
suggested a national initiative to bring together executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of statewide programs around the state planning agenda.
The goal was to focus executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> on the fundamentals of
planning for client-centered, comprehensive, integrated statewide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX>. This initiative was specifically designed to
bring together executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> from newly created statewide
LSC-funded programs and the experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the more
historical statewide programs. This peer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> benefited from the
opportunity to come together to discuss the challenges and new
opportunities created by the processes of state planning.


Background
This meeting was originally scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 13 - 15</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, but was postponed in the aftermath of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> 11th
attack on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> planned and coordinated this conference, and the
Corporation sponsored the participation of executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> by
covering their travel costs. Additionally, programs were offered
the option of sending additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to the conference at their
own expense. Amidst a professional and amiable backdrop, the
conference was convened at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott Hotel</ENAMEX> in downtown
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> program representatives
attended, and every statewide program was represented with the
exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>, whose executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and senior management
were unable to attend. Also in attendance were representatives from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX> and Virgin Islands programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Saunders</ENAMEX>
attended from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLADA</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in attendance included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
Relations/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Affairs</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Genz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
Program Performance; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Program Counsel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Team</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea Hayward</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Team</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diversity</ENAMEX>);
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Pershing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Team</ENAMEX> (who, with input and
assistance from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, prepared and coordinated the agenda);
and assistants <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Burnette</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Wilson</ENAMEX>, who were responsible
for conference logistics, registration, and on-site conference
assistance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Legal Services</ENAMEX> (ILS) Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Metzger</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Cotter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS Indiana Justice Center</ENAMEX>,
were marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> attended <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX>'s presentation on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Relations</ENAMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s lunch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> also testified to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX>'s keen interest in and support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Legal Services</ENAMEX>
and the provision of pro bono by the private bar. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX>, conference <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were joined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS Board</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, and bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> (including the new executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>) for dinner. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President-Elect</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana State Bar</ENAMEX> spoke eloquently and at length about her support
for legal services and pro bono.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>, provided opening and
closing remarks for the conference; and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> update during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch</TIMEX>.
Her timely comments set a tone for open and extensive information
sharing and collaboration. A copy of the conference agenda is
included with this Report as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attachment A.</ENAMEX>


<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 8, 2002</TIMEX>

Session <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I - Three Statewide Models - A Panel Presentation</ENAMEX>
This session provided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with a snapshot of three
statewide programs, and focused on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planning for Client Centered</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State-wide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice Communities</ENAMEX>."
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nan Heald</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McIntyre</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Asher</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>) spoke from the perspectives
of a longtime statewide program (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>); a state that was
reconfigured <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>); and, a newly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">reconfigured</ENAMEX> statewide (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>). Each provided a perspective on
developing a vision, setting goals and determining strategies for
achieving access to a full range of civil legal services. Each
emphasized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> central themes:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The imperative that each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> must have a vision that
encompasses a full range of services;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The challenge of orienting existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to a new or
changing vision, inculcating the vision and mission within the
staff, and, uniting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> (old and new) over a common vision,
whether in a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or scattered office setting; and,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The challenge of balancing vision with fiscal reality,
recognizing that as funds remain static or decline, the need for
collaboration increases and, at the same time, the threat of
fractionalization increases.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Session II - Group Discussion</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> discussion, facilitated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gross</ENAMEX> and Melissa
Pershing, followed. The discussion provided a forum for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to share thoughts, challenges and best practices in
the context of developing and fostering a statewide vision.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> suggested that statewide program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> needed
to be able to:


•
Talk consistently and constantly about vision and
quality;


•
Set high expectations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>;


•
Delegate appropriate management functions so that the
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> can be a visible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and the
greater equal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>;


•
Work closely with the state court system, and get
involved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">collaborations</TIMEX>;


•
Build on the program strengths that already
exist;


•
Seek assistance from experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>;


•
Visualize state planning holistically;


•
Know that there are positive long-term advantages that
ensue from the state planning initiative;


•
Perform environmental scans for information vital to the
creation of a statewide vision;


•
Appreciate and respect the differences in office and
staff culture and use them as a genesis for a unified
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision</ENAMEX>;


•
Think critically about how to unify systems-noting that
sometimes uniformity is necessary, and sometimes it is not
appropriate;


•
Understand that the pursuit of justice is different from
the pursuit of access to justice.




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Session III - Press & Public Relations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmental Affairs/Public</ENAMEX>
Relations, presented a session that focused on how programs can
develop effective public relations campaigns. Focusing on the
findings of the national <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Russenello</ENAMEX> research, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vivero</ENAMEX> encouraged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to use the media to publicize meaningful program
events. He stressed the importance of getting the right message
out, delivered by the most credible and prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX>(s).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> formed small discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and brainstormed about
events or ideas that could form the basis for a program's media
campaign.

On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, the conference agenda consisted of thematic
discussions or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-</ENAMEX>sessions that provided an exposition of the
state planning concept, entitled, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breaking the Concept into Parts</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-Client-Centered</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Statewide</ENAMEX>."


<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Session IV -Client Centered</ENAMEX>
This discussion was co-facilitated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Cotter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gross</ENAMEX> (LSC) and focused on the
challenges of creating a service delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> that is
client-centered through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client leadership</ENAMEX> in the state planning
process and through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> involvement on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of directors.



Session V -<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn McNamara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrienne Worthy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>) facilitated this discussion. It provided a forum for
sharing how programs can build <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> with other equal justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX> and explored the need for creativity in forming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">partnerships</ENAMEX> and collaborations that may consist of unusual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Session VI -Integrated</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Milne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger McCollister</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>) facilitated
this discussion on innovative ways to integrate and combine
fundraising to produce a creative resource development program.



<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII -Statewide</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Metzger</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Millard</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>) facilitated
this session, which included defining the term "statewide" and
discussion of various statewide program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>. The session also
examined the impact of planning and creation of a vision on pro
bono involvement, leveraging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human resources</ENAMEX>, and related service
delivery issues.




<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, February 9, 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIII -Technology</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhonda Lipkin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Geminiani</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nan Heald</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Genz</ENAMEX> (LSC) presented this session.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Legal Assistance Network</ENAMEX> (MLAN) - Rhonda Lipkin
provided a demonstration of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">peoples</ENAMEX>-law.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mdjustice</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>, which is designed to be a virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Geminiani</ENAMEX> demonstrated how video conferencing
is being used extensively by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">islands</ENAMEX>. A hotline is the gateway to a self help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> offering
court forms, a web page, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> self-help packets, phone advice,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinics</ENAMEX>, and outcomes follow-up.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nan Heald</ENAMEX> provided a demonstration of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helpmelaw</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> with smart search capability and www.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ptla</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org,</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree Legal Assistance</ENAMEX> site. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client leadership</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
has email. They found <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> who will translate documents for
free at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteermatch</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) LSC - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Genz</ENAMEX> provided an overview of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s technology
efforts: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Initiative Grants</ENAMEX>) program is
developing templates for statewide websites. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> is studying
document assembly software, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> is studying the
combination of audio-video conferencing with document <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shared National TIG</ENAMEX> grants include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Technical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assistance Project</ENAMEX> (NTAP), creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lstech</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>, and
development of measurement and evaluation tools,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legalmeetings</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genz</ENAMEX> announced the deadlines for this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TIG Requests For Proposals</ENAMEX>.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IX</NUMEX> -Diversity
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-facilitated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Cosby</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayward</ENAMEX> (LSC), this discussion focused on the importance of
embracing cultural diversity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> succession planning, and
the general expansion of program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, especially as a part
of a state planning initiative.



Transformation: An <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Overarching Achievement Identified</ENAMEX>
It was obvious from the remarks made by a number of recently
merged states that some kind of critical phase had been passed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> recognized that programs were turning or had turned
that critical corner--from being resistant to or resentful of
change to an embracing of new visions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> shared experiences about these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transformations</ENAMEX> and acknowledged the benefits of reconfiguration,
as programs complete the critical work of reorganization.


The Future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> have already been provided detailed contact
information so that they can network and follow-up with others who
attended the conference. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> to identify what they
feel would be the next appropriate steps. A report of the
conference will also be provided to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> complete with
a package containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">handouts</ENAMEX>. This information will also be shared
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.
A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> completed evaluations were received from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. All were unanimous in their praise and appreciation
for the statewide conference, and expressed a desire for an annual
or semi-annual conference of this nature to be held either in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or with the use of videoconferencing. Several suggested that
separate break-out sessions could be developed for long-time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statewides</ENAMEX> and recently merged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">statewides</ENAMEX>, which would allow more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, attention and specifically tailored agendas and discussions
for both. It was also noted that not all programs were "state"wides
and that perhaps there would be value in getting the island
programs together (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin Islands</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Micronesia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX>) since they face similar delivery issues.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">• Ideas</ENAMEX> from both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> for additional follow-up
included:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">i. Regional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> conferences - small intense retreat-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> meetings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Directors</ENAMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> identified
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> from each of



<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">iv</ENAMEX>.
Mentoring/exchange program for newer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> or leaders
who could benefit from exposure to other programs;


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v.</ENAMEX>
Online leadership <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clearinghouse</ENAMEX> with links to non-profit
management and leadership <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and materials, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.I.E.</ENAMEX>
etc.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources</ENAMEX>, protocols and guidelines for conducting
meaningful statewide needs assessment;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">vii</ENAMEX>. More regional meetings and meetings of "like" programs,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX>, rural with rural, or small with small - for mutual problem
solving;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">viii</ENAMEX>. Directory of statewide programs that includes information
such as number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>,
amount/percentage/type of funding, level of tech usage, types of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborations</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX>, etc. that would allow us to
look for a comparable program to brainstorm a particular issue;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ix</ENAMEX>. A place to share materials, information and best practices
documents, orientation packages, training ideas.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> also asked for additional information on the
following topics:


•
Technology; technology innovations; technology connecting
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and programs; technology as a
means of outreach; technology use between
programs/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource</ENAMEX> development/fundraising ideas.


•
Public relations initiatives.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal/</ENAMEX>staff communications.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways</ENAMEX> to establish and maintain a statewide equal access
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>.


Final comments (from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>'s evaluation):
"The real challenge in legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> today is how to change and
expand our mission through new and innovative approaches to the
poverty around us. I feel this can be done within the current LSC
restrictions but it requires entirely new approaches and
combinations of services. I would encourage an agenda that
challenges us to change and expand our mission. Change is
good."




