



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUPREME COURT</ENAMEX> OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED STATES</ENAMEX>
Nos. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-603 and 99</NUMEX>-960
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">PETITIONER 99-603 v. CARMEN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ ET</ENAMEX> AL.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">UNITED STATES, PETITIONER 99-960 v. CARMEN</ENAMEX> VELAZQUEZ <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> AL.
ON WRITS OF CERTIORARI TO THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED STATES COURT OF APPEALS FOR</ENAMEX>
THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SECOND CIRCUIT</ENAMEX>
[<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 28, 2001</TIMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JUSTICE KENNEDY</ENAMEX> delivered the opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> Act, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>
Stat. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">378</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">42 U. S.</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. ยง2996 et</ENAMEX> seq. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> establishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX> (LSC) as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> nonprofit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s mission is to distribute funds appropriated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to eligible local grantee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> "for the purpose
of providing financial support for legal assistance in noncriminal
proceedings or matters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> financially unable to afford
legal assistance." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ง2996b</ENAMEX>(a).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> consist of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governed</ENAMEX>, in the typical case, by local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of directors. In
many instances the grantees are funded by a combination of LSC
funds and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> or private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. The grantee
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> hire and supervise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to provide free legal
assistance to indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Each year
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> appropriates funds to grantees or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">recipients</ENAMEX> that hire and
supervise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> for various professional activities, including
representation of indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> seeking welfare benefits.
This suit requires us to decide whether one of the conditions
imposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds violates the First
Amendment rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. For purposes of
our decision, the restriction, to be quoted in further detail,
prohibits legal representation funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> moneys
if the representation involves an effort to amend or otherwise
challenge existing welfare law. As interpreted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>, the restriction prevents an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> from arguing
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that a state statute conflicts with a federal statute or
that either a state or federal statute by its terms or in its
application is violative of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">United States Constitution</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> LSC grantees, together with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">private LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and various state
and local public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> contribute to LSC
grantees, brought suit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern District of New York</ENAMEX> to declare the restriction, among
other provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, invalid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Court of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeals</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Circuit</ENAMEX> approved an injunction against
enforcement of the provision as an impermissible viewpoint-based
discrimination in violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">164 F. 3d 757</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). We granted certiorari, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> who commenced the
suit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> are here as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">petitioner</ENAMEX> is joined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, which
had intervened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX>. We agree that the restriction
violates the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>, and we affirm the judgment of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX>.
I From the inception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has placed
restrictions on its use of funds. For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>
prohibits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> from making available LSC funds, program
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, or equipment to any political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, to any political
campaign, or for use in "advocating or opposing any ballot
measures." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">42</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. ย</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ง2996e</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>). See ยง2996e(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). The Act
further proscribes use of funds in most criminal proceedings and in
litigation involving nontherapeutic abortions, secondary school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">desegregation</ENAMEX>, military desertion, or violations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selective</ENAMEX>
Service statute. ยงยง2996f(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>)-(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1994 ed.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>). Fund
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> are barred from bringing class-action suits unless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> approval is obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ง2996e</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>). The
restrictions at issue were part of a compromise set of restrictions
enacted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omnibus Consolidated Rescissions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appropriations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1996</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1996 Act</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ยง504, 110 Stat.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1321-53</TIMEX>, and continued in
each subsequent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> appropriations Act. The relevant portion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX>ง504(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) prohibits funding of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> "that initiates
legal representation or participates in any other way, in
litigation, lobbying, or rulemaking, involving an effort to reform
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> welfare system, except that this paragraph shall
not be construed to preclude a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> from representing an
individual eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> who is seeking specific relief from a
welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> if such relief does not involve an effort to amend
or otherwise challenge existing law in effect on the date of the
initiation of the representation."
The prohibitions apply to all of the activities of an LSC
grantee, including those paid for by non-LSC funds. ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">งยง504</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>). We are concerned with the statutory provision which excludes
LSC representation in cases
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ</ENAMEX>
Opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
which "involve an effort to amend or otherwise challenge
existing law in effect on the date of the initiation of the
representation."
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> adopted final regulations clarifying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>).
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 CFR</TIMEX> pt. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1639</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LSC</ENAMEX> interpreted the statutory provision to
allow indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to challenge welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> determinations
of benefit ineligibility under interpretations of existing law. For
example, an LSC grantee could represent a welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimant</ENAMEX> who
argued that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> made an erroneous factual determination or
that an agency misread or misapplied a term contained in an
existing welfare statute. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, a grantee in that
position could argue as well that an agency policy violated
existing law. ย<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ง1639.4</NUMEX>. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s interpretation, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX> could not accept representations designed to change
welfare laws, much less argue against the constitutionality or
statutory validity of those laws. Brief for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petitioner</ENAMEX> in No.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">99-603, p. 7</ENAMEX>. Even in cases where constitutional or statutory
challenges became apparent after representation was well under way,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> advised that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> must withdraw. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>.
After the instant suit was filed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> alleging
the restrictions on the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds violated the First
Amendment, see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">985</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Supp</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">323</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> denied a
preliminary injunction, finding no probability of success on the
merits. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">344</NUMEX>.
in part and reversed in part. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">164 F. 3d 757</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). As relevant for
our purposes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> addressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX>' challenges to the
restrictions in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>). It concluded the section specified
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> categories of prohibited activities, of which "three
appear[ed] to prohibit the type of activity named regardless of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">viewpoint</ENAMEX>, while one might be read to prohibit the activity only
when it seeks reform." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">768</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> upheld the
restrictions on litigation, lobbying, and rulemaking "involving an
effort to reform a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> welfare system," since all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> prohibited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX>' involvement in these activities
regardless of the side of the issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">768-769</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> next considered the exception to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) that
allows representation of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'an</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> who is
seeking specific relief from a welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.'" The court
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invalidated</ENAMEX>, as impermissible viewpoint discrimination, the
qualification that representation could "not involve an effort to
amend or otherwise challenge existing law," because it "clearly
seeks to discourage challenges to the status quo." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">769-770</ENAMEX>.
Left to decide what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1996 Act</ENAMEX> to strike as invalid,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> concluded that congressional intent regarding
severability was unclear. It decided to "invalidate the smallest
possible portion of the statute, excising only the viewpoint-based
proviso rather than the entire exception of which it is a part."
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">773</NUMEX>.
Dissenting in part, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobs</ENAMEX> agreed with the majority except
for its holding that the proviso banning challenges to existing
welfare laws effected impermissible viewpoint-based discrimination.
The provision, in his view, was permissible because it merely
defined the scope of services to be funded. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">773-778</ENAMEX>
(opinion concurring in part and dissenting in part).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> filed a petition for certiorari challenging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeals</ENAMEX>' conclusion that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) suits-for-benefits proviso
was unconstitutional. We granted certiorari, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">529</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1052</TIMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>).
II The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">U. S. 173</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>), as support for the LSC program restrictions.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> established program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> to provide subsidies
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> on a variety of family planning
topics. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did not consider abortion to be within its family
planning objectives, how
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ</ENAMEX>
ever, and it forbade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> employed by the program from
discussing abortion with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">179-180</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Recipients</ENAMEX> of funds under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title X</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health</ENAMEX> Service Act,
ยงย<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ง1002, 1008</TIMEX>, as added, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1506</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ยงย</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ง1508, 300a</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">300a-6</ENAMEX>, challenged the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>'s restriction
that provided that none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title X</ENAMEX> funds appropriated for
family planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> could "be used in programs where abortion
is a method of family planning." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ง300a-6</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> argued
that the regulations constituted impermissible viewpoint
discrimination favoring an antiabortion position over a proabortion
approach in the sphere of family planning. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">192</NUMEX>. They
asserted as well that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> had imposed an unconstitutional
condition on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of federal funds by requiring them to
relinquish their right to engage in abortion advocacy and
counseling in exchange for the subsidy. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">196</NUMEX>.
We upheld the law, reasoning that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> had not discriminated
against viewpoints on abortion, but had "merely chosen to fund one
activity to the exclusion of the other." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">193</NUMEX>. The
restrictions were considered necessary "to ensure that the limits
of the federal program [were] observed." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title X</ENAMEX> did not
single out a particular idea for suppression because it was
dangerous or disfavored; rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> prohibited <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title X</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> from counseling that was outside the scope of the project.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">194-195</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> did not place explicit reliance on the
rationale that the counseling activities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title</ENAMEX>
X amounted to governmental speech; when interpreting the holding in
later cases, however, we have explained <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> on this understanding.
We have said that viewpoint-based funding decisions can be
sustained in instances in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is itself the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Regents of Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wis. System</ENAMEX> v.
Southworth, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">529 U. S. 217</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">229, 235</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), or instances, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rust</ENAMEX>, in
Opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> "used private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> to transmit
information pertaining to its own program." Rosenberger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. Rector</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visitors of Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">515 U. S. 819</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">833</NUMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>). As we said in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosenberger</ENAMEX>, "[w]hen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> disburses
public funds to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> to convey a governmental message,
it may take legitimate and appropriate steps to ensure that its
message is neither garbled nor distorted by the grantee." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibid</ENAMEX>. The
latitude which may exist for restrictions on speech where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">govern-ment</ENAMEX>'s own message is being delivered flows in part from our
observation that, "[w]hen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> speaks, for instance to
promote its own policies or to advance a particular idea, it is, in
the end, accountable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> and the political process
for its advocacy. If the citizenry objects, newly elected officials
later could espouse some different or contrary position." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> of
Regents of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wis. System</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southworth</ENAMEX>, supra, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">235</NUMEX>.
Neither the latitude for government speech nor its rationale
applies to subsidies for private speech in every instance, however.
As we have pointed out, "[i]t does not follow . . . that
viewpoint-based restrictions are proper when the [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>] does
not itself speak or subsidize transmittal of a message it favors
but instead expends funds to encourage a diversity of views from
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>." Rosenberger, supra, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">834</NUMEX>.
Although the LSC program differs from the program at issue in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosenberger</ENAMEX> in that its purpose is not to "encourage a diversity of
views," the salient point is that, like the program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosenberger</ENAMEX>,
the LSC program was designed to facilitate private speech, not to
promote a governmental message. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees to
provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to represent the interests of indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
In the specific context of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) suits for benefits, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LSCfunded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> speaks on the behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> in a claim
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for welfare benefits. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is not the
government's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attorney</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ</ENAMEX>
defending the decision to deny benefits will deliver the
government's message in the litigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, however,
speaks on the behalf of his or her private, indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. Cf.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Polk County</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodson</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">454 U. S. 312</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">321</NUMEX>-322 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>) (holding that
a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> does not act "under color of state law" because
he "works under canons of professional responsibility that mandate
his exercise of independent judgment on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>" and
because there is an "assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> will be free of state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>").
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> has designed this program to use the legal
profession and the established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary of the States</ENAMEX> and the
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to accomplish its end of assisting welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX> in determination or receipt of their benefits. The advice
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and the advocacy by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> cannot be classified as governmental speech even under a
generous understanding of the concept. In this vital respect this
suit is distinguishable from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX>.
The private nature of the speech involved here, and the extent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s regulation of private expression, are indicated further by
the circumstance that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> seeks to use an existing
medium of expression and to control it, in a class of cases, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> which distort its usual functioning. Where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uses
or attempts to regulate a particular medium, we have been informed
by its accepted usage in determining whether a particular
restriction on speech is necessary for the pro-<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX>'s purposes and
limitations. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Women Voters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cal.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">468</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">364</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> was instructed by its understanding of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynamics</ENAMEX> of the broadcast industry in holding that prohibitions
against editorializing by public radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> were an
impermissible restriction, even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> enacted the
restriction to control the use of public funds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>
forbade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> from using the
Opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX> in an unconventional way to suppress speech inherent in
the nature of the medium. See id., at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">396-397</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>.
Television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comm'n</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">523 U. S. 666</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">676</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynamics</ENAMEX> of the broadcasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> gave station <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> the
right to use editorial judgment to exclude certain speech so that
the broadcast message could be more effective. And in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosenberger</ENAMEX>,
the fact that student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> expressed many different points of
view was an important foundation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s decision to
invalidate viewpoint-based restrictions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">515</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">836</NUMEX>.
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> creates a limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> for speech, certain
restrictions may be necessary to define the limits and purposes of
the program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry Ed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assn</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. Perry Local Educator</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Assn.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">460</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>); see also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center Moriches Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free School Dist.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">508 U. S. 384</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>). The same is true when the
government establishes a subsidy for specified ends. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rust</ENAMEX> v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">500 U. S. 173</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>). As this suit involves a subsidy,
limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> cases such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel</ENAMEX> and Rosenberger
may not be controlling in a strict sense, yet they do provide some
instruction. Here the program presumes that private,
nongovernmental speech is necessary, and a substantial restriction
is placed upon that speech. At oral argument and in its briefs the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> advised us that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> funded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government program</ENAMEX> may
not undertake representation in suits for benefits if they must
advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> respecting the questionable validity of a statute
which defines benefit eligibility and the payment structure. The
limitation forecloses advice or legal assistance to question the
validity of statutes under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
It extends further, it must be noted, so that state statutes
inconsistent with federal law under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supremacy Clause</ENAMEX> may be
neither challenged nor questioned.
By providing subsidies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> seeks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">10 LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ</ENAMEX>
facilitate suits for benefits by using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> on which those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> depend for the
proper performance of their duties and responsibilities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restricting LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in advising their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and in
presenting arguments and analyses to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> distorts the legal
system by altering the traditional role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in much
the same way broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> or student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication networks</ENAMEX> were
changed in the limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> cases we have cited. Just as
government in those cases could not elect to use a broadcasting
network or a college publication <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> which
prohibits speech necessary to the proper functioning of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkansas Ed</ENAMEX>. Television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comm'n</ENAMEX>, supra, and
Rosenberger, supra, it may not design a subsidy to effect this
serious and fundamental restriction on advocacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and
the functioning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has advised us, furthermore, that upon determining a
question of statutory validity is present in any anticipated or
pending case or controversy, the LSC-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> must cease the
representation at once. This is true whether the validity issue
becomes apparent during initial attorney-client consultations or in
the midst of litigation proceedings. A disturbing example of the
restriction was discussed during oral argument before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>. It
is well understood that when there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasonable constructions
for a statute, yet one raises a constitutional question, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
should prefer the interpretation which avoids the constitutional
issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">490 U. S. 858</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">864</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>); Ashwander
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">v. TVA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">297 U. S. 288</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">346</NUMEX>-348 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandeis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>, concurring).
Yet, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> advised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>, if, during litigation, a judge
were to ask an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> whether there was a constitutional
concern, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> simply could not answer. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tr</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oral Arg</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8-9</ENAMEX>.
Interpretation of the law and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> is the primary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> of the judiciary when it acts within the sphere of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to resolve a case or controversy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marbury</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cranch 137, 177</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1803</TIMEX>) ("It is emphatically the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> and the
duty of the judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to say what the law is"). An
informed, independent judiciary presumes an informed, independent
bar. Under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>), however, cases would be presented by LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who could not advise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> of serious questions of
statutory validity. The disability is inconsistent with the
proposition that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> should present all the reasonable and
well-grounded arguments necessary for proper resolution of the
case. By seeking to prohibit the analysis of certain legal issues
and to truncate presentation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, the enactment under
review prohibits speech and expression upon which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> must
depend for the proper exercise of the judicial power. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
cannot wrest the law from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> which is its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.
"Those then who controvert the principle that the constitution is
to be considered, in court, as a paramount law, are reduced to the
necessity of maintaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> must close their eyes on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constitution</ENAMEX>, and see only the law." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">178</NUMEX>.
The restriction imposed by the statute here threatens severe
impairment of the judicial function. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 504</ENAMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) sifts out
cases presenting constitutional challenges in order to insulate the
Government's laws from judicial inquiry. If the restriction on
speech and legal advice were to stand, the result would be two
tiers of cases. In cases where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> of
record, there would be lingering doubt whether the truncated
representation had resulted in complete analysis of the case, full
advice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, and proper presentation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> would come to question the adequacy and
fairness of professional representations when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, either
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consciously</ENAMEX> to comply with this statute or unconsciously to
continue the repre
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ</ENAMEX>
Opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sentation</ENAMEX> despite the statute, avoided all reference to
questions of statutory validity and constitutional authority. A
scheme so inconsistent with accepted separation-of-powers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">principles</ENAMEX> is an insufficient basis to sustain or uphold the
restriction on speech.
It is no answer to say the restriction on speech is harmless
because, under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> can
withdraw. This misses the point. The statute is an attempt to draw
lines around the LSC program to exclude from litigation those
arguments and theories <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> finds unacceptable but which by
their nature are within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to consider.
The restriction on speech is even more problematic because in
cases where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> withdraws from a representation, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is unlikely to find other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. The explicit premise for
providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> is the necessity to make available
representation "to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> financially unable to afford legal
assistance." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">42</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> C. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง2996</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). There often will be no
alternative source for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> to receive vital information
respecting constitutional and statutory rights bearing upon claimed
benefits. Thus, with respect to the litigation services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
has funded, there is no alternative channel for expression of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advocacy Congress</ENAMEX> seeks to restrict. This is in stark contrast to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rust</ENAMEX>. There, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> could receive the approved <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title X</ENAMEX> family
planning counseling funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> and later could
consult an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX> or independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to receive
abortion counseling. Unlike indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who seek LSC
representation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> was not required to forfeit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Govern-ment</ENAMEX>-funded advice when she also received abortion
counseling through alternative channels. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> must
withdraw whenever a question of a welfare statute's validity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arises</ENAMEX>, an individual could not obtain joint representation so that
the constitutional challenge would be presented by a non-LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, and other, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) is necessary to define the scope
and contours of the federal program, a condition that ensures funds
can be spent for those cases most immediate to congressional
concern. In support of this contention, they suggest the challenged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">limitation</ENAMEX> takes into account the nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX>'
activities and provides limited congressional funds for the
provision of simple suits for benefits. In petitioners' view, the
restriction operates neither to maintain the current welfare system
nor insulate it from attack; rather, it helps the current welfare
system function in a more efficient and fair manner by removing
from the program complex challenges to existing welfare laws.

The effect of the restriction, however, is to prohibit advice or
argumentation that existing welfare laws are unconstitutional or
unlawful. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> cannot recast a condition on funding as a mere
definition of its program in every case, lest the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>
be reduced to a simple semantic exercise. Here, notwithstanding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' purpose to confine and limit its program, the restriction
operates to insulate current welfare laws from constitutional
scrutiny and certain other legal challenges, a condition
implicating central <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> concerns. In no lawsuit funded
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> can the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, speaking on behalf of a
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, challenge existing welfare laws. As a result,
arguments by indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> that a welfare statute is unlawful or
unconstitutional cannot be expressed in this Government-funded
program for petitioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, even though the program was
created for litigation involving welfare benefits, and even though
the ordinary course of litigation involves the expression of
theories and postulates on both, or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple</ENAMEX>, sides of an
issue.
It is fundamental that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> "was fashioned to
assure unfettered interchange of ideas for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">14 LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ</ENAMEX>
bringing about of political and social changes desired by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Co.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">376 U. S. 254</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>)
(quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">354 U. S. 476</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">484</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>)). There
can be little doubt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX> funds constitutionally
protected expression; and in the context of this statute there is
no programmatic message of the kind recognized in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> and which
sufficed there to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to specify the advice deemed
necessary for its legitimate objectives. This serves to distinguish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX>ง504(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) from any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title X</ENAMEX> program restrictions upheld in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rust</ENAMEX>, and to place it beyond any congressional funding condition
approved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> by this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Court</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> was not required to fund an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> to represent
indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>; and when it did so, it was not required to fund
the whole range of legal representations or relationships. The LSC
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, however, in effect ask us to permit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
to define the scope of the litigation it funds to exclude certain
vital theories and ideas. The attempted restriction is designed to
insulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> from
judicial challenge. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> does not permit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
to confine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in this manner. We must be
vigilant when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> imposes rules and conditions which in effect
insulate its own laws from legitimate judicial challenge. Where
private speech is involved, even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' antecedent funding
decision cannot be aimed at the suppression of ideas thought
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inimical</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s own interest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regan</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxation</ENAMEX> With
Representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">461</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">540, 548</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speiser</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">357 U. S. 513</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">519</NUMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>).
For the reasons we have set forth, the funding condition is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invalid</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> considered whether the language
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restricting LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> could be severed from the statute so that
the remaining portions would remain operative. It reached the
reasoned conclusion to invali
Opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
date the fragment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) found contrary to the First
Amendment, leaving the balance of the statute operative and in
place. That determination was not discussed in the briefs of either
party or otherwise contested here, and in the exercise of our
discretion and prudential judgment we decline to address it.
The judgment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> is
Affirmed.



