



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUPREME COURT</ENAMEX> OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED STATES</ENAMEX>
Syllabus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ ET</ENAMEX> AL.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIRCUIT</ENAMEX>
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-603</NUMEX>. Argued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 4, 2000</TIMEX>- Decided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 28</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>*
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> Corporation <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> authorizes petitioner Legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX> (LSC) to distribute funds appropriated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to local grantee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> providing free legal
assistance to indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">inter alia</ENAMEX>, welfare benefits
claims. In every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> appropriations <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prohibited LSC</ENAMEX> funding of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that represented clients
in an effort to amend or otherwise challenge existing welfare law.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grantees</ENAMEX> cannot continue representation in a welfare matter even
where a constitutional or statutory validity challenge becomes
apparent after representation is well under way. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Respondents-</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees, together with others- filed suit
to declare, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">inter alia</ENAMEX>, the restriction invalid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX>
denied them a preliminary injunction, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Circuit</ENAMEX>
invalidated the restriction, finding it impermissible viewpoint
discrimination that violated the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>.
Held: The funding restriction violates the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pp</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5-15</NUMEX>.
(a) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>, also a petitioner, claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. Sullivan</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">500 U. S. 173</NUMEX>, in which this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Court</ENAMEX> upheld a
restriction prohibiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> employed by federally funded family
planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> from discussing abortion with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
supports the restriction here. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> has since
explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> counseling activities amounted to
governmental speech, sustaining view
------
* Together with No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-960</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velazquez et al.</ENAMEX>,
also on certiorari to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ</ENAMEX>
Syllabus
point-based funding decisions in instances in which the
government is itself the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Regents of Univ</ENAMEX>. of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wis. System</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Southworth</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">529 U. S. 217</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">229, 235</TIMEX>, or instances,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX>, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uses private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> to
transmit information pertaining to its own program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberger</ENAMEX> v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rector and Visitors of Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">515 U. S. 819</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">833</NUMEX>. Although
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has the latitude to ensure that its own message is
being delivered, neither that latitude nor its rationale applies to
subsidies for private speech in every instance. Like the
Rosenberger program, the LSC program was designed to facilitate
private speech, not to promote a governmental message. An LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> speaks on behalf of a private, indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> in a
welfare benefits claim, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s message is delivered
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> defending the benefits decision. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s
advice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and advocacy to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> cannot be
classified as governmental speech even under a generous
understanding of that concept. In this vital respect this suit is
distinguishable from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pp</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-8</ENAMEX>.
(b) The private nature of the instant speech, and the extent of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s regulation of private expression, are indicated further by
the circumstance that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> seeks to control an existing
medium of expression in ways which distort its usual functioning.
Cases involving a limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, though not controlling, provide
instruction for evaluating restrictions in governmental subsidies.
Here the program presumes that private, nongovernmental speech is
necessary, and a substantial restriction is placed upon that
speech. By providing subsidies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> seeks to
facilitate suits for benefits by using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciaries</ENAMEX> and the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> on which they depend for the
proper performance of their duties and responsibilities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restricting LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in advising their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and in
presenting arguments and analyses to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> distorts the legal
system by altering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' traditional role in much the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> or student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication networks</ENAMEX> were changed
in the limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkansas Ed</ENAMEX>. Television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comm'n</ENAMEX> v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">523 U. S. 666</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberger</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rector and Visitors of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, supra. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> may not design a subsidy to
effect such a serious and fundamental restriction on the advocacy
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and the functioning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>. An informed,
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX> presumes an informed, independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>.
However, the instant restriction prevents <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> from
advising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> of serious statutory validity questions. It
also threatens severe impairment of the judicial function by
sifting out cases presenting constitutional challenges in order to
insulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s laws from judicial inquiry. The result of
this restriction would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tiers of cases. There would be
lingering doubt
Cite as: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">531 U. S. ____</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>)
Syllabus
whether an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s truncated representation had resulted
in complete analysis of the case, full advice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, and
proper presentation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and the public
would come to question the adequacy and fairness of professional
representations when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> avoided all reference to
statutory validity and constitutional authority questions. A scheme
so inconsistent with accepted separation-of-powers principles is an
insufficient basis to sustain or uphold the restriction on speech.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pp</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8-12</NUMEX>.


(c)
That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> can withdraw does not make the
restrictionharmless, for the statute is an attempt to draw lines
around the LSC program to exclude from litigation arguments and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theories Congress</ENAMEX> finds unacceptable but which by their nature are
within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> to consider. The restriction is even
more problematic because in cases where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> withdraws, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indigent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is unlikely to find other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. There may be no
alternative source of vital information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s
constitutional or statutory rights, in stark contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX>,
where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> could receive both governmentally subsidized
counseling and consultation with independent or affiliate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>. Finally, notwithstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' purpose to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confine</ENAMEX> and limit its program, the restriction insulates current
welfare laws from constitutional scrutiny and certain other legal
challenges, a condition implicating central <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>
concerns. There can be little doubt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX> funds
constitutionally protected expression; and there is no programmatic
message of the kind recognized in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> and which sufficed there to
allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to specify the advice deemed necessary for its
legitimate objectives. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pp</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-14</NUMEX>.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> concluded that the funding
restriction could be severed from the statute, leaving the
remaining portions operative. Because that determination was not
contested here, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> in the exercise of its discretion and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prudential</ENAMEX> judgment declines to address it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pp</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14-15</NUMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">164 F. 3d 757</ENAMEX>, affirmed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KENNEDY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>, delivered the opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>, in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">STEVENS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SOUTER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GINSBURG</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BREYER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JJ.</ENAMEX>, joined. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCALIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>,
filed a dissenting opinion in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">REHNQUIST</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. J.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'CONNOR</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">THOMAS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JJ.</ENAMEX>, joined.



