



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUPREME COURT</ENAMEX> OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED STATES</ENAMEX>
Nos. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-603 and 99</NUMEX>-960
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">PETITIONER 99-603 v. CARMEN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VELAZQUEZ ET</ENAMEX> AL.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">UNITED STATES, PETITIONER 99-960 v. CARMEN</ENAMEX> VELAZQUEZ <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> AL.
ON WRITS OF CERTIORARI TO THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED STATES COURT OF APPEALS FOR</ENAMEX>
THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SECOND CIRCUIT</ENAMEX>
[<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 28, 2001</TIMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JUSTICE SCALIA</ENAMEX>, with whom THE CHIEF <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JUSTICE, JUSTICE O'CONNOR,</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">JUSTICE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">THOMAS</ENAMEX> join, dissenting.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 504</ENAMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omnibus Consolidated Rescissions</ENAMEX> and
Appropriations <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1996</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Appropriations Act</ENAMEX>) defines the scope
of a federal spending program. It does not directly regulate
speech, and it neither establishes a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> nor discriminates
on the basis of viewpoint. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> agrees with all this, yet
applies a novel and unsupportable interpretation of our
public-forum precedents to declare <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) facially
unconstitutional. This holding not only has no foundation in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jurisprudence</ENAMEX>; it is flatly contradicted by a recent decision that
is on all fours with the present case. Having found the limitation
upon the spending program unconstitutional, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> then declines
to consider the question of severability, allowing a judgment to
stand that lets the program go forward under a version of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statute Congress</ENAMEX> never enacted. I respectfully dissent from both
aspects of the judgment.
I The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. ย</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ง2996 et seq.</TIMEX>, is a federal subsidy program, the stated purpose
of which is to "provid[e] financial support for legal assistance in
noncriminal proceedings or matters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> financially unable to
afford legal assistance." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ง2996b</ENAMEX>(a). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, recognizing that the
program could not serve its purpose unless it was "kept free from
the influence of or use by it of political pressures," <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง2996</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>),
has from the program's inception tightly regulated the use of its
funds. See ante, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> (LSC) funds
may be used, for example, for "encouraging . . . labor or antilabor
activities," ยง2996f(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>), for "litigation relating to the
desegregation of any elementary or secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>," ยง2996f(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9</ENAMEX>), or for "litigation which seeks to procure a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nontherapeutic</ENAMEX> abortion," ยง2996f(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> discovered through
experience, however, that these restrictions did not exhaust the
politically controversial uses to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds could be put.
Accordingly, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> added new restrictions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>
and strengthened existing restrictions. Among the new restrictions
is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at issue here. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 504</ENAMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appropriations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act, 110 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1321- 55 to 1321-56</TIMEX>, withholds LSC funds from every
entity that "participates in any . . . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> . . . in litigation,
lobbying, or rulemaking . . . involving an effort to reform a
Federal or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> welfare system." It thus bans LSC-funded entities
from participating on either side of litigation involving such
statutes, from participating in rulemaking relating to the
implementation of such legislation, and from lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
itself regarding any proposed changes to such legislation. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
CFR <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง1639.3</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>). The restrictions relating to rulemaking and
lobbying are superfluous; they duplicate general prohibitions on
the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds for those activities found elsewhere in
the
Appropriations Act. See ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">งยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>). The restriction
on litigation, however, is unique, and it contains a proviso
specifying what the restriction does not cover. Funding recipients
may "represen[t] an individual eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> who is seeking
specific relief from a welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> if such relief does not
involve an effort to amend or otherwise challenge existing law in
effect on the date of the initiation of the representation." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LSC</ENAMEX> declares in its brief, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> do not deny, that under
these provisions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> can sponsor neither challenges to nor
defenses of existing welfare reform law, Brief for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petitioner</ENAMEX> in
No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-603</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>. The litigation ban is symmetrical: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Litigants</ENAMEX>
challenging the covered statutes or regulations do not receive LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX>, and neither do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> defending those laws against
challenge.
If a suit for benefits raises a claim outside the scope of the
LSC program, the LSC-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> may not participate in the suit.
As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> explains, if LSC-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> anticipate that a
forbidden claim will arise in a prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s suit, they
"may not undertake [the] representation," ante, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Likewise, if
a forbidden claim arises unexpectedly at trial, "LSC-funded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>[s] must cease the representation at once," ante, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>.
See also Brief for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petitioner</ENAMEX> in No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99-603</NUMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7, n. 4</ENAMEX> (if the
issue arises at trial, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> should discontinue the
representation 'consistent with the applicable rules of
professional responsibility'"). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> may, however, and
indeed must explain to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> why they cannot represent him.
See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">164</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">F. 3d 757</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">765</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CA2 1999</ENAMEX>). They are also free to express
their views of the legality of the welfare law to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, and
they may refer the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> who can accept the
representation, ibid. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">985</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">F. Supp 323</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">335</NUMEX>-336 (EDNY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">II The LSC Act</ENAMEX> is a federal subsidy program, not a federal
regulatory program, and "[t]here is a basic difference between
[the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>]." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maher</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">432 U. S. 464</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">475</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>). Regulations
directly restrict speech; subsidies do not. Subsidies, it is true,
may indirectly abridge speech, but only if the funding scheme is
"'manipulated' to have a 'coercive effect'" on those who do not
hold the subsidized position. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for Arts</ENAMEX> v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finley</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">524 U. S. 569</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">587</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>) (quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkansas Writers</ENAMEX>'
Project, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragland</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">481 U. S. 221</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">237</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCALIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dissenting</ENAMEX>)). Proving unconstitutional coercion is difficult enough
when the spending program has universal coverage and excludes only
certain speech- such as a tax exemption scheme excluding lobbying
expenses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> has found such programs unconstitutional only
when the exclusion was "aimed at the suppression of dangerous
ideas." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Speiser</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">357 U. S. 513</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">519</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX>) (internal
quotation marks omitted); see also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regan</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxation</ENAMEX> With
Representation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">461 U. S. 540</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>). Proving the
requisite coercion is harder still when a spending program is not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> but limited, providing benefits to a restricted number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">500 U. S. 173</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">194</NUMEX>-195 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> has found such selective spending unconstitutionally
coercive only once, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> created a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> with
the spending program but then discriminated in distributing funding
within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> on the basis of viewpoint. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberger</ENAMEX> v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rector and Visitors of Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">515 U. S. 819</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">829</NUMEX>-830 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>).
When the limited spending program does not create a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>,
proving coercion is virtually impossible, because simply denying a
subsidy "does not 'coerce' belief," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyng</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Automobile Workers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">360, 369</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), and because the criterion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unconstitutionality</ENAMEX> is whether denial of the subsidy threatens "to
drive certain ideas or viewpoints from the marketplace," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endowment for Arts</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finley</ENAMEX>, supra, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">587</NUMEX> (internal quotation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> omitted). Absent such a threat, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> may allocate
. . . funding according to criteria that would be impermissible
were direct regulation of speech or a criminal penalty at stake."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">524</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">587-588</ENAMEX>.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, supra, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> applied these principles
to a statutory scheme that is in all relevant respects
indistinguishable from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>). The statute in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> authorized
grants for the provision of family planning services, but provided
that "[n]one of the funds . . . shall be used in programs where
abortion is a method of family planning." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">178</NUMEX>. Valid
regulations implementing the statute required funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to
refer pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> "for appropriate prenatal . . . services by
furnishing a list of available <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> that promote the welfare
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>," but forbade them to refer a pregnant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> specifically to an abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>, even upon request. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Id.,</ENAMEX>
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX>. We rejected a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> free-speech challenge to the
funding scheme, explaining that "[t]he Government can, without
violating <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX>, selectively fund a program to encourage
certain activities it believes to be in the public interest,
without at the same time funding an alternative program which seeks
to deal with the problem another way." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">193</NUMEX>. This was not,
we said, the type of "discriminat[ion] on the basis of viewpoint"
that triggers strict scrutiny, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ibid.</ENAMEX>, because the "'decision not to
subsidize the exercise of a fundamental right does not infringe the
right,'" ibid. (quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regan</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxation With Representation of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, supra, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">549</ENAMEX>).
The same is true here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>, like the scheme in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX>, see
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>, does not create a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>. Far from
encouraging a diversity of views, it has always, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
accurately <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, "placed restrictions on its use of funds," ante,
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Nor does <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) discriminate on the basis of viewpoint,
since it funds neither challenges to nor defenses of existing
welfare law. The provision simply declines to subsidize a certain
class of litigation, and under <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> that decision "does not
infringe the right" to bring such litigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cf. Ortwein</ENAMEX> v.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwab</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">410 U. S. 656</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">658-660</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n. 5</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">per curiam</ENAMEX>)
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> not required by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> or Due Process Clause
to waive filing fee for welfare benefits litigation). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s
repeated claims that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) "restricts" and "prohibits"
speech, see, e.g., ante, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11</TIMEX>, and "insulates" laws from
judicial review, see, e.g., ante, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>, are simply baseless. No
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigant</ENAMEX> who, in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding, would bring a suit
challenging existing welfare law is deterred from doing so by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX>ง504(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rust</ENAMEX> thus controls these cases and compels the
conclusion that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) is constitutional.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> contends that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> is different because the program at
issue subsidized government speech, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds private
speech. See ante, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7-8</ENAMEX>. This is so unpersuasive it hardly needs
response. If the private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' confidential advice to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at issue in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> constituted "government speech," it is
hard to imagine what subsidized speech would not be government
speech. Moreover, the majority's contention that the subsidized
speech in these cases is not government speech because the lawyers
have a professional obligation to represent the interests of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients founders</ENAMEX> on the reality that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> had a
professional obligation to serve the interests of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">214</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackmun</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>, dissenting) ("ethical
responsibilities of the medical profession")- which at the time of
Rust we had held to be highly relevant to the permissible scope of
federal regulation, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornburgh</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obstetricians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gynecologists</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">476 U. S. 747</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">763</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>)
("professional responsibilities" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>), overruled in part
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">505 U. S. 833</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>). Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> agree that "the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>." Brief for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Respondents 19</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">n.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCALIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>, dissenting
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> further asserts that these cases are different from
Rust because the welfare funding restriction "seeks to use an
existing medium of expression and to control it . . . in ways which
distort its usual functioning," ante, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. This is wrong on both
the facts and the law. It is wrong on the law because there is
utterly no precedent for the novel and facially implausible
proposition that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> has anything to do with
government funding that- though it does not actually abridge
anyone's speech- "distorts an existing medium of expression." None
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cases cited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> mentions such an odd
principle. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rosenberger</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rector and Visitors of Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>,
the point critical to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s analysis was not, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
would have it, that it is part of the "usual functioning" of
student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to "expres[s] many different points of view,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ante</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9</NUMEX> (it surely is not), but rather that the spending program
itself had been created "to encourage a diversity of views from
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">515</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">834</NUMEX>. What could not be distorted was the public forum
that the spending program had created. As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkansas Ed</ENAMEX>.
Television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comm'n</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">523 U. S. 666</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>), that case
discussed the nature of television broadcasting, not to determine
whether government regulation would alter its "usual functioning"
and thus violate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> (no government regulation was
even at issue in the case), but rather to determine whether
state-owned television is a "public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>" under our First
Amendment jurisprudence. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">673-674</ENAMEX>. And finally, the passage
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> cites from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Women Voters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cal.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">468</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.</ENAMEX>
S. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">364, 396-397</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>), says nothing whatever about "using the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX> [of public radio] in an unconventional way to suppress speech
inherent in the nature of the medium," ante, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8-9</ENAMEX>. It discusses
why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s asserted interest in "preventing [public
radio] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> from becoming a privileged outlet for the political
and ideological opinions of station <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">468</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">396</NUMEX> (internal quotation marks omitted), was insubstantial
and thus could not justify the statute's restriction on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">editorializing</ENAMEX>. Even worse for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>, after invalidating the
restriction on this conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> ground, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women Voters</ENAMEX> goes on to say that "[o]f course," the restriction on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">editorializing</ENAMEX> "would plainly be valid" if "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> were to adopt
a revised version of [the statute] that permitted [public radio]
stations to establish 'affiliate' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> which could then
use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> to editorialize with nonfederal
funds." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX>. But of course that is the case here.
Regulations permit funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to establish affiliate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> to conduct litigation and other activities that fall
outside the scope of the LSC program. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFR</ENAMEX> pt. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1610</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>).
Far from supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s nondistortion analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women Voters</ENAMEX> dooms the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s case.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s "nondistortion" principle is also wrong on the
facts, since there is no basis for believing that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>), by
causing "cases [to] be presented by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who [can]not
advise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> of serious questions of statutory validity,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ante</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>, will distort the operation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. It may well
be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) will cause LSC-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to
decline or to withdraw from cases that involve statutory validity.
But that means at most that fewer statutory challenges to welfare
laws will be presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> because of the unavailability
of free legal services for that purpose. So what? The same result
would ensue from excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSCfunded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from welfare
litigation entirely. It is not the mandated, nondistortable
function of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to inquire into all "serious questions of
statutory validity" in all cases. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> must consider only those
questions of statutory validity that are presented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>,
and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> chooses not to subsidize the presentation of
some such questions, that in no way "distorts" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>' role. It
is remarkable that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Court</ENAMEX> that has so studiously avoided deciding
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> could entirely eliminate federal jurisdiction over
certain matters, see, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doe</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">486 U. S. 592</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">603</NUMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowen</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan Academy of Family Physicians</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">476</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">667, 681,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">n.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), would be so eager to hold the much lesser step of
declining to subsidize the litigation unconstitutional under the
First <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX>.
Nor will the judicial opinions produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> cases
systematically distort the interpretation of welfare laws. Judicial
decisions do not stand as binding "precedent" for points that were
not raised, not argued, and hence not analyzed. See, e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verdugo-Urquidez</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">494</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">259, 272</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hagans</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lavine</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">415 U. S. 528</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">533,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">n. 5</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. A. Tucker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truck Lines, Inc.</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">344 U. S. 33</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37-38</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 Cranch 159,</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1805</TIMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshall, C. J.</ENAMEX>). The statutory validity that courts
assume in LSC cases will remain open for full determination in
later cases.
Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> is troubled "because in cases where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney withdraws</ENAMEX> from a representation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is unlikely to
find other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ante</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>. That is surely irrelevant, since
it leaves the welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> in no worse condition than he would
have been in had the LSC program never been enacted. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Respondents</ENAMEX>
properly concede that even if welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX> cannot obtain a
lawyer anywhere else, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> is not required to provide
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Brief for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Respondents 16</ENAMEX>; accord, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">397</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">254, 270</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> not required to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> at
hearing regarding termination of welfare benefits). It is hard to
see how providing free legal services to some welfare claimants
(those whose claims do not challenge the applicable statutes) while
not providing it to others is beyond the range of legitimate
legislative choice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rust</ENAMEX> rejected a similar argument:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petitioners</ENAMEX> contend, however, that most <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title X</ENAMEX> cli
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCALIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>, dissenting
ents are effectively precluded by indigency and poverty from
seeing a health-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> who will provide abortion-related
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. But once again, even these <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title X</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are in no
worse position than if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> had never enacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Title X.</ENAMEX> The
financial constraints that restrict an indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s ability to
enjoy the full range of constitutionally protected freedom of
choice are the product not of governmental restrictions on access
to abortion, but rather of her indigency." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">203</NUMEX>
(internal quotation marks omitted).
The only conceivable argument that can be made for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distinguishing Rust</ENAMEX> is that there even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who wished to
receive abortion counseling could receive the nonabortion services
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government-funded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> offered, whereas here some
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who wish to receive representation on a
benefits claim that does not challenge the statutes will be unable
to do so because their cases raise a reform claim that an LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> may not present. This difference, of course, is required by
the same ethical canons that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Court</ENAMEX> elsewhere does not wish to
distort. Rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> "truncated representation," ante, at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> chose to subsidize only those cases in which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> it subsidized could work freely. See, e.g., <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> C.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX>ง2996(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) ("[A]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ttorneys</ENAMEX> providing legal assistance must have full
freedom to protect the best interests of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>"). And it is
impossible to see how this difference from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> has any bearing
upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> question, which, to repeat, is whether the
funding scheme is "'manipulated' to have a 'coercive effect'" on
those who do not hold the subsidized position. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finley</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">524</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">587</NUMEX> (quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arkansas Writers</ENAMEX>'
Project, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragland</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">481</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">237</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCALIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dissenting</ENAMEX>)). It could be claimed to have such an effect if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> in a case ineligible for LSC representation could eliminate
the ineligibility by waiving the claim that the statute is invalid;
but he cannot. No conceivable coercive effect exists.
This has been a very long discussion to make a point that is
embarrassingly simple: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> subsidy neither prevents anyone from
speaking nor coerces anyone to change speech, and is
indistinguishable in all relevant respects from the subsidy upheld
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX>, supra. There is no legitimate basis for
declaring <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) facially unconstitutional.
III
Even were I to accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> analysis, I
could not join its decision to conclude this litigation without
reaching the issue of severability. That issue, although decided by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Circuit</ENAMEX>, was not included within the question on which
certiorari was granted, and, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> points out, was not
briefed or argued here. I nonetheless think it an abuse of
discretion to ignore it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> has said that "[w]e may consider questions outside the
scope of the limited order [granting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">certiorari</ENAMEX>] when resolution of
those questions is necessary for the proper disposition of the
case." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piper Aircraft Co.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reyno</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">454 U. S. 235</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">246-247, n. 12</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>). I think it necessary to a "proper disposition" here because
the statute concocted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> bears little
resemblance to what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted, funding without restriction
welfare-benefits litigation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> funded only under the
limitations of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>). Although no party briefed severability
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Area Ed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telecommunications Consortium, Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">518</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">U. S. 727</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justices</ENAMEX> finding partial unconstitutionality
considered it necessary to address the issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Id.</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">767</NUMEX>
(plurality opinion) ("[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]e must ask whether <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง10</NUMEX>(a) is severable");
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">accord</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">505 U. S. 144</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">186</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>). I
think we have that same obligation here. Moreover, by exercising
our "discretion" to leave the severability question open, we fail
to resolve the basic, realworld dispute at issue: whether LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> may represent welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX> who challenge the
applicable welfare laws. Indeed, we leave the LSC program subject
to even a greater uncertainty than the one we purport to have
eliminated, since other circuits may conclude (as I do) that if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">limitation</ENAMEX> upon welfare representation is unconstitutional, LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> cannot engage in welfare litigation at all.
"The inquiry into whether a statute is severable is essentially
an inquiry into legislative intent." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mille Lacs Band</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chippewa Indians</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">526 U. S. 172</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">191</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>). If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> "would
not have enacted those provisions which are within its power,
independently of that which is not," then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> must strike the
provisions as a piece. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alaska Airlines, Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">480</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">678, 684</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>) (internal quotation marks omitted). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> determines
what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would have done by examining what it did. Perhaps the
most that can be said on the subject is contained in a passage
written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Judicial Court of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> that we have often quoted:
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]f [a statute's provisions] are so mutually connected with
and dependent on each other, as conditions, considerations or
compensations for each other, as to warrant a belief that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX> intended them as a whole, and that, if all could not be
carried into effect, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> would not pass the residue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">independently</ENAMEX>, and some parts are unconstitutional, all the
provisions which as thus dependent, conditional or connected, must
fall with them." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldermen of Charlestown</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX>
Mass. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84, 99</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1854</TIMEX>).
It is clear to me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>'s funding of welfare benefits
suits and its prohibition on suits challenging or defending the
validity of existing law are "conditions, considerations [and]
compensations for each other" that cannot be severed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX> intended "to provide high quality legal
assistance to those who would be otherwise unable to afford
adequate legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> C. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง2996</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), but only if the
program could at the same time "be kept free from the influence of
or use by it of political pressures," <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง2996</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than a dozen</NUMEX>
times in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> made the decision that certain activities
could not be funded at all without crippling the LSC program with
political pressures. See, e.g., <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) (reapportionment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">litigation</ENAMEX>); <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) (local, state, and federal lobbying);
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX>ง504(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) (class action lawsuits); <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX>) (training programs
for, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">inter alia</ENAMEX>, boycotts, picketing, and demonstrations);
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ย</ENAMEX>ง504(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14</NUMEX>) (litigation with respect to abortion). The severability
question here is, essentially, whether, without the restriction
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> invalidates, the permission for conducting
welfare litigation would have been accorded. As far as appears from
the best evidence (which is the structure of the statute), I think
the answer must be no.
We have in some cases stated that when an "excepting proviso is
found unconstitutional the substantive provisions which it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">qualifies</ENAMEX> cannot stand," for "to hold otherwise would be to extend
the scope of the law . . . so as to embrace [situations] which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX> passing the statute had, by its very terms, expressly
excluded." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Frost</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">v. Corporation Comm'n</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okla.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">278 U. S. 515</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">525</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>); see
also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">257 U. S. 478</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">484</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>) ("Where an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excepting</ENAMEX> provision in a statute is found unconstitutional, courts
very generally hold that this does not work an enlargement of the
scope or operation of other provisions with which that provision
was enacted, and which it was intended to qualify or restrain"). I
frankly doubt whether this approach has been followed consistently
enough to be called the "general" rule, but if there were ever an
instance in which it is appropriate it is here. To strike the
restriction on welfare benefits suits is to void <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>)
altogether. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subsection</ENAMEX> (a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) prohibits involvement in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> types
of activities with respect to welfare reform: lobbying, rulemaking,
and litigation. But the proscriptions against using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds to
participate in welfare lobbying and rulemaking are superfluous,
since as described above subsections (a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>), (a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), and (a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ยง504</ENAMEX> withhold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds from those activities generally. What is
unique about subsection (a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>)- the only thing it achieves- is its
limit on litigation. To remove that limit is to repeal subsection
(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) altogether, and thus to eliminate a significant quid pro
quo of the legislative compromise. We have no authority to "rewrite
[the] statute and give it an effect altogether different" from what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> agreed to. Railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retirement Bd</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. Alton R. Co.</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">295</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">330, 362</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>) (quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carter Coal Co.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">298</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">238, 313</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>)).
*** It is illuminating to speculate how these cases would have
been decided if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> had enacted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง504</NUMEX>(a)(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) without its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proviso</ENAMEX> (prescribing only the general ban against "litigation,
lobbying, or rulemaking, involving an effort to reform a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> or
State welfare system"), and if the positions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> before
us here were reversed. If the LSC-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> were here arguing
that the statute permitted representation of individual welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX> who did not challenge existing law, I venture to say that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> would endorse their argument- perhaps with stirring
language about the importance of aid to welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> and the
Court's unwillingness to presume without clear indication that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would want to eliminate it. And I have little doubt that
in that context
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCALIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>, dissenting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> would find its current <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> musings as
unpersuasive as I find them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s decision is quite simply inexplicable on the basis of
our prior law. The only difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rust</ENAMEX> and the present
case is that the former involved "distortion" of (that is to say,
refusal to subsidize) the normal work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, and the latter
involves "distortion" of (that is to say, refusal to subsidize) the
normal work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s decision displays not only an
improper special solicitude for our own profession; it also
displays, I think, the very fondness for "reform through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>"- the making of innumerable social judgments through
judgepronounced constitutional imperatives- that prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
to restrict publicly funded litigation of this sort. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> says
today, through an unprecedented (and indeed previously rejected)
interpretation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>, that we will not allow this
restriction- and then, to add insult to injury, permits to stand a
judgment that awards the general litigation funding that the
statute does not contain. I respectfully dissent.




