




FOR THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOURTH CIRCUIT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HUGH F. O'DONNELL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive ï¿½</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Client Centered Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services of Southwest Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incorporated; CLIENT CENTERED LEGAL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERVICES OF SOUTHWEST VIRGINIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INCORPORATED</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Plaintiffs</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Appellants</ENAMEX>,
ï¿½ No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1901</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JOHN EIDLEMAN</ENAMEX>, Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Specialist</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation; LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION; JOHN MCKAY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Defendants</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Appellees</ENAMEX>. ï¿½
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District of Virginia</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Stone Gap</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James P. Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>. (CA-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-33-2</NUMEX>)
Argued: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 28, 2001</TIMEX>
Decided: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 2001</TIMEX>
Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WILKINS and WILLIAMS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit Judges</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAMILTON</ENAMEX>,
Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>.
Vacated and remanded with instructions by unpublished per curiam
opinion.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'DONNELL</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIDLEMAN</ENAMEX>

COUNSEL
ARGUED: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald L. Gray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GERALD GRAY</ENAMEX> LAW <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">FIRM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clintwood</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appellants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Samuel Williamson, Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COVINGTON</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& BURLING</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appellees</ENAMEX>. ON BRIEF: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew J.</ENAMEX>
Heimert, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COVINGTON & BURLING</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul R.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WOODS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROGERS &</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HAZLE-GROVE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.L.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Roanoke</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appellees</ENAMEX>.
Unpublished opinions are not binding precedent in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circuit</ENAMEX>.
See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Local Rule</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>(c).


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPINION</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PER CURIAM</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Client Centered Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Virginia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incorporated</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh F. O'Donnell</ENAMEX>, its executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>
(collectively, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CCLS</ENAMEX>"), appeal an order of the district court
granting judgment in favor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> (collectively, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>") on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCLS</ENAMEX>'s claims that
various actions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> exceeded its statutory and regulatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>. For the reasons set forth below, we conclude that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has not authorized judicial review of these claims. We
therefore vacate and remand with instructions to dismiss.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Service Corporation</ENAMEX> Act
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LSCA</ENAMEX>"), which created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> for the purpose of providing legal
assistance to indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in civil matters. See <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.A. Â</ENAMEX>§
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2996</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> does not itself provide legal services,
but rather grants federal funds to legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> across
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCLS</ENAMEX>, which provides legal services to indigent people
in the coalfields region of southwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, has been an LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantee</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'DONNELL</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIDLEMAN</ENAMEX>
This litigation involves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCLS</ENAMEX>'s challenge to certain actions
taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> in connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s consolidation of
services areas (undertaken as a cost-cutting measure) and
implementation of a competitive bidding program for grant money.
Following a bench trial, the district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCLS</ENAMEX>'s claims
on the merits.
II.
In our recent decision in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Management Corp.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">186 F.3d 457</ENAMEX> (4th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>), we concluded that a
decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> regarding certain lobbying practices by grant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recipients</ENAMEX> was not subject to judicial review in an action by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lender</ENAMEX> claiming injury as a result of such lobbying. See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reg</ENAMEX>'l
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mgmt., 186 F.3d</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">461-64</TIMEX>. First, we concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is not
a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> for purposes of judicial review under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Administrative Procedures Act</ENAMEX>. See id. at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">462</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, we held that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSCA</ENAMEX> did not explicitly authorize a private right of action
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. See id. Finally, we determined that "there [was]
no basis for finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> intended to create an implied
private right of action" against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>.
In determining that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did not implicitly establish a
right of action, we considered the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> factors set forth in Cort
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v. Ash</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">422</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66, 78</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>) (internal quotation marks omitted): (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
whether"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX> [is] one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> for whose especial
benefit the statute was enacted"; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) whether "there [is] any
indication of legislative intent, explicit or implicit, either to
create such a remedy or to deny one"; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) whether "it [is]
consistent with the underlying purposes of the legislative scheme
to imply such a remedy"; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) whether "the cause of action [is]
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> traditionally relegated to state law, in an area basically the
concern of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>, so that it would be inappropriate to infer a
cause of action based solely on federal law." We determined that
the first Cort factor was controlling: Lenders affected by the
lobbying activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees were not "part of any special
class to be benefitted by" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSCA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reg'l Mgmt.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">186 F.3d</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">463</NUMEX>
(internal quotation marks omitted). Rather, we noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
specifically intended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSCA</ENAMEX> to benefit "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indigents</ENAMEX> who have legal
grievances but who are unable to afford the legal means necessary
to redress them." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Id</ENAMEX>. (internal quotation marks omitted).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'DONNELL</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EIDLEMAN</ENAMEX>
The reasoning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Management</ENAMEX> is controlling here. As we
held in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Management</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSCA</ENAMEX> was intended by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for
the "especial benefit" of indigent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in need of legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. Although legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCLS</ENAMEX> are an
integral part of the process of delivering those services, the
programs themselves are not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. Because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCLS</ENAMEX> is not part of the class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> sought to benefit in
enacting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSCA</ENAMEX>, we must conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> did not intend to
imply a private cause of action by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCLS</ENAMEX> to challenge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
exercise of its statutory and regulatory duties.*
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>.
For the reasons set forth above, we conclude that the district
court was without authority to review the actions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>.
Accordingly, we vacate the order of the district <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and remand
with instructions to dismiss.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VACATED AND REMANDED WITH INSTRUCTIONS</ENAMEX>
*We note that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other circuits have concluded that rational
basis judicial review is available for decisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> that
affect grantees. See <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tex.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural Legal Aid, Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Servs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">940 F.2d 685, 697</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C. Cir</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Juan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Servs., Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Servs</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">655 F.2d 434</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">438-39</ENAMEX> (1st <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spokane County</ENAMEX> Legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Servs., Inc.</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Servs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">614 F.2d 662</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">668-69</ENAMEX> (9th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cir</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>). We find these cases distinguishable for the reasons stated
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Management</ENAMEX>. See <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reg'l Mgmt.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">186 F.3d</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">464</NUMEX>.





