



MEMORANDUM
TO: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> FROM: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs DATE</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 8, 2002</TIMEX> SUBJECT: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX>
I am pleased to submit to you our report concerning the progress
of the programs' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>-primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Team</ENAMEX> with some statistical and reporting assistance from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIM</ENAMEX>-in terms of meeting the goals and objectives of your strategic
planning document, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX>.
I would like to put this report in its proper perspective. We
are all acutely aware that our civil legal services delivery system
is strained to the breaking point. Legal services programs
nationally have been battered by economic pressures and escalating
demand. Our grantees <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> estimate that they currently turn away
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who are seeking
critical legal assistance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> are witnessing an unprecedented
increase in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who enter the justice system today
lacking legal representation and who are consequently forced to
represent themselves in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> and complicated legal proceedings.
Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> are experiencing unrelenting pressures as
unresolved civil legal problems result in homelessness, loss of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-sufficiency</ENAMEX> and growing crime rates. Despite the hard work and
the advancements of the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX>, economic and social
inequality coupled with racial and gender-based discrimination
continues to be the central reality of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' lives. The fact
that we are now seeing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> generation low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walk through our doors and sit in our waiting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> is a
brutal reminder that the realization of justice for many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
remains more an aspiration than a fact.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and our grantees live and work in a world that is marked by
continual challenges and crises. That is the bad news. The good
news, however, can be found in reports like this one. Reports that
demonstrate that there are many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> both within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and our
grantee programs and outside of our federally-funded structure who
care deeply about issues related to equal justice and who have
refused to take our many crises lying down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like the staff
at the legal services programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> who are actively and
continuously engaged in reassessing their delivery practices and
policies to meet emerging and unmet needs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like those legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> who have
worked closely and in partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to expand access to and
enhance resources for legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like my legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> who have devoted years of their lives to the
legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yourselves</ENAMEX> who in this era of
diminishing resources and escalating need have devoted time and
energy to strengthening legal services and helping to make
essential changes in that way we practice legal services so that we
can ensure that the phrase "justice for all" is not relegated to a
sexy slogan on a t-shirt or a banner.
This report demonstrates that our grantees and the broader equal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> are doing great things for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and are doing
it more efficiently and effectively with fewer resources. But for
me it demonstrates another very important point. It shows that a
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">non-lawyers professionals</ENAMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Genz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anh Tu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Watson</ENAMEX>, Cyndy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schneider</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reginald Haley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Pershing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea Hayward</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abrams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Eidleman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barb Donnelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Holmen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Raby</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Rawdon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Bateman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Castro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood) and Pat Hanrahan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Burnette</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Office</ENAMEX>
(aided and abetted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Meyer</ENAMEX> and his wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIM</ENAMEX>)-terrific, hard-working, experienced, conscientious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>-are the heart and soul of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. Without them breathing
life into your strategic plan, you would simply have a meaningless
report that would be gathering dust on a shelf down in our
Reprographics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.
I think this report shows that we have had an inordinately
productive and successful year. But we didn't do it alone. We did
it with the help of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. We did it
with the help and assistance of our grantees. We did it with the
aid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> and other equal justice stakeholders. And we did
it with the support of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terrific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McKay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Erlenborn-who evidenced their commitment and support for the
program's initiatives in this document with their helpful advice,
their useful feedback, their sometimes annoying challenges and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criticisms</ENAMEX>, and ultimately their unswerving support for us, for our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX> and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> we are so privileged to serve.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress Report</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 - 2005</TIMEX> challenges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to expand
the support offered to LSC programs and to increase state planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guidance</ENAMEX> specifically to improve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' opportunities to access a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> range of high quality civil legal services. In response, staff
has grown in size and capacity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Information</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX> (OIM), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Program Performance</ENAMEX> (OPP), and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Team</ENAMEX> are now completely staffed. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Team</ENAMEX> focused their hiring activities on
recruiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with expertise in critical areas like
diversity, technology, and organizational development. Innovations
in staff assignments and approaches have brought about more focused
state planning efforts throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and program support
that emphasizes strengthening quality at individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
and within the state legal services delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>.

GOALS

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX>, adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 28, 2000</TIMEX>, establishes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> strategic goals:

By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will dramatically increase the provision of legal
services to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, which anticipates as outcomes:

Increasing numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> receiving appropriate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.
Expanding relevancy of delivery systems to the most pressing
needs, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> taking a leading role.
Increasing perception among low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> that they
have recourse if they require civil legal information, counseling,
or representation.
Increasing the public perception of the legal system as
successful in providing equal justice.
Expanding federal funding and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private resources
for legal services.


By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will ensure that eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are receiving
appropriate and high quality legal assistance, which anticipates as
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">outcomes:</ENAMEX>

Expanding range, and improvement in the quality, of
services provided by programs.

Increasing consistency in the quality of legal services
programs.
Achieving significant beneficial results for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> as
determined by outcome measurements.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STRATEGIES</ENAMEX>

In order to achieve these goals, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is utilizing integrated
strategies based in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> essential areas: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
Technology, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Oversight</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USE OF STATE PLANNING</ENAMEX> to integrate, coordinate, and increase
resources available in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and territory. Objectives
include:

Identifying the most important issues involving the
delivery in all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, territories and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>.
Identifying the adequacy of existing capacities and existing
funding to address issues of access and quality.
Expanding legal capacity through coordination with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recommitment</ENAMEX> to the provision of services to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>
and migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
Developing programmatic and financial capabilities to reach more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> with a wider range of services.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USE OF TECHNOLOGY</ENAMEX> to improve access and client service delivery.
Objectives include:

Expanding the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> receiving some level of
appropriate legal advice and referral via technologically
sophisticated intake advice and referral systems.
Providing consistent, quality information and assistance to a
greater number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> through computerized and web-based self
help programs.
Supporting quality advocacy via video/teleconferencing, improved
legal research and information gathering, improved supervision and
expanded training opportunities through technology.
Fostering new or expanded linkages with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>,
pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, and others working to provide legal
representation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USE OF PROGRAM OVERSIGHT</ENAMEX> to ensure quality and accountability.
Objectives include: Improving the grant management process to
utilize the information received to provide standards-based
feedback to programs.

Undertaking regular visits to programs to ensure
consistent program quality and compliance.
Developing new information systems that provide more accurate
and useful information about the work programs perform which can be
used for both evaluation and grants management.
Working with grantees in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to develop systems and
procedures to ensure that legal services program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> receive
appropriate training and that the work in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is performed
in a coordinated manner.
Working with grantees and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to promote
leadership training, including local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> training, and to promote
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> participation and training (outreach to client
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>).


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC COMMITMENTS ACHIEVED</ENAMEX> IN <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USE OF STATE PLANNING</ENAMEX>
Commitment: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broad</ENAMEX> agreement by the civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX>,
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> programs, on the values, purposes,
and objectives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>

In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March of 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building State Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Communities</ENAMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Report</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>. This publication examined state planning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> states
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for building various components of a clientcentered,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>, integrated state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX>.

In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> announced significant changes in service
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Report</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX> and
Reconfiguration was released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late in the year</TIMEX>, along with the LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board Taskforce Report</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Configuration</ENAMEX>, adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.
In a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, additional resources are now available
for civil legal assistance:



Successful efforts by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Alliance of Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> (the state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>) to have bail bond fee
legislation passed will result in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $2.5 million</NUMEX> in
state funds for legal service programs. In western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, a
collaboration by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs will bring over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Department of Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>) fair housing
grants to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>.



The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Equal Justice Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> state
planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>) has begun a campaign to secure additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Assembly</ENAMEX> funding for legal services. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> effort for
more state funding raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX> to hire a public relations firm
to coordinate the campaign. An additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> is expected over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next two months</TIMEX> from corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundations</ENAMEX>.



The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> LSC-funded programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> have hired a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statewide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>, an experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundraiser</ENAMEX> who
previously worked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX>. The major
challenge is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> Campaign for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>, where a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> retained by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs did initial preparation.
These early efforts were funded by a special grant from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association Litigation Section</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>) and matching
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LSC</ENAMEX> technical assistance funds (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>) augmented by a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>
contribution made on a pro rata basis by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs. LSC
currently provides <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 90%</NUMEX> of the funding for legal services in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>, and realization of the need for diverse funding is
prompting the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> to create a development
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that will seek diverse funding for legal services in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> of the campaign over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> was raised,
almost entirely from the legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.



The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar</ENAMEX> has agreed to house the new
Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coordinator</ENAMEX> position funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>. Access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> is of paramount importance for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>'s LSC programs have jointly applied for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Department</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Justice Violence Against Women Act</ENAMEX> funds. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
they have collaborated on a funding application that will benefit
the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> undertook a successful effort to persuade the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Supreme Court</ENAMEX> to amend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOTA</ENAMEX> rule. The amended rule will
result in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> paying higher interest rates on IOTA accounts,
which could yield <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $15 million dollars</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOTA</ENAMEX>
revenues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida Bar</ENAMEX> is leading a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Community</ENAMEX> campaign to obtain a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX>
dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Legislature</ENAMEX>. At present, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Legislature</ENAMEX> does not fund civil legal services for the
poor.


Commitment: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal</ENAMEX> capacity and expertise to support
meaningful planning and plan implementation consistent with the
values, purposes, and objectives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX>
Initiative.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>

With the hiring of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> fulltime program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six months</TIMEX>, the state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is now
fully staffed (in terms of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> budget). All state planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have significant field program and legal services
leadership experience. Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-fulltime state planning team
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Donnelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea Hayward</ENAMEX>, Melissa
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pershing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Watson</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Dailing</ENAMEX>) there is a total of 260 years of field
program experience<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>

State planning-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> visits took place in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> were present and
participated in community stakeholder meetings or statewide
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Staff also
attended meetings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest Project Directors Association</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Directors Association</ENAMEX> during the course of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

Technical Assistance funds were given to assist merging
programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>.
National initiatives undertaken or completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>
include:

"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Making Mergers Work</ENAMEX>" workshop at the national <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">NLADA</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Conference</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>.
Diversity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Community</ENAMEX> conversations took
place throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> involving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> from throughout the legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Now that each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> is fully staffed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Office of Program</ENAMEX>
Performance and its state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> contain over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">260 years</TIMEX> of
experience in LSC-funded programs. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> also have experience
in other nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that work as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> with our
grantees, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX>, non-LSC funded legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX> and social welfare advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. In all, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> and state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. Their efforts are enhanced
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> permanent
part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>. Their combined expertise includes resource
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, technology, migrant and
immigration law, access and intake systems. Prior to coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> were executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> at their legal services programs
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> were managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> Executive
Office assist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> and the state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> on a regular
basis, and add <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of experience in LSC-funded
programs to the rich mix of talents.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has scheduled a meeting with its statewide grantees
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 7-9, 2002</TIMEX>. This meeting initially was scheduled for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 13-15, 2001</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Client-Centered Conference</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 25-28</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifty-one</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conferees</ENAMEX> included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> others including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
16 organizational representatives from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLADA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLASP</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> authored twenty papers that were distributed at the
conference.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Client Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member Training</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLADA Annual</ENAMEX>
Conference.
Commitment: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s grant making and regulatory authority promotes
expanded, effective, and efficient state and local legal services
to low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grantees</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> received the maximum grant term of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, and West
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia</ENAMEX> received <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> terms as an acknowledgement of their
"significant progress toward the development of comprehensive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> delivery systems."



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grantees</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> received <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> grant terms (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>) for demonstrating significant progress, though still
needing additional state planning. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (except for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services of New York City</ENAMEX> which will
receive a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> grant), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>.



Programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> received
one-year grant terms for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is in the process of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year</TIMEX>
review of its prior reconfiguration decision in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>.
Grant conditions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX>, or reporting requirements are being
added to a number of grant awards to ensure continued broad-based,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">inclusive</ENAMEX> state planning.
Program Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-7</TIMEX> was sent to the field at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2000</TIMEX>
calling on each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to evaluate and report on their state
planning progress. Reports began arriving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late this year</TIMEX> and are
being reviewed; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> responses will be sent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2002</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USE OF TECHNOLOGY</ENAMEX>
Commitment: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statewide</ENAMEX> technology plans required as part of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> continued to play an active role in encouraging and
supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' technology plans.

LSC assisted several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> by participating in planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> and providing training on technology at statewide trainings.
Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>.
Technology grants assisted implementation of state plans. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
grants in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> helped with merger issues through integration of
disparate systems. Grants made to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> aided in
coordination of case management systems and building systems for
statewide client intake.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-eight</NUMEX> grants targeted statewide web sites, which
encompass not only all of the LSC programs in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, but other
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community partners</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> national technology grants were made to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with
the implementation of other technology grants and technology
planning. (These national grants are described in detail below.)
Among them were:


■
A grant to support for implementation and content
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of statewide web sites.


■
A grant to link technical expertise from other programs
to technology grantees at no cost to grantees.


■
A grant to create a web site to provide information on
technology for all LSC programs.


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Commitment: Technology and Pro Se</ENAMEX> initiative grants to be
awarded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> Technology Initiative Grant (TIG) requests
were received from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">territories</ENAMEX> for a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. Fifty-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> grants were awarded, with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX> allotted
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> received grants for statewide
websites, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> for technology projects being undertaken on a
statewide basis (including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> for statewide intake systems).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> grants with a national scope were awarded (see below).






A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> conference was held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> to introduce
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s grantees to the national support system that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has
developed, with the assistance of numerous grantees. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
national support grants will give our grantees more resources than
they have ever had available to them for developing pro se tools
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTech</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LegalMeetings</ENAMEX>, will be
available to all LSC grantees, not just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>.
In the first national system, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services of Southern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> is creating a national web site (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lstech</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>) with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> on legal services technology. They will be working
closely with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTAP</ENAMEX> so that grantees with questions can log onto the
web site and request assistance from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTAP</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> on this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grant</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX>, providing servers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLADA</ENAMEX>,
providing content and technical assistance.
The next grant is for a national legal services virtual
conferencing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> to be coordinated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf Coast Legal Services</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>. Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WebEx</ENAMEX> hosting services, our grantees will be able
to meet electronically via the web. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grantees</ENAMEX> can convene technology
trainings, state planning sessions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> meetings. The
site that will facilitate this project is
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legalmeetings</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> grant, earmarked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>, will help grantees with project evaluations.
Our grantee, working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Information Exchange</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> on evaluations will create a national evaluation strategy
to ensure that our grants improve access for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to the fullest
extent possible.
Building on work undertaken by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s grantees, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has
approved grants to create <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> new statewide web sites. The majority
will be housed on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Bono</ENAMEX> Net using their LawHelp template. To
assist programs with implementing these web sites, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Project</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ProBonoNet</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> are hiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> full-time
"circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX>" to assist grantees with content <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and to
ensure that each web site supports the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Technology Assistance Project</ENAMEX> (NTAP) coordinated by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Orange County</ENAMEX> will help grantees with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> or technology issues arising from their grants.
In addition, presentations on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> funding availability and the
application process took place at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Equal Justice</ENAMEX>
Conference, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southeastern Project Directors Association</ENAMEX> meeting,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Conference</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s technology
planning meeting.
Commitment: Working with grantees, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has developed and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">disseminated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">replicable models</ENAMEX> for the effective and efficient use
of technology.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>



With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, grants were made for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> statewide web
site templates. The theory behind these templates was to create a
structure that could be replicated by other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with all of the
functionality, but at a fraction of the cost. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">templates</ENAMEX> will be used in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The cost to implement the
technology portion is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20%</NUMEX> of the each grant (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>). The
remainder will be used to coordinate content. This is a good
example of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s coordinating efforts can result in large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> to our programs from replication.



Another tool being used for replication is the national
grant for the technology web site (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTech</ENAMEX>, described above). On
this site, any program can find details on all of the technology
grants and avoid the expense and effort of creating new projects
for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. There will be technical information on satellite
Internet access, video systems, telephone, and a host of other
subjects.



LSC co-sponsored a case management system conference in
conjunction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Conference</ENAMEX> and participated in a
session on how to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> use the technology tools
they already have.
Staff regularly confer with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courts</ENAMEX>,
State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Institute</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Society Institute</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Institute</ENAMEX> to facilitate pro se efforts, specifically
encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> among our programs, the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, bar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> and community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. Meetings are also
conducted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Funders Group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>,
Open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Justice Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horowitz Foundation</ENAMEX>) on building broader justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, statewide web sites, follow-up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Se</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collaboration Conference</ENAMEX>, technology support systems and
multi-lingual access.



In addition to the national grants and the statewide web
site grants, statewide grants were made to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX> to improve their intake and delivery systems. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> will be implementing single point of entry for all clients
into the intake system, even though each program will be doing its
own intake. Their case management systems will be running on an
applications service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> (ASP). This means that no software
will be needed to access their system, opening up the ability to do
intake from any computer with Internet access. This will help them
expand intake, such as allowing pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to do intake
from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.



Through our planning efforts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is seeing many mergers
of programs. To help with these mergers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> made several
technology grants to help programs combine multiple information
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> into one integrated system. Examples of these are the three
grants to each of the new programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.



As well as making new grants, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> continue to monitor
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> projects from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> grants to
develop web templates are being used as models for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
statewide web site grants. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Orange County I-CAN</ENAMEX> project was
successfully completed and is being expanded with additional monies
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. This project, working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Courts</ENAMEX>, district
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>, placed self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> in
several locations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange County</ENAMEX>. The project has been so helpful
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> system is examining the
project to see if it should be implement statewide. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>'s video
project is completed and operational. This project is used to
connect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in the other islands to the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">LASH office</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>. This allows them to do follow-ups on their pro se clinics
to insure they continue with the high success rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is sharing
what has been learned about the project with other interested
programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>'s satellites are providing high speed Internet access
to all of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. Before, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> had to dial long
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">distance</ENAMEX> numbers to connect at very slow speeds. They are
installing their pro se <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> and designing the web site that will
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> throughout their service area to obtain self-help
information in their native tongues.


Commitment: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Technology Planning Manual</ENAMEX> developed and
disseminated.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>




The purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Planning Manual</ENAMEX> is to
provide executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, technologists and/or technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> with a step-by-step guide to successfully creating a
statewide technology plan. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manual</ENAMEX> will identify the main issues
involved in planning successfully for technology and will capture
information on planning, technology standards, legal services
issues, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner communities</ENAMEX>.

The proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table of Contents</ENAMEX> is as follows:


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
Introduction (purpose of the manual, how to use it,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overview</ENAMEX>)


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
Process of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning</ENAMEX> (staffing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, identifying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">constituencies</ENAMEX>, timeline, funding the effort)


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
Components of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Written Work Plan</ENAMEX> (state technology
support structure, standards in key technology areas, i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAN/WAN</ENAMEX>,
hardware, software, connectivity, email, training, video
conferencing, etc.)


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>)
Implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Work Plan</ENAMEX> (status tracking,
training, evaluations, periodic reports, staffing on-going support,
funding statewide efforts)


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funding</ENAMEX> (success stories, budgets,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnerships</ENAMEX>)


(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources</ENAMEX> for Help (website links to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>)



Using the national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">NTAP</ENAMEX> grant (see above) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is
gathering information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> within the legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> to prepare this manual. We believe disseminating the
broad experience of this group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> will be useful for state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> and technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. There was a planning meeting to
discuss the preparation of this manual at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> conference
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and soon we will have a timetable for its
completion.


Use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Oversight</ENAMEX>
Commitment: Develop methods to assess program quality, to ensure
that case handling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> are well trained and that the legal work
among programs is coordinated and of high quality.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> uses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> primary tools to assure quality in the
programs that it represents:


■
The competition process;


■
Quality review visits; and


■
Provision of support and technical assistance to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>.





In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> the Corporation again used the competition
process to review programs assure quality. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s competition
criteria have been refined to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> respond
and adhere to performance standards that result in effective legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. An extensive guide has been
developed for evaluations that considers each criterion and
provides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> with standards against which to judge funding
applications.



In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> created a protocol for on-site programs
reviews, published as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Program Review Guide</ENAMEX>." It is a reference
tool for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> in reviewing programs and to draft
reports and recommendations based on the reviews. Program reviews
are one way to monitor program development, solve problems, and
establish new strategies for expanding access and enhancing
quality. Among other resources, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> contains a sample letter
introducing the program to the review process, a comprehensive list
of items to request prior to a visit; a simplified work form to
capture information while on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>; a model work plan, a form to
help determine the quality of the legal work and suggestions for
conducting personal interviews. The implementation of the program
review process is discussed in the next section.



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LSC</ENAMEX> engages in other efforts to increase quality. LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> are frequently asked by grantees for assistance with
various aspects of running a successful program. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> can be a link
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> making the request and other


programs that have addressed the same concern. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, LSC
began to systematize this effort by creating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Project</ENAMEX>. The project's purpose is to obtain and
publicize information on model practices, programs, and systems. A
staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> is engaged full-time in launching this effort.
Other activities that support increasing program quality
undertaken in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> are:

Producing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Draft Characteristics on Intake, Advice</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Referral System</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> developed and distributed the document to the
public for comment; it will be final early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>.
Contracting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center of Poverty Law</ENAMEX> (NCPL) to
provide training on legal research for poverty law practice to
legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> selected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, and to
write and distribute a desktop research manual on poverty law.
Commitment: Undertake a series of program evaluation performance
pilot projects that are intended to provide in-depth understanding
of unique issues facing each program, more relevant and accurate
reporting of program activities and resource utilization,
performance measures that describe and project program success,
information that will lead to an improvement of the overall
effectiveness and efficiency of service delivery.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Program Performance</ENAMEX> conducted twelve on-site
program reviews in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. Under review were programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> also organized a peer review of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Consortium Pro Bono Program</ENAMEX>. These reviews allowed us to
monitor program development, to learn about problems and to suggest
new strategies for expanding access and enhancing quality.
Commitment: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design</ENAMEX> a new management information system to obtain
more complete and accurate information about the quality and level
of work performed by each grantee and about outcomes achieved for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>

In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> devised a method to measure other significant
responsibilities that programs undertake to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, in
addition to handling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> cases. These "matters" consist of
activities such as pro se work, community legal education, and
analyzing client problems for referral to other resources. Programs
have been counting "matters" since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s first report
on this activity is due in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March of 2002</TIMEX>.

The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant Activity Report</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAR</ENAMEX>) cycle, including Case
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Reports</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX>'s) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allied Self-Inspection</ENAMEX> process, has
been successfully completed.
The results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Inspection</ENAMEX> show a great improvement in
the accuracy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> submissions, with the error rate reduced <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX>,
from an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX> error rate for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX>'s to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> error rate for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX>'s. With this reduction in error rate, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX>'s now meet the
standard of "substantial accuracy" which was the objective when LSC
initiated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Inspection</ENAMEX> process in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.

The total cases reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,012,368</NUMEX>.
While this total is nominally a slight reduction from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,038,714</NUMEX>
reported for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, it is actually an increase because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> had to
adjust the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> total downward to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">924,000</NUMEX> cases to take account of
the high error rate. With the great improvement in the accuracy for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> can return to using the reported figures without any
adjustment.
Commitment: Performance standards will include criteria for
ensuring that grantees have effective administrative systems in
place and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> receive quality assistance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will provide
regular feedback to programs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> on the quality of their
applications.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has developed performance guidelines for assessing
grant applications. These guidelines, embodied in the LSC
Competition <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evaluation Guide</ENAMEX>, cover all aspects of program
performance including components of the delivery approach,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, legal work supervision, identifying and establishing
the most critical legal needs, coordination within the delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, and experience and reputation. They track, and are built on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Performance Criteria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA Standards for Providers of</ENAMEX>
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poor</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spring 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will publish
these guidelines. Following the competition for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> intends
to inform each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> about how well their program met each
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criterion</ENAMEX>.
Commitment: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> the competitive grant making process, the
performance standards applicable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
statutory and regulatory compliance requirements for efficiency,
unnecessary duplication and implications for the delivery of high
quality, appropriate legal services.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>

Additions to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> Request for Proposal (RFP) include
questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> on staff diversity, recruitment and
retention strategies and training, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s strategic
planning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX> inquiries on technology and on state planning were
streamlined. Some modifications resulted in more comprehensive
information on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>' proposed subgrantee relationships. LSC
staff conducted telephonic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applicant Information Sessions</ENAMEX> or
discussions on the application process with interested grantees and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>. Another comprehensive review of the competition process is
scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of 2002</TIMEX>.
Commitment: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will seek additional funds to increase the
presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in the field.


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2001 Achievements</ENAMEX>

With the hiring of new state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> as well
as the additions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matilde Lacayo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Holman</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP Main</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Raby</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology</ENAMEX>, there is now an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP Main</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> member
and a state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> assigned to every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and
territory. Staff are also able to assume special initiatives and
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> and to participate in national, regional and statewide
meetings and conferences.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADDITIONAL PROGRAM OUTCOMES ACHIEVED</ENAMEX> IN <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Evaluation Instrument</ENAMEX>
An RFP was created, proposals reviewed and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> hired in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> to design a state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> outcomes measurement tool.
Soon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will be in a position to quantitatively evaluate the
impact of state planning; for now we will demonstrate that state
planning activities have caused beneficial outcomes for state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX>, outcomes that position programs to
achieve:

Increased number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> receiving appropriate legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.
Expanded relevancy of the delivery system to the most pressing
needs of lowincome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> Increased perception among low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> that they have recourse if they require civil legal
information, counseling or representation.
Increased public perception of the legal justice system as
successful in providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice</ENAMEX>.
Expansion of federal funding and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private
resources dedicated to meeting civil legal needs of eligible
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
Expanded range and improved quality of services provided by
legal services programs.
Greater consistency in the quality of legal services
programs.

Significant beneficial results for low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, as
determined by outcome measurements.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Creation of Efforts to Link</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has moved into a leadership position in the
international legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2001</TIMEX> and again in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Programs Randi Youells</ENAMEX>
participated in conferences that brought together <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visionaries</ENAMEX> from the legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in common law
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> along with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to discuss emerging
legal issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and alternative funding sources, access,
technology and other urgent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> facing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of legal
services to poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> around the world.



Addressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan Pacific Legal Aid Conference</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX> observed that now, largely as a result
of strategic planning, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has more efficient programs, new
partnerships with unlikely stakeholders, powerful new funding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX> and the private bar, and
state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> have become more sensitive to the needs
of low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>."



In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, in remarks titled Why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> Has to
Change, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youells</ENAMEX> said, "over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX>, the legal
services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has pursued a fundamental
review of our delivery system-the most far-reaching and challenging
we have ever undertaken. The objective has been to create
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coordinated</ENAMEX> and integrated equal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, which live up
to the values and ideals which legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> were
initially created to protect, but which also make sense in this new
and ever-changing environment."




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Diversity Initiative</ENAMEX>

In conjunction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Aid and Defender</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> (NLADA), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> launched a series of conversations on
diversity in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> separate conversations on
broad issues of diversity including disability, age, gender, race,
sexual orientation and ethnicity took place. Several were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> hour discussions with small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. There was also a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> national conference
on diversity in the legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLADA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> participated. Reports
on each event will be the foundation for an action agenda for LSC
and the legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.

Suggestions and observations raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> diversity events intensified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s focus
on diversity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Applicants</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds must now describe efforts
underway to cultivate new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in their program and in the
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX>, including how they ensure that leadership
is diverse. State <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> self-evaluations include a
series of inquiries on the diversity work advanced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
plan and related activities. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has hired a state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whose area of expertise and emphasis is
diversity. She will assist state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX> with this
critical initiative.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Programs Randi Youells</ENAMEX> repeatedly
emphasized diversity and inclusion in her speeches to the legal
services community. Keynote addresses for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> staff retreat and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> state planning meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> provided opportunities to highlight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s support for
multi-cultural competence in program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> along with expanded
outreach to marginalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client communities</ENAMEX>.



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LSC</ENAMEX> retained a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to review staff data submitted
annually by grantees, and report on the diversity trends the
statistics show. While executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of color or who are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in our programs has not diminished in spite of a decreasing
number of programs (from reconfiguration) the number of women
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of color is small compared with their numbers
in our pool of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and other professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. The results
of these data will further inform the action agenda, noted
above.




Increased Quality and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Region</ENAMEX>
Collaborations



In several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and regions, collaborations around
client issues have resulted in the expansion of services to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. A benefit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>'s fair housing efforts (noted
earlier) is that LSC-funded programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, in
collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Tennessee Legal Services</ENAMEX>, will receive a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> grant of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350,000</NUMEX> to develop and administer a fair
housing initiative in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>. Initially, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, a program that has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> of experience in running
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> projects, will oversee the grant. Gradually <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> will
be transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>, which will hire
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Coordinator</ENAMEX>. Together, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> LSC
programs will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$99,000</NUMEX> to implement the initiative in their
service areas under the guidance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coordinator</ENAMEX>.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey</ENAMEX> continued its comprehensive efforts to ensure
that each legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> was integrated with
the others such that all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> had a "critical mass" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, allowing for specialization. Further, their
efforts allowed all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> to understand
their role as part of a statewide delivery system.



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missouri Legal Services Commission</ENAMEX>
to, among other tasks, ensure that all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> delivery
system components work together.




<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> have formed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advocacy Coordinating</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> (ACG) with the participation of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and non-LSC programs,
combining expertise across practice areas to address broader issues
such as access to employment, quality of education and barriers to
service. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACG</ENAMEX> identifies gaps in services around the state
relating to these issue areas along with making recommendation
about how best to address those gaps.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and non-LSC legal services programs are
collaborating with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Kent College of Law</ENAMEX> to establish the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Center for Law and Technology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech Center</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> will offer training, information, and other support to legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, paralegals, pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund of Illinois</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>
funded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> of operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC/TIG</ENAMEX> funds will support the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of operation, allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech Center</ENAMEX> to develop and
expand resources to include video streaming training, legal
research, community legal education materials and other supportive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech Center</ENAMEX> is governed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of directors
composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the collaborative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, and is
currently housed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Kent College of Law</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> held its largest meeting of legal services
staff and stakeholders since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> also,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Commission</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Association</ENAMEX>
and the LSC-funded program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> agreed to focus on delivery of
legal services in rural areas, including the reallocation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adoption of Uniform "Core Priorities</ENAMEX>"
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> followed the lead of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>) and adopted
uniform "core priorities" for all programs to assure consistency of
service throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">102</NUMEX> legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Trust Fund</ENAMEX>
Program (IOLTA), including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX> field programs and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> support
programs serving an eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost five million</NUMEX> poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">224</ENAMEX> languages. Of the field programs, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> are
LSC-funded. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s planning and collaborative efforts in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> have been numerous and complex, reflecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
many programs, languages, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and needs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of California</ENAMEX> (LAAC) is a membership <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of
legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> staffed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Interest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clearinghouse</ENAMEX>. It is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> responsible for state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX>, and has already adopted core principles for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> integrated system for the provision of legal services
in the following topical areas:


■
Meaningful Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>


■
Client-centered planning


■
Stable and adequate resources


■
Continuum of services


■
Innovative and responsive delivery system


■
Program Evaluation


■
Coordination of regional and state planning


■
Special needs communities


■
Expansive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> to increase resources


■
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cultivating</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of tomorrow




Collaboration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Programs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Courts</ENAMEX>
In many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, legal services programs and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are
working closely together to expand access to the judicial
system.

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> held their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice</ENAMEX>
Conferences. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX> were critical in the design
of the curriculum and as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> held an extremely well attended
statewide pro se conference. The state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are now developing the goals and strategies that resulted
from that event.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> has led the development of pro se clinics
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. In conjunction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clark County</ENAMEX>, a
non-LSC program, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clark County</ENAMEX> judicial system, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> has
established a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Law Self-Help Center</ENAMEX>, located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Courthouse</ENAMEX> across from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
staff the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, supervised by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>, who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.
In the near future, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> wants its forms on line so that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> can provide the information and forms will be generated
automatically. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> also offers educational seminars to
potential self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. A similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> has been established
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washoe County</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing self-help center</ENAMEX> has been
established in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. It is staffed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> as well.
More recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> has joined with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nevada Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
and others to draft a uniform set of pleadings that can be used in
family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>. Currently <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> has no uniform set
of forms, and local variations often pose barriers for pro se
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> created a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Equal Justice Funding</ENAMEX>.
To enhance our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX>' work in these areas, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX> spoke before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of Chief</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of State Court Administrators Taskforce</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Se</ENAMEX>
Litigation. In her remarks she urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and court
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX> to (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) initiate efforts with local and state bar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> to overcome resistance to pro se activities and
self-represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) study selfrepresented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> to
determine how many of them would have hired (and could have
afforded) a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> at the time that they were denied
services by a legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) promote acceptance of
the practice of "unbundling" legal services.






