



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M E M O R A N D U M</ENAMEX>

Attached you will find a document entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Access to Records</ENAMEX>."
This document summarizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s internal practices with
respect to accessing information contained in records maintained by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> prides itself on thorough and
effective monitoring of recipient activities and on its training of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> with regard to compliance issues.
Of particular importance, however, are the methods for ensuring
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> obtain necessary access to information in ways that ensure
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> compliance consistent with its statutory obligations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
has mandated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> effectively monitor and audit its grant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> respect attorney-client privilege and
ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> carry out their work consistent with
their professional responsibilities.
Please note that the statement of practices appended hereto as
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Access to Records</ENAMEX>" does not and is not intended to waive or alter
any of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s rights to documents and other information and does not
apply to audits, investigations and other OIG activities.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Protocol</ENAMEX> is intended to set forth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s policy with respect
to accessing grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>' files and to facilitate better
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> and understanding on this topic. With appropriate
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">notice</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> may
change or alter this Protocol as circumstances warrant.
ACCESS TO RECORDS

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 25, 2002</TIMEX>
This document sets forth procedures to be used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Compliance and Enforcement</ENAMEX> (OCE) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Program</ENAMEX>
Performance (OPP) when making requests to review documents that
contain information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and their cases that may be
protected from disclosure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> by the attorney-client privilege
or the rules of professional responsibility.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STATUTORY FRAMEWORK</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has the statutory responsibility to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">recipients</ENAMEX>
comply with the provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX> and regulations and any
other laws, including appropriation provisions, which apply to LSC
funds or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>. See Section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1006</TIMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)(A). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is given
explicit authority "to prescribe the keeping of records with
respect to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">funds</NUMEX> provided by grant or contract and shall have
access to such records at all reasonable times for the purpose of
insuring compliance with the grant or contract or the terms and
conditions upon which financial assistance was provided." See
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 1008</ENAMEX> (b).
However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX> recognizes that some records contain
information that is protected by the attorney-client privilege
and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s ethical responsibilities under rules of
professional responsibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 1009</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>
explicitly provides that "neither the Corporation nor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> shall have access to any reports or records
subject to the attorneyclient privilege." In addition, section
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1006</TIMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) includes both a prohibition that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> "shall not, under
any provision of this title, interfere with any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in
carrying out his professional responsibilities" and also imposes an
affirmative duty that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> "shall ensure that activities under this
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> are carried out in a manner consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>'
professional responsibilities."
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 509</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>) of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> appropriation, which has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reenacted</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each subsequent year</TIMEX>, provides that, notwithstanding
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 1006</ENAMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> are given explicit
access to "financial records, time records, retainer agreements,
client trust fund and eligibility records, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> names, for
each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">recipient …</ENAMEX> except for reports or records subject to the
attorney-client privilege." See <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> v. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">249 F.</ENAMEX>3d <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1077</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C. Cir</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). In addition, section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">504</NUMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8</ENAMEX>) of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> appropriation authorizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> access to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> "statement of facts." Disclosure of information not
required by these sections of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> appropriation provisions is
governed by sections <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1006</TIMEX>(b)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1009</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>.


PURPOSE
The purpose of this document is to inform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and
other interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> of the procedure for providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> access
to records in a manner consistent with the attorney-client
privilege and applicable rules of professional responsibility and
the mechanism to resolve issues of how such access can be
obtained.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GENERAL PRINCIPLES</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will act to carry out its statutory responsibilities to
ensure compliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>, appropriation provisions and
any other provisions of law and will do so consistent with the
statutory provisions on both privileged and confidential
information.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> are obligated to provide information to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> under
the applicable LSC statutes, regulations, grant terms, grant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurances</ENAMEX>, and other rules and provisions regarding the receipt
and use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds. For example, upon request, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> must
provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> access to all records specified in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 509</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>)
unless, as provided in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 509</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>), the information sought is
protected by the attorney-client privilege. In addition, upon
request, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> must also provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> access to original
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unredacted</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> "statement of facts," as required by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> CFR
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">§1636</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Recipients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will work together in good faith
regarding issues of access to records that may contain information
protected by rules of professional responsibility or the law on
attorney-client privilege.


PROCEDURES


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Applicability</ENAMEX>: This procedure applies to requests by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Compliance and Enforcement</ENAMEX> (OCE) or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Program</ENAMEX>
Performance (OPP) for access to records of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> that may
include information that may be protected by rules of professional
responsibility or the law on attorney-client privilege. Such
information will hereafter be referred to as privileged or
confidential information. As applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX>, references to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> shall be to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> and the Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recipient</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whenever OCE</ENAMEX> proposes to review
the records of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> either through an on-site visit or
otherwise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> notifies the recipient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">orally</ENAMEX> and in writing about
the purpose of the visit or review, what activities OCE will
conduct, and what specific information and records are planned to
be within the scope of the review. Each review is an ongoing
process that may expand based on information reviewed. As such, OCE
will notify the recipient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">orally</ENAMEX> and in writing when the scope of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review</ENAMEX> has changed or expanded and what information and records
are further required.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intermediaries</ENAMEX>: In all written and oral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> will affirmatively propose that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> use program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediary</ENAMEX> to review case
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">files</ENAMEX> (or other records containing privileged or confidential
information) and to answer questions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX>. During on-site visits,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> will affirmatively encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to use such
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intermediaries</ENAMEX> and will not request direct access to or control
over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> case files or any other records containing privileged
or confidential information.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
Flexibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Approaches</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> shall consider and seek to
accommodate reasonable approaches to access to records proposed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to protect privileged or confidential information so
long as such proposed approaches also ensure access by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> to
information it needs to carry out its responsibilities. Such
reasonable approaches may include unique <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> identifiers when
appropriate.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unique State Ethics Rules</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> acknowledges that there
may be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where the rules of professional responsibility,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethics</ENAMEX> rulings, case law or other laws differ from the general
framework under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Model Rules of Professional Responsibility</ENAMEX> and
where the disclosures sought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> may implicate the recipient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' professional responsibilities or other law. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Recipients</ENAMEX>
have the responsibility to bring such ethical rulings to the
attention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> as set forth in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 7</ENAMEX> below after they have
been notified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> of an impending request for access to records
containing privileged or confidential information


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.
Questions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attorney-Client Privilege</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> shall not
have access to information protected by the attorney-client
privilege, including information covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 509</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>). A
recipient shall notify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> under the procedures set forth in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section 7</ENAMEX> below, that the information sought is, in the recipient's
view, protected by the attorney-client privilege.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>.
Procedures for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Addressing Privileged or Confidential</ENAMEX>
Information: If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> believes that documents or information
requested by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> contain information that is protected by the
attorney-client privilege, applicable rules of professional
responsibility or other law, the recipient will send written notice
to OCE as soon as possible setting forth (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a full description of
the nature of the privileged or confidential information, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) a
statement explaining the basis for determining that such
information is privileged or confidential, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) any
recommendations of reasonable approaches to accessing such
information. Upon receipt of this notice, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> will so notify the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> and seek to find a mutually
satisfactory manner for obtaining access to the information
consistent with the applicable rules of attorney-client privilege
and professional responsibility and consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s need for
information to ensure compliance.


If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> is not able to expediently resolve all outstanding issues
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, it will, through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX>,
promptly so advise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice Presidents</ENAMEX> for
Programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Affairs and Government Relations</ENAMEX> of the access
issues raised and the specific reasons why the proposed alternative
methods of access are inadequate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for
Administration and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>, with advice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX>, then will review the concerns raised by the recipient. If
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice Presidents</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> do not agree
with the position of the recipient, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will so notify the
recipient in writing and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> will proceed with the review.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice Presidents</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> agree that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> has a reasonable claim that the information is
privileged or confidential, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> will further seek to develop a
mutually satisfactory manner for obtaining access to the
information consistent with the applicable rules of attorney-client
privilege and professional responsibility and consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
need for information to ensure compliance.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>.
Disputes Between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Recipients</ENAMEX>: If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recipient</ENAMEX> cannot agree on an approach that will give OCE
appropriate access to the records it needs and is consistent with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX>'s responsibilities to protect privileged or
confidential information, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX>, through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice-President</ENAMEX> for
Administration, may recommend to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> should take appropriate action with respect to the
recipient. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> will review the
recommendation and make further inquiry as appropriate. The Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> may request that and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> may
direct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCE</ENAMEX> to further work with the recipient on an acceptable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> or appropriately modify the request.

If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> determines that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> should
proceed to take action affecting the recipient, it shall notify the
recipient in writing of the action that is proposed. If the action
involves suspension or termination of funding, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will proceed in
a manner consistent with Parts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1606 or 1623</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 45 of the Code</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Regulations</ENAMEX>. However, if the action involves a sanction
or adverse action other than termination or suspension, then LSC
may, and is encouraged to, allow a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> an opportunity to
further present it's position. Such a process could follow the
following procedure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> would be given an opportunity to
request a meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> to ask for
reconsideration of the proposed action. If the recipient requests
such a face-to-face meeting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> would
convene such a meeting and make a recommendation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
as to how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> should proceed. As soon thereafter as is practical,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> would notify the recipient in
writing of the recommendation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and the reasons
therefore. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> may then request a meeting with the LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to ask for reconsideration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>'s
recommendation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> would be given the opportunity to
provide such additional written information as it believes will
assist the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to fully and fairly consider its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> and
objections. Upon such request, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> could also convene a
face-to-face meeting with the authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the
recipient. As soon thereafter as practical, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> would
advise the recipient of the final decision and reasons therefore.
The decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> would be in writing and shall be
final and binding.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> determines that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> has taken
an unreasonable position or refused to work in good faith with OCE
on these issues, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> may take reasonable corrective action in
addition to pursuing access to the information in
question.


10.
In describing these procedures, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> does not in any way
waive the statutory rights and obligations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>
regarding access to and review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>' records and
information. These procedures do not create new rights or
obligations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and may be modified by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> as warranted, with appropriate notice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>
and field programs.







