



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL SERVICES CORPORATION</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">SERVING THE CIVIL LEGAL NEEDS OF LOW-INCOME AMERICANS</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPECIAL REPORT</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONGRESSï</ENAMEX>¿½APRIL <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 2000</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. Summary</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX> (LSC) is a private, non-membership,
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who are
appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with the advice and
consent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. By law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> is bipartisan: no more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> can be of the same political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> plays a central role in providing low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with
access to legal assistance and information concerning critical
civil legal problems. Created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is charged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
"to provide equal access to the system of justice in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Nation</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who seek redress of grievances" and "to provide high
quality legal assistance to those who would otherwise be unable to
afford adequate legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>."
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> reported closing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,038,662</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">million1</TIMEX> civil
legal cases relating to issues such as domestic violence, child
custody and visitation rights, evictions, access to health care,
bankruptcy, unemployment and disability claims, and many other
issues that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> face throughout their
lives. Without the funding provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, many of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> would have no other source of legal assistance for
these problems.


II. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Services Program</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX> funds local legal services programs
to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX>, and congressional district
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as well as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin Islands</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Micronesia</ENAMEX>. In addition, special service areas are funded
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> with special needs - <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> and
migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. Eligibility for services is determined on a
case-by-case basis pursuant to grantee eligibility criteria
established under parameters set forth in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> regulations. Each
grantee establishes a maximum income eligibility level, not to
exceed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">125 percent</NUMEX> of the current official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Poverty Income</ENAMEX>
Guidelines.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> implemented a number of new accountability
requirements including competitive bidding for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> grants. This system of competitive bidding eliminated
the right of grantees to a hearing to contest a funding decision
awarding a grant to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, ensuring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> can award grants to
the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> without unnecessary administrative barriers.
Additionally, new compliance monitoring procedures, which use
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> to monitor grantee compliance with regulations and
to perform comprehensive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> oversight of grantee activities,
were formulated. Another new provision adopted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> prohibits
any local program that has been found to engage in a substantial
violation of the law or its grant conditions from being considered
for an LSC grant in future competitions.
Also in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, other new requirements were adopted governing what
legal services programs can do and whom they can represent. These
new guidelines have refocused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> delivery system on serving
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> with particular legal needs. With the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> For a complete explanation of the number of cases closed for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, see Section V, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Statistics</ENAMEX>.
implementation of these restrictions, legal services attorneys
are not permitted to initiate or participate in class action
lawsuits. They may not challenge or engage in any activity to
influence welfare reform. They may not collect court-awarded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' fees. Litigation on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> and
representation of undocumented and other categories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> is
also prohibited. Other new requirements address redistricting,
cases involving eviction from public housing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> charged
with or convicted of drug violations and participation in
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulemaking</ENAMEX> and solicitation. Unlike past laws
restricting the work of legal services, these provisions apply to
all the funds of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX>, with very few specified
exceptions.
All local LSC-funded programs are administered by local boards
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> (or other governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, in certain instances), a
majority of whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are appointed by local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX>,
and provide legal assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> pursuant to locally
determined priorities that respond to community conditions and
needs. Based on these priorities, local programs hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>,
contact local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, and develop pro bono programs for the
direct delivery of legal assistance to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. LSC
requires each legal services program to spend an amount equal to at
least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.5 percent</NUMEX> of its annualized grant to encourage
participation by private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in the provision of legal
assistance to poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
The legal services delivery system offers a model of efficient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> of disputes and avoidance of unnecessary litigation.
Only a very small percentage (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>) of LSC-funded cases are
resolved by the decision of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and the majority of these are
family law cases that require a court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX>.
Rather than litigating cases, legal services lawyers
consistently find other, more efficient ways to solve problems for
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Under tremendous pressure from the demand for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, they know they must use their limited resources wisely.
As in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past years</TIMEX>, nearly threefourths of cases in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> were
resolved through advice, referral, or brief services.

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2% 20%</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Statistics Issue</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> acknowledges that serious questions have been raised
concerning the accuracy and validity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Service</ENAMEX> Report
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX>) data submitted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> by our grantees<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is aware that
problems exist in the statistical reports received and is taking
steps to identify and correct those problems. The problems
identified stem, in part, from a lack of clarity in some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
past case reporting guidelines and, more generally, from
insufficient attention by grantees to the existing reporting and
documentation requirements.
It should be kept in mind that the issue is largely one of
grantee compliance with technical and administrative guidance on
how and when to report certain activities. In no instance has LSC,
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX>, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> identified
any fraud or intentional misrepresentation by any of the grantees
in their compilation and reporting of this data. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will
aggressively take steps to correct problems associated with the CSR
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, and will continue to make full and timely reports to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> and the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> views the issues concerning the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data to be akin to those encountered by many government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX> as they attempt to meet the goals envisioned by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Performance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX> (GPRA).

Self-initiated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review of CSR Data</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s review of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data was an outgrowth of its ongoing
oversight responsibilities and it has become integral to its
voluntary strategic planning process. Although not subject to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Performance</ENAMEX> and Results Act, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> shares the aspirations
of that law to rationalize the budget and appropriations processes
by tying funding into objective measures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
performance.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> adopted its first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Plan</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998-2003</TIMEX>. The strategic directions adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>
will achieve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s vision3 by accomplishing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major strategic
goals: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will dramatically increase the provision of
legal services to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will ensure
that eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are receiving appropriate and high quality
legal assistance. That plan is currently being revised - as are
the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conferees</ENAMEX> have concerns about the case service reporting
and associated data reports submitted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX> and the case statistical reports submitted by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conferees</ENAMEX> direct the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> to make improvement of the accuracy of these
submissions a top priority, per directions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> report. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conferees</ENAMEX> also direct the Corporation to submit its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> annual
case service reports and associated data reports to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> no
later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30, 2000</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments of Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, and
State, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Related Agencies Appropriations</ENAMEX> Act of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">113</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">112 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1501</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 Twenty-five</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> made a pledge to help
ensure that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> have access to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s civil justice
system by enacting legislation that created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past quarter century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has helped millions
of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> solve important, sometimes life-threatening,
legal problems. Despite the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and its many
contributions to access to justice for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, its
achievements are overshadowed by the fact that so many in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> continue to suffer injustice and are unable to gain access
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for critical legal assistance. Until all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> are afforded that access, this promise of our government
will continue to be unfulfilled. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is committed to promoting a
new vision of legal services that will achieve the goal of bringing
legal services to those currently denied access to the justice
system.
initial plans submitted by many governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. As
recently reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, most federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are far from
meeting the goals set by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPRA</ENAMEX> for performance data on which the
Administration and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can rely on in setting budget amounts
and appropriations levels.
Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, having embarked on the path laid out by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPRA</ENAMEX>,
recognizes the need to assess the data currently available on
grantee activity for its accuracy and adequacy as a measure of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s performance. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">first Strategic Plan</ENAMEX> was published, and
adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> served as a performance measure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Inspector</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> decided there was a need to determine the accuracy of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX>' reports on which the measure was based. A series of
audits of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> data was conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> in anticipation of the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> performance report due in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. These audits examined the
accuracy of case statistical reports submitted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> grantees, and
the causes of identified deficiencies, rather than validating or
testing the accuracy of national or system-wide data.


Initial Findings
What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> found when it began the assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> system
was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> reporting structure, the guidance for which had
not been updated since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. The reporting system rested on the
definition of a "case." However clear and meaningful the definition
of a case may have been in the past, it became evident the
definition had not kept pace with the changes in the service
delivery systems. As the pace of the evolution of service delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> and the reconfiguration of grantees accelerated following
the funding cutbacks and program reforms in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, and spurred on by
the technological revolution, the reporting of grantee activity
solely on the basis of "cases" was becoming increasingly
inadequate. This resulted in inconsistent and inaccurate reporting.
Critical legal services were now being provided, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">inter alia</ENAMEX>,
through Internet web sites, through toll-free telephone intake and
brief advice systems, through pro se <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> and projects, and
through stand-alone <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> representing a client
before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> was no longer the norm of a "case" when
delivering critical legal services to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
The audits conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>) and
reported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1999</TIMEX>, confirmed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX>'s findings
as to the factors causing systemic errors in grantee case
reporting. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> visited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> large programs: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Rico Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Assistance Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Bureau, Inc.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>. Overall, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
deemed questionable <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 34 percent</NUMEX> of both open and
closed cases reported by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> grantees in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. The percentage
of questionable cases for individual programs ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX>. A problem common to all programs was the untimely
closure of cases, although again the extent of the problem in any
particular program varied from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">under 4 percent</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> program to
over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> in another. Overall, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> questioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 5</NUMEX>-9
percent of the cases reported because of the lack of adequate
financial eligibility documentation and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 7-24 percent</NUMEX> of the
cases for lack of citizenship or alien status documentation. It
should
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4 GAO/GGD-99-135R LSC Case Reporting Problems</ENAMEX>.
be noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> concluded only that the case files failed to
contain the documentation necessary to confirm the eligibility or
ineligibility of any of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrective Action</ENAMEX>
As these concerns surfaced, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> decided as an initial step to
reissue the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CSR Handbook</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1998</TIMEX>, providing additional
guidance on particular areas that were considered to be most prone
to error. In general, clearer guidance was provided to programs on
reviewing their own reporting procedures and practices, ensuring
they conformed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Handbook</ENAMEX> and ensuring all branch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> were
aware of and were following these procedures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LSC</ENAMEX> reiterated
guidance on not reporting financially or otherwise ineligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, referrals of ineligible cases or cases for which no legal
work was performed. Recognizing this guidance would not affect the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data, which had already been submitted by the grantees,
but wanting to improve the accuracy of future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> sought
to heighten the awareness of grantees to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CSR</ENAMEX> requirements and
to focus their attention on potential problem areas. As previously
reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, though, a number of grantees did voluntarily
submit corrections to their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
As the audit information became available during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> and into
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> gained a fuller understanding of the extent of the CSR
problem and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX>. Even though quantifiable data was
lacking during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most of 1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> had sufficient information to
begin taking actions to address the problems. As previously noted,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> reissued its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> instructions to all grantees, calling
attention to problem areas known at that time. Recognizing that
more action was needed to improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> system, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> provided
additional written guidance to the field, including a substantial
revision to its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CSR Handbook</ENAMEX> (reissued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>), and
conducted training sessions on that guidance. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has
required all grantees to perform a self-inspection of their CSR
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, has followed up on grantees where corrective action was found
necessary, and has increased its on-site presence to test grantee
compliance. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>. What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is A Case</ENAMEX>?
A case is defined as the provision of permissible legal
assistance to an eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> with a legal problem, or set of
closely related legal problems, accepted for assistance supported
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> or non-LSC funds in accordance with the requirements of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>, regulations, and other applicable law. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">FY2001</NUMEX> budget request includes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.54 million</NUMEX> in additional
funds to provide <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> specialized on-site compliance reviews.
These on-site reviews will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to identify program
weaknesses, engage in effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corrective Actions</ENAMEX> Plans oversight,
and provide program-specific needed guidance and oversight. The
reviews will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to more effectively execute its compliance
function and ensure the accuracy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> reporting by its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> may record and report the provision of
legal assistance as a case only if: (a) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is financially
and otherwise eligible to receive assistance under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>,
regulations, and other applicable law; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s case is within
program priorities (or is an emergency case accepted under the
program's emergency case acceptance procedures); the legal services
program has actually accepted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> for service through its
intake system or another established procedure for ensuring client
eligibility; (b) the type of legal assistance provided to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is not prohibited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX>, regulations, or other
applicable law (e.g. a class action); (c) the legal
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has significantly tightened its requirements for
what constitutes a case. A case that is eligible to be counted as
such must include some actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and advice or other legal
assistance provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. Thus, analysis and referral of a
case to another legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> cannot be counted, nor can
service where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is accepted and work is done, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client withdraws</ENAMEX> or loses contact with the program before any
actual legal assistance is provided.
Programs have been required to screen their submissions for
"duplicates." A duplicate is not merely the submission of exactly
the same case twice by computer or other error, but also any
situation in which the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> returns to the program with the
same legal problem in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX>. The test as to how similar the
issue in two separate requests for assistance has to be before it
is counted as one case has presented significant borderline
problems, but there have been a large number of clear duplicates
eliminated from the case reports.
It has also been clarified that if a case fails to meet any
required documentation (financial eligibility, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>/eligible
alien status, within program priorities, etc.) it may not be
reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> as a case. Especially for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has
substantially strengthened the documentation requirements for
reporting a case to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. As a result, numerous cases have been
excluded from reporting, even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> received legal
service, because the case was not documented according to LSC
requirements. For many of these cases, it was overwhelmingly likely
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and the service would have been eligible to be
counted as a closed case but for the lack of proper
documentation.
Programs, however, are allowed to count closed cases for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> and for battered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the following specific
programs without financial eligibility information because these
Federal programs require that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> be accepted regardless of
financial circumstances: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Title XX Social Security</ENAMEX> Act, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titles III</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Older Americans Act, and Violence Against Women Act</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Statistics</ENAMEX>
For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> reported closing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,038,662</NUMEX> civil legal
cases relating to issues such as domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">violence7</ENAMEX>, child custody
and visitation rights, evictions, access to health care,
bankruptcy, unemployment and disability claims, and many other
issues faced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. The consequences
of such problems may be as serious as the loss of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s only
source of income or homelessness. Left unresolved, they can cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> far more than the expense of providing legal services to
address them. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">case types</ENAMEX> frequently encountered include
foreclosures, collections and repossessions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support, and
wage claims. Without the federal funding provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to local
legal services programs, many, and
problem(s) of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> are not of a type prohibited by the LSC
Act, regulations, or other applicable law (e.g., an abortion
case).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, it is estimated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees received
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.5 million</NUMEX> in federal funds under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Violence</ENAMEX>
Against <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Women Act</ENAMEX> (VAWA) for use in rendering assistance in
domestic violence cases. It is estimated that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> they
will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $11.5 million</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VAWA</ENAMEX> funding.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
Consumer

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
possibly most, of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with these problems would
have no other source of legal assistance.
Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s significant efforts to improve the data accuracy,
there may be occurrences of errors in documentation or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX> in
this number. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January of this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> instructed all programs
to conduct a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Inspection</ENAMEX> of a sample of closed cases prior to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">submitting 1999 CSR</ENAMEX> data to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. The purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Inspection</ENAMEX>
process was to provide programs a means to verify, by reviewing a
sample of cases, that their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data satisfies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s standards
for accuracy. In addition, it provides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> useful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX> into the current nature and extent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data
issue.
Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Inspection</ENAMEX> was not constructed, or executed,
to yield a statistically valid assessment of the accuracy of the
closed cases for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Inspection</ENAMEX> did reveal, LSC
believes, significant improvements in data accuracy from previous
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Again stressing this process did not produce an extensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> submits that it is sufficient to
reasonably estimate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of reported cases contains an
error rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX>.
In order to fulfill our pledge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> and to the
general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> concerning our commitment to providing the most
accurate and reliable data, we adjusted the number of cases
reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,038,662</NUMEX>) by the average estimated error
rate (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX>). Accordingly, we submit a total of cases closed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">924,000</NUMEX>. For reasons that will be discussed in subsequent
sections of this report, we also highlight that this figure
represents only a portion of the work conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees.
Nonetheless, it represents the most reliable, albeit conservative
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, estimate of cases closed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> The adjusted total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">924,000</NUMEX> is conservative because: (a)
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> did use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Inspection</ENAMEX> data to exclude

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leveraging Federal Resources</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> funding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> provides the
national infrastructure for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> civil legal services delivery system. But for the federal
investment, the overwhelming majority of cases reported by LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX> would not have been possible. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the federal
investment represents almost the entire contribution for providing
civil legal services to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.9 In another sixteen
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding represents <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 50%</NUMEX> of the total investment in
the civil legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>.10
Beginning with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1999</NUMEX> cases, another significant change is the
requirement for programs to report all cases eligible for LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>, regardless of the funding source. The prior rule mandated
that each case had to be at least partially funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds, as
well as being LSCeligible. This new change is intended to make case
reporting more consistent among grantee programs as these programs
have varying mixes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding and varying,
legitimate methods of allocating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding among
their activities that produce case closures.
As noted above, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> case count for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> includes all cases
that meet LSC eligibility criteria, regardless of the funding mix
of any particular grantee. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> strongly encourages all its grantees
to obtain other funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client community</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislated</ENAMEX> is eligible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding. The ability to leverage
other funds to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> is a factor LSC
considers in evaluating its grantees. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> believes that the total
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> served by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees is of
considerable relevance.
It has been suggested that this change may cause an artificial
increase in the number of cases reported through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> system.
The purpose of the change, however, was to achieve better accuracy
and more consistency in the reporting of work made possible by LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> have successfully leveraged their federal
funding by attracting other private and public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of funding.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grantees</ENAMEX> use their mix of funding in a variety of ways. The former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> system did not consistently collect and identify much of this
effort on behalf of eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. In fact, because of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inconsistency</ENAMEX> in reporting, the old system often produced
artificial variations in reported case statistics among similar
programs. The revised reporting requirement will greatly enhance
the accuracy of the data on services to the eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> lowincome
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and will produce more complete data on the work of
grantees that can be reasonably attributable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees.
from their submission to LSC <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 17,000</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insufficiently</ENAMEX> supported cases that made up the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> error
rate, and (b) in the process of requiring more rigorous
documentation of cases, some cases that actually had sufficient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">documentation</ENAMEX>, and many cases where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> was almost certainly
eligible, were excluded, resulting in a countervailing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undercount</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">State-wide</ENAMEX> civil legal services' percentages of total funding
received from LSC: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91%</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83%</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89%</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84%</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPAN Update</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Planning</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1999</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Aid & Defender Association</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPAN Update</ENAMEX>: A
Guide to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Planning</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1999</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Aid & Defender Association</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FUNDING FOR LSC GRANTEES</ENAMEX> -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>



Developing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Performance Measures</ENAMEX>
In addition to providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the public more reliable
and accurate statistics on closed cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is committed to
developing and to implementing by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2001</TIMEX>, a new reporting
system to document and assess the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has
contracted with an independent research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to develop and
implement a pilot project at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees that will gather the
necessary information needed to create a reporting system that
captures all the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees, not simply the traditional
"closed cases." This reporting system will detail and describe the
delivery of services that are not cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> such as community
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, information through Internet web sites, self-help forms
and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX>. The reporting system may also provide information on
the impact to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> by describing
non-"case" services' in the following manner:
Â¤ the type of innovative service provided, Â¤ the number of
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> receiving the service, Â¤ the nature of the legal
problems addressed through the innovative service, and Â¤ the impact
of the innovative service on the legal problems.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> also will develop systems for measuring the outcomes (or
benefits) of the assistance that the programs provide to eligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Outcome measurement may include an assessment of:
Â¤ the monetary impact of employment and benefits cases, Â¤ the
effect on quality of life of health and housing cases, Â¤ the impact
on minor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of assistance in family cases, and Â¤ the
financial stability afforded in consumer/finance cases.
In addition to establishing a more complete reporting system,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is committed to using economic analysis and performance
measures to evaluate the impact of federal funding and individual
grantee performance. Discussed below are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> methods of analysis
currently under review to accomplish these goals. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will
implement these performance measures on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2001</TIMEX>, it will
diligently evaluate the chosen method of analysis prior to
implementation to ensure it provides useful and meaningful data. By
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will require grantees to provide information that allows
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to comparatively analyze the cost per case among similarly
situated programs and similar types of services, i.e., brief advice
and referral. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> statistics for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CY 2002</ENAMEX> will reflect the input of
all these performance measures.
The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cost per Case" Model: The</ENAMEX> first methodology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is
developing and evaluating to assess the work of grantees is a
"cost-per-case" analysis. "Cost per case" is a rough quantitative
output measure of the efficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX>' delivery of case
services to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. In the past, it has been computed by
dividing a program's annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding by its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> total cases
closed. The calculation uses all of a program's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding, even
though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> programs provide services to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> that do
not meet the definition of a "closed case," as previously detailed.
While a "cost-per-case" analysis is limited in that it only
addresses quantity, and not quality of services, it does provide
some useful quantitative information. The raw cost per case figure
can be further analyzed to take into account the level of service
(from brief advice and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> up to a court case).
Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> uses a "cost-per-case" analysis when it conducts
on-site evaluations of grantees. By comparing the "cost per case"
of a particular grantee over a period of time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> may gain useful
information on the workload and performance of a program from year
to year. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> also uses a "cost-per-case" analysis to compare
similarly situated grantees. This measure does require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to
understand how services differ from grantee to grantee, so that the
differences in levels of service can be adjusted to arrive at
meaningful cost-per-case figures.
For example, grantee A receives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds and serves
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> at a cost-per-case ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>. The majority of
these cases involve the provision of advice and brief service,
traditionally not very time-consuming or labor intensive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grantee</ENAMEX> B
also receives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds, but only serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> at
a cost-per case ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600</NUMEX>. However, grantee B primarily handles
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> facing domestic violence, eviction from their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>,
or issues involving access to health care. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grantee B</ENAMEX>'s cases
usually involve protracted negotiation or litigation. Given the
differences in the types of cases handled by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these two grantees</TIMEX>, a
simple cost-per-case analysis, without further definition, would
yield meaningless data in terms of the comparative value of
services provide by these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs.
Another caution that must be raised with this particular
approach is that all LSC-funded programs engage in a wide range of
very important activities that do not fall within the definition of
"case," which would thus not be included in valuing the program's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. LSC-funded programs use many means (newsletters,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pamphlets</ENAMEX>, speaking engagements, and web sites) to provide legal
information to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, helping them avoid legal
problems or aiding them in learning to handle problems when they
surface. Where appropriate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> refer low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that can help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> with their problems -
either to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternate sources</ENAMEX> of legal assistance or to other sources
of assistance, such as charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and social services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Through the provision of legal information, programs also
assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in preparing to represent themselves in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
Resources expended in supporting efforts such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, outreach, state planning and resource development also
would not be factored into the program's "cost-per-case."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is carefully studying how to refine the "cost-per-case"
analysis in order to use it effectively as a management tool.
Toward this end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has recently initiated activities to develop
more appropriate strategies and mechanisms to gather and to
quantify data on all of the work -- cases and matters, regardless
of funding source -- being performed by its grantees.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cases Funded Exclusively with LSC Resources Model</ENAMEX>: The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> methodology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is developing is a model to estimate the
number of cases funded exclusively with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds. To arrive at
this estimate, total cases reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees would be
augmented with an estimate of all cases handled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>-funded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>. These are cases traditionally not reported to LSC -
either because documentation <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC</ENAMEX> requires is not present in these
cases or because they are expressly handled with funding that
allows financial eligibility standards that are more lax than LSC
standards. This number would then be added to the total reported to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> (to produce a total caseload number) and then reduced by the
national rate of funding of LSC programs by other sources.
This process would yield an estimate for cases that are funded
exclusively with LSC resources. In using such a number, however,
several factors need to be kept in mind.


â€¢
This figure would only be an estimate. We do not compile
an actual count of the number of cases that are not within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
definition of a case.


â€¢
The reportable and not reportable cases, on average, do
not take the same amount of time. Other funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> may be
funding a different mix of cases that may, on average, take more or
less time than the average case for LSC-eligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will receive additional information on the ability of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX> to leverage federal dollars using an estimate of cases
funded exclusively with federal resources, through this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">methodology</ENAMEX>, although it is a less than perfect method of analysis.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> routinely evaluates its grantees on their ability to leverage
additional dollars from alternative sources to expand their ability
to provide critical legal services to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. For
example, as noted above, grantees often seek alternative funding to
expand services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in potentially abusive
situations. Further, under its state planning initiative that
mandates all grantees within a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> work together to
create a comprehensive and integrated statewide delivery system,
grantees are required to address how they will work together to
expand the resources available within that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to support legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX>. The Need for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
The need for legal services is overwhelming. Although we live in
a time of great economic prosperity, there are currently still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> with an income below the
poverty level<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> Some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with
incomes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 100 and 125 percent</NUMEX> of the poverty level are also
potentially eligible for legal services. This means that almost one
out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> is eligible for legal services
assistance. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are particularly affected by
poverty. Even though the poverty rate has slightly declined, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18.9</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are still poor<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> In order to ensure these
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are not left out of the justice system, a strong federal
role in supporting legal services is vital.
A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> study for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar Association</ENAMEX> concluded that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 80 percent</NUMEX> of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do not have the
advantage of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> when they are faced with serious situation
where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s advice and assistance would make a difference.
Similar conclusions have been reached by state legal needs' studies
in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, using a variety of methodologies for estimating
the unmet legal needs of the poor.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Bureau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">census</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/prod/99pubs/p60-</ENAMEX>207.pdf
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Budget</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Policy Priorities, Analysis</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
Poverty and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Income Data</ENAMEX>, (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1999</TIMEX>).


Estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unmet Legal Need</ENAMEX>
Eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Clients</ENAMEX> unable to attain needed legal assistance

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eligible Clients</ENAMEX> served by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Programs</ENAMEX>-- <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>
Because of limited resources, local legal services programs are
forced to turn away <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with critical legal
problems. A survey of selected programs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 1993</TIMEX>, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding was substantially higher than it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, revealed
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who applied for assistance from
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> were turned away because of a lack of program
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>. Most programs are forced to limit the cases they accept
to emergencies or other situations that threaten the safety and
stability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or individual involved. Recent studies
estimate that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between one and four million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> women
experience an assault by an intimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> each year, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are exposed to violence by family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> against
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> or female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">caretakers</ENAMEX>. 13

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Client Demographics</ENAMEX>
Legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are as diverse as our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>,
encompassing all races, ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and ages. They include the
working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>, family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with disabilities,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of natural disasters. Many were formerly middle class,
and became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> because of age, unemployment, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, or the
breakup of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, as in the past, nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-fourths</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> clients
were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, most of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Although the named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is usually an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>, most LSC cases also involve and benefit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The legal problems faced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in poverty can
result in particularly serious, long-term consequences for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
13 According to an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Justice Statistics</ENAMEX>
Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Violence Against Women</ENAMEX>: Estimates from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redesigned Survey</ENAMEX> (NCJ-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">154348</NUMEX>) and a report by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychological Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Violence and the Family: Report of the</ENAMEX>
Violence and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Elderly people</ENAMEX> often require legal assistance because of their
special health, income and social needs, especially in coping with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> administered benefits on which many depend for
income and health care.


Ethnicity

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> -- Not of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> Origin <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38%</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> -- Not of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> Origin <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX>
Under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> & Over
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%18-59 85%</NUMEX>



Gender

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73.6%</NUMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII</ENAMEX>. Conclusion
Established by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> plays a central role in
providing low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with access to legal assistance and
information critical to resolving their civil legal problems. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> reported closing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,038,662</NUMEX> civil
legal cases relating to issues such as domestic violence, child
custody and visitation rights, evictions, access to health care,
bankruptcy, unemployment and disability claims, and many other
issues faced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
significant efforts to improve data accuracy, there may be
occurrences of errors in documentation or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>.
In order to fulfill our pledge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> and to the
general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> concerning our commitment to providing the most
accurate and reliable data, we adjusted the number of cases
reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,038,662</NUMEX>) by the average estimated error
rate (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX>). Accordingly, we submit a total of cases closed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">924,000</NUMEX>. This number represents the most reliable, albeit
conservative, estimate of cases closed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees.
Recognizing that valid questions have been raised regarding the
accuracy and validity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Service Reports</ENAMEX> (CSR) data that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s grantees <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> submit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has committed itself to
ensuring that reliable data is provided<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> The decrease in the
number of closed cases for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> is, in large measure, the result of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s new, more stringent reporting guidelines. For example, it has
been clarified that if a case file fails to contain any required
documentation
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law</ENAMEX> held an
oversight hearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 29, 1999</TIMEX>.
The hearing heightened awareness of some of the problems LSC was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">encountering</ENAMEX> in attempting to provide accurate statistics relating
to services provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gekas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chabot</ENAMEX> informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> of their expectation that the
statistics provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> concerning their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX>'
activities be accurate. For example, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chabot</ENAMEX> stated "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
certainly does look at the statistics that we are provided, and we
expect those statistics to be accurate when we are determining what
programs are going to be funded and at what levels, so we expect
those numbers to be accurate, and when they're not it disturbs us a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> deal, as it should." Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oversight</ENAMEX>
hearing before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcomm</ENAMEX>. on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial and Admin</ENAMEX>. Law of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Comm</ENAMEX>. on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>. 106th <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cong.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1st Sess</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
(financial eligibility, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX>/eligible alien status,
within program priorities, etc.) it may not be reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> as a
case. As a result, numerous cases have been excluded from
reporting, even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> received legal service, because
the case lacked the required documentation.
Unfortunately, the civil legal needs of all low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
are not being adequately met due to severe funding shortages at the
federal and state level. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FY95</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> appropriated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$402.5</NUMEX>
million for grants to local legal services programs. Assuming
inflation remains at current rates through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $450</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> is required in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FY01</TIMEX> to maintain the purchasing power (and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>) of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the FY95</TIMEX> level. Unless the federal investment for
civil legal services is substantially increased, a large segment of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> will continue to be without access to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> system. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget Request</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FY01</TIMEX> includes a modest
increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24 million</NUMEX> for grants to local programs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is committed to continuing to improve the accuracy of its
case statistics, vigorously enforcing the Congressional
restrictions enacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, and creating new and more meaningful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to evaluate the work of legal services programs receiving
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funds</ENAMEX>. We call on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the private bar, and local and
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to support LSC in fulfilling its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>
mandate to provide low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> with
real, meaningful access to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s justice system.





