




Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX>

A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Report</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STATE PLANNING &</ENAMEX> RECONFIGURATION
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2001</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOARD OF DIRECTORS</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANAGEMENT AND ADMINISTRATION</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OFFICE OF INSPECTOR GENERAL</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas S. Eakeley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chair LaVeeda Morgan Battle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vice Chair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulett H. Askew John T. Broderick, Jr. John N. Erlenborn Edna</ENAMEX>
Fairbanks-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Wm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCalpinMaria Luisa Mercado Nancy H. Rogers Thomas F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smegal, Jr. Ernestine P. Watlington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John N. Erlenborn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor M. Fortuno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Affairs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Counsel</ENAMEX>, and Corporate Secretary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauricio Vivero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmental Relations</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Affairs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David L. Richardson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Acting Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danilo A. Cardona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Compliance and Enforcement Alice</ENAMEX>
Dickerson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Genz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of
Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Performance John C. Meyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Acting Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Q. Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
Technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard J. Koczur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Acting Inspector General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David C. Maddox</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial and Information Resource Management Laurie</ENAMEX>
Tarantowicz, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Inspector General</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Review</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTRODUCTION</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX> (LSC) is a private, non-membership,
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> voting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with the
advice and consent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, compose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX>. By law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> is bipartisan: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no more than six</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> can be of the same political party<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> was created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> and continues to play a
central role in providing low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with access to legal
assistance and information concerning critical civil legal
problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is
guided by its congressionally mandated mission, spelled
out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act of 1974</ENAMEX>, "to provide equal access to
the system of justice in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Nation</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who
seek redress of grievances" and "to provide high quality
legal assistance to those who would otherwise be unable
to afford adequate legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>."<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds local legal services programs to serve
diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX> in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX>, and congressional
district in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, as well as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin Islands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guam</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Micronesia</ENAMEX>. As one of the primary
funders of civil equal justice in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has a duty to
stimulate the most effective means of delivering legal services to
low-in-come <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is committed to meaningful
partnerships with our grantees and the broader civil equal justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is also obligated to ensure that the federal
investment promotes efficient and effective client service and
complements the efforts of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of civil legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed a major overhaul of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s grant-making
and regulatory structure that included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major reforms
impacting the legal services community<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> adopted a
number of new accountability requirements governing what services
LSC-funded programs may provide, what they may do with non-LSC
funds, and whom they may represent. These new guidelines have
refocused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> delivery system on serving individual clients
with particular legal needs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX> working for LSC-funded
programs may no longer, for example, initiate or participate in
class action lawsuits, collect courtawarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>' fees,
represent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> or certain categories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, or take cases
involving political redistricting, abortion, or drug-related public
housing evictions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX> Another major reform of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> instituted a
competitive bidding process for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> service contracts, requiring
programs to demonstrate results and progress as a condition of
continued federal funding<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finally</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> approved a
one-third reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s annual appropriation, from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$278 million</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1995</TIMEX>, in anticipation of the funding cutbacks, LSC
initiated the broad outlines of its "state planning process" to
highlight strategies by which programs could stretch scarce federal
dollars to help ensure that all low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> have an equal
opportunity to receive the most accessible, effective legal
assistance possible. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of development in the field,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX> was formally launched in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. In
the ensuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Annual Appropriation</ENAMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">198519861987</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19881989199019911992199319941995199619971998199920002001</NUMEX>
Fiscal Year




II. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC CONVENES RECONFIGURATION TASK FORCE</ENAMEX>
This document, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Special Report</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
Planning and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reconfiguration</ENAMEX>, was prepared in response to a request
made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. House of Representatives</ENAMEX> during the FY2002
Appropriations process, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Appropriations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX>
stated:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> supports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s efforts to streamline its service
area configurations through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> planning process. However,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> has been made aware of concerns that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has
attempted to impose its own reconfiguration plans on certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">States</ENAMEX>
without clearly articulating standards for such decisions. In
several instances the Corporation rejected reconfiguration plans
developed and approved by all relevant stakeholders within a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>,
and provided no opportunity for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> to appeal that decision.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> expects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to review the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> planning process and
the concerns raised, and report back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> by no later
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 4, 200110</TIMEX>, with a proposal that articulates the
reconfiguration standards and process for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX> to appeal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
decisions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> intends that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> consult with appropriate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX> in developing this proposal.11
Since implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has sought to apply a set of detailed criteria in making all
decisions on whether a given service area arrangement is optimally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">configured</ENAMEX> to provide high-quality legal services to the greatest
number of eligible low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. These criteria were created
to complement the goals of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX> and to guide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in
evaluating the efficacy of service area plans submitted by
recognized stakeholders in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. These guidelines were
conveyed to LSC-funded programs through the release of a series of
Program Letters and other field correspondences<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furthermore</ENAMEX>, as
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19, 2001</TIMEX>, all recognized stakeholders have a right to a de
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">novo</ENAMEX> review of service area decisions by both the LSC Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> decisions run
contrary to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>' proposed configuration schemes<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX>
In response to inquiries from the legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 2001</TIMEX>,
established the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Task Force</ENAMEX> to Study and Report on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Configuration</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Areas</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX> was charged with reviewing
"existing policies, standards, and procedures governing state
planning and for defining service areas; and any revisions to
existing policies, standards, and procedures which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX>
concludes to warrant serious consideration by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>."14
Co-chaired by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John T. Broderick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernestine Watlington</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX>
convened the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of several meetings on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 21, 2001</TIMEX>, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> Representing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulett H. Askew</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Luisa Mercado</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Legal Aid & Defender Association</ENAMEX>; Melville
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Miller, Jr.</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Ross</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ofthe American Bar Association</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing Committee on Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indigent Defendants; Faith Rivers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Carolina Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanne Charn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinical Legal Education</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law School</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broderick</ENAMEX> delivered an interim report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s meeting on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 8, 2001</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broderick</ENAMEX> reported that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX> has made considerable progress in examining concerns
pertinent to service area configuration and the right of designated
stakeholders to appeal decisions with which they disagree. He
stated that broad consensus exists on a majority of issues before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX> and that remaining areas of disagreement are
expected to be resolved in short order. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> specific area of
consensus among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> was that all LSC reconfiguration
criteria should be codified into one document. The current LSC
reconfiguration standards, which are under review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>, are compiled and discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section IV</ENAMEX> of this Special
Report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
A final report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX> is expected to be presented
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> for consideration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2001</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> will give due consideration to any and all
recommendations embodied in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Task Force</ENAMEX>'s final report. In the
interim, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> believes it crucial to relay to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress LSC</ENAMEX>'s
current standards governing state planning, service area
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">configuration</ENAMEX>, and review processes.
In this report, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> is pleased to provide
information addressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> principal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>:

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review of the State Planning Process</ENAMEX>;


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
A Report on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconfiguration Standards</ENAMEX>;
and


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
The Process to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appeal LSC</ENAMEX>'s Reconfiguration
Decisions.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>. AN OVERVIEW OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STATE PLANNING PROCESS</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX>
embraces a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">vision15</ENAMEX> for legal services in which eligible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would be afforded an equal opportunity to
avail themselves of high-quality civil legal assistance. In an
effort to foster more consistent levels of state
wide service and to eliminate "service gaps" that leave cli
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ents</ENAMEX> in geographically remote areas under-represented <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
pared to their urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has asked its grant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ees</ENAMEX> to undergo a fundamental paradigm shift in their pro
gram visions. Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have been instructed to aban
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">don</ENAMEX> the parochial thinking of "What's best for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in my
service area?" and asked instead to consider "What's best
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> throughout my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> initially stressed the importance of state plan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ning</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> when it asked its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to
participate in the development of plans for the design, con
figuration, and operation of LSC-funded programs in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> Program Letters16 containing this directive
also enumerated the issues and criteria that state planning
should address.

Launching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX>, LSC
staff developed and issued Program Letters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998-117 and 199818</TIMEX>
which directed programs to plan for the creation of comprehensive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>-centered legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> and defined the
terms of such systems. Grantees were required to submit reports
outlining their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> plans by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1, 1998</TIMEX>. Their plans were to
include responses to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> central tenets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX>:
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) development of intake, advice, and referral services; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
effective usage of technology; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) increased access to legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-help</ENAMEX> and prevention information; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) coordination of legal
work, training, information, and ex

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pert</ENAMEX> assistance; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) engagement of pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>)
development of additional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, local, and private resources; and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) optimal configuration of service areas.
In designing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> plans, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> instructed its programs to
collaborate with a range of local, state, and national
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, including state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX>, Interest
On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust</ENAMEX> Account (IOLTA) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>, state judiciaries,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client groups</ENAMEX>, pro bono commissions, state legislatures,
non-LSC-funded legal services programs, and a host of others. LSC
requires its grantees in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to work with each other and
equal justice stakeholders to develop justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that best
respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' most compelling needs, ensure the most
strategic and cost-effective use of all available resources, and
maximize the opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> statewide to receive timely,
effective, and appropriate legal services.
Guided by the belief that access to quality legal services is
critical to a fair adversarial justice system and committed to
making significant improvements in their delivery, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> approved and enacted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>. Its twin objectives are to dramatically increase the
number of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who can access the civil justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> and to ensure that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> receive quality legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REPORT ON LSC</ENAMEX>'S <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RECONFIGURATION STANDARDS</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has vested in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> the
responsibility of specifying the service areas for which it will
offer grants for the provision of legal services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> awards one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">service</ENAMEX> contract per delineated service area. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, comprise multiple service areas and,
therefore, feature multiple LSC-funded grantees. Others, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> service area encompassing the entire
state and one corresponding statewide program.
Each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is different, and in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, intra-state regions
differ significantly as well. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has stated in numerous letters
to the field, there is no "magic number" of legal services programs
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given</TIMEX> state or a single delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> that fits every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
Each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> plan must be viewed based on the totality of the
circumstances, with the bottom-line consideration turning on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
studied determination as to whether a given service area
configuration inures to the benefit of the greatest number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in the most cost-effective way.
As a general rule, service area configuration decisions are
evaluated against one overarching principle: Program configuration
should occur in a manner that maximizes the effective and efficient
delivery of high quality legal services to eligible clients
throughout the state within a comprehensive, integrated delivery
system. In some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, it may be possible to develop and implement
statewide initiatives to improve service delivery, increase
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>, and enhance the capacity of the system to meet the civil
legal needs of all low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without altering service areas
or historical relationships. In other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the very development
and implementation of such initiatives may require overhauling or
establishing new organizational relationships and service
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>.
In the vast majority of cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has agreed with the
recommendations of state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and
has configured service areas accordingly. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, in the
proper exercise of its statutory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, may sometimes reject a
state plan as insufficiently responsive to the tenets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
Planning and substitute a reconfiguration plan adjudged to better
maximize effective and efficient delivery of high quality legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.

In deciding to accept or reject a proposed state plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> must
ultimately determine whether, when taken together with strategies
outlined in the plan in question, the proposed configuration is
best calibrated to:

Until the implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX>,
determining service areas in a given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was more a product of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographic</ENAMEX> and historical happenstance than a reasoned judgment
about the precise configuration that would yield the best legal
services system for the greatest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> reform replacing presumptive refunding of grantees with
competitive bidding for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> service contracts19
- coupled with budget cuts of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> - necessitated a
thoroughreexamination of the efficacy of existing service area
arrangements in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. With fewer resources to expend and a
growing client base to serve, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has embraced service area
reconfiguration as one important way to "insure that grants and
contracts are made so as to provide the most economical and
effective delivery of legal assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in both urban and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> areas."20 Rather than viewing service area reconfiguration as
a punitive measure against under-performing programs currently
receiving federal funds, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> instead considers statewide
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconfiguration</ENAMEX> to be one of several tools to ensure that federal
dollars are being spent in the most efficient, cost-effective
manner possible, in a way that will result in the best service to
the most low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.



11

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V. RECONFIGURATION</ENAMEX> REVIEW PROCESS
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> implemented a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconfiguration Re</ENAMEX>
view Process establishing an official framework by which
designated state planning bodies21 may seek review of LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconfiguration</ENAMEX> decisions. This formal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Process</ENAMEX> guarantees
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of every designated state planning body the right
to direct communication with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> at the highest level in
seeking reconsideration of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> decision. The objective of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Process</ENAMEX> is to maximize the potential for full communication
between stakeholders and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> before any configuration
decisions are made final and effective.
Central to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Process</ENAMEX> is the right of designated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders to de novo</ENAMEX> reviews of all configuration decisions,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> and then by the LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, whose decision is final and binding. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Process</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guarantees DSPB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> a face-to-face meeting with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> to make their case. If the state
planning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> disagrees with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>'s decision, they
may then request a face-to-face meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to
seek reconsideration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>'s recommendation. After
due consideration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>' ultimate appeal, the LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> will promptly advise the state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of a final
decision on configuration.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is committed to effective communication and coordination
with designated state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> (DSPB) on matters in which
decisions are likely to have a direct impact on other civil equal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> planning initiatives in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> recognizes the
increasingly active role that state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> have assumed in
overseeing state civil equal justice delivery activities. LSC
further recognizes that its decisions have the potential to
directly affect state funding, resource allocation, and other
considerations. In recognition of this crucial symbiosis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconfiguration Review Process</ENAMEX> prescribes a clear review mechanism
that guarantees recognized stakeholders a full opportunity to make
their case:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) At the earliest possible time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> will
advise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of any issues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> with respect
to service area configuration and provide guidance on how to
address those concerns consistent with the enumerated
reconfiguration standards.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) To the extent reasonably practical, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s state planning team
will work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX>, grantees, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> to foster
timely and effective consideration of issues relating to service
area reconfiguration.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will identify in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, if any, it proposes to
define new service areas at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> prior to
publishing those service areas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>. At that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> also will notify the relevant state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of
pending service area changes.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> recommends a service area
configuration that differs from that proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX>,
authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX> may seek a meeting with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> to ask for reconsideration. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> will be asked to articulate in writing their
concerns and objections.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Upon such a request, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> will convene a
face-to-face meeting with the authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX>. As soon as practical thereafter, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> shall
advise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX> of the service area configuration recommendation to
be forwarded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. In making the recommendation,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> shall be guided by state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">responsiveness</ENAMEX> to the enumerated reconfiguration standards; the
analysis and recommendations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>; the
articulated concerns of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX>; and any other information deemed
to be relevant by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP of Programs</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX> is not satisfied with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>'
recommendation, it may seek a meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to ask
for reconsideration. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX> will be asked to provide any
additional written information it wishes to be considered to assist
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> in fully and fairly entertaining all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> and
objections.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) Upon such a request, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> will convene a
face-to-face meeting with the authorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX>. As soon as practical thereafter, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> will
advise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX> of the final decision on service area configuration
in the affected state or territory. In making the decision, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> shall be guided by state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>' responsiveness to
enumerated reconfiguration standards; the analyses and
recommendations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> for
Programs; the articulated concerns of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSPB</ENAMEX>; and any other
information deemed relevant by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX>. CONCLUSION
Congressional reforms passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> necessitated a fundamental
shift in how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> apportions federal dollars to legal services
providers across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The shift to a competitive bidding
process, coupled with sizeable reductions in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget, compelled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board of Directors</ENAMEX>
to adopt a new approach to allocating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> investment
in civil equal justice for the poor. The expectations underlying
this new approach have been spelled out in considerable detail in
Program Letters issued broadly to the field, and in state-by-state
correspondences between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and various equal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice stakeholders</ENAMEX>.
In the current climate of scarce resources, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> must remain
committed to pursuing bold new approaches that foster effective
legal assistance to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, including overhauling
service areas adjudged to be insufficiently responsive to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tenets of State Planning</ENAMEX>. In an overwhelming majority of instances,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has used the competitive bidding process to forge deeper bonds
with its grantees and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to serve as an
active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in planting the seeds of comprehensive, integrated
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX> nationwide. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have embraced the new approach fully and reported
back enthusiastically on their progress since initiating their own
state planning processes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> understands that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> can be reluctant to embrace
major change. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> also recognizes that opinions may differ as to
the most appropriate configuration of service areas, and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> may have a better perspective on
how to best serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and enhance access in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> of these tensions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has worked diligently since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
to convey the expectations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX> and to
establish meaningful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> with stakeholders aimed at
fostering a new symbiosis between the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of legal services funding. However, if an impasse is
ultimately reached in a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, it is critical that LSC
maintain its statutory right to decide the configuration of service
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> in order to foster greater access and service for all
eligible low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
ENDNOTES
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> Corporation <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1974</ENAMEX>, as amended, ยง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1004</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2996c</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>) ("<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act of 1974</ENAMEX>"). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Id. at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ย</NUMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1001</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ย</ENAMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 Omnibus Consolidated Rescissions</ENAMEX> and
Appropriations <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1996, Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">110 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1321</TIMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>). These new LSC administrative provisions have been
incorporated into each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> appropriation since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, subject to
some modifications made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments of Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary and Related Agencies Appropriations</ENAMEX> Act,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">L. 105-119, 111 Stat.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2440</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Id. at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง 504</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Id.
at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ยง 503</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> Id. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional FY01</ENAMEX> appropriation is
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$329.3 million</NUMEX>. Consolidated <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Appropria- tions Act</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L. No.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">106-553, 114 Stat.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2762</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7 Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX>,
page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Programmatic Strategies</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act of 1974</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ย</NUMEX>ง
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1007</TIMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2996f</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s budget was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, its highest level ever, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association's</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>) legal needs study was concluded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. Using
a variety of methodologies for estimating the unmet legal need of
the poor, several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have since reached conclusions similar to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX> study, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> asked for funding to conduct a new national
legal needs study in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its FY2001</TIMEX> budget request to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>;
however, no funds were allocated for that purpose. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>
subsequently extended its deadline until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 12, 2001</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H.</ENAMEX>
Rep. No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">139</NUMEX>, 107th <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cong.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1st Sess</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> The reconfiguration
standards spelled out in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Report</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
consolidate informa- tion taken from the following previously
published <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building State Justice</ENAMEX> Communi- ties: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Report</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letter</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLADA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLASP</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAG</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Letter</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-1</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Letter</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-6</NUMEX>; Program Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-1</TIMEX>; and Program
Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001-7</TIMEX>. Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has issued
numerous other targeted field correspondences to individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX> who have submitted configuration plans adjudged
insufficiently responsive to the tenets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX>. 13 On
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19, 2001</TIMEX>, prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' request for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>, LSC
issued Program Letter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-4 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconfiguration Review Process</ENAMEX>),
which implemented a review mechanism by which designated state
planning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> may appeal LSC reconfiguration decisions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resolution</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">#2001-008</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resolution Establishing A Task Force To</ENAMEX>
Study and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Report on Configuration of Service Areas</ENAMEX>," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 Twenty</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> made a pledge to help
ensure that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> have access to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s civil justice
system by enacting legislation that created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has helped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> solve
important, sometimes life-threatening, civil legal problems.
Despite the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and its many contributions to access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, its achievements are overshadowed
by the fact that so many in our society continue to suffer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">injustice</ENAMEX> and are unable to gain access to our system of justice.
Until all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of our society are afforded that access, this
promise of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will continue to be unfulfilled. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is
committed to promoting a new vision of legal services that will
achieve the goal of bringing legal services to those currently
denied access to the justice system. 16 Program Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-1</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to develop plans to stretch scarce federal
dollars in the most effective, efficient ways possible. The letter
also anticipated the passage of congressional restrictions on the
activities of LSC programs, prompting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to instruct its programs
to forge deeper bonds with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, including non-LSC
funded programs, state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX>, IOLTA
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client groups</ENAMEX>. Program Letter
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-4</TIMEX> provided a general outline as to the issues and criteria
that the state planning process should address. Significant
emphasis was placed on the integration of LSC-funded programs into
statewide legal services delivery systems and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> central
tenets of state planning were identified. 17 Program Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998-1</TIMEX>,
published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 12, 1998</TIMEX>, called upon all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to
analyze any progress made toward the development of the legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> model envisioned by state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>. Programs were to
evaluate whether all programs were working cohesively to assure
that urgent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> needs were being addressed; whether sufficient
capacities for training and information-sharing existed; whether
programs were moving forward on technology; and whether they were
collaborating to increase resources and develop new initiatives to
expand the scope of their services. Grantees were also asked to
examine whether the existing program configuration was conducive to
the most effective state delivery system. Grantees were asked to
examine their progress in each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> principal areas of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX> in a manner that included assessing the strengths
and weaknesses of the current approach, establishing goals to
strengthen and expand services to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and determining
the major steps yet to be taken and a timetable necessary to
achieve those goals. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> set a deadline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1, 1998</TIMEX>, for
submission of state planning reports. 18 Program Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998-6</TIMEX>,
published on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6, 1998</TIMEX>, responded to recipient requests for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guidance</ENAMEX> and additional information on what was expected in their
state planning reports. It included "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Considerations</ENAMEX>"
designed to address requests for additional information regarding
statewide goals, capacities, and approaches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> should
consider in their state planning processes. Program Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998-6</TIMEX>
stated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX> will provide information
to aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> in exercising its statutory responsibility to "insure
that grants and contracts are made so as to provide the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">economical</ENAMEX> and effective delivery of legal assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in
both urban and rural areas." 19 As part of the competitive bidding
requirement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> mandated that current and past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>
may not "be given any preference in the competitive selection
process." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omnibus Consolidated Rescissions</ENAMEX> and Appropriations Act
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> ย<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ง 503</NUMEX>(e), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pub</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">110 Stat</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1321</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>). 20
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act of 1974</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ย</NUMEX>ง <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1007</TIMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S.C. ยง</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2996f</ENAMEX>(a)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>). 21 If no
designated state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> has been recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, the
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> may avail themselves of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review Process</ENAMEX>.
17




