



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizations</ENAMEX> are like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> -- slow to change
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James A. Belasco</ENAMEX>

Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last ten years</TIMEX>, many civil legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> began to wonder whether the civil legal services delivery
structure that had been in place for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter of a century</TIMEX> was
positioned to meets its many future challenges. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funding</ENAMEX> was
declining or stagnant, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in leadership positions were
weary after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of fighting for survival, demand for the delivery
of quality legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> was increasing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> were questioning
their work environments and their personal goals, technology was
fundamentally changing the practice of law, and society was growing
increasingly inhospitable to the needs of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The legal
services delivery system, created in another time and place, didn't
seem to be working in the ways that we--stakeholders, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>--expected it to work. And although we were proud of our
collective past, many of us had serious doubts as to whether the
delivery system that we had created, and that had performed well
for us and for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past twenty years</TIMEX>, was the most
effective and efficient delivery system for the difficult and
challenging times ahead.
Programs and program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> responded to these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> in
different ways. Some pursued strategic planning initiatives. Others
engaged in aggressive resource development, pursued alternative
methods of providing legal services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, reconfigured their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, or, in some instances, took their skills and talents
elsewhere. And, unfortunately, too many of us did nothing.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>
recognized that legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> were going to have to
change the method and manner in which they conducted their business
if they were going to remain viable and responsive to the needs of
low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> wanted to encourage all programs
to pursue some semblance of planning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, therefore, required its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX> to begin to examine, on a statewide level, how all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX> in a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would serve in the present, and plan
to serve in the future, the civil legal needs of low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s state planning initiative was primarily
focused on how grantees would work together to address funding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shortfalls</ENAMEX> and to respond to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX> restrictions. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, LSC
Program Letters <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-1 and 98</NUMEX>-6 broadened the scope of the state
planning initiative, asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX> to determine how they could
expand services and ensure that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> received similar levels
of assistance regardless of their location in the state or other
factors such as language, disability or political popularity.
In essence, these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> Program Letters asked grantees to expand
their horizons from "what's best for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in my service
area" to "what's best for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>." Programs
were requested to develop plans to coordinate and integrate their
work in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> important areas--enhancing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> access and
efficiency in delivering high quality legal assistance; using
technology to expand access and enhance services; promoting client
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-help</ENAMEX> and preventive legal education and advice; coordinating
legal work and training; collaborating with the private bar;
expanding resources to support legal services; and designing a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">system</ENAMEX> configuration that enhances client services, reduces
barriers and operates efficiently and effectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s grantees
were asked to:


•
Investigate the strengths and weaknesses of and resources
available to individual programs as well as the overall strengths
and weaknesses of and resources available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s legal
services "system;"


•
Assess the needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> served by the
programs and the overall "system;"


•
Anticipate changes and trends that will most likely
affect civil legal services programs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming years</TIMEX>;
and


•
Devise a plan of action, on a statewide basis, to address
the identified needs of low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in the present while
ensuring that the civil legal needs of future generations of
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> can be efficiently and effectively
addressed.


A handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> answered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s call to action. They
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consolidated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> to increase efficiency and deploy resources
more effectively; they took advantage of technology advances to
improve intake systems; they expanded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> of stakeholders
to increase the support and guidance available to service
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>. Their successes inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and other national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> to a deeper involvement in state planning and higher
expectations for all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> approved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Direction Plan</ENAMEX>. This document commits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to
dramatically expand the impact of legal services programs
throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> by improving access to legal services among
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> while enhancing the quality of the services
delivered. The Plan highlights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX> as
the primary strategy for achieving these goals. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> issued its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> program letter on state planning. Program
Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-7</TIMEX> renewed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s challenge to its grantees to actively
engage in assessing their delivery practices and policies and the
allocation of their legal services dollars. Program Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-7</TIMEX>
makes clear that the state planning initiative will continue to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s highest priority.
What does LSC mean when it talks about state planning? It has
often been pointed out that the term state planning does not
capture the full scope of the activities that are included in the
process as it is playing out across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Developing a plan
is only the beginning of an ongoing effort that includes
implementation of the plan's initiatives, continuous outreach to
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, regular assessment of progress toward goals, and
modifications of the plan as circumstances change.
Because these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> are all included in the concept of
strategic planning, as it is currently understood in management
practice, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> advantage of the term state planning is that it
emphasizes that what is involved is strategic planning for state
equal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.
Developing structures and processes for building and maintaining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>, integrated, statewide civil legal assistance
delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> may define the process more accurately but it is
certainly a mouthful. Building state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX> captures
the concepts of partnership and shared responsibility that are
involved, but may under-emphasize the ultimate goal to which the
building of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is directed--the creation and maintenance
of a system capable of providing equal justice for low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, actions do speak louder than words. It doesn't
really matter if we talk about state planning or state justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> or worldclass delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> or the creation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>, integrated and coordinated legal services delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>. It just matters that we do it. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>, however,
the term state planning should be understood in its broadest sense,
as inclusive of all these concepts and various structures,
processes, and individual initiatives described in the following
sections.
One final thought. Although state planning is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s highest
priority and we have put considerable resources into it over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> did not embark upon this journey alone. As we
proceeded with state planning activities, our national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>
also introduced projects targeted to the same goals--the creation
in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of a "state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX>" collaborating on the
creation and maintenance of a civil legal assistance system fully
responsive to the needs of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Among these
initiatives we would like to specifically recognize are the joint
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA-NLADA SPAN</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Assistance Network</ENAMEX>) project, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">joint NLADA-CLASP Project</ENAMEX> for the Future of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice</ENAMEX>. On the
state level, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX>--based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funders</ENAMEX> including but not limited to
IOLTA programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>--have also been a key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in state
planning.
This Report describes progress that the legal services community
has made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the six years</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> issued its first Program Letter
on the subject. It identifies some lessons gleaned from these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">achievements</ENAMEX>, describes the growth in selected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> toward
building a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> capable of responding to the full
range of civil legal needs of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Part II</ENAMEX>), and
identifies some lessons that have emerged from successful or
promising planning processes, as well as the particular structures
and strategies that these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have employed (Part III).
We acknowledge the hard work of building state justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and salute all those who have rolled up their sleeves
to take part in this exciting effort. We believe this report
demonstrates there is a big payoff for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>--which, after all,
is what it is all about.

Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six years</TIMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have developed a range of
initiatives aimed at expanding access and improving services to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Their achievements, like the planning processes they have
followed, have varied according to local circumstances, challenges,
and opportunities. As expected, one size truly does not fit all.
However, there have been important similarities in terms of
successes. These include:


•
Obtaining or significantly expanding state funding for
legal services;


•
Establishing systems for coordinating advocacy and
training among programs;


•
Making the court system more responsive and accessible to
low-income and pro se <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>;


•
Reconfiguring programs within a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to strengthen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coordination</ENAMEX>, access, and services;


•
Establishing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> to more creatively involve the
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> in the delivery of civil legal assistance;


•
Creating and executing a statewide technology plan to
improve access and enhance delivery;


•
Developing a statewide coordinated intake system;
and


•
Expanding the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> within a state
committed to the concept of equal justice.


This <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> describes the progress that has taken place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>
selected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> toward building state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX> capable
of responding to the civil legal needs of their low-income
residents. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are at different stages in the planning
process. In a few <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, a fully developed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> justice community
is in place and its accomplishments are paying off in terms of
expanded and improved services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have
developed key justice community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> whose significant
improvements in the structure of civil legal assistance in their
state position them to make real changes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Some states
are still in an early phase: they have developed a plan that shows
real promise and are just beginning to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> and
launch the initiatives to implement it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> described here are by no means the only ones that
have made progress. Others could have been included as well. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, made major
changes in their delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX> and are working
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diligently</ENAMEX> to realize the full potential of those systems. Others,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, are engaged in
promising efforts to overcome particular challenges associated with
their size and diversity. Still others--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>--while relatively slow to embrace the concept of state
planning have, within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, made significant progress in
addressing issues of access and quality in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
What we hope to demonstrate in describing what has been achieved
in these selected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> is both their differences and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">similarities</ENAMEX>, the range of different processes, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>, and
strategies that have led to their successes, and the basic
commonalties that underlie them in terms of vision, inclusiveness,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and commitment. Each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> described in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX> provides insights and lessons that can be of benefit to
others.


In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> in recognition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s size,
diversity and complexity asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to allow it to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> develop
regional plans for the creation of "regional" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> approved this proposal and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> received regional plans
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> regions. The current configuration and planning successes
in each of these regions are described below:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Region</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1999</TIMEX>, as the result of program
mergers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern California</ENAMEX> has been the sole
LSC-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> has made significant progress in
developing a comprehensive, integrated delivery system to provide
high-quality services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern California</ENAMEX>. In
addition to instituting a programwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Counsel</ENAMEX> advocate
support/case review system, which emphasizes collaboration and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-counseling on common issues throughout the whole region, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNC</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coordinating</ENAMEX> and advancing a region-wide advocacy agenda in welfare
to work and housing and economic development. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> has also
developed additional resources for region-wide initiatives, such as
increase the capacities of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> community-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX> was one of three geographical areas
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> involuntarily reconfigured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1, 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Area Legal Aid</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Legal</ENAMEX>") became the only LSC-funded
program for all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> area. The new
program, headquartered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, was the result of a merger
between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Francisco Neighborhood Legal Assistance</ENAMEX> (SFNLAF),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Services</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Foundation</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Contra Costa</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Legal</ENAMEX> was the recipient of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175,235</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Technology Initiative Grant</ENAMEX>. This grant will enable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> throughout the region to use networked
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX> to easily access forms and information. In its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Legal</ENAMEX> also successfully conducted a region-wide
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Campaign for Justice</ENAMEX>" fundraising effort which brought in
significant funds to all of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central California Region</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> LSC-funded programs
previously served the central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> region. Today, the region
is served by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> LSC-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Rural Legal</ENAMEX>
Assistance (CRLA), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central California Legal Services</ENAMEX> (CCLS) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Bakersfield Legal Assistance</ENAMEX> (GBLA). These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs
created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Rural Justice Consortium</ENAMEX>, a planning entity
dedicated to the vision of a seamless justice system in the region.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consortium</ENAMEX> is working on issues throughout the region,
including the legal problems of migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheepherders</ENAMEX> and health and
environmental issues affecting rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. In order to address
the access barriers that face rural and isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and
enhance communication between and among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs, the
programs have developed highly sophisticated video-conferencing
capability. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs have also agreed to allow and
encourage staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to move freely among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs in
order to respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> needs most effectively.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Basin</ENAMEX>. As a result of the merger between the
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, there are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs serving this region. The
programs have hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Advocacy Coordinator</ENAMEX> who staffs the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Advocacy Project</ENAMEX> to respond to major issues that cut across
program lines and can be addressed most effectively by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>
from multiple programs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> projects jointly pursued
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Basin</ENAMEX> programs will address the diverse languages spoken
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client population</ENAMEX>. Under a grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Society</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>, the programs contracted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Pacific American</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center of Southern California</ENAMEX> to provide centralized intake
for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who do not speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> require
extended service or representation, their cases are then matched
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs depending on the specific
language capabilities of each program. Through this project the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basin</ENAMEX> has found a way to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> who do not speak
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
The programs are also poised to make a major investment in
technology to expand the delivery of legal services. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>CAN
project, funded initially by an LSC technology initiative grant,
was developed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Orange County</ENAMEX> (LASOC) to
help "pro per" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> fill out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Council</ENAMEX> forms in family
law matters. Future plans includes replicating I-CAN throughout the
region and locating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> that can be used by clients
for on-line filings of certain legal matters.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern Region</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs in this region, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of San Diego</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland Counties Legal Services</ENAMEX>, were
relatively late in region-wide planning. Recently, these two
programs have committed to an agenda of specific collaborative
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>, including joint technology consultations, joint efforts
by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> in areas of mutual interest, joint
economic development projects, and assistance in developing intake
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>. Both programs are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>" grants to
run projects to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spanish-speaking</ENAMEX> "pro per" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in their
respective county <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouses</ENAMEX>. Both are also active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in
other statewide initiatives. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> have
both partnered with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRLA</ENAMEX> to respond to migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> needs in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coachella</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial</ENAMEX> valleys. However, significant integration
and planning work remains to be done in this area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Activities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> call for state planning coincided
with an active period within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX>. The
Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Commission</ENAMEX> was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> as a coordinating
body to seek support for legal services programs and develop
strategies to address the severe lack of access to justice that had
been identified <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar</ENAMEX>-sponsored blue ribbon study
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> consisted of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> from the bench and bar, including many long-term
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of legal services, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, and business, labor and
religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the provider
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> priority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> was resource
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development and the Commission</ENAMEX> led a sustained effort in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> to obtain state funds to support the
provision of civil legal services to lowincome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> appropriated, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> for legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The same amount was appropriated in FY <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>
increase to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> is expected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> priority was the improvement of access
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> for "pro per" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>
dedicated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> appropriation for civil legal services
to fund innovative projects that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> legal services providers
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to assist low-income self-represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>.
With support from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC's Technology Initiative</ENAMEX> Grants, LSC-funded
programs are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s plan
to utilize technology to expand access and improve legal services
delivery. Other promising technology initiatives include the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CalJustice Technology Project of the Public Interest Clearinghouse</ENAMEX>,
which focuses on increasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> access to the judicial system
through the development of an artificial intelligence-based tool to
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> quickly spot issues in and strategize about cases.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has also recently adopted statewide priorities for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">connectivity</ENAMEX> and communication, developed minimum technology
standards and created mechanisms to share best practices.
Other statewide non-technology initiatives include:


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inter</ENAMEX>-program and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">inter-region</ENAMEX> collaborative projects to
develop new substantive expertise and new programs to respond to
changes in policy and law impacting upon low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>;


•
A system of advocacy training and litigation support
through a network of support <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in the areas of health, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>,
housing, and economic development;


•
The development of standards and assessment tools
tovaluate the support <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>.




State planning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> with the formation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statewide Legal Services Planning Group</ENAMEX>. Represented in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> were LSC-funded programs, the organized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>,
both law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Account Foundation</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>=s IOLTA program), the
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> (the statewide fundraising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>=s
federally-funded legal services programs) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> of specialized
legal services and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> interested in the provision of
legal assistance to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Early planning efforts focused on development of additional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>, expansion of pro bono assistance and support from the
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and ensuring effective delivery of services by the
federally funded programs. Initial efforts addressed a variety of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> issues including training and support, increased use of
technology, more efficient and uniform intake and the provision of
legal advice and brief service, and meeting the needs of
particularly vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">migrants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and disabled
and institutionalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
Progress was made on a number of issues important to the legal
services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, but despite signs of chronic weakness in two
programs, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-program LSC structure was left intact. During <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> competition, the service area of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these programs was
awarded to an adjacent program. The other received limited funding,
and ultimately was provided a very short grant. Together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> Program Letters, this decision provided the impetus for more
serious discussion of program configuration which resulted in the
formation of a single statewide program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Legal Services</ENAMEX>,
effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1, 1999</TIMEX>.
The formation of a single statewide program was adopted to
breathe life into a single program that will provide meaningful
access to high quality legal services, in the pursuit of justice
for as many low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> as possible.@
This vision became a touchstone for decisions as to program
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">governance</ENAMEX>, delivery issues, including office staffing, support,
training, technology, and increased access to high quality legal
advice, brief service and more extensive legal representation.
During the consolidation process, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX>
technical assistance grants enabled the program to utilize the
services of a skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> and facilitator to move the
process to conclusion, to send program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to visit and observe
other programs with well respected and technologically
sophisticated centralized intake systems, to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to the
program to help design a transition to statewide administrative and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personnel</ENAMEX> systems, and helped fund the statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> meeting
which launched and celebrated the new statewide program.
The goals of the single statewide program included establishing
uniform standards for high quality legal representation, increased
administrative efficiency and the provision of more effective,
accurate and helpful brief service and advice, increased training,
technical assistance and support for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, but particularly
for casehandlers in small remote rural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and significantly
increased access for more low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coloradans</ENAMEX> in need of service.
Many of these goals have been met and others continue as work in
progress.
Initiatives that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLS</ENAMEX> has undertaken to improve and expand
services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> on a statewide basis included:


•
The establishment of statewide priorities that pay
particular attention to the needs of rural, hard-to-reach
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>;


•
Increased training and advocacy support throughout the
state;


•
Detailed plans to initiate a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Client Access Plan</ENAMEX> which
will feature a highlycentralized telephone-based intake
system;


•
Vastly upgraded technological equipment, Internet access
and computer capability;


•
A new case information system that will provide improved
information about numerous aspects of the provision of legal
assistance to the low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> throughout the
state;


•
Casehandlers standards to be used as benchmarks by staff
in the representation of all program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.


Successful efforts have also been made to expand resources
necessary for the delivery of civil legal assistance to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indigent</ENAMEX>. Other efforts focus on how to increase pro bono
representation of both eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in
need of service provided by the federally funded statewide program,
and to locate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> for services that may not be available from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funds.
Increases in resource for civil legal assistance have
included:


•
Significantly expanded giving by law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>;



•
After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> of effort, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State General Assembly</ENAMEX>
appropriated funds in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX>) to serve the civil needs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic and family violence and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

The coordinated and focused efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Group</ENAMEX>
have also brought major positive changes to pro bono activities
throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> including:


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Supreme Court</ENAMEX> revised Rule <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.1</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Rules of Professional Conduct</ENAMEX>, effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2000</TIMEX>,
to provide an aspirational goal that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> provide not less
than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 hours</TIMEX> per year of pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> each year;


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Supreme Court</ENAMEX> amended the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Code</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial</ENAMEX>
Conduct to more clearly specify that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> may engage in
activities to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to perform pro bono
service;


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Bar Association</ENAMEX>=s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Governors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> approved a set of guidelines to encourage pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> by
government and public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>;


•
A thorough review and revision of its Private Attorney
Involvement activities by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLS</ENAMEX> to further encourage pro bono
participation throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>;


•
Efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLS</ENAMEX> to maximize local pro bono participation
while further coordinating statewide technical assistance and legal
support provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who participate in pro bono programs
as well as increased recognition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer lawyers</ENAMEX> at both the
local and state level.


The relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>
in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> has always been
positive. The consolidation of the federally-funded programs into a
single statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> has provided the opportunity for increased
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> and collaboration throughout the state both within
legal services and between legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> in the private bar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and with
other key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX>. It is expected that continued planning
and concerted effort will result in higher quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> provided
more uniformly throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in increasing
numbers will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of a more thoughtful and better
coordinated state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> planning efforts began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> with The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida Bar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Commission on the Delivery of Legal</ENAMEX>
Assistance study and report. Its recommendation to increase pro
bono engagement was addressed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court mandated pro bono reporting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Bar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
Recommendations contained in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> plan also resulted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX> of tri-annual peer reviews for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>) funded programs, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> LSC <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. Recommendations that programs improve
technology capacities were addressed in large part by a revolving
loan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>, established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, that enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> programs
and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IOTA recipients</ENAMEX> to purchase needed computer and related
technology. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s "companion system" was created to
serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> whom LSC-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> could not
represent.
More recently, and in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s state planning letters,
planning moved to a new level when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s
largest legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> held a retreat to consider how to
improve civil legal assistance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical Assistance</ENAMEX>
Grant from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, matched by a grant from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Florida Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>,
enabled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> to retain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> who
has continued to guide the planning process.
At the retreat, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> examined changes in client
needs and the practice of law over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past ten years</TIMEX>. They asked
themselves what accomplishments they and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> were most
proud of, and how they could expand these achievements. They
considered ways in which the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> civil legal services programs in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> (including the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> LSC <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>) should expand
partnerships to ensure that low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Floridians</ENAMEX> had access to a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> array of the highest quality legal services possible. They
realized that significant change in the service delivery system was
the number of legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, the
restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and, most important, changes in laws
and programs affecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. It became clear that restructuring
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s delivery system could increase the work that made staff
most proud and brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> the best services. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The directors</ENAMEX>
developed the concept of "statewide, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>-centered, energetic,
affirmative advocacy" as a key value against which to measure all
proposals for change. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> were identified as:


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shared</ENAMEX> responsibility for the statewide delivery
system


•
Collaborative attitudes on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> and
programs


•
Strategic thinking about the most effective way to
achieve results for clients


•
Advocacy skills needed to provide effective, high-quality
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Client</ENAMEX> centered provision of services


•
Ongoing self-assessment


A survey was sent to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33</NUMEX> nonprofit civil legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> asking them to describe how they could become (or maintain
themselves as) energetic, affirmative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, as well as what
support they might require and how collaborative efforts in the
state could meet those needs. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">273</NUMEX> responses from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
programs. The results were reported to the equal justice community
and posted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Legal Services</ENAMEX> website,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">floridalegal</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>.
The initial planning effort sparked by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> program directors
grew to become a broadly inclusive structure. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX>
represent key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> including funders, bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, among others. Its principal components
are:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oversight Committee</ENAMEX>. Consisting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State Bar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Florida Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, the statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing Committee on Pro Bono Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Directors Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, this group guides the
planning process, seeks input from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, establishes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">timeline</ENAMEX> and gives final approval of the state plan.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action Committees</ENAMEX>. Charged with exploring problems and
opportunities in the areas identified in the project director
retreat and the advocacy survey, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vision, Technology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislative/Administrative</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Advocacy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Client Access, Collaboration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">and Training</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical</ENAMEX>
Assistance. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> developed measurable goals with
estimated dates for completion. Close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> serve on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coordinating Committee</ENAMEX>. Composed of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chairs of the Action</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committees</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> considered the recommendations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committees</ENAMEX> and integrated them into a draft state plan.
Project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>. Consisting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33</NUMEX> nonprofit civil legal services
programs, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> has responsibility for ensuring implementation
at the program level.
After circulation for comment to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> largest source of legal services
funding in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>), local pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>, local bar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations and Area Agencies on Aging</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oversight Committee</ENAMEX>
released the draft plan for public comment in late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX>. A
final version was adopted at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of February 2001</TIMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Plan divides the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> regions, and
highlights a regional approach in its collaboration and
configuration strategies. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> houses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and other
nonprofit civil legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> bound together by a
commitment to collaborate. Programs in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> will sign an
"enforceable agreement" enunciating the specific activities each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> will undertake. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> to more carefully explore whether the current
configuration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and non-LSC funded programs is one that will
best advance their goals. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> requested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> seriously
consider the advantages of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> LSC-funded program anchor
each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> regions identified in the plan.
Programs have already moved to carry out some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plan</ENAMEX>'s
recommendations. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> programs receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> funds have
jointly hired a statewide resource <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>, along
with The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State Bar</ENAMEX> and several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>, have provided
funds to hire a statewide pro bono development <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Planners</ENAMEX>
are seeking funds to improve the statewide website and expand
internet access to community education <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> beyond the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> education site for immigrant advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
Other initiatives include a statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child Support Task Force</ENAMEX> and
a statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma Lazarus</ENAMEX> Project.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regionwide</ENAMEX> efforts are also underway. In one region, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> LSC
programs have established a regional intake system, funded by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Technology Initiative Grant</ENAMEX>, with a second planned for another
region, to be developed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. A region-wide community economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> initiative housed at an LSC program provides expertise
and other resources to all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IOTA recipients</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> region. A
regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Educational Advisory Project</ENAMEX> (involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
programs) to do outreach and advocacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and a regional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team Child Project</ENAMEX> on joint advocacy between legal services
programs and public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">defender offices</ENAMEX> for youth entering the
juvenile justice system have also been established.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>, which gives substantial funding to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33</NUMEX> nonprofit civil legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, has
pledged to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> evaluate each of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> on their state
planning work as well as their contribution to the regional effort.
Regional efforts will be a critical component of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>'s
tri-annual on-site peer review of each program. Thus, programs will
be measured not only on their individual contributions to regional
and state planning, but also on the quality of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX>'s
accomplishments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> anticipates that this approach to
evaluations will help maintain the productive pace of the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>' planning and emphasize the importance of joint endeavors.
Furthermore, planning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have indicated that configuration is
a priority for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, and have developed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and
strategies to address this critical issue.


The LSC-funded programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> have a long history of
working together on joint projects, state support and other
matters. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> program letter, the
programs requested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois State Bar Association</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bar Association</ENAMEX> join them in the planning process. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, under the authority of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar associations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Project</ENAMEX> was established. The mission of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Project</ENAMEX> included: protecting the integrity and
accessibility of the legal system for all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>;
educating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> about the self-help
process within the judicial system; and promoting costeffective
legal services for low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Project</ENAMEX> brought together a very diverse group
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the low-income client
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, social service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, civil
legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to address the need for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> costeffective legal services in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>. The project was governed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steering Committee</ENAMEX>. In
addition, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working groups</ENAMEX> were created: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Non-Adjudicatory</ENAMEX>
Problem <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Solving; User Friendly Pro Se Adjudication</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Delivery System</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project</ENAMEX> adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> guiding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">principles</ENAMEX>:


•
Equal justice is a basic right, which is fundamental to
our democracy. Thus, the integrity of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and
our justice system depends on protecting and enforcing the rights
of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on an equal basis;


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> must be educated to protect their
legal rights and accept their legal responsibilities. They must
also have information about self-help processes and available
remedies;


•
The justice system must work with social services,
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to promote holistic,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">multi-disciplinary</ENAMEX> approaches to preventing and resolving legal
difficulties;


•
Since demand for services continues to increase, legal
aid programs must be supported in avoiding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">duplication</ENAMEX>, maximizing
coordination and promoting effective use of existing and emerging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>;


•
Legitimate political discourse requires constructive
alternatives. Attacks on the current system, often based on
misleading anecdotes, have failed to enlighten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> or
improve services to the public; and


•
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, which comprise our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> system, are largely local. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">is an integral</ENAMEX>
part of the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> welfare and funding equal justice is a
fundamental obligation of state and county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.


Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working group</ENAMEX> met several times to develop recommendations
for changes to the legal services delivery system. The
recommendations were adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associations</ENAMEX>, and, along with an appendix of existing and proposed
implementation measures, submitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Assembly</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>,
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, legal services programs, bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. The focus was on creating a true system of
equal justice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>. (The report also recognized work that
had already begun among all legal services programs with the
establishment of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statewide Legal Services Delivery and Technology</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working Group</ENAMEX>, which was meeting to share information on the use of
technology.)
As part of the goals developed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Project</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Associations</ENAMEX> agreed to support the
introduction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Equal Justice</ENAMEX> Act in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Assembly.</ENAMEX> The bill failed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-98</TIMEX> session but passed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX>. Although stripped of any funding mechanism, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> authorized the establishment the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Equal Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> to receive and distribute any money appropriated by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX>. Finally, in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999-2000</TIMEX> session, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> was
appropriated. While <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than the $1,000,000</NUMEX> sought by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, it is a start.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> commented upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois State Plan</ENAMEX> and
implementation to date. In its feedback letter, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> noted that it
was "impressed with the steps you have taken and will continue to
take under this plan to develop an integrated and comprehensive
delivery system that is designed to meet the present as well as the
future needs of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> within your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>." However, LSC
also asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> to reopen their consideration of the
configuration of the LSC-funded programs believing that "a thorough
review of this plan leads to the almost inescapable conclusion that
while reconfiguration may not be a front-burner issue within this
state, there is merit to seriously exploring reconfiguration of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> LSC-funded programs into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> also suggested that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> develop ways to involve more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and community
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> in the planning process and develop plans to expand
their funding base.
Reconsideration of the configuration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> has led
to decisions to consolidate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, final
reconfiguration of the LSC-funded delivery system will be
completed, leaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prairie State Legal Services</ENAMEX>,
Land of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Legal Assistance Foundation</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assistance Foundation of Metropolitan Chicago</ENAMEX>.
The programs have also followed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice</ENAMEX>
Project recommendations to consider more streamlined and
cooperative ways of operating. While <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> initially had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
federally funded legal services programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> identified
another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs that were providing legal services to
the economically disadvantaged. Many of these programs were small
and most operated within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook County</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-
ever meeting of all of these programs was held. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX> provided funding for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> facilitators and lodging and
meal costs were paid for by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund of Illinois</ENAMEX>. The
programs met for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> to plan areas of need and cooperation.
Working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were established to coordinate training statewide,
to focus on the establishment of a statewide website and to
continue coordination and sharing in technology matters.
The programs continue to explore <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> for improving services
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. With funding from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lawyers Trust Fund of Illinois</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Working Group</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CARPLS</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>-based hotline and referral services), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Assistance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation of Metropolitan Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prairie State Legal Services</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land of Lincoln Legal Assistance Foundation</ENAMEX> have formed a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best</ENAMEX>
Practices" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> have visited one another's
programs as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> additional model hotline/telephone intake
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. As they have observed better, more
efficient and more innovative ways of doing business, new
procedures have been adopted.
In cooperation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIT Kent College of Law</ENAMEX>, legal services
programs are also involved in establishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Center for</ENAMEX>
Law and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Interest</ENAMEX>. This will be a single database that
will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> portals for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> separate interest groups
including a portal for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> that would provide them access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client community</ENAMEX> legal education materials and self-help legal
materials. (This would expand upon materials that are currently
available from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Illinois Self-Help Center</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
legal services website.) A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> portal would provide information
and video streaming training for pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. The final
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">portal</ENAMEX> would provide access for legal services staff to training
materials, discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, legal research and other matters. The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in this collaboration have recently signed
agreements specifying the duties of each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. The site will be
located at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIT-Kent College of Law</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois Equal Justice Foundation</ENAMEX> has recently made its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">first</ENAMEX> grants from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">money</NUMEX> appropriated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illinois General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assembly</ENAMEX>. Because of the limited money available, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grants
were restricted to funding for civil legal services and hotlines.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later this year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> will initiate a study to evaluate
the most effective way in which pro bono can be encouraged and
supported. At the present time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pro Bono Center</ENAMEX>
whose function is to work with the organized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and legal services
programs in encouraging participation in existing pro bono programs
as well as to help develop new pro bono programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>. The
focus of the study will be to determine what changes need to be
made in the existing structure to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> to effectively
meet its mission or, alternatively, to recommend a new structure.
This study will be funded by an LSC technical assistance grant and
will be coordinated with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX> peer study.


In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> LSC-funded programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> submitted a
state plan to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> that was seriously flawed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> were told
that their plan was "non-responsive to the issues identified in LSC
Program Letters <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-1 and 98-6</NUMEX> and in need of major work." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
was instructed to submit a revised plan to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and develop a
"collaborative, inclusive and values-driven plan and planning
process that strengthens services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> throughout the
state."
Serious planning within the legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> began in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1999</TIMEX> with a commitment to "plan to plan" on the part of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> LSC-funded programs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> at that time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> gave
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> a technical assistance grant to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to assist
with the planning efforts. Over the course of a long series of
meetings and discussions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> and staff
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> programs reached the conclusion that if all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> were to have access to high quality legal services,
significant changes needed to be made in the configuration of
programs within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> programs passed a resolution approving the concept of merger.
Although merger discussions continued among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> programs, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the programs did not vote in favor of the merger
plan, and therefore the plan moved forward with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> programs:
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Organization of Indiana, Inc.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Indiana, Inc.</ENAMEX>
As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31, 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northwest Indiana</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> joined with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Organization of Indiana, Inc.</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSOI</ENAMEX>) by transferring its assets to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSOI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSOI</ENAMEX> then changed its
name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Legal Services, Inc.</ENAMEX> (ILS) and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2001</TIMEX>
became the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funded program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> currently has a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-month</TIMEX> sub-grant agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Program</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Indiana, Inc.</ENAMEX> (LSPNI) which previously received an LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grant</ENAMEX>, in order to attempt to reach an agreement with LSPNI
regarding transfer of staff and other assets from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSPNI</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX>. ILS
is opening an office in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Wayne</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maumee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley, Inc.</ENAMEX> (LSMV) still operates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSMV</ENAMEX> has non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding to
represent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in specific substantive areas, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> and LSMV
are in the process of developing referral protocols to ensure that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are referred to the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
The formation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> is based on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Plan</ENAMEX>"
developed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSOI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNI</ENAMEX>. The plan describes the
legal work, allocation of resources, role of private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>,
role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client community</ENAMEX>, role of service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, governance
and program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and intake for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Legal Services, Inc.</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Plan</ENAMEX> provides for a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>-member
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> that is appointed in proportion to poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> from
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
The major values included in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Plan</ENAMEX>" are:


•
The need to remain responsive to and work with local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Legal Services Plan</ENAMEX> makes it clear that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> must look at problems faced by the lowincome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> from
both a state and a local perspective. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> is designed so that it
can bring together statewide resources in order to meet the needs
of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. Priorities will be set statewide, but each
region of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> will have its own case acceptance guidelines,
which will take into consideration local needs and resources. Each
region will have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Advisory Council</ENAMEX>, with a large number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client representatives</ENAMEX>, which will develop these guidelines and
work with the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to ensure that it is meeting the
needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in the region.


•
The need to ensure high quality legal work. In order to
ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are linked to each
other, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> programs developed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Justice Center</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IJC</ENAMEX> developed a website with both public and private sections
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indianajustice</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> training events, coordinates
community legal education materials, oversees the pilot hotline
project and serves as a voice for legal services to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IJC</ENAMEX> also supports the work of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Round Table</ENAMEX>, which has a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> (senior law, consumer
law, public benefits, housing, family law, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> Law, etc.) to
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> from throughout the state belong. These sections
meet regularly by conference call and in person in order to share
ideas and strategies and conduct training events. Each section also
has a "listserv," hosted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IJC</ENAMEX>, and a section on the website
to which they can post pleadings and other documents that could be
useful to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Round Table</ENAMEX> sections are chaired by
casehandlers from throughout the state and responsibility for
organizing the agendas for meetings is shared. The philosophy
behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Round Table</ENAMEX> is that all legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are
responsible for ensuring high quality legal work of the program.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Round Table</ENAMEX> sections also include non-legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>,
providing an opportunity to share expertise between programs. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Legal Services Plan</ENAMEX> also described the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pilot</ENAMEX> Hotline
Project, which was begun in an effort to increase the effectiveness
and efficiency of intake and advice. This Project is piloting new
telephone and case management systems so that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> can determine the
most effective way of implementing a statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotline</ENAMEX>.



•
The need to expand funding for the provision of civil
legal services to low income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> is the
last <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to have an IOLTA Program. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Supreme</ENAMEX> adopted
Rule <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rules Professional Responsibility</ENAMEX>, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">establishes Pro Bono Committees</ENAMEX> in each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial</ENAMEX>
Districts. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Committees</ENAMEX> are charged with developing and
implementing plans to meet the civil legal needs of low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> through pro bono systems. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Committees</ENAMEX>' plans now
receive funding from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>. Each of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> has legal services representation, and many of the plans
are integrally linked to the current legal services pro bono
programs. Rule <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5</NUMEX> also created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pro Bono Commission</ENAMEX>, which
oversees these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and recommends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> distributions to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Bar Foundation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBF</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBF</ENAMEX> is responsible for
the

IOLTA program and has worked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and bar in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
to launch a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> program. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> continues to work with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Equal Justice Fund, Inc.</ENAMEX> (IEJF), a separate not for
profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> to raise funds for legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IEJF</ENAMEX> conducts an annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> campaign, for the
benefit for legal services and legal aid programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IEJF</ENAMEX> was also
instrumental in the passage of a general appropriation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana General Assembly.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> is also committed to
increasing local funds for each of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>


•
The need to bring stakeholders together on an annual
basis to continue the process of equal justice planning and to
celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s successes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>, with support from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Bar Foundation</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Pro Bono Commission</ENAMEX>, sponsored the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Annual Access</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Conference</ENAMEX>, a statewide meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>,
law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>, legal services and legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and others to continue the
process of statewide Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> planning. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> people
attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">2001 Conference</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of whom were not from
legal services. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX>, attended by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX> included presentations from bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> who reported on those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' progress in state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX>, an update on state planning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and breakout
sessions addressing technology, resource development, pro bono and
pro se. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">2001 Conference</ENAMEX> featured an introduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services, Inc.</ENAMEX> and an introduction of the new pro bono plans
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several of the 14</TIMEX> judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> delivered keynote addresses at both conferences, calling
upon <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> state bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> to work
together in developing a statewide system that ensures equal access
to justice for all low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKay</ENAMEX> spoke at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">2001 Conference in</ENAMEX> celebration of the new
statewide program and recognition of the importance of developing
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX>. Breakout sessions addressed pro bono
issues, pro se and technology. Planning for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">2002 Conference</ENAMEX>,
which will be a working conference, has begun.


•
The need to expand the use of technology to provide
essential services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> has a technology plan that will enable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, both staff
and pro bono, from throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to access information. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IJC</ENAMEX> website provides a place for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> to share information.
The technology sessions at the Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conferences</ENAMEX> have
focused on how technology can be used to link <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> across the
state and across program lines, and how it can be used to directly
benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> by providing information and tools for pro se
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">litigants</ENAMEX>.
• The need to improve and expand the role of the private bar in
civil legal services delivery. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> worked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court to submit a successful grant application to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Statewide Pro Se Office</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Supreme</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court Administration</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> will work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> pro se
programs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS Pilot Hotline Project</ENAMEX>, to
determine best practices for pro se support, and will develop form
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleadings</ENAMEX>, approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, for use throughout the
state. These forms will be posted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IJC</ENAMEX> website. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collaborative</ENAMEX> effort is a major step for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> in the area of pro
se support. These form pleadings will be used at pro se clinics
sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pro Bono Committees</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> will oversee this
project, which will include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILS</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Indiana</ENAMEX> differs from many other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> have made considerable progress in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>
beyond the reconfiguration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funded programs but, unlike
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> does not have a formal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.
This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> conducts its planning activities through ad hoc groups
addressing discreet issues. In this way they have involved the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX>, the private bar, law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, social service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>,
court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, legal services staff and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and clients
in their planning effort.


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>

-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>

In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, much of the groundwork for comprehensive state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX> had already been laid when the Corporation issued its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> program letter on the subject in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, the
Commission on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Needs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, chaired by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Muskie</ENAMEX> and made up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioners</ENAMEX> drawn from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">judiciary</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>, the private bar, and the low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>, convened a series of hearings around the state and
issued a report calling for increased resources for legal services
with a number of recommendations for improving access. Under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of an implementation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> created in the wake of
the report, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX> a number of steps were taken
to increase and support pro bono participation in the delivery of
civil legal assistance, support pro se <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>, increase IOLTA
participation, and eliminate barriers to access. The state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX> also followed up on the report by creating the
Commission on the Future of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Courts</ENAMEX>, with a similarly broad
composition. In response to its report, issued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, a number of
steps were taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to assist low-income and pro se
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">litigants</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, anticipating the imposition of restrictions on LSC
activities and cuts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> funding, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Association</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Foundation</ENAMEX> sponsored a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-long</TIMEX> forum on the future
of legal services, attended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> from the private bar, the
legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, the state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">judiciary</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX>, and executive branch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> led to the creation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Action Group</ENAMEX>, staffed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Association</ENAMEX> and
chaired by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank M. Coffin</ENAMEX>. Other members
included <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Wathen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> (and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Dana</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidents</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Association</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Bar Foundation</ENAMEX>, a member
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> each from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maine School of Law and the Boards of Pine Tree</ENAMEX>
Legal Assistance and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Elderly</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action Group</ENAMEX> undertook responsibility for overseeing the work of a
number of task <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> for specific issue areas. The work of the
task <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> was supported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Response Team</ENAMEX>,
consisting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of the legal services programs and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar Foundation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bar Association</ENAMEX>. A second
statewide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> took place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, focusing on the needs of pro se
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">litigants</ENAMEX>, with continuing follow-up from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>.
Among the most significant achievements resulting from these
phases of the planning process were the following:


•
A substantial increase in IOLTA rates at most major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>;


•
Enactment of bipartisan legislation to increase court
filing fees and fines to provide funding for legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>;


•
Creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maine Equal Justice Project</ENAMEX>, to provide
representation of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> before the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maine Equal Justice Partners</ENAMEX>, a network of pro bono litigators
willing to engage in administrative advocacy, class actions, and
other broad systemic advocacy;


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX> and implementation, with substantial donated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX> and in-kind donations, of a statewide technology plan,
enabling the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> to computerize their operations
fully and to improve their telephone systems dramatically, as well
as creation of a shared "information technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>"
position housed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pine Tree Legal Services</ENAMEX>, the LSC
program;


•
Establishment of a new public interest fellowship program
named in honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coffin</ENAMEX>, supported with funding by the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> largest law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>. Between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Coffin</ENAMEX>
Fellows" housed at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pine Tree</ENAMEX> have handled family law cases on
behalf of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year since 1998</TIMEX>;


•
Creation of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Division</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to handle
family law matters and to be more responsive to the needs of pro se
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">litigants</ENAMEX>, accompanied by simplification of court forms and hiring
of a volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> within the court system to promote the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recruitment</ENAMEX> and training of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> to help pro se
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">litigants</ENAMEX>.

