



Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002-2005 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress Report</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>

Introduction
In my capacity as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice-President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX>, I am pleased and
proud to provide to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> progress
report documenting the work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Programs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC - OPP</ENAMEX>, OIM
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for
Programs (and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>)-- in addressing the challenges
placed before us in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> adopted a strategic
planning document entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX>. This
document established twin goals to be attained by the national
legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>: to dramatically increase the
provision of legal services to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>; and to ensure that
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> are receiving appropriate and high-quality legal
assistance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX> also identified
anticipated outcomes, including: increased numbers of clients
receiving legal services appropriate to the legal issues they
encounter; expanded relevancy of the delivery system to the most
pressing needs of low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> themselves
taking a leading role in this effort; an expanded range and
improvement in the quality of services provided by legal services
programs; and finally, greater consistency in the quality of legal
services programs. State planning is identified in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>
document as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s key strategy to achieve the goals stated
above.
Because state planning was identified as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s prime
strategy for fulfilling the mandate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX>, a brief review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s state planning initiative is
probably in order. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Initiative</ENAMEX> began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
primarily in response to the programmatic changes and budget cuts
that were threatening the very survival of legal services delivery
across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. State planning was built on the understanding
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and territories serve as the relevant geographic areas
of a planning focus for developing strategies to meet the civil
equal justice needs of poor and vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Several years
later, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, state planning became a key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> strategy to achieve
access and to improve the quality of services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> specifically
announced its intent to put resources into the creation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>, coordinated, and integrated state legal services
delivery systems in Program Letters <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-1 and 98-6</NUMEX>. These program
letters declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> was no longer limiting its focus on
outcomes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> within and by individual programs, but rather
it believed that quality legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> could be delivered only in
a statewide context. It challenged each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to examine its
organizational structures, its use of technology, intake systems,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX> development, and private bar involvement through a
statewide lens.
In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 - eleven months</TIMEX> after the adoption of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Directions 2000-2005</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> issued its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> program letter on
state planning that set forth expectations for each justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>. These expectations, for purposes of brevity, can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summarized</ENAMEX> as follows: a delivery system in which eligible clients
in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are afforded an equal opportunity to avail
themselves and ultimately to attain high-quality civil legal
assistance.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Programs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> have worked assiduously these past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> to help create a world-class national legal services
delivery system in which eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are
afforded an equal opportunity to avail themselves and ultimately to
attain high-quality civil legal assistance. However, as we moved to
address the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s mandate, we quickly realized that the creation
of a world-class delivery system involved more than "state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX>," per se. After all, we do not pursue state planning
because we are "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>" by education or trade-most of us, indeed,
are <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>. And
we do not pursue state planning because we love planning. We don't
really love planning-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least</NUMEX> most of us do not. We love legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and are committed to making legal services better. And
frankly, we do not pursue state planning because we want our
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">naysayers</ENAMEX>" to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has reformed itself. We pursue
state planning because we believe that our low-income clients
deserve the highest quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> that can be made available to
them despite our limited funding. Accordingly, in our quest to
create world-class justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and territory
in this great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, we began to focus on other initiatives that
were, to us, just as important as state planning to the creation of
a delivery system in which eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> are
afforded an equal opportunity to avail themselves and ultimately to
attain high-quality civil legal assistance. often refer to these
initiatives as state planning's companion initiatives, and these
initiatives - competition, the quality initiative, the diversity
initiative, technology initiative grants, the matters initiative,
our efforts to enhance services for self-represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX>, the
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource Library</ENAMEX>, to name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a few</NUMEX> - have become as
important to the creation of a world-class delivery system as state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX> has proved itself to be. These, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> initiatives and
the hardworking and talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> who carry out these initiatives,
work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX>-in-glove with the equally well-qualified state planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> to promote the development of high quality, world-class
delivery systems.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>, we issued our first progress report to the LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> describing our efforts to help build premier
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX> throughout our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. We issued our second
report in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>. In this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> report, we have decided to
present our work to you in a fashion slightly different from the
format we have used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two</TIMEX> reports. Because we have
learned over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> have two
primary legs upon which they ultimately stand or fall - healthy and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vibrant LSC</ENAMEX>-funded programs and healthy and vibrant state justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> to which all LSC- funded programs belong - we will
present our work in this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> report in terms of our activities to
promote healthy programs and healthy state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX>. We
believe this format will provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> a
complete and true picture of the work we pursued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> to build
legal services delivery system in which no eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is
turned away, and in which every eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> is provided high
quality legal services.
We thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> for giving us this
opportunity to present our work. More importantly, we thank the LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> for giving us the opportunity to improve a legal
services delivery system that is so valuable to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, so
essential to a democratic way of life, and so very important to all
of us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Corporation</ENAMEX> exists to help our clients
address their legal wrongs and promote their legal rights. To the
extent that we have been given the opportunity to participate fully
in addressing this important and primary mission of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, we have
been truly fortunate.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. Structural Changes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delivery System</ENAMEX>
Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has initiated and overseen significant
structural changes in the number and configuration of LSC-funded
programs in order to develop more powerful and effective state
delivery systems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Program Performance</ENAMEX> (OPP) staff
have assisted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees and state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX> with this
change process in a number of ways, including the provision of
significant technical assistance to help with planning and
implementation. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> available to help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> develop effective plans and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130,000</NUMEX> to assist <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institute</ENAMEX> new delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>. Significant staff resources also
have been devoted to on-site visits and to sharing information and
best practices, targeting programs undergoing consolidation.

Planning for Change


•
Technical Assistance for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> gave
technical assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, enabling these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to obtain
important consulting and facilitative assistance with configuration
and overall planning.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Configuration Changes</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> completed
configuration planning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> and submitted proposals for
significant structural change, with completion dates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. Each of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> planning assistance funds.
Configuration planning commenced in another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.




Changes Effective in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> will become one statewide service area. The
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Corporation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, which serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>, has absorbed the assets of the single county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polk County</ENAMEX>
program and changed its name to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa Legal Aid</ENAMEX>, reflecting its
expanded service area.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>. After years of effort, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> basic field service
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> have been consolidated into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>. The new configuration
improves opportunities to increase resources and access and achieve
greater equity in client service.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> service areas have been
consolidated into a much more manageable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of our most
highly integrated and comprehensive delivery systems, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> is
now poised to deliver even better services to low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> separate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> areas
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Field</ENAMEX> service areas have been combined into one
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> area and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Basic Field</ENAMEX> area, and a grant for both
made to a single program. This will yield more geographically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equitable</ENAMEX> service, especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.




Changes Effective in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> LSC-funded service areas have been
combined into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> regions. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>'s plan, which was
accepted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>, the LSC-funded programs will continue
to anchor the delivery system and provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of basic
legal services to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> plan, also accepted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, reduces the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> service areas to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>. By combining
many of the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> areas, the new configuration
establishes a sturdier platform for client services and the future
growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s equal justice system.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> has just submitted its plan to
consolidate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> service areas into a statewide program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Planners</ENAMEX>
believe this will improve coordination of resources with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and
non-LSC programs, and assure uniform delivery of services to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Commission</ENAMEX>, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX> from the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri Bar</ENAMEX>,
recommended consolidation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> service areas into one
LSC-funded program, beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of planning, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> has
committed to producing a reconfiguration proposal by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 15</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.




Future Changes
• <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakota</ENAMEX>. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> territory received notices of
configuration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. Nearly all have experienced
structural changes in their delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. Now each
will embark on a review of the efficacy of current configuration
patterns, and report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> on their studies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.


Implementing Change



•
Assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merging Programs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> give
substantial assistance to merging programs. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, programs
merged or prepared for merger in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. Our efforts with these
programs varied depending on need. We wrote checklists of merger
issues to consider during the merger process and shared model
documents developed by other programs. When asked, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> made
available information on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> with special expertise in
merging non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. We referred programs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> that had
successfully addressed similar merger challenges. Over and above
assisting with the technical aspects of merger, we helped programs
resolve issues that interfered with

creating and maintaining a comprehensive integrated delivery
system in the reconfigured service area.


•
Special grant conditions for programs that merged in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. Our special grant conditions required periodic submission of
written progress reports on achieving a comprehensive integrated
delivery system. Programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> received special grant
conditions. In many instances, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> responded to their reports
with written feedback.


•
Technical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Assistance to Assist with Consolidations</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130,000</NUMEX> in merger technical assistance to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>. This money
underwrote assistance for technology; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> building;
labor relations, including salaries, benefits, pensions and revised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> policies; fund balances; due diligence and other
merger-related legal work; office space and insurance; planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> efforts; changes in intake, hotlines and case management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>; and other consolidation issues. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, our funds
helped leverage new resources.





II. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Improvement</ENAMEX>
At the core of powerful and effective delivery systems are high
quality legal services programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> work with grantees to
enhance the quality of their work through ongoing contact, through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library Resource Initiative</ENAMEX> (see section <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>), and through
program visits. Program visits allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to monitor program
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">developments</ENAMEX>, to learn about problems, and to develop new
strategies for expanding access and enhancing quality.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">On-site</ENAMEX> reviews take a number of forms. Technical assistance
visits are conducted after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> receives a request from a program
for assistance in a particular area such as intake systems, legal
work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and supervision, or technology. Program inquiry
visits are designed to gather information and to give LSC
additional knowledge about programs that have not been visited
recently. Program inquiry visits also occur when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> believe
that certain challenges facing the program need <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s attention.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> visits are made to Technology Initiative Grant (TIG)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, we visited programs that received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> funding
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 and 2001</TIMEX> to review technology progress under the grant.)
Finally, post-reconfiguration visits occur <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> after a
service area has been reconfigured to assess how well the program
is serving the new service area and the extent to which the
restructured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> is operating cohesively.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> conducted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> on-site visits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> visits
lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> (one required <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 business days</TIMEX> due to the size
and location of the program), and involved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consultants</ENAMEX> sometimes served as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and often OPP
technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to lend their special expertise.


•
Program-inquiry Visits. Occurred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>. In addition, program-inquiry
visits conducted in combination with state planning visits took
place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>.


•
Post-reconfiguration Visits. Occurred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>.


•
Technical Assistance Visits. We responded to requests
from programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> for technical assistance
visits.


•
TIG Visits. In addition to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> on-site program quality
reviews, OPP technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> visited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our 2000 and 2001</TIMEX> Technology
Initiative Grant (TIG) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>.




<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>. Diversity, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leadership and Inclusion</ENAMEX>
Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> invited a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of national leaders
with a deep interest in promoting multicultural diversity to advise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> on how best to help grantees reach their diversity goals. The
advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s preeminent project was to help create and
produce a training tool on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and diversity for program
boards and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. This resource was completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2002</TIMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> acted on several other items listed in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action</ENAMEX>
Agenda on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diversity</ENAMEX>, a summary of ideas and suggestions raised in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> national conversations on diversity.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">• Board Training Module on Leadership and Diversity</ENAMEX>
This resource is intended to assist programs with diversity
initiatives and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> grantee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and management discussions on
the importance of diversity in providing high-quality and
appropriate services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. It can be used in conjunction with
regular board trainings or as a stand-alone device. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leadership</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diversity: The Link That Promotes Effective Delivery</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> was tested with good results at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> - a statewide
program in the northeast and a large southwestern program. Early in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, the module will be given to every LSC-funded program. We
anticipate that the module will increase commitment to building a
multi-culturally competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and services that reflect the
diverse backgrounds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client communities</ENAMEX> by engaging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> in
candid conversations and exercises on fostering inclusion,
cultivating new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and expanding diversity parameters in
their programs. Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> research, (explained below in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collecting Diversity Data</ENAMEX>), indicates that many program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> need to reemphasize diversity in staff recruitment,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promotion</ENAMEX>, and strategies to reach overlooked client <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• Education</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outreach</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project Directors Association</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> organized a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">well-received</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEPDA Conference</ENAMEX> to showcase how well
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state communities</ENAMEX> of justice and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> programs used
reconfiguration activities to expand diversity within <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteer</ENAMEX> ranks, and for instituting programmatic measures that
will generate a new cadre of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Annual Legal Aid Conference</ENAMEX>. At this statewide training
event, we joined a panel that addressed how legal services programs
and equal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> can effectively recruit and retain a
diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX>, among other critical diversity activities.
Later in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, building on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assembly</ENAMEX> began creating an action plan of goals for obtaining
diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>, growing a diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and
deeper engagement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client community</ENAMEX>.
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Forums</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Programs Randi Youells</ENAMEX>
repeatedly highlighted diversity's essential role in a healthy and
effective legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in talks she gave throughout the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> to program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice leaders</ENAMEX>, and state justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. In this way, the LSC diversity message was delivered
locally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>, and nationally through
articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIE Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLADA Update</ENAMEX>. She promoted
diversity in speeches she was invited to give to partner
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> - the combined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of State Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX> and
Conference of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Court Administrators</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Legal</ENAMEX>
Aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> and through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Speakers</ENAMEX>
Series. Our commitment to a nuanced approach to diversity was
apparent in each meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board Provisions Committee</ENAMEX> as
staff regularly reported on activities in this area, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenters</ENAMEX>
invited from our programs reflected the importance of inclusion in
the topics they addressed and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> they
represented.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• Leadership Mentoring</ENAMEX> Efforts
Responding to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> raised at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> conference for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of statewide programs, we designed a pilot mentoring
project for new statewide program executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>. In its
initial phase, the project matched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new statewide program
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> with an experienced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> convened at each
other's programs and over the telephone to explore topics such as
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, managing change, and state planning in states
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantee.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• Collecting Diversity Data</ENAMEX>
Through the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Competition Process</ENAMEX>. Through its competitive grant
process, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> obtains and reviews substantial data on an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>'s
capacity to respond to a diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client community</ENAMEX>. Using this
information, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> can learn how each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> proposes to diminish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> access barriers including cultural, geographic, and language
barriers; how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> will engage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> with access
barriers; the racial, ethnic and gender distribution of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applicant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>; strategies used to recruit, retain, and promote
diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>; training events that address diversity; and how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> is building <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that is diverse.
Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Service Reports</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX>'s, which grantees are required
to submit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, contain data on program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> as well as
on cases closed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a calendar year</TIMEX>. Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, we reported
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our</TIMEX> examination of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-2000</TIMEX> data on gender and race of
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of LSC-funded programs. We discovered that
reconfiguration, within the confines of state planning, did not
diminish the percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in leadership
positions in our programs. We saw that, despite vigorous efforts to
increase diversity in state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX> and particularly in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership positions</ENAMEX>, the ethnic profiles of our executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> remained virtually unchanged, and the number of women
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX> was significantly lower than their percentage in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney workforce</ENAMEX>. Later in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, we were able to study the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>. These indicated that the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of color rose
from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent to 21 percent</NUMEX> of the director <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
Unfortunately, the data also showed that the number of women
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX> continues to lag behind their increasing presence in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> ranks.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>. Identifying and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sharing Best Practices</ENAMEX>
Legal services programs often pioneer creative responses to the
challenge of high quality, effective services for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>,
we are frequently impressed with the range of novel approaches that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> have devised.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2002</TIMEX>, we launched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Resource Library Initiative</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRI</ENAMEX>), a website committed to ensuring that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> programs are aware
of and have access to innovations in civil legal services work. The
project is dedicated to raising the standard of practice in legal
services programs by encouraging the cross-fertilization of
innovative practices through facilitating the voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of
exemplary practices. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRI</ENAMEX> showcases a variety of original and
effective activities ranging from how to conduct a comprehensive
strategic planning process to new ideas for serving hard-to-reach
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten weeks</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> launched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRI</ENAMEX>, site activity
reports showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> had viewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 15,500</NUMEX> pages.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRI</ENAMEX> is available online at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lri</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lsc</ENAMEX>.gov.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V. Managing Information</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Improve Grants Administration</ENAMEX> and
Program Quality
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Information Management</ENAMEX> (OIM) along with OPP
recently launched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Grants Award Letter</ENAMEX> (EGAL) system.
This initiative permits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to distribute grant award letters
electronically from a secure website. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGAL</ENAMEX>'s benefits include an
electronic archive of competitive grant contracts, immediate access
to digital grant award documents, reduction in administrative cost,
and faster and more efficient transmittal of information to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX>. Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIM</ENAMEX> revised the electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant Renewal</ENAMEX>
Application to accommodate new information sought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and to
ensure greater ease for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIM</ENAMEX> obtained the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> figures, at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">county</ENAMEX> levels, and devoted substantial time to calculating poverty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> for each of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX>' service areas under these new
figures. This information was supplied to all grantees and will be
the basis of our grant awards for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is committed to providing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Congress</ENAMEX> and the
public with the most accurate information possible. Closed case
statistics form a major component of the program activity data
collected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>, and are a critical measure of the impact of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> funding on the legal problems of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in poverty.
Therefore, it is essential to assure the accuracy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> assists our grantees in verifying the
reporting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> self-inspection
process.
The purpose of the self-inspection process is to give our
grantees a means to ensure that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data meet LSC standards
for accuracy. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January of each year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> distributes a Case
Review Form. The Form contains a list of questions that identify
key requirements that need to be met in order to report a case to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. Grantees statistically "sample" the cases closed in the
previous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> to determine if the "sampled" cases generally meet
the requirements for reporting cases to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>. If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent or more
of the cases sampled in the self-inspection process have problems,
then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> assumes that there are overall problems within the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantee</ENAMEX>'s case closing records, which may affect the accuracy of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data. In the event that the selfinspection process does
reveal problems, grantees are asked to consult with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> to
determine the appropriate corrective action. All grantees are
required to submit their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Inspection Certification and Summary</ENAMEX>
Forms to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March of each year</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>. The
information is turned over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Compliance</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> system and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> data.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX>. Technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Directions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-2005</TIMEX> identifies technology as a
primary strategy for enhancing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> access to services. We have
observed that many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> receive some assistance when
technologically sophisticated intake systems are installed.
Computerized and web-based self-help programs make high quality
information available to those who would be denied aid because of
resource limitations and case acceptance criteria. Technology
innovations can improve full representation through quicker legal
research and information gathering capacities. Finally, stronger
technology systems allow a program's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to experience more
effective supervision and coordination.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Initiative Grant Program</ENAMEX> (TIG) is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s most
powerful tool to help programs ramp up existing technology systems.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> awards were granted. The improvements and projects
they funded are discussed below (see Section <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">VII</ENAMEX>. Training, Section
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IX</NUMEX>. Pro <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Se Enhancement, Section XI</ENAMEX>. Pro <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono Enhancement</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section XII</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intake Enhancement</ENAMEX>).

The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Initiatives Grant Program</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">98</NUMEX> grant applications for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> funding.
Screening them required <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven</TIMEX> review sessions with outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> review sessions, and special sessions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to
analyze how the applications affected program quality and state
planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. Staff recommendations went <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX> and then to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erlenborn</ENAMEX> for final
funding decisions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> grants totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.4 million</NUMEX>. They foster our
objective of improving access to justice for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. For example,
the grants will allow:


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> to install computers in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouses</ENAMEX> with
access to legal information and self-help materials on the
statewide legal services website.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX> to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> computers in the village <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>,
with access to legal information and self-help materials that are
mounted on a new statewide website.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> to create a web-based pro se litigant support
system for some of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>-funded assisted pro se programs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> will be able to view their own personal web pages as
"personal case account <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>," and resource their files. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> is information about a panel of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> to provide
"unbundled" services and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> who offer free services to pro
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">se litigants</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>CAN!
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interactive Community Assistance Network</ENAMEX>) services to include an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Credit</ENAMEX> module. Low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> will be able to
complete the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schedule EIC</ENAMEX> and related tax forms, and file them
electronically. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in this
project.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> to support their joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>/legal
services planning for the effective utilization of technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> for self represented litigants


Expanding on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> grants for statewide websites, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
new awards, bringing the total number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that are building
and maintaining statewide websites to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 40</NUMEX>. These sites
enable a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> to benefit from centrally maintained and
up-to-date resources for legal information and self-help
materials.



<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII</ENAMEX>. Training
Many areas of poverty law are highly specialized. To ensure top
quality representation, legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> need ongoing training in new
and complex areas of law. Low levels of funding and the absence of
state, regional and national poverty training materials and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> can diminish opportunities for staff education on
substantive poverty law issues. Through the competition process,
our work with state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX> and with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> funding, LSC
helps grantees meet critical training needs. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, we designed
several new approaches.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Lawyer Training Project</ENAMEX>
Pursuant to a contract with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX> Law,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCPL</ENAMEX> held training events at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> nationally on conducting
poverty law research via the Internet and other webbased tools. The
training was structured to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> to subsequently train
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who did not attend the sessions. These events were so
popular that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCPL</ENAMEX> replicated them at new sites, not funded under
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> contract.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> contract required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCPL</ENAMEX> to produce a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poverty Law</ENAMEX>
Manual that introduces <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> to the fundamentals of poverty
law. A hard copy of this manual was distributed to all new legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It is available electronically
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCPL</ENAMEX>'s website.


Technology Grants <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Focused On Training</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two 2002</TIMEX> TIG awards focus on training. In one, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Line of Vermont, Inc.</ENAMEX> will make nationally available on-line
the core curriculum of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Services Training Consortium</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>, and provide a platform for other legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> to obtain distance learning opportunities, allowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> to get skills training without the usual financial and
travel costs. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society of Orange County</ENAMEX>
will create a national technology training and curriculum project
to build capacity across many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> within the legal services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>. This will extend the implementation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> technology
innovations that improve justice for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.


Technology <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Technical Assistance Days of Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> staff offer hands-on technology training by building on
national legal services events. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example is our "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day</ENAMEX> of
Service." This project is supported by our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> funds and is
organized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Technology Assistance Project</ENAMEX> (NTAP). A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day of Service</ENAMEX> occurs on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before the opening of a national
conference. The technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> of all the programs attending the
conference (including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>) convene <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before the
conference begins to lend technical expertise to the legal services
program in the host <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> have benefited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> (in conjunction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA/NLADA Equal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Conference</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Action of Wisconsin</ENAMEX> (prior to the NLADA
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Meeting</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Orlando Area Legal Services</ENAMEX> (in
conjunction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonprofit Technology Enterprise Network</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-TEN</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX>).
Another innovative project that is held on conjunction with
national legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> meetings is our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cyber Café</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, we
hosted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cyber Caf</ENAMEX> at both the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">NLADA Annual Meeting</ENAMEX> and at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice Conference</ENAMEX> to give Internet access to conference
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, allowing them to check their email. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cyber Caf</ENAMEX>
also allows technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to demonstrate
new software and discuss technology resources with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conferees</ENAMEX>.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIII</ENAMEX>. Measurement and Evaluation
It is crucial to the strategic planning process to measure the
volume of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX>' work and to evaluate the success of their
approaches. To this end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX> has built systems for determining the
effectiveness of our strategic initiatives. Described below are
measures we have been refining over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> to capture
information on the effects of state planning, the amount and type
of service that programs give, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> outcomes, program delivery
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>, and the impact on services of our technology grants.

State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Communities Planning Initiative Evaluation</ENAMEX>
Instrument
In order to insure the highest quality and maximum level of
services to potentially eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and so that
the goal of meeting those needs will be realized, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has developed
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Justice Communities Planning Initiative Evaluation</ENAMEX>
Instrument. A design <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> from the legal
services community - including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and other
stakeholder <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> - worked assiduously over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> to produce
a tool that will be tested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, revised pursuant to that
process, and ultimately used nationally. The instrument is designed
to assess the health and vibrancy of each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community/state</ENAMEX> legal services delivery system, establish
benchmarks against which further progress can be measured, and
begin to gather data to allow comparisons of state justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Self Evaluation Process</ENAMEX>
Pending implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Planning Evaluation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Instrument</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> responded to and engaged state justice communities
around the self-evaluations reports they sent in pursuant to
Program Letter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-07</TIMEX>. Our feedback focus is on the relationship
between the structure of a delivery system and its capacity to
provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> access to a full range of services no matter where
in the state the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> resides, while at the same time
anticipating and providing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' emerging legal needs and
aspirations.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analyses of Case Closing Data</ENAMEX>
Program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Information Management</ENAMEX> reviewed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Service Reports</ENAMEX> (CSR) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991 through 2000</TIMEX> to discern trends
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> and numbers of cases closed by grantees. Their
analysis revealed that most programs experienced declines in cases
closed during periods of dramatic funding reductions and before
they (with and without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> assistance) aggressively sought other
forms of funding (e.g., <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1990</TIMEX>'s). In spite of a diminution in
cases closed, however, programs showed remarkable stability in the
kinds of cases they reported. The data indicate correlations
between the number of brief service and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> and advice cases
closed and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of telephone intake systems. They also
show that the percentage of extended service cases also grew,
demonstrating that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees continue to vigorously represent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in the more traditional forums of administrative hearings,
mediations, and trial and appellate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> even as they institute
innovative full-service intake systems. Our study, reported
nationally by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randi Youells</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of State Court Judges</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of State Court Administrators</ENAMEX>, also vividly
illustrated what we do not know about our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX>' work - the
difference it makes in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>' lives and how it has benefited the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Measurement of Services Programs Provide</ENAMEX> in Addition to
Cases
Some low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who seek assistance at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> need
only legal information, guidance with self-representation or a
referral to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> more appropriate to their needs. LSC
has stressed the merit of these limited services though several
strategies, including technology grants to support statewide
websites, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRI</ENAMEX> to share innovative practices, and state planning
requirements that touch on pro se assistance, community legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and similar services.
The matters reports allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPP</ENAMEX>, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, to learn
about the type and volume of grantee work that does not constitute
"cases." These activities include community legal education, some
forms of pro se assistance, referrals, outreach, indirect services
including training to non-legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> who help low income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and other services, including mediation and alternative
dispute resolution.
Although we collected data on matters work undertaken during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last six months of 2001</TIMEX>, we were not able to analyze and report on
them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> and on our website until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than two</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> received significant matters services from grantees
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half of 2001</TIMEX>. All but one of the programs provided
community legal education, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89 percent</NUMEX> engaged in outreach
activities, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> disseminated pro se information.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grantees</ENAMEX> reported providing referral information to more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">530,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The importance of matters services to the
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is demonstrated in our report, which also
includes summaries of innovative approaches that have allowed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grantees</ENAMEX> to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients services</ENAMEX> that do not fall into the
"cases" category, but are nonetheless significant.
The matters report is at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lsc</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/Websitedocs/MR080802.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pdf</ENAMEX>.


Measurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outcomes</ENAMEX>
Development of an outcome measures reporting system to
supplement or replace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX> system is underway. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, LSC
posted a Request for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX>, as the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step to issuing a Request for Proposals to develop an outcome
measurement system. In late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> hired an experienced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to study and report on existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> in the legal
services community and make recommendations on approaches LSC could
adopt.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Measurement of Quality</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Review</ENAMEX> Visits
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> expanded its on-site program reviews to include internal
protocols for visiting recently merged programs and for evaluating
a program's closed case statistics. The purpose of the former is to
learn whether all elements of a newly merged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> are
functioning cohesively, and to identify areas where technical
assistance may help achieve a unified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX>. Protocols on
closed cases will ensure the consistent application of our analysis
factors. Both new protocols will be used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>
who review programs and in their reports and recommendations based
on the reviews.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Measurement of Quality</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grant Application</ENAMEX>
Process
Through the competitive grants process, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> evaluates an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applicant</ENAMEX>'s capacity to provide effective and efficient high
quality legal representation to eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assessments</ENAMEX> also
are made of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>'s participation in an integrated delivery
system that seeks to make the most efficient use of all resources,
strives for innovations in delivery mechanisms and creatively
involves the private bar. Criteria and standards used to measure
the strength of a legal services delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> are derived from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LSC Act</ENAMEX> and regulations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Performance Criteria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>) Standards for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Programs Providing Civil Pro Bono</ENAMEX>
Legal Services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Persons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limited Means</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA Standards</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Providers of Civil Legal Services</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poor</ENAMEX>.
Recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> examined its competitive grants process, through a
series of discussions, and surveys and interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> grantees and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, to determine its effectiveness in measuring
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>'s capacity to provide high quality, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>-centered
legal services. The results demonstrated that our process is a
useful and effective tool for assessing the quality of legal
services delivery. Suggestions on how to improve the current
process were implemented and, as a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> will be sending
feedback letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> that filed grant proposals for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>
funding to begin a dialogue about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>'s delivery system
based on the grant application. Additionally, our Request for
Proposals now encourages applicants to describe the quality of
their delivery approach, the unique features of their service area
and any model projects.


The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evaluation of Technology Projects</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> funds support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Evaluation Project</ENAMEX>, an
initiative of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legal Aid Society</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Project</ENAMEX>
creates evaluation instruments for statewide websites, also
supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> awards. Created over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, the
tools were distributed to programs for comment at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2002</TIMEX>.
User feedback is expected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in 2003</TIMEX>, after which the tools will
be modified if necessary and distributed. When perfected, the tools
will allow programs to evaluate their technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> during
implementation phases to both assure successful completion and,
ultimately, to determine whether their goals were achieved.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IX</NUMEX>. Pro <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Se Enhancement</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the best ways to help the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 80 percent</NUMEX> of
low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who need legal assistance but must do without,
is to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> self-represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> with quality information and
assistance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> does this in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. One is by giving self-help
assistance directly through our programs (such as with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>CAN
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> and the statewide websites) and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is by enhancing
existing efforts on behalf of pro se <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">TIG Pro Se</ENAMEX> Efforts
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> grants that directly touch on pro se.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighteen</NUMEX> were website renewal grants to statewide websites begun in
previous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Thirteen were for new statewide websites. An
additional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> were for other pro se projects. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> put self-help
computers in each of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX>' community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>; another
put self-help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">remote courthouses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>. A
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, made to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Legal Aid</ENAMEX> (partnering with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>), built on earlier efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX> and created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self Help</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Offices</ENAMEX> (SHO) for an urban setting (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>) and a rural setting (a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mobile</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that will move from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> presented the TIG-funded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-CAN</ENAMEX> project from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Court System</ENAMEX>. We also organized
a conference on document assembly software in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. At
that event, legal services personnel, court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and other
technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> saw demonstrations by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> on their
products, and assessed their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> for preparing pro se
documents. After weighing the options, we arranged for a donation
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lexis</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HotDocs</ENAMEX> document assembly software for each
state, which will greatly enhance the availability of legal forms
that lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can easily fill out online.
Recognizing that self-represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigants</ENAMEX> are a challenge for
court systems, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> has collaborated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for</ENAMEX>
State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Courts</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Justice Institute</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Judicature
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pro Bono Net</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zorza Associates</ENAMEX> to create a website
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> involved in self-help projects.
This is one of several endeavors by an ad hoc pro se <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that has
continued to work jointly on enhancements for pro se since it was
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> organized, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG Conference</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>,
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Conference of Chief Justices-Conference of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court Administrators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> held <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sessions on successful self help
initiatives, and met informally with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> to
examine potential and existing pro se <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> between civil
court systems and legal services programs.



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource Development</ENAMEX>
Substantial new resources are essential to increased access to
and availability of services to low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>. Level LSC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX>, census-related cuts in many program budgets, downturns in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOLTA</ENAMEX> and state government revenues made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX> one where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> support for resource development was essential to the vitality
of programs and state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice communities</ENAMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> continued to offer technical assistance to lower
funded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to increase resources. For example, our funds made it
possible for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> to adopt a multi-year development plan, and
allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> to launch a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> private bar campaign
that secured <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $300,000</NUMEX> in contributions and pledges prior to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kickoff</ENAMEX>, with the expectation of reaching its goal of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collaborative</ENAMEX> efforts also are yielding gains in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice community stakeholders</ENAMEX> joined
to bring about passage of a filing fee surcharge law that will
ultimately give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $7.6 million</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> funding for civil
legal aid.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> collaborated on an endowment fund
that will provide longterm support for legal services. It was made
possible by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Combined Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, a coordinated
fundraising effort by the state planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> sponsored by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware State Bar Association</ENAMEX> and other justice community
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX>.


•
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> were able to increase filing
fee funding by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> and, through the statewide funding
planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, created a statewide funding action plan adopted by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Statewide Planning Assembly.</ENAMEX>




<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">XI</ENAMEX>. Pro <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bono Enhancement</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most powerful ways to expand client services and
support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> is to engage the private bar in poverty law
activities. Historically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> barriers have interfered with broad
participation in pro bono projects. One is that few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are
experienced in poverty law and most are reluctant - without support
and assistance - to handle such cases. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, many private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> are unwilling to take a case when the effort it will
require is not clearly set forth at the outset. Fortunately, many
of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are willing and able to help in other ways.

Websites
Early indications are that pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">websites</ENAMEX> have the potential
to address the expertise gap. As currently utilized, a pro bono
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">website</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> functions. One is to list cases and projects
that will benefit from private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> involvement. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is
to provide resources relevant to the cases and projects listed on
the website by making available <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> (such as forms and
briefing information) relevant to the cases listed on the website
and electronic access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who will assist the pro bono
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> function acts as a forum for finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>
for such activities as consulting on cases, handling economic
development transactions or working on intake systems. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
website function supports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> who are uncomfortable in a new
area of law and need guidance and direction.


Special Communities
LSC administers the grant for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Consortium Pro Bono</ENAMEX>
Program to make available high quality free legal assistance to
litigants before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims</ENAMEX> who
cannot afford the cost of representation. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> through the
competitive grants process, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> awarded a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year</TIMEX> grant to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Pro Bono Consortium</ENAMEX>, a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that assists
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> with their appeals process by linking them with pro bono
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG Initiatives</ENAMEX>
In each of the statewide websites supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> funds, there
is or soon will be a section committed to pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> is modeled after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ProBono</ENAMEX>.Net in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, a popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX> that contains substantial information on areas of law
relevant to pro bono projects, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a calendar</TIMEX> for CLE events and forms
through which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> can pose questions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, among other
tools. Pro bono <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> are a valuable asset for low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have legal problems. We want to sustain and grow private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> engagement by giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> the necessary tools and
support. And website pro bono sections are essential to doing
so.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XII</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intake Enhancement</ENAMEX>
Efficient intake systems not only screen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> for eligibility
but also give advice, brief service and referral assistance to
those who cannot be fully represented. Used well, intake systems
offer the promise of increasing assistance to many who are not
currently served. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> were struck by the many innovative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> used across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, we took the steps to
encourage their growth and improvement through a program letter
outlining what we believe to be model intake practices. We also
added review of and feedback on intake systems to all of our
quality review visits, and, through our technology grants, we made
it possible for programs to improve their own systems using the
experiences of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Letter on Intake</ENAMEX>
Our Program Letter on the characteristics of a telephone intake,
advice and referral system sets out the attributes of a superb
system for grantees to both inform the field and create a set of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standards LSC</ENAMEX> can use during on-site visits and for evaluating
grant applications. Intrinsic to the development of the Program
Letter, was the input we solicited on exemplary systems from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> with special knowledge or experience
about the topic.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intake</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Critical Component of Quality Review</ENAMEX> Visits
Intake systems are examined during our on-site program quality
visits. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, recommendations and requirements issued in the
wake of our visits led several programs to substantially modify
their intake procedures. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> program was told to restructure its
capacity for telephone advice and brief service so that clients
would not have to personally come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for an intake
interview. We strongly encouraged another program to adopt
program-wide intake protocols that would make case handling
consistent among all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TIG Grants Enhancing Intake</ENAMEX>
Before a low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can receive appropriate legal
assistance, that individual has to gain access to legal services
system. LSC promotes the use of technology to remove barriers to
access by establishing seamless intake systems that cover an entire
state. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several 2002</TIMEX> TIG awards, now well underway, targeted intake
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> to the statewide toll free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> now
are not only routed to an intake <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> serving
their area, but can hear informative recordings on relevant legal
topics <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-four hours a day</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>.
Building on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s grant, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> award to Potomac
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aid Society</ENAMEX> (PLAS) allows the program to reach the area's
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">underserved Asian American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. The ASP database program will
enable the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian Pacific American Legal Resource Center</ENAMEX> (APALRC) to
conduct client intake at their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of mono-lingual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, and then transfer eligibility and case data over
the Internet to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLAS</ENAMEX> if the client needs brief legal advice, or to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSNV</ENAMEX> for extended representation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interpreters</ENAMEX> will be provided by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APALRC</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> award to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Justice Project</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">streamlines</ENAMEX> case referral from CLEAR (the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s telephone intake
program) to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s other legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. Instead of
printing out intake forms and faxing them to the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>,
who then must manually enter the data into their systems, intake
information will be transferred electronically from one system to
the other. The result is an extraordinary savings in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> time and
has become a model for other intake systems.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XIII</ENAMEX>. Promoting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development of Effective Legal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> also relied on a broader national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> and
collaborations with national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> to underline the centrality
of new and more effective strategies to expand access and
availability of legal services.



•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Programs Randi Youells</ENAMEX> tirelessly
promoted our message of vigorous and effective justice communities
that serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> across a given <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> no matter what cultural,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographic</ENAMEX> or linguistic barriers interfere with their access. She
traveled to meetings with local, regional and state grantees,
participated in access to justice conferences and responded to
international invitations to address legal aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Highpoints
of her peripatetic proselytizing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> were:



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Conference</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Legal Services</ENAMEX> 50th <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year Anniversary</TIMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>)


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southeast Project Directors Association Conference</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orleans</ENAMEX>)


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o NLADA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mid-Year</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Meetings</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> LSC-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Funded Programs Meeting</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>)


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Area Legal Services</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX>)


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> Access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Meeting</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference of State Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administrators</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>)


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ontario Legal Aid Speakers Series</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>)


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Legal Aid Group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>)


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o Bellow-Sacks Symposium</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Represented Litigants</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>)


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG Conference</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>)


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o Access</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meeting</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>)




•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> held a conference on building state justice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> for executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of state and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">territory</ENAMEX>-wide
recipient programs. Our goal was to focus executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> on
the fundamentals of planning for client-centered, comprehensive,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> statewide justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. We convened the executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> from newly created statewide LSC-funded programs and the
experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the more historical statewide programs to
share observations on challenges and opportunities created by state
planning. Thirty-one program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> attended, and every
statewide LSC-funded program but one was represented. Also
represented were our grantees in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX> and Virgin
Islands programs.



•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> held its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural Issues</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delivery Symposium</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Programs Randi Youells</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Luisa Mercado</ENAMEX> opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the three-day</TIMEX>
symposium by challenging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conferees</ENAMEX> to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> develop practices
and policies that guarantee high quality legal services to rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> - whether they are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> on
reservations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conferees</ENAMEX>' answers to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> questions (how to build
collaborative relationships in rural environments; how to balance
resources between urban and rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>; how to achieve
world-class delivery systems for rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>; and how to expand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> for rural delivery) led to a list of broad
recommendations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> and the legal services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, with
particular emphasis on the development of a national voice for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rural</ENAMEX> legal services.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Information Exchange</ENAMEX> (MIE)
to host "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Innovations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Legal Services</ENAMEX>," a workshop at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLADA Annual Conference</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> to showcase best practices in
the effective delivery of civil legal services to low-income
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. We highlighted qualitative improvements in current
structures along with innovative approaches to reaching
hard-to-reach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> traditionally overlooked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. These
exemplary practices also were posted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC Resource Library</ENAMEX>
Initiative website (LRI), ensuring easy and public access to
information about them.


•
Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> staff presentations at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Conference</ENAMEX> was the session highlighting several TIG
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> in final implementation stage. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> projects were
presented: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio Statewide Website</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ohiolegalservices</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>)
that became the national <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kaivo</ENAMEX> template, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> Domestic
Violence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ohiodvresources</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>), a website
containing document creation software and replete with information
specific to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of domestic violence. The presentation also
covered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>'s use of videoconferencing to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey</ENAMEX>'s voice over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IP</ENAMEX> (VOIP) technology, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>'s computer guide
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lowincome residents</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> responded to a request from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeanne Charn</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorr Legal Services Center</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law</ENAMEX>
School, to advise the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Center</ENAMEX> on their current technology systems.
The daylong meeting at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> looked at case management and
quality assessment issues, and concluded with hopes for future
partnerships between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX>.



•
Over and above the activities described above, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIG</ENAMEX> staff
made presentations at:



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law School</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellows-Sacks</ENAMEX> Legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinic</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA National Conference of Bar Presidents</ENAMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX> Techshow


<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Legal Aid Delegation</ENAMEX> sponsored by the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on United States-China Relations</ENAMEX>




•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> convened a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> seeking feedback
about the TIG program and on broader technology issues. Invited was
a representative sample of program grantees and technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>.
We wanted to learn about the TIG program's effectiveness to date,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> for improvement, and ways we could encourage grantees to
improve client services through emerging technologies.
Deliberations ranged widely and many topics were aired. The report,
summarizing the discussions of major issues and how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> is
responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>' recommendations, will issue in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XIV</ENAMEX>. Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Work Management and Supervision</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of best ways to obtain uniformly high quality services is to
ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantees</ENAMEX>' legal work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and supervision is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rigorous</ENAMEX> and effective. Below, we describe our efforts during
on-site visits and in the competition process to achieve this goal.
We also show how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> component of statewide websites
promotes effective representation by sharing legal resources and
expertise - generally a function of legal work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX>.

Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Work Management Reviews</ENAMEX> in Quality Visits
Legal work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and supervision systems are always on the
table when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> staff conduct an on-site program quality review. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, our reviews resulted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> recommending modifications in
several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX>' legal work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and supervision systems.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> program lacked an effective way to
monitor the quality of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>' written legal work, we gave
specific directions on how the program could establish a system to
ensure high quality written legal work. In another situation, we
noted that a program lacked an effective method to monitor the
professional growth of new and inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. Again, we made
specific suggestions on approaches to mentoring these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.

