
 
     		
 	
 		i haven't done any camping lately how about you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh not recently we we've done a little bit of car camping  uh since since i got married and did a little bit of backpacking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> but uh not recently
 	
 	
 		were these extended trips or just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well not real long maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three four days</TIMEX> at the most how about you
 	
 	
 		uh that's about what i've done but it goes back even further to my childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camping</ENAMEX> went out camping and and the purpose was not to camp the purpose was to fish
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there were no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> in in the wilds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
 		so if you wanted to go <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> you would uh and at certain lakes that were definitely off the beaten track you would do what you i think what you call car camping
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s there and and you may or may not sleep on a cot outside of it or inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or
 		but uh nothing too elaborate in the way of tents and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've actually even slept on the ground
 	
 	
 		yeah well i've done a little bit of that too um i guess i've kind of done the full range of camping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from backpacking</NUMEX> in the mountains for
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> at a time to the the car camping kind of thing
 	
 	
 		where did you do your backpacking
 	
 	
 		well i've done some down in um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> that area <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and then done some in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
 		and some out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana Colorado</ENAMEX>
 		so i've kind of gone around and done it number of places
 	
 	
 		but this was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years past</TIMEX> or yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		i used to work at um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camps um a lot when i was in high school and college and i worked at some summer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> where um
 		the emphasis there was on backpacking exclusively
 	
 	
 		around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Philmont</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		right um-hum you've been there
 	
 	
 		no i haven't no but every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> i've ever known has camped at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philmont</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah well it's a very popular place and i worked there  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three summers so</TIMEX>  got to know it pretty well
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess i don't know do you think it's it's as safe as it used to be to go camping
 	
 	
 		well probably the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> that i would have now is getting safe drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> um
 		cause a lot of times we'd just pull <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> out of a stream and um use that and i was never really big on using a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> purification and treatment um
 		and nowadays i think i'd be a little bit more cautious about that than i used to be
 	
 	
 		yeah when when i was in growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> if we went on a picnic or whatever it was always in the mountains we lived in the southwestern corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> so we could go to the mountains or the desert
 		just pick a place and if you were needed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> the you'd find a stream and drink right out of the stream
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when i left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> i would not have dreamed  drinking out of any stream that i saw there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i guess partly it depends on on how isolated the river is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh course i i mean even in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> you always had the possibility of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> or uh some other critter upstream  a ways from you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um what about crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp sites</ENAMEX> do you think that's a problem
 	
 	
 		well i suppose in some of the real big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and stuff that could be an issue
 		but generally i haven't ever found that to be a problem usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very friendly and
 		um cooperative all the way around so i've never deemed that as a threat to myself but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		been been fairly careful about not leaving tempting things out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campsite</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah it you hide your fishing gear and your camera and all that sort of stuff don't tempt people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and usually if i'm backpacking of course there i don't worry about it much at all because if
 		there's something there that they want  they'd have to haul it out a long ways so they usually would think twice about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who goes backpacking about twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's he's really uh hung up on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i've had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine that have made the trip down through there a couple of times they really enjoy it but
 		there's something about going down in a hole that  just um doesn't really relate that strongly to me i suppose i'll try it someday but i always like to climb mountains and get up where i can see something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i i think with the case like in the case of the canyon you see more from the rim than you would ever camping down inside of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah are there mountains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> for you to go out and climb or
 	
 	
 		well no it's more mostly just some rolling hills so there isn't really much
 		
 		
 	