
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well all right um i i guess i'll start um by mentioning that um being <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty four years old</TIMEX> i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX>
 		who's still alive at this point who was just recently placed in a nursing home after the death of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX>
 		and it was a real problem  in doing that because uh she has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she had no wish or desire to go into that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> and uh we were very concerned about uh
 		her long-term care my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> after he was found out he was going to go into a nursing home uh actually gave up the ghost more or less
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and passed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only only about a week</TIMEX> after that
 	
 	
 		well my um
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> is um
 		had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> and through the process we had to remove we tried to keep her at home at our we had to remove her from her home because she was getting paranoiac and tried to keep her at our home and
 		did that as long as we could but again the process is very difficult even
 		even you know i think that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did a good job at it when when they went through but it's not an easy thing when they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> but my other grandparents
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> signed up for a retirement
 		type thing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um</ENAMEX> already my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s much older than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> so
 		well no i guess it anyway my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> are much younger and um
 		they what they did is they sold their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and bought a house
 		figuratively speaking in this retirement complex and they live in that house
 		and there there there's minimal because they you know they bought it um they've kind of bought into the whole system and there's there's care given for the lawn and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and um as they get older more care can be given and there's some minimal fees that they'll always be paying but the basic fee for health care and all that is already taken care of
 		and when they get too old they can move into an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> instead it's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX> they have now
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		they can move into an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and then later nursing
 	
 	
 		we had
 		yeah we had up here when they got into uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> came over my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX> came over here she actually spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime</TIMEX> with us and we had to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> come in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because we simply we couldn't handle it she kind of she'd lost all bearings as to where she was and she would actually wander around uh we were afraid she would wander herself into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> and fall down the stairs or
 		uh you know it was incredible because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> had taken care of her and she demanded absolute <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hour</TIMEX> care she had to be watched she had to be cleaned
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		everything you know it was a demeaning process for my for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather great-grandfather</ENAMEX> we had never realized how much
 		um how bad she had deteriorated over the uh years i mean i she would forget my name and she would forget you know how to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> or how to take care of herself but we didn't realize the extent
 		until after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> had a bad stroke
 		and um um  we had her here and we had to take care of her and it even kind of drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> a little crazy
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what happened to my other my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> had died and she wanted to stay on and then she got <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> and it was a really hard thing for the whole family i'm much more appreciative of what my
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my other set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> has done and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have already um kind of like gone on a waiting list cause it's such a long thing because it preserves the dignity
 		of the you know the whole situation and it's a decision that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have made and it won't be a drain on our resources because it'll mean just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know sell selling their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and buying into that at the same time
 		and it's familiar
 	
 	
 		yeah my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> had found uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> was was was around during the depression so he had actually hidden a lot of money in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> over there
 		and of course you know the moment you go into a nursing home situation they take everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and it was it was terrible and very demeaning he didn't wanna lose the independence and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh that was the biggest problem because we didn't really catch it as early as you seem to have as far as you know planning you know of long-term
 	
 	
 		well we didn't catch it for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first grandmother</ENAMEX> my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> set of grandparents
 		but my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> had apparently it's like a retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and they knew a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who had done the same thing and when they got there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	