
 
     		
 	
 		what kind of pollution do you have in Flagstaff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we have the the usual automotive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> that and although it's not very visible you don't worry about that uh too much uh but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have a lot of wood smoke
 		uh here now i heat with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> so ah and i'm one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">polluters</ENAMEX> if you think that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood smoke</ENAMEX> is a is a source a source of pollution but there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> who
 		who think that uh
 		it's gone beyond the part of being part of the charm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to the point of being part of the pollution
 		and
 		and uh we're very close to the uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where air pollution is a very big issue
 		because on of pollution well it's debatable as to whether it's coming from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> area on the jet stream or whether it's coming from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Four Corners</ENAMEX> power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> up near Page <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but because it's a national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> that's a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a big issue</TIMEX> there uh  here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flagstaff</ENAMEX> actually uh it it's something that's unique to us the the biggest pollutant that we have in our air is cinder dust
 	
 	
 		i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		and that's because uh we're in a volcanic region
 		and we uh we have dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> uh in a lot of areas that are covered with with cinders but what they also cinders on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> in the winter time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in place of uh using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> like that that they might in the eastern part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and when the snow goes away and it dries up and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> drive over it we get a lot of cinder dust kicked up into the air and as of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the largest the largest quantity that's the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> that we have to to deal with here
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i'm sure that cinder dust is pretty unique  um in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area of course the the biggest issue of air pollution is just automobiles
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh we don't have much in the way of heavy industry i mean this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for electronics and banking and insurance and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		which are not typically bad polluters
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um
 		so i i'd think you'd have to blame most of it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		does does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> sits sit in any kind of uh uh i've been there but i don't remember if you sit in any kind of a trough that uh where you get temperature inversions that that capture air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 	
 	
 		we have we yes we occasionally have them not if they're not
 		not not too significant
 		but they do occasionally occasionally occur uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> of pollution for us is the dust and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> in uh west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> time we'll have parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm serious these enormous clouds
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> or dust or whatever you wanna call it
 	
 	
 		i laugh because i made the journey once from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and then continuing east uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Coast</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and uh i joked that uh all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Texas</ENAMEX> where the green rolling hills are and and when they finally beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> said fine you can have East <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but as long as long only as long as you take west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right i can understand that it's interesting though that you mentioned the uh wood stoves
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and but that was long enough ago that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't really heat that much with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> that was sort of a backward way of doing things if you will
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> heating with with particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pinon</ENAMEX> pine is really an issue
 	
 	
 		right and
 	
 	
 		not only from the pollution point of view but it takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many many years</TIMEX> to grow those trees
 	
 	
 		yes
 		and
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are chopping them down and heating their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> with them um
 		and it's it's such a distinctive smell when it burns i had forgotten it i mean i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it it's one of those smells you forget but then when you step outside your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you go oop yep somebody's burning pinon
 	
 	
 		here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flagstaff</ENAMEX> uh juniper is the the very distinctive smelling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> that you can smell in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood smoke uh</ENAMEX> and one of the issues here ah it which gets into forest management but has an impact on on air pollution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is that uh we're surrounded by the largest stand of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ponderosa</ENAMEX> pine in the world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't wanna burn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ponderosa</ENAMEX> pine they wanna burn <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oak</ENAMEX> which is very hard to find in this region or juniper because it's the more plentiful hardwood
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		and uh aspen uh it burns very cleanly but doesn't put out a lot of heat uh and and ponderosa
 		we also have pinon but uh it uh it it like ponderosa is very dirty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so they're not preferable woods and so here we have this great abundance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ponderosa</ENAMEX> pine
 		and the forest service is really saying we really wish that we could find a way to make it uh less of a
 		
 		
 	