
 
     		
 	
 		okay how you do you have kids
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i have a uh twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh they're just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers huh</ENAMEX> almost
 	
 	
 		right  so uh
 		so it's uh an interesting experience for us but we're kind of lucky uh in that regard because uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> we belong to has a a program that they've had for quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> that they call family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>
 		and that program is designed to uh
 		bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> together at least once a week on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		so we uh i guess i could say religiously
 		dedicate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> to doing just that  and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each each week</TIMEX> uh each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of us takes uh responsibility for that particular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		now now do you find that that that's uh
 		see how would i say that do you find that uh
 		that that it's well i mean it's it's
 	
 	
 		that it works
 	
 	
 		you could do that on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> do you find it
 		that it's easy to do that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> or is it
 	
 	
 		um-hum it because it turns out that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of all of the other <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> generally is the one that has the least number of other outside influences going on
 		so we find that it works out quite well and
 		uh we actually look forward to it because we get to spend so little time together otherwise
 		and uh as i said each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of us'll plan uh something for the particular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and it can be anything  because it is kind of a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> sponsored thing once in a while we'll have a a religious lesson maybe once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> that alternates amongst us but uh we might go to a movie or we might watch something here or play a game or just sit and read or uh
 		or whatever that individual feels that they would like to do
 		that's what we do
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds pretty good are do you find that that uh uh i guess with us
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i have uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		let's see uh a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a five year old a thirteen year old</TIMEX> uh excuse me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thirteen</ENAMEX> and seventeen
 		and uh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saturdays</ENAMEX> is a is it's difficult to get everybody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		organized and rounded up uh so they get the chores done and don't home in on the television immediately when they when they get up
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um actually and during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school nights</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh the we have a rule now that that uh because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are so easily distracted by the you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh  that uh no television on school <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hum</ENAMEX> and right not at all or until it's all done or uh
 	
 	
 		none at all
 	
 	
 		not at all that's that's a good but uh that's a good idea but
 	
 	
 		it's well they think it's draconian they think it's terrible you know
 	
 	
 		right yeah  hard to enforce i'm sure
 	
 	
 		uh well no it's not that hard to enforce it's just uh because if there's you know if it's
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i found out that if
 		if uh
 		if i let one of them watch pretty soon they'd all be watching
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's right including yourself yeah can't let yourself watch either that'll work
 	
 	
 		so i so i said that
 		
 
 		well no television and no ball games and the reason no ball games is because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>'ll stick their earphones on and and listen to ball games and try and do their piano believe it or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		we have another uh another advantage to is that uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of us are <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh is that that's that's a pretty good hobby isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah so we have a uh a hobby in common and we can talk to one another over the air too on uh on many occasions
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh matter of fact we're my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and i are watching the the shuttle right now uh they've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> on board the shuttle
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh so we been trying to make contact with them and it's uh it's headed towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> area right now yeah matter of fact it's uh it's over the horizon now
 	
 	
 		oh is that right that's very nice
 		well now that's kind of that's interesting to me because
 		a lot of uh you know in keeping on the uh the family thing here the reason that's interesting is because i've noticed that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		like the the parent i knew some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		there's a tendency and i i think a lot of it depends on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for like the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> to go in his in his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and shut the door
 	
 	
 		right in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham shack um</ENAMEX> hum
 	
 	
 		in a shack and shut the door and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was excluded
 	
 	
 		right and that's the last you ever see of him and uh
 	
 	
 		and that's
 	
 	
 		and uh he speaks a totally different language
 	
 	
 		and the fact that and i read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time that uh there was a high divorce rate in in uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Canaveral</ENAMEX> down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">there or Cape Kennedy</ENAMEX> or whatever you call it because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> would come home go in his study close the door and that was it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh just sort of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autocrat</ENAMEX> so the fact that you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that uh that do that is that's a credit to you what are
 	
 	
 		hum
 		
 
 	
 	
 		let's say i i guess my other question about uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		um
 		when it comes to when they're on their own
 		you know i mean if if you have to go if you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> go someplace
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what typically
 		
 		
 	