
 
     		
 	
 		play
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i uh consider myself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker</ENAMEX> how about you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well i'm into it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i'm not as good as i'd like to be but it's a
 	
 	
 		is anybody
 	
 	
 		no i don't think so um i started playing when i was in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> actually we lived really close to a par three <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and i'd go up there with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> after school <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		for uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i don't know after elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> all through junior high and stuff i didn't play because i think i just got so frustrated when i was little i'd my body wasn't you know physically developed and all that kind of stuff and then i'd started started started picking it up again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years back</TIMEX> and i've really been enjoying it
 	
 	
 		right
 		super yeah that's kind of the way i did it too actually i i played uh just a tiny bit when i was real young and then uh i went i got on to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in high school but wasn't very good still
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but and then quit for awhile and recently i picked it up like you say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a couple years ago</TIMEX> and uh i've been playing you know off and on when i can up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> it's not too easy to play in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> of course but
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i actually live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> so uh uh i'll be going back down there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and hopefully be picking it up a little more regularly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right the the one factor that really bothers me is the expense of playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was going to say
 	
 	
 		i mean it's a great game but i mean to play a really nice course you've got to have a really big wallet  i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's true all too many times
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		fortunately uh down where i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> there's some golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that are pretty reasonable if you know where to look
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um one of them is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> which is open to the public and that's pretty pretty good
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i uh attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> and it's the same way here they have a really nice championship style course that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is fairly reasonable to play on
 	
 	
 		can you get like a a student discount type of thing or
 	
 	
 		uh a little bit but not a whole lot i mean i you'd think you would but uh you don't so i
 	
 	
 		yeah what uh what uh what are <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> fees run there
 	
 	
 		uh well they range from anywhere from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> bucks for uh your basic city type course up to fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> dollars for a really really nice course
 	
 	
 		okay that's yeah that's about the same i guess as it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		uh-huh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a golf club over in my home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and i can play for free there and it's a pretty nice course
 	
 	
 		really oh that's super
 	
 	
 		yeah and i guess it well it's free for me  yeah somebody's paying but
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		not me
 	
 	
 		well that's the way to do it though that's the way to get in to some good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> without having to pay for it all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah definitely as far as watching golf i mean i can watch it on TV but it's kind of boring it's nice to see those who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> they have such good style that uh it's uh  it's pretty fun to watch
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		they need to get a new photography method because once the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> hits the ball and they got to try to follow the ball  that's that's a little difficult i mean it they do they do a generally okay job but like you said it's it's kind of boring actually
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		uh-huh what i really uh i uh had a chance they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGA</ENAMEX> tournament up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i was able to go and see one of the rounds of that and that was really fun
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah i bet that would be great
 	
 	
 		i mean you knew it yeah i never really thought it was would be that much fun to go to a big golf tournament and watch but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> it was it was something else just to follow those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> around and actually watch them play
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i've never been to a tournament uh you know looking at it on TV you you thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>  what a boring thing you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh that's that's wild though i'll have to see if i can't get a a chance to go
 	
 	
 		you got
 		i mean it's uh it's a lot more exciting than actually watching watching than watching it on TV and if you pick a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> and follow them around i mean it's just
 		watching them the whole time instead of like on TV you get to see them make a tee shot and then they go off to some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hole</ENAMEX> and they come back when they're putting but you know it's really something else
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		yeah i can imagine  what do you do for a living
 	
 	
 		uh i'm a student right now
 	
 	
 		oh you are which uh which university
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay all right great what are you going into
 	
 	
 		uh i don't really know i'm a math computer science major right now
 	
 	
 		okay definitely not golf right
 	
 	
 		no i wish it'd be nice to be a pro golfer i mean it seems like that that would be an okay life just to hang out and
 	
 	
 		yeah if you're good you can really rake in the bucks what was that what was that movie that they had out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there there was a movie about a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfer</ENAMEX> and i i can't remember it was on network TV <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		huh
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well you know you it seems like well you go to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> play maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one two</NUMEX> tournaments a month and come in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about tenth</NUMEX> you'd still be doing pretty well
 	
 	
 		that's right you got to take it easy   yeah that's a good thing
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah i guess when i get back i'm going to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> actually um and fortunately i've been able to to play some golf on a student budget which is real helpful you know but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's unfortunate you know you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> i guess you know it's it's like
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred</TIMEX> and fifty dollar minimum or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred dollar</NUMEX> minimum just to like to practice even insane
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and those fees to join a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> or whatever is just that is out of control
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean you'd really want to really be liking your golf
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess they have those uh driving ranges that are actually stacked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on top of each other
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those on TV that is pretty wild
 	
 	
 		they do yeah yeah i yeah i played uh uh eighteen holes with some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gainesville</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact
 		and it was really wild they were into it you know they kicked our butt all the way to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		
 		
 	