
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um anyway we're supposed talk about recycling basically what what your personal opinion is on it uh this is this is really for a speech research project they're doing
 		so um i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> is pretty good about recycling isn't it
 	
 	
 		well they just kicked it off down here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota county</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh they did
 	
 	
 		they had been doing it they started <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota City</ENAMEX> um you know which makes up a pretty small portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> actually and um they've got these i don't know what if you're familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota county</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		not quite no
 	
 	
 		they've got these on it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> wide program now and what they've done is they've broken everything down into garbage uh yard trash
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		plastic cans cans and glass
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and then uh paper
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		which in the paper it's just um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and corrugated cardboard is the only thing you're supposed to put in there no slicks um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 		oh that's that's good let me ask you this do they require you to presort it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay see that's something in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> they're really strict on in terms of you got to put everything in its own little bag and really presort it really
 		you know tightly but when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> it's like you could put almost anything in there and they'd just sort it out for you  it was really pretty good if you're lazy like i am so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah right well you know um i talked to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who um she's a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an  an acquaintance</NUMEX> of mine and and she's involved with uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh what is the name of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway</ENAMEX> but it's the other big vitamin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> Shaklee
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and um and and she's just Shaklee crazy you know because it's her business and everything and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and she asked we were talking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and and she asked me a couple of questions you know and she and and what she said that that generally the problems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have with being environmentally conscious is number one
 		they don't want it to change their lifestyle and and like you know especially make it anymore complicated or any extra work or anything which that's that's what recycling at home sorting does you know i mean it's a little extra work and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it can actually turn out to be a lot of extra work because what they do what they do here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota county</ENAMEX> is they've got
 	
 	
 		it can yeah
 	
 	
 		okay you put your garbage in a garbage bag and you set it out by the curb if you have yard trash you put your yard trash in some kind of container
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um or you can have bundles up to a certain weight and certain certain dimensions tie them up and put them by the curb well the plastic cans and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> they give you this little tub and it's about a foot and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> deep and it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and a half</NUMEX> foot wide and long
 	
 	
 		yeah you got to tie them up and everything and
 		right
 	
 	
 		this is a little container and they have another one the same size that one's red and then they have a blue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the same size for the paper goods
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so like
 		you know you would have to rinse out your pop cans otherwise you got <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX> and you know and and if you've got uh food containers or anything like that it's a big problem so not only do you
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		it is you know big hassle
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true i mean up here they give you one one of those containers and you put everything in it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's like if if you use a lot of stuff you it's like well you know let's say if you're a partying kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and you drink you know like a couple of twelve packs maybe over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's gonna be hard pressed to pressed to put all your recyclables in that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place you know so it's kind of a pain in the butt
 	
 	
 		this is true this is true
 	
 	
 		but um i don't know that's definitely one thing they could do to make it easier is to just you know have have those garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that make how every many make <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> bucks an hour have them do a little bit of the sorting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and and maybe come up with a better system make it a little more convenient
 		but i
 	
 	
 		yeah they've got these large garbage cans that you can rent from the waste management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> here um if you wanna have a nice garbage can you know and it's on wheels and it's big
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh you can actually rent those
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay that's interesting yeah up here the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> provides them kind of like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think in i think in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> they do but out here in the county you have to rent them
 	
 	
 		oh okay so
 	
 	
 		and they just add it on to your water bill or something
 	
 	
 		so where exactly are you in terms of of like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota</ENAMEX> are you north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east of Sarasota</ENAMEX> um-hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">east</ENAMEX> okay and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota</ENAMEX> is on the west coast
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay like south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay i'm
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about an hour about an hour</NUMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um  yeah well i i listen to this talk radio station down here and it's it's really they they i don't if you ever listen to talk radio but
 	
 	
 		um occasionally
 	
 	
 		those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> they just kind of get into
 		to stewing stewing stewing up trouble you know with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> and things like that but they get into some really good conversations sometimes you know and some of it sometimes it's serious and they have some good feedback and all that stuff and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i'm listening to that i kind of got an idea that i thought would be good was and this kind of fits into the uh the aid program the welfare program that's going on right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's like um
 		
 		
 	