
 
     		
 	
 		all right are you a music fan
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh by all means various types um my tastes range from
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX> and roll to classical
 		in fact about the only type of music that i really find offensive would be uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> western
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i take that back rap but i consider rap music to be an oxymoron
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess i i'll have to agree with you on rap uh that's uh it's not my that's not my style my uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		let's let's see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more question here do you uh do you play an instrument
 	
 	
 		yes i do i play two
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass guitar</ENAMEX> and kalimba
 	
 	
 		okay so that's
 	
 	
 		i used to play three which was the clarinet but i've that's since gone into disuse
 	
 	
 		well now there's there's multiple kinds of country western music uh
 		not that i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in that uh area but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well there was rockabilly in the fifties and that's what gave rise to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Perkins uh Jerry Lee Lewis uh Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> in the beginning
 	
 	
 		but there's
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that type of music i do appreciate
 		it had some it had it had the spark of creativity it was it was out there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh since then it's sort of fallen into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formula</ENAMEX> and i guess that's my thing is i have a problem with formula music
 	
 	
 		
 
 		now is is uh  i guess the other thing that that uh
 		there there is one kind of music that i don't know i wouldn't consider it country western but
 		but it is in a sense
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and that's bluegrass what about that
 	
 	
 		well i've only been exposed to that minimally and that's usually through occasional you know viewings of concerts of said type on public television
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		did you watch the the
 		did did you watch it for very long or was it just
 	
 	
 		oh it was something i had basically for background it was not uh obtrusive
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		it was something i could listen to and uh
 		and do my chores around the house
 	
 	
 		okay so you listen to it i i mean it's not
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		it not
 	
 	
 		it's not completely offensive
 	
 	
 		it's not offensive to you is what i'm
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's that's interesting my uh there for uh a long time uh
 		i i liked folk music but uh folk music is you know a a back in the seventies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so to speak <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> and seventies and then
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and uh then i became a a bluegrass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and i listened to it all the time and i've got lots of tapes of it and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i like but i'm kind of like you i i i mean in some ways i'm like you i i don't uh
 		uh i don't like  music that it's this uh  where you where you know what the next phrase is going to be because you know they have these dumb rhymes like a lot of i mean the where the how shall i say it the words are just so predictable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and although i do laugh at some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> western things they have this one uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> western
 		song about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> the perfect country western song and he said it had to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> and all that stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> and mama i don't know if you've heard that one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that that that's cute i would've liked to have heard that
 	
 	
 		and then he uh basically said okay so i went back to him and finally it what he came up with was the song about
 		uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> got hit by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and
 		and uh she or it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> she got out of jail she got hit by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and and things like that  so you know and anyways went to see her in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup truck</ENAMEX> and stuff like that so it was kind of creative i like that but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		yeah had to have some beer too or or some sort of alcoholic substance
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh
 		the thing one of the things that that the northwest i've been told has has got a lot of uh it's kind of the center of activity is uh
 		uh i don't know if you would call it new wave music or or uh new age music i is that it
 	
 	
 		new age yes
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Winston</ENAMEX> and which is he's a little bit uh
 		uh well he's kind of the recognized  uh i don't know if he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of it but
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windham Hill</ENAMEX> stuff it's it's
 	
 	
 		but they
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windham Hill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh new age classical so to speak
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well what i what i often uh call air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pudding</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		now they have some of that uh uh some of it's very interesting and other and and others uh is
 		how shall i say it it's very predictable now that's interesting you'd say the air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pudding</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would call it yuppie music
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i only use it when i'm studying and that's the extent of it it's just it's good background filter stuff
 		and you know it what it is it's pleasant but it's not
 		talent in in my view it's not genius um when i really wish to get into
 		listening pleasure uh with something of that nature i put on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX> something that will evoke a response
 		something that almost reaches in and and
 		hits those proverbial heart strings
 	
 	
 		the i i can respond to that a little bit by uh i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX> and of course the some of the i mean what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 		
 	