
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		any uh child care situations or experiences
 	
 	
 		i i have had um i did a stint as a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> for awhile and
 		my circumstance dealt with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who were in school
 		and i thought that that was probably more difficult to deal with because finding someone who would fill those small time slots
 		early in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and after school what you were left with were uh high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> or boys
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh never mind that they had all those noble
 		uh qualities like you know you know the same philosophy of raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that you did you were probably lucky to get anybody because you weren't paying them very much and uh it was just a short period of time so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		indeed yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it was really kind of someone who would sit and watch TV with them it it wasn't the kind of thing that you would get involved in if you had small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 		you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> raising thoughts in mind it was kind of a temporary
 		um babysitting kind of thing have you dealt with that
 	
 	
 		yeah right well i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the oldest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and the youngest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and we have actually a live in child care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> here
 		that we you know a nanny that lives here and that makes it very easy for us
 	
 	
 		oh are you pleased with the situation
 	
 	
 		yeah we've had um we're on our um <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our third our second our our second</TIMEX> long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you know it's been  just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we've had
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and prior to that we had you know to take child care we took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to somebody else's home and that worked out okay but it wasn't that great
 	
 	
 		it wasn't convenient
 	
 	
 		well we you know it was just
 		it was partly the convenience and partly you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that took care of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> also had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of their own and  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> were a little hectic you know how it sometimes is
 	
 	
 		hm i understand from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have live in help au pairs and and you know just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live with them that very often you end up involved in their personal problems and
 		they're taking care of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you're taking care of them do you find that
 	
 	
 		oh yes definitely without a doubt i'm  you know it's like having a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
 		a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> just about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that's okay i mean you you know as long as as their problems don't get too far out of hand
 		well
 	
 	
 		you said you have a couple of changes do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get attached to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and then it's a problem to wean them off them
 	
 	
 		a little bit of a problem but you know that's just reality of it and you know you have to work with them and tell them ahead of time that somebody's leaving and somebody else is gonna be coming in
 		and help them adjust to the situation
 	
 	
 		how old are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh the youngest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and the oldest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and the middle one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and the after school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> situation is great it's really convenient to have
 		somebody whose job it is to make sure they're that they get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and and you know are taken care of properly
 	
 	
 		hm i imagine that is a luxury of sorts
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  it it's expensive it'll it'll probably have to change when they get
 		you know all old enough to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> have to use some after school service our local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> has something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> have you ever discussed with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> how you want your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> raised what your philosophies are
 	
 	
 		but it
 		
 
 		well yeah to a certain extent um
 		i guess you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> does more of that sort of i mean she
 		she and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> have intense discussions about that and i suppose i'm
 		sort of a slug for not getting more involved but that's the way it is
 	
 	
 		you just appreciate the situation oh
 	
 	
 		oh it works out pretty well i think it's a good plan um i think it's kind of disgraceful that it's so hard for so many people
 	
 	
 		well i you know i think this the thing is um your situation is what i would call ideal
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but it's probably taking both you working you know you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> working to afford this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> isn't that so
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 		oh no doubt if one of us got laid off she'd be gone in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two seconds</TIMEX> i'm afraid i'm or have to
 	
 	
 		right when i was home by myself and i had a uh an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six year old</TIMEX> um
 		there aren't that many choices and that's the scary part you're just happy to get someone
 		you know you really are in such desperate need and if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s sick there's the panic it's like i can't stay home what do i do
 		and you know you import grandma from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to come over it was an emergency you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas vacation</TIMEX> comes around and then you've got to fill in that block of time
 	
 	
 		oh we've got those situations and you know we've got to deal with that kind of stuff but
 		but it's absolutely you know situation like ours you know where we could make enough money to cover it properly
 		you know both we both work and then we pay the pay the nanny and we pay the compensation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> compensation insurance and we pay the the withholding taxes we
 		
 		
 	