
 
     		
 	
 		the best to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for voting
 	
 	
 		well i think that uh
 		i guess i just
 		everybody knows that education is is important but i guess the main thing is there's some things you just don't care about
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so if you don't care about them you don't vote for them right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the biggest stumbling block is at first getting registered
 	
 	
 		yeah although although uh that's there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that'll do that for you that
 		i just thought of something now that that made a big difference to me and uh come to think of it it's got to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Brown</ENAMEX> and that's when i was in i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and when he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> there
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that he did was he sent out a booklet and the booklet was
 		uh here are the issues here's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> here's the cons here's the pro rebuttal to the cons and here's the con rebuttal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> by the time i got through reading that article by the time i got through reading that booklet i knew exactly what the issues were
 	
 	
 		isn't that what you have now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> you have the booklets
 	
 	
 		well we had a little booklet and it says here's the issues
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and each uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or whatever
 		against or for the proposition or
 	
 	
 		but for fifty bucks you can or whatever it is fifty or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred or five hundred</NUMEX> or something like that you can put in a statement for or against
 		but the nice thing about this other thing was that
 		and
 		was that you have uh
 		like i say you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well it's going to uh it's gonna reduce taxes and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say yeah it'll reduce taxes but at the expense of something else and so it was how shall i say it it was kind of focused pros and the cons and then the rebuttal
 		and so i got to see both sides whereas in the current booklet it just says here's
 		uh if somebody thinks it's a good idea he tells me but you know it's are you uh are you involved in software
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		are you an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> or or involved in software at all
 	
 	
 		oh well that yeah
 	
 	
 		okay well one of the things about a lot of programs is they tell you what they do but they don't tell you what they don't do
 		and the only way you know what i mean they say oh look this is great this this slices slices <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> but they don't tell you that  that it also mashes it at the same time and uh so that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i i understand to giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons and being informed but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i thinking also uh you can you should have voter registration by phone things like that
 	
 	
 		well out here they do it by uh mail you can do it by mail that
 	
 	
 		yeah well you you know a lot of places do it by mail but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't but you know get to the step of putting it into the mail you know and uh
 		if you can do it from the phone and pick it up at anytime <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours a day</TIMEX> and do it that's that'll make
 	
 	
 		well the problem with that i think is fraud
 		we haven't been around voter fraud uh too much but
 	
 	
 		well
 		well actually there's there are ways i mean if they can get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> identity verification and those kind of technologies out there it would help um
 		you know in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">verifying</ENAMEX> who they are and what they're saying and and uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could uh use that you know
 	
 	
 		or the other option i guess is to i mean why do you even have to do it over the phone why couldn't you just walk up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> and and uh register right there and then they have with uh everything hooked up by the computer you could say okay you've already voted
 	
 	
 		where do you live yeah
 		and all that stuff yeah they don't do that which is a problem and uh
 		i don't know i think um that or you can also the problem is also oh motivating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do it seeing that their voting has an impact on the process and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> frankly don't see
 		any connection with what they they vote and what happens so they very frustrated and they don't do anything so there's learned helplessness type of you know no matter what i do it's not gonna help so why bother
 	
 	
 		that's that's certainly true too
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		there's uh the other side of the coin is that uh in the educational side
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> does a wonderful job right about now at putting articles in the paper about uh motivating motivating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to turn in their taxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i don't think the
 		that very many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> try to motivate you to to vote
 	
 	
 		um-hum well they should i you know what i think also they should do is build in the process the election process
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		is not just vote getting i mean to get those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people candidates</ENAMEX> saying that not that their votes aren't any good unless they also motivate so many percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> to vote they could be identified by them
 	
 	
 		oh i see what you're saying
 	
 	
 		so put it in the political process that that you know not only you have to get petitions in order to get on the ballot
 		but you have to attract you know you have to attract so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just to come to vote they don't have to vote for you but they have to come to the polls and actually vote
 		you know those something built in to the system to motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to bring them into the process and especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wanna hold office i mean that's what
 		
 		
 	