
  
    
      
        
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Antihypertensive and Lipid Lowering Treatment to</ENAMEX>
        Prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heart Attack Trial</ENAMEX> (ALLHAT) is a randomized,
        two-component clinical trial sponsored by the National
        Heart, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lung</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blood Institute</ENAMEX> (NHLBI). A double-blind,
        active-controlled hypertension component is designed to
        compare the rate of fatal coronary <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX> (CHD) or
        nonfatal myocardial infarction (MI) (the primary endpoint)
        in high-risk hypertensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 55 years</TIMEX> or
        older, between those randomized to treatment initiated with
        a diuretic (chlorthalidone) and treatment initiated with
        each of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antihypertensive drugs</ENAMEX>: a
        calcium-channel blocker (amlodipine), an
        or an alpha-adrenergic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blocker</ENAMEX> (doxazosin). An open-label
        lipid-lowering component is designed to determine if
        lowering LDL <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> with pravastatin compared to
        "usual care" reduces all-cause mortality in a subset of
        moderately hypercholesterolemic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Randomization</ENAMEX> to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> component began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February, 1994</TIMEX>, and
        continued through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January, 1998</TIMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42,418</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
        recruited at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">623</NUMEX> clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US Virgin Islands</ENAMEX>.
        Randomization of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,355</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> into the lipid trial
        ended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31, 1998</TIMEX>. Follow-up on all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> continued
        through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March, 2002</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] .
        Following independent reviews by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safety</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monitoring Board</ENAMEX> (DSMB) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 6, 2000</TIMEX>, and by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoc Committee</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 21, 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the
        recommendation to discontinue the doxazosin treatment arm
        of the antihypertensive trial. This recommendation was
        based on the low probability of doxazosin showing benefit
        over chlorthalidone for the primary endpoint, as well as
        the significantly increased occurrence of the secondary
        endpoint, combined cardiovascular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> (CVD)
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">encompassing CHD</ENAMEX> deaths, nonfatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, coronary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revascularization</ENAMEX> procedures [coronary artery bypass graft
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTCA/stent</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">angina</ENAMEX> [hospitalized or treated as an
        outpatient], <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart failure [HF</ENAMEX>/treated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> or
        as an outpatient], and peripheral arterial disease
        [in-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> or outpatient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revascularization</ENAMEX>]) in the
        doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RR 1.25</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.17</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.33</NUMEX>; 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .001</NUMEX>), with a doubling of risk
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> (fatal, hospitalized and treated but nonhospitalized)
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RR 2.04</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.79</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.32</NUMEX>; 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .001</NUMEX>). When only fatal and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospitalized HF</ENAMEX> were analyzed, the large difference
        remained (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RR 1.83</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.58</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.13</NUMEX>; 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .001</NUMEX>). The findings and
        operational aspects of stopping the doxazosin arm of the
        study have been previously described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4</NUMEX> ] .
        The observed increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> in the doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as
        compared to the chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> led to several
        additional analyses aimed toward validation of the
        diagnoses, with a focus on hospitalized and fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>. The
        purposes of these analyses were: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) to evaluate the reality
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> cases, i.e. whether diagnosis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and
        clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> were what might be expected, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) to
        compare these features between the two treatment
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design</ENAMEX>
          The rationale and design of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX> are described in
          detail elsewhere [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Briefly, those eligible for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">randomization</ENAMEX> had systolic blood pressure (SBP) of at
          least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> mm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX> and/or diastolic blood pressure of at
          least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> mm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX>, or took <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>, and
          had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> other risk factor for CHD events. Risk
          factors included previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, left ventricular
          hypertrophy by electrocardiogram or echocardiogram,
          history of type 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, current cigarette smoking,
          and low high-density lipoprotein (HDL) level.
          The primary endpoint of the blood pressure (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX>) trial
          is the composite of nonfatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> and fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
          protocol-defined secondary clinical outcomes are
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-cause mortality, combined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> death,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonfatal MI</ENAMEX>, coronary revascularization procedures and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hospitalized angina</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, and combined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVD</ENAMEX> (including
          CHD death, nonfatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, coronary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revascularization</ENAMEX> procedures, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">angina</ENAMEX> treated in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> or as an outpatient, lower extremity peripheral
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arterial disease</ENAMEX> treated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> or with
          outpatient revascularization, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, fatal or treated in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> or as an outpatient).
          The validation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HF</ENAMEX> diagnosis entailed answering
          several questions:
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Did HF cases meet ALLHAT diagnostic criteria?
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Were baseline characteristics and medical
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> for HF cases as expected and similar across
          the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>?
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Were prevalence and severity of systolic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dysfunction</ENAMEX> as expected and similar across drug
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>?
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Were case-fatality rates as expected and similar
          across drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>?
          Unless otherwise specified, all data for these
          analyses were collected as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart Failure Diagnosis</ENAMEX>
          At each follow-up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> visit the occurrence of study
          clinical events was assessed, and, if identified by the
          clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>, reported on an endpoint form. For
          each event involving hospitalization, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
          discharge summary or expiration summary was to be
          submitted, and for each death a death certificate was
          required. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endpoint</ENAMEX> forms and supporting documentation
          were reviewed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">ALLHAT Clinical Trials Center</ENAMEX> (CTC)
          for accuracy and appropriateness. When a discrepancy or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambiguity</ENAMEX> was found, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> sent a written query to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Principal Investigator</ENAMEX>, who retained the final word
          concerning the diagnosis or cause of death. A random <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          sample of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfatal MIs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX> deaths was
          selected for blinded quality control evaluation by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT Endpoints Subcommittee</ENAMEX>; for these cases additional
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">documentation</ENAMEX> was requested.
          No such routine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endpoints Subcommittee</ENAMEX> quality control
          was initially planned for reported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>. However, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> was subsequently called upon to evaluate a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> sample of reported fatal and hospitalized nonfatal
          HF events. As this occurred prior to the termination of
          the doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, neither the chair nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> was informed of the major reason for
          this review, namely, the trend toward a higher HF event
          rate in the doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> compared to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chlorthalidone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> was told that the
          review was undertaken at the request of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSMB</ENAMEX> to
          address the reliability and validity of reported HF
          events. This evaluation consisted of fifty events, evenly
          distributed across the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, reported as
          fatal or hospitalized nonfatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> and with
          protocol-required documentation (discharge summary for
          hospitalized events, death certificates for deaths).
          Additional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> was not requested, since this would
          have posed an undue burden on the clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> staff and
          would have risked raising questions about emerging
          differences among treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX> definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, used previously in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systolic Hypertension</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Elderly</ENAMEX> Program (SHEP) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ]
          , includes "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with clear-cut signs or symptoms of
          left or right ventricular dysfunction that cannot be
          attributed to other causes..." The diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> must
          include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> stated symptoms [paroxysmal
          nocturnal dyspnea, dyspnea at rest, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Heart</ENAMEX>
          Classification functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> (for definition see
          Additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Item 1</ENAMEX>), or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">orthopnea</ENAMEX>], and one
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> stated signs (rales, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ or greater ankle edema,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tachycardia</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> beats/minute or more after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> at rest, cardiomegaly by chest x-ray, chest x-ray
          characteristic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, S 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> gallop, or jugular venous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distention</ENAMEX>). Since lower extremity edema or exertional
          dyspnea may be due to non-cardiac causes, the presence of
          either of these alone, without other indications of heart
          failure, is not sufficient for a diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>. Study
          guidelines caution against a hasty <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HF</ENAMEX> diagnosis in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with severe pulmonary <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, including chronic
          obstructive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pulmonary disease</ENAMEX> (COPD), <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX>, or other
          severe, documented lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baseline Characteristics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical</ENAMEX>
          Management
          Baseline characteristics of chlorthalidone and
          doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were compared. These analyses were
          stratified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> outcome: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) fatal and hospitalized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>;
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) treated, non-hospitalized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>; and, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) no HF.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-HF</ENAMEX> event medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> may provide
          additional evidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>' confidence in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> diagnosis. The post-event use of open-label diuretics,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACE-inhibitors</ENAMEX>, and beta-blockers, i.e., accepted
          treatments for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7 8 9</NUMEX> ] , was compared between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doxazosin</ENAMEX> and chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, as was the
          proportion in each group of those who remained on
          assigned blinded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> after the event. (For study
          guidelines regarding the use and reporting of open-label
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">medicines</ENAMEX> of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> as the blinded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, see
          Additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>, Items <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX>.)
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ejection Fraction Review</ENAMEX>
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> plus non-medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> reviewed in a
          blinded fashion 361 hospitalized HF events (representing
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">278</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>) for ejection fraction data: looking for
          whether an ejection fraction was measured, the method
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">utilized</ENAMEX>, and the measurement. Results, tabulated by
          randomization <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, reflected data that had been
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">collected</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to July</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the time of the review.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Case-Fatality Rates and Causes of Death</ENAMEX>
          As a measure of the diagnostic validity and severity
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> and comparability between drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>-from-event-to-death analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with
          hospitalized or treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> were compared between the two
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Causes of death of such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were also
          compared in the doxazosin and chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analyses</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were analyzed according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>'
          randomization assignments and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> outcome status,
          regardless of subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication adherence</ENAMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplan-Meier</ENAMEX> method was utilized in calculating
          cumulative event rates. Descriptive statistics by
          treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were presented for baseline
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characteristics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> ascertainment, ejection fractions and
          use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HF medications</ENAMEX>. Comparability of baseline
          characteristics of the treatment and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> outcome groups
          was ascertained by the χ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2test</ENAMEX> for categorical variables
          and standard normal (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">z</ENAMEX>) test for continuous
          variables.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart Failure Diagnostic Criteria</ENAMEX>
          The blinded review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endpoints Subcommittee</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          fatal or hospitalized HF events from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> groups
          determined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX>) to have incomplete data for a
          definitive review. Of the remaining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39, 33</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX>) were
          confirmed to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>. For both
          the chlorthalidone and doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, the diagnosis of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> was confirmed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18/20</NUMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baseline Characteristics</ENAMEX>
          Baseline characteristics for the doxazosin and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chlorthalidone</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, stratified for HF
          status, are described in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>.
          Baseline characteristics of doxazosin and
          chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with subsequent hospitalized
          or fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> were compared. Doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with
          hospitalized or fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> had a higher baseline SBP than
          the chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">150.1</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">147.8</NUMEX> mm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX> at
          the randomization visit). More doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> had
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LVH</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.3%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20.5%</NUMEX> of chlorthalidone
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>); slightly more chlorthalidone than
          doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LVH</ENAMEX> by echocardiogram. Several
          eligibility risk factors, including previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIs</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>, coronary revascularization procedures, other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease</ENAMEX> (ASCVD), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ST</ENAMEX>-T
          wave changes, were reported more often in chlorthalidone
          than in doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, though the differences
          were not significant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chlorthalidone</ENAMEX> and doxazosin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with hospitalized or fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> had similar
          pre-trial antihypertensive treatment durations. None of
          these differences was significant at 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.05</NUMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> events displayed higher rates of
          most cardiovascular risk factors compared to those
          without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> events. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately 35-36%</NUMEX> of chlorthalidone
          and doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with fatal or hospitalized HF
          had reported prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> as baseline eligibility
          risk factors, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22-23%</NUMEX> of those without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .001</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> with
          hospitalized/fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> had significantly higher rates of
          pre-randomization coronary artery bypass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grafts</ENAMEX> (CABGs)
          and coronary angioplasties (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19-23%</NUMEX> of those with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> vs.
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX> of those without; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .001</NUMEX>) and other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease</ENAMEX> (ASCVD) (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29-33%</NUMEX> of
          those with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23-25%</NUMEX> of those without; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .001</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Diabetes</ENAMEX> as a
          baseline risk factor occurred more frequently in those
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47-48%</NUMEX> in those with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35-36%</NUMEX> in those without
          ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .001</NUMEX>). Left ventricular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypertrophy</ENAMEX> (LVH) by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX> was a risk factor in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> of
          those who later developed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HF</ENAMEX>, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16%</NUMEX> of those
          in each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> who did not develop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .001</NUMEX>).
          Baseline pulse pressure (PP) showed some variation
          between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> who did and did not develop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>. For
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with subsequent hospitalization or death
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67 and 68</NUMEX> mm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX> for the chlorthalidone
          and doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, respectively. Treated,
          non-hospitalized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> showed a lower mean
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">baseline PP</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">65</NUMEX> (chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX> mm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX>
          (doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>), and an even lower mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP</ENAMEX> in those
          without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> mm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2presents</ENAMEX> post-event pharmacologic treatment of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> and antihypertensive treatment of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>. Following hospitalization for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">83/232</NUMEX>) of chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">126/281</NUMEX>) of doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> remained on their
          blinded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>. Percentages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> on
          open-label diuretics and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACE-inhibitors</ENAMEX> were similar
          following the event: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">135/232</NUMEX>) of chlorthalidone
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">180/281</NUMEX>) of doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
          were prescribed open-label diuretics; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">90/232</NUMEX>) of
          chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">114/281</NUMEX>) of
          doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were prescribed open-label
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACE-inhibitors</ENAMEX>. Beta-blockers were prescribed for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> of
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> following the event, which was actually
          somewhat less than for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> who did not develop
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Three-quarters</ENAMEX> of hospitalized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">169/232</NUMEX> in chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210/281</NUMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doxazosin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>) received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of the three
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">medications</ENAMEX> (diuretic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACE-inhibitor</ENAMEX>, or beta-blocker)
          post-hospitalization.
          Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> treated but not hospitalized for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">54/93</NUMEX>) of the chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64%</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">93/145</NUMEX>) of the doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> remained on their blinded
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>. Over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in each group were
          prescribed open-label diuretics and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 30%</NUMEX> received
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACE-inhibitors</ENAMEX>. Open-label beta-blocker use post-event
          occurred in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18/93</NUMEX>) of the chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">32/145</NUMEX>) of the doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, approximately the
          same frequency as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>. In both
          treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, a diuretic, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ACE</ENAMEX>-inhibitor or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beta-blocker</ENAMEX> was prescribed for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 75%</NUMEX> of these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">72/93</NUMEX> in chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119/145</NUMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doxazosin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ejection Fraction Review</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3displays</ENAMEX> the ejection fraction data. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About half</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">178/361</NUMEX>) of reviewed discharge summaries mentioned
          ejection fractions measured during hospitalization,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">116/169</NUMEX>) of which had quantitative
          measurements reported in the discharge summaries (data
          not given). Considering only the earliest ejection
          fraction information ascertained for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">29/46</NUMEX>) of the chlorthalidone and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">41/59</NUMEX>) of the
          doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> had ejection fractions at or below
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just under half</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">27/59</NUMEX>) of the ejection fractions
          reported in the doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were at or below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>,
          compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one third</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15/46</NUMEX>) in the chlorthalidone
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two-thirds</NUMEX> of ejection fractions were obtained by
          echocardiograms, though catheterizations accounted for a
          larger percentage of results in the doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> than
          in the chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24%</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Causes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death and 2-Year Case-Fatality</ENAMEX>
          Causes of death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with previous HF
          hospitalization were distributed similarly in the two
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, with slight variations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21.2%</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/52</NUMEX>) of the deaths among chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17.1%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12/70</NUMEX>) of the deaths among doxazosin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the deaths in each group
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">29/52</NUMEX> in the chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">43/70</NUMEX> in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doxazosin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>) were due to cardiovascular events.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> percent (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/52</NUMEX>) of deaths in the chlorthalidone
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> were attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6/70</NUMEX>) in
          the doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>).
          Case-fatality for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with hospitalized HF
          events showed no significant differences (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RR 0.96</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.67</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.38</NUMEX>, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.83</NUMEX>) between the two treatment
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the doxazosin
          treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> who had been previously hospitalized for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.1%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70/317</NUMEX>) subsequently died, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18.6%</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">52/280</NUMEX>) of those in the chlorthalidone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>).
          As previously reported, all-cause mortality did not
          significantly differ in the two treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (RR
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.03</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.90</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.15</NUMEX>, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.56</NUMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The finding of significantly increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> events in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doxazosin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> compared with the chlorthalidone group
        created a dilemma for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX>. Since the trial was not
        designed to focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, a component of a secondary
        endpoint, the validity of reported HF events became an
        issue. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, we have described several analyses to
        address this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.
        As previously reported, lost-to-follow-up and event
        documentation were similar in the two treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        ] . Steps employed to validate the HF outcome in these
        treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> confirmed the consistency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> event
        reporting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> had similar
        baseline characteristics when stratified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> status. The
        differences in eligibility risk factors between those
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> and those without is not surprising:
        larger percentages of those with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> had a history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABG</ENAMEX>, angioplasty, other atherosclerotic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiovascular disease</ENAMEX> (ASCVD), <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, low HDL levels
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX> abnormalities. Nonetheless, these eligibility
        factors were not substantially different between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chlorthalidone</ENAMEX> and doxazosin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>.
        Post-diagnosis pharmacologic management of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> is
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> measure of the strength of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>' confidence in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> diagnoses. Open-label diuretics, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACE-inhibitors</ENAMEX> and
        beta-blockers, all recognized treatments for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>, were
        prescribed similarly for the chlorthalidone and doxazosin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, suggesting similar assessment of these events in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALLHAT</ENAMEX> criteria for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> were equivalently met in the two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. While the sample (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>) of hospitalized or fatal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> reports reviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT Endpoints Subcommittee</ENAMEX>
        was limited in number and in adequacy of corroborating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">documentation</ENAMEX>, the review nonetheless showed adherence to
        study criteria for the majority (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX>) of the event reports.
        The sometimes-discrepant results between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>
        pertained more often to incomplete data than to rejection
        of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HF</ENAMEX> diagnosis.
        Clinical use of more objective measures, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noninvasive</ENAMEX> and/or invasive tools for the measurement of
        left ventricular function, offers a means of establishing
        and quantifying systolic failure in cases clinically
        suggestive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7 10</ENAMEX> ] . Among the ejection fractions
        reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX> events that were reviewed, the
        majority fell at or below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX>, indicating some degree of
        systolic dysfunction. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> is a clinical diagnosis
        that does not necessarily exclude those with intact left
        ventricular systolic function [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hypertension</ENAMEX> is a
        major risk factor for diastolic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as many as 25%</NUMEX> of
        asymptomatic hypertensives with left ventricular
        hypertrophy have diastolic dysfunction. Additionally, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with coronary artery disease may have some
        degree of diastolic dysfunction [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] .
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold increased relative risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doxazosin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> compared to the chlorthalidone group
        changed little when confined to hospitalized and fatal
        events. Further, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in both the doxazosin and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chlorthalidone</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> showed a rather high <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>
        case-fatality rate over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, as expected in HF
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 13 14</NUMEX> ] , further supporting the validity of
        the diagnoses in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
        hospitalized for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> who subsequently died, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> of the
        deaths in each drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were attributed to cardiovascular
        causes.
        Treatment group differences in mortality attributed to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> may take time to be recognized. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> are at
        risk for other competing causes of death. Accordingly, it
        may be too early to determine if a higher rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doxazosin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> translates into a higher overall mortality
        rate. A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-year</TIMEX> case-fatality rate with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> difference
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> incidence rate translates into a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.8%</NUMEX> potential
        difference in total mortality without any competing causes
        of death. With competing causes, the difference would be
        smaller and difficult to detect even in a trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX>'s
        size.
        The diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> is generally made on the basis of
        signs and symptoms that may overlap with those of other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cardiovascular</ENAMEX> and pulmonary pathologies. Moreover, the
        clinical picture may be further complicated for patients
        taking doxazosin, side effects of which (edema, dyspnea,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tachycardia</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] may be misinterpreted as
        manifestations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX>.
        The capture of events in a "large and simple trial" such
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX> has potential limitations. Built into a structure
        composed largely of community-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> is the
        assumption that their characterization of clinical events
        reflects diagnostic standards of the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,
        and, as such, meets study criteria. However, with its large
        number of endpoints, resources available to ALLHAT
        precluded more than modest confirmatory event
        documentation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources</ENAMEX> were allocated for additional
        documentation for quality control validation only for a
        sample of the primary endpoint (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX> and fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHD</ENAMEX>) and for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>. While all reported events are reviewed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTC</ENAMEX>,
        the sometimes incomplete supporting details in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">documentation</ENAMEX> may not allow for validation of all events
        according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX> criteria. Some discharge summaries and
        death certificates may lack sufficient descriptive
        information needed to confirm the clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">diagnoses</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> are unable to provide corroborating
        documentation for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX> event reports.
        Efforts to authenticate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HF</ENAMEX> events in the doxazosin
        and chlorthalidone treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> represented a desirable
        step in the examination of the increased rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HR</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doxazosin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. All methods employed provided confirmatory
        evidence that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HF</ENAMEX> diagnosis and the difference in
        HF rates noted between the doxazosin and chlorthalidone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were valid. Results of this exploratory
        investigation support the event ascertainment methods
        developed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX>, specifically for HF events. This
        validation exercise further illustrates the ability of
        large, simple trials to answer important public health
        questions requiring large sample sizes and to grapple with
        unexpected results in a responsible and meaningful
        manner.
      
      
        Competing Interests
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of this paper disclose their affiliations
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aventis</ENAMEX> (A), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AstraZeneca</ENAMEX> (AZ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biovail</ENAMEX> (BV), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bristol-Myers Squibb</ENAMEX> (BMS), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glaxo-SmithKline/SmithKline Beecham</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSK/SKB</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>
        Pharmaceuticals/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monarch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KM</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novartis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nu-Pharm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia/Upjohn</ENAMEX> (PHU), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfizer, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sankyo</ENAMEX> (SY), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Searle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solvay</ENAMEX> (SV), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Takeda</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>). These
        relate to personal or institutional<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-</ENAMEX>affiliated receipt of
        income in the areas of research grants, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> fees, or
        other compensation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMS</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M,P</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHU</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSK/SKB</ENAMEX>), WCC
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AZ</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMS</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M,P</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHU</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SV</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JTW</ENAMEX> (A,B,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMS</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N,P</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHHL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AZ</ENAMEX>,B,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMS</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP,P</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHU</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LJH</ENAMEX> (PHU); the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        report no competing interests.
      
      
        Additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Heart Classification</ENAMEX> functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>:
        "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac disease</ENAMEX> resulting in marked
        limitation of physical activity. They are comfortable at
        rest. Less than ordinary physical activity causes fatigue,
        palpitation, dyspnea, or anginal pain." <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1994 Revisions</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Classification of Functional Capacity and Objective</ENAMEX>
        Assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Diseases</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX>: AHA
        Medical/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific Statement</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT Manual of Operations</ENAMEX> provides for
        prescription of open-label <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> as
        the blinded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>, when a compelling indication
        exists, such that the total dose of the added open-label
        drug should not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/2</NUMEX> of the maximum dose as
        recommended in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sixth Report</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint National</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Detection, Evaluation and Treatment of High</ENAMEX>
        Blood Pressure (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNC VI</ENAMEX>). If a compelling reason requires a
        higher dose, it is permitted.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALLHAT</ENAMEX> follow-up form allows for reporting of
        open-label <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACE-inhibitors</ENAMEX> and diuretics; among
        beta-blockers, only atenolol is reported. The use of other
        beta-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blockers</ENAMEX> cannot be ascertained from the data.
      
    
  
