
  
    
      
        Background
        Engagement of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen receptors</ENAMEX> on lymphocytes leads to
        the rapid sequential activation of non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> tyrosine
        kinases, including well-studied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZAP-70/Syk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2</ENAMEX>]. Recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> have
        also been implicated as important components of signaling
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> and other lymphocyte cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
        (reviewed in [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3, 4, 5</ENAMEX>].) This subfamily includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk, Tec, Itk/Tsk/Emt, Bmx/Emt</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dsrc29</TIMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk/Txk</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3, 6, 7</ENAMEX>]. The importance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tec</ENAMEX> kinases in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> receptor signaling was first demonstrated by the
        observation that mutations in BTK result in the human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease X-linked</ENAMEX> agammaglobulinemia (XLA) and the murine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counterpart X-linked</ENAMEX> immunodeficiency ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xid</ENAMEX> ). These severe B cell
        immunodeficiencies are characterized by diminished numbers
        of mature B cells and reduced immunoglobulin levels
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with impaired PLC-γ activation and Ca
        ++mobilization in response to surface IgM stimulation
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sIgM</NUMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8, 9, 10, 11</ENAMEX>]. Btk kinase activity and tyrosine
        phosphorylation increase upon stimulation of sIgM as well
        as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-5</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL6 receptors</ENAMEX> in B cells, and upon
        crosslinking of the high affinity IgE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FcεRII</ENAMEX>) in
        mast cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 13, 14, 15</TIMEX>]. It is now clear that the
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tec</ENAMEX> kinases participate in similar signaling cascades
        in multiple cell-types. Itk, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinase that is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predominantly</ENAMEX> expressed in T cells, is tyrosine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylated</ENAMEX> and activated after stimulation of either
        the T cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CD28</NUMEX> in T cell lines, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FcεRII</ENAMEX> in mast cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 16, 17, 18</TIMEX>]. Recently, we have
        found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk/Txk</ENAMEX> can also be phosphorylated after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>
        engagement [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. Furthermore, we have found that combined
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutation of Rlk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itk</ENAMEX> leads to profound defects in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>
        signaling associated with impaired activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLC</ENAMEX>-γ [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>]. Such data suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> may
        function similarly in signaling pathways downstream from
        these cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen receptors</ENAMEX>.
        Several lines of evidence indicate that, in these
        signaling cascades, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tec</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> act downstream of
        Src kinases. Src kinases are activated within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> of
        sIgM stimulation in B cells, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> is activated within
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>]. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> have been found
        to phosphorylate and activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk, Itk, Tec</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-expressed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 19, 21, 22, 23</TIMEX>]. Phosphopeptide mapping
        and mutational analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> have identified Y551 in the
        activation loop of the kinase domain as the major
        Src-transphosphorylation site. Phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Y551</ENAMEX> and
        a putative autophosphorylation site <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Y223</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the SH3</TIMEX> domain
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 24</TIMEX>] are observed following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCR</ENAMEX> activation,
        suggesting that these tyrosine phosphorylations are
        functionally important for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> receptor signaling.
        Although physical binding of full length <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family
        kinases 
        in vivo has not been reported, 
        in vitro interactions have been
        demonstrated between proline-rich motifs in the
        amino-terminal sequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> homology (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SH</ENAMEX>) 3
        domains of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 26</TIMEX>].
        Recently, it has been found that the activation of Btk
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Itk by Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases is potentiated by and
        requires the activity of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Phosphoinositide 3-kinase</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PI3K</NUMEX>),
        the products of which interact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PH</ENAMEX> domains of Tec
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 28</TIMEX>]. This interaction helps localize Tec
        family kinases to the membrane where phosphorylation by Src
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> can occur. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> suggest that, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX>, this
        membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> specifically targets the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> to
        glycolipid enriched <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX>-insoluble membrane
        microdomains known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">RAFTs</ENAMEX>" and that both this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> and the activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX> requires the PH
        domain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>].
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rlk/TXK</ENAMEX> encodes a kinase expressed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells and mast cells that closely resembles <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk/Tec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinases</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 31, 32</TIMEX>]. However, in
        contrast to the other Tec family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> lacks a
        pleckstrin homology domain. Instead, we have found that the
        
        rlk gene encodes a distinctive
        palmitoylated cysteine-string motif near its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">amino-terminus.</ENAMEX> Furthermore, we have found that an internal
        translational start-site, downstream of the region encoding
        the cysteine-string motif, gives rise to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> isoform
        that lacks the palmitoylated cysteine string and that can
        be localized in the nucleus [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. Although these
        distinctive features suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> may have atypical
        functions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> shares with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> kinases the homologous
        proline-rich motif that binds the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SH3</NUMEX> domains of Src
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> and the tyrosines at equivalent sites in the SH3
        and kinase domains.
        We have recently shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> can be phosphorylated
        and activated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX>. However,
        consistent with the lack of a pleckstrin homology domain,
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> is independent of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PI3K</TIMEX> activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. To
        further characterize the mechanism of activation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk/Txk</ENAMEX>, we studied the nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>'s localization and
        interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases. We report here a
        physical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> both 
        in vitro and when co-expressed in
        293T cells. Similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itk</ENAMEX>, we find that a
        conserved tyrosine in the activation loop of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> kinase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">domain</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y420</TIMEX>, mediates specificity for transphosphorylation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases. This tyrosine is also
        critical for in vivo activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>, since mutation of
        Y420 to phenylalanine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y420F</NUMEX>) reduces phosphorylation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> upon co-expression with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> or after engagement of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, we have observed that the phosphorylation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> turnover, consistent with the
        increased turnover observed with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> signaling
        molecules following activation. In contrast, localization
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> does not appear to rely on tyrosine phosphorylation
        or kinase activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>. Instead, we find a constitutive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of a fraction of the full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> with a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent-insoluble RAFT</ENAMEX> fraction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> with the
        RAFT compartment does not depend on tyrosine
        phosphorylation, nor on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PI3K</TIMEX> activation, but rather on the
        presence of the cysteine string motif. Thus, despite
        lacking a pleckstrin homology domain, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> is localized in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>, is phosphorylated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases, and may
        transduce signals downstream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases during T
        cell activation.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk Interacts</ENAMEX> with Fyn
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk/Txk</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tec</ENAMEX> related kinase that is predominantly
          expressed in cells of the T cell lineage [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 31, 32</TIMEX>].
          We have recently demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> is phosphorylated
          following stimulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat T</ENAMEX> cell line by
          crosslinking of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD3ε</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. We have
          further observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> can be phosphorylated and
          activated by co-expression with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinase,
          Fyn, in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">PI3K</NUMEX>-independent fashion. In contrast,
          activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Itk by Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases is
          PI3K-dependent. To further characterize the mechanism of
          Rlk activation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases, we examined
          potential interactions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rlk with Src</ENAMEX> kinases both 
          in vitro and 
          in vivo .
          The proline-rich region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> has been found to bind
          to SH3 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">domains</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinses in vitro. To
          determine whether the amino-terminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk/Txk</ENAMEX> interacts
          with Src family <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SH3</NUMEX> domains 
          in vitro , we performed 
          in vitro filter binding analyses.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> fusions encoding the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rlk amino-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> and SH3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">domains</ENAMEX> or the amino-terminus alone (containing the
          cysteine string and proline-rich region) bound
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biotinylated GST</ENAMEX> fusions of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SH3</NUMEX> domains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn, Hck</ENAMEX>,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyn</ENAMEX>, but not those of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lck</ENAMEX>, despite the ability
          of these constructs to bind other proline rich sequences
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1Band data not shown) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 33</TIMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> fusion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> also failed to efficiently bind SH3 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">domains</ENAMEX> from
          other kinases, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abl, Csk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX>. A weaker but
          detectable binding to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SH3</NUMEX> domain of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Grb2</TIMEX>, however,
          was observed. These data agree both with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid
          experiments and 
          in vitro filter binding assays that
          have demonstrated specific binding of the proline-rich
          region near the amino-terminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BTK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tec</ENAMEX> to the SH3
          domains of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hck</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 26</TIMEX>].
          Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> is expressed in T cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyn</ENAMEX>
          are not, we pursued the connection between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and the T
          cell-specific isoform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p59 FynT</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-immunoprecipitation
          demonstrated an interaction between these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> in
          extracts of cells in which both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> were
          expressed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C). Anti-Rlk serum precipitated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> from
          lysates only when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> was expressed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C, lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>).
          Likewise, anti-Fyn serum could precipitate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> only when
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> were produced (data not shown). This
          interaction was not dependent on the activity of either
          kinase, as co-immunoprecipitation was observed with
          either wild-type (WT) or kinase-inactive versions of the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, both isoforms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> were also
          able to co-precipitate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
          Finally, we have not observed co-precipitation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">full-length Rlk</ENAMEX> with several other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> involved in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> signaling (unpublished observations).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> co-localizes with a portion of Fyn
          To further examine potential interactions between Rlk
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fyn</ENAMEX> we compared the subcellular distribution of Rlk
          to that of p59 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FynT</ENAMEX>. For these and subsequent analyses,
          we utilized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green Fluorescent Protein</ENAMEX> (GFP)-tagged
          versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>. We have previously demonstrated that
          these fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are kinase-active and exhibit
          localization patterns similar to those observed by
          indirect immunofluorescence for wild type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rlk</ENAMEX> .
          Furthermore, we have found that, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT Rlk</ENAMEX>, they
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-precipitate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX> (data not shown). However, unlike
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT Rlk, Rlk-GFP</ENAMEX> does not co-migrate with immunoglobulin
          heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. Since these GFP fusions behaved similarly to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wildtype Rlk</ENAMEX> in all known respects except for
          electrophoretic mobility, we used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GFP</ENAMEX> fusions of mutant
          and wild type versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> to facilitate studies of
          Rlk localization and activation.
          We co-transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rlk</ENAMEX>-GFP expressing
          constructs into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HeLa</ENAMEX> cells, and visualized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> with
          anti-Fyn serum and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>-red conjugated secondary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Examination of cells expressing both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> demonstrated that a portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX> co-localized
          with a portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> as indicated by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yellow staining</ENAMEX> in overlapping images (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center panel</ENAMEX>).
          Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> can reside in similar compartments
          within the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, further supporting a potential
          interaction between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> molecules.
        
        
          Fyn phosphorylates and activates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>: A Conserved
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyrosine</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y420</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Provides Specificity For</ENAMEX> Phosphorylation
          of Rlk By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src Kinases</ENAMEX>
          To further examine the consequences of the interaction
          between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Src Family</ENAMEX> kinases, we examined tyrosine
          phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rlk by Fyn</ENAMEX> using co-expression
          studies. As previously demonstrated, co-expression of
          kinase-active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk-GFP</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293T</NUMEX> cells led to a
          marked increase in the tyrosine phosphorylation and
          kinase activity of wild type <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk-GFP (Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A, lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3B</TIMEX>, lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX>). This was not observed in cells
          transfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">kinase-inactive Fyn</ENAMEX>, and the increase in
          kinase activity on enolase appeared to be due to Rlk
          rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX>, since we barely detect phosphorylation
          of enolase when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT Fyn</ENAMEX> is co-expressed with
          kinase-inactive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. Thus, the phosphorylation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> appears to cause an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rlk</ENAMEX> kinase
          activity.
          Like other Btk family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rlk</ENAMEX> contains a highly
          conserved tyrosine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y420</NUMEX>) within a consensus sequence for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> tyrosine kinases
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. This site corresponds to the location of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autophosphorylation</ENAMEX> site in the activation loop of
          Src-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>]. To determine whether this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tyrosine</ENAMEX> is required for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> activation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family
          kinases, we mutated it to phenylalanine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y420F</NUMEX>). In
          contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT Rlk-GFP</ENAMEX>, tyrosine phosphorylation and
          kinase activity of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">RlkY420F</NUMEX> mutant was not
          significantly increased by co-expression with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3A, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Band</ENAMEX> data not shown). These results suggest that Y420
          is a major site of phosphorylation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> and that
          phosphorylation at this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">site</ENAMEX> leads to activation of the
          Rlk kinase. Furthermore, since baseline tyrosine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> and kinase activity of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y420F</NUMEX> mutant
          is also lower than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3Band data not shown), it is
          possible that phosphorylation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">endogenous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family
          kinases may contribute to the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> in 293T
          cells, although we cannot exclude the possibility that
          this mutant lowers kinase activity for other reasons.
          The major autophosphorylation site in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Btk</ENAMEX> maps to Y223
          within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the SH3</TIMEX> domain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]; an analogous tyrosine is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conserved</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rlk</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y91</NUMEX>). Mutation of this tyrosine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y91F</NUMEX>)
          reduced tyrosine phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold when the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y91F</NUMEX> mutant was expressed alone or with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A). However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> still significantly enhanced
          the phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y91F</NUMEX>), consistent with use of
          an intact transphosphorylation site (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y420</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A). The
          
          in vitro kinase activity of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rlk-Y91F</ENAMEX> was also lower (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> that of wild type);
          however, the kinase activity was still augmented by the
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3C). These results suggest that
          tyrosine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX> may be required for optimal phosphorylation
          and kinase activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>, but is distinct from the
          major site phosphorylated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases.
          Finally, since the larger isoform of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> consistently
          exhibits higher levels of tyrosine phosphorylation (see
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A), we mutated the single tyrosine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y6</NUMEX>) not found
          on the shorter isoform. Mutation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y6</ENAMEX> did not greatly
          reduce the tyrosine phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>, either in the
          presence or absence of co-expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fyn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3D).
          Significantly, the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">isoform</ENAMEX> still exhibited a
          higher level of tyrosine phosphorylation than the shorter
          form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>. Thus, the increased tyrosine phosphorylation
          of the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">isoform</ENAMEX> cannot be attributed solely to a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> site present on the larger protein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Rlk localizes in RAFTs
          Since the relative increase in tyrosine
          phosphorylation of the larger form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> did not result
          solely from an additional site for tyrosine
          phosphorylation, it was possible that this increased
          phosphorylation of the longer isoform of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> may result
          from preferential localization close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX>. Like other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> modified by palmitoylation,
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX> is found localized in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>, a
          membrane microdomain fraction enriched in signaling
          molecules that can be isolated by sucrose gradient
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fractionation</ENAMEX>. To examine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> is also associated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>, we performed sucrose gradiant fractionation
          of lysates from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat</ENAMEX> lymphoma cell lines transfected
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk-GFP</ENAMEX>. Upon such fractionation, we observe the Src
          family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX> constitutively associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFT</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fraction</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A). In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLC</ENAMEX>-γ was not found in
          the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">RAFT fraction constitutively</TIMEX>, but a portion became
          inducibly associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX> upon activation. Similar
          to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX>, a portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> was also found constitutively
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>. Notably, this association
          consisted primarily of the larger form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> which
          contains the cysteine-string and is palmitoylated.
          Furthermore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX> only
          marginally increased upon stimulation through the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>.
          Upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> signaling, many molecules have been found to
          show markedly increased association with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>. Since we
          have found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> can be phosphorylated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family
          kinases leading to activation of its kinase, we evaluated
          whether phosphorylation could influence RAFT <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>.
          Neither mutation of a conserved lysine in the kinase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">domain</ENAMEX>, which rendered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> kinase inactive, nor mutation
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinase phosphorylation site, tyrosine
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">420</NUMEX>, prevented association with the RAFT fraction. Thus,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> and activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> does not appear to
          contribute to its association with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B).
          A key mechanism of targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX> is
          lipid modification. Since the long form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> is
          palmitoylated on its cysteine string motif and
          palmitoylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> can be associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>, we
          examined the localization of a mutant version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RlkCM</ENAMEX> in
          which the cysteine string is mutated, thereby preventing
          palmitoylation of the long form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>. The
          cysteine-string mutant demonstrated marked reduction in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFT association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B). Indeed, while a small amount
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> cysteine-string mutant was still found
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">RAFT fraction</TIMEX>, the amount of the long
          isoform of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RlkCM</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the RAFT fraction</TIMEX> was equivalent to
          that of the short isoform. This observation suggests that
          the cysteine-string may be a major mechanism of targeting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">full-length Rlk</ENAMEX> to lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RAFTs</ENAMEX>. However, the localization
          of a small portion of both the short and long isoforms of
          the cysteine string mutant to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX> suggests that other
          targeting mechanisms may also contribute to the
          localization of this kinase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>.
          Recent data suggests that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> can also be
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RAFTs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29, 35</TIMEX>]. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX>, this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> requires the PH domain and products of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PI3K</TIMEX>.
          For example, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat</ENAMEX> lymphoma cell line, which is
          deficient in the inositol phosphatase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX> is
          constitutively associated with the membrane [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>]. Since
          our RAFT analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RLK</ENAMEX> were performed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jurkat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>,
          we also examined the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PI3K</ENAMEX> inhibition on Rlk
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">localization</ENAMEX>. Treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat</ENAMEX> cells with Wortmannin
          had no effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rlk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4C).
          Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFT</ENAMEX> localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>, like its activation by
          Src family kinases, appears to be independent of the
          activity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PI3K</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Fyn alters the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> life of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> in the detergent
          soluble fraction of transfected cells
          In experiments with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>, we often observed a change in
          the relative ratio of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> isoforms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> when
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-expressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, activation of Jurkats
          appeared to be associated with a loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">non-RAFT fractions</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A). Since phosphorylation
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> did not seem to affect association with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>, we
          examined whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> altered other properties of the Rlk
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. To start to address this issue, we measured the
          effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> stability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>. Rlk was
          expressed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293T</NUMEX> cells, either in the absence or the
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fyn</ENAMEX>; the cells were labeled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">35S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">methionine</ENAMEX> and cysteine, then incubated for
          increasing times with unlabelled methionine and cysteine.
          When expressed alone, labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> appeared stable in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX>-soluble fraction for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90 minutes</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A, top
          panel). When co-expressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX>, however, Rlk
          disappeared from the soluble fraction at a significantly
          faster rate (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A, lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, half-life between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 minutes</TIMEX>). The change in half-life was particularly
          noticeable for the larger form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>. In the presence of
          kinase-inactive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX>, the half-life of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> was not
          altered, suggesting that the phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> is necessary for the decrease in half-life of Rlk
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B). Similarly, co-transfection of wild type Fyn
          with RlkY420F did not alter the half-life of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RlkY420F</ENAMEX> in
          the soluble fraction (data not shown), again arguing that
          phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> is required for this
          increased turnover in the soluble fraction.
          Since this analysis included only Rlk <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in the
          soluble fractions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent lysates</ENAMEX>, these results may
          represent changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> stability, or subcellular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">localization</ENAMEX> and detergent solubility, factors that all
          can contribute to changes in intracellular signaling. In
          particular, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> can be associated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detergent-insoluble RAFTs</ENAMEX>, it is possible that a change
          in subcellular localization or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> may
          contribute to the decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. To address
          these possibilities, we performed similar analyses after
          lysing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> under harsh detergent conditions (using <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>), then diluting the samples before performing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunoprecipitations</ENAMEX>. Consistent with our observation
          that the phosphorylation status of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> does not
          significantly contribute to its association with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>,
          we still observed a decreased half-life of Rlk
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-expressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> when lysed under these harsh
          conditions (data not shown), arguing that phosphorylation
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> specifically accelerates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> turnover.
        
        
          Rlk phosphorylation in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> engagement
          requires Tyrosine 420
          The ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases to activate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> and
          to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rlk protein</ENAMEX> turnover suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> may
          function downstream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases in T cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>) signaling. To determine the requirements
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> activation downstream from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>, we introduced
          constructs expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk-GFP</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rlk-GFPY420F</ENAMEX> into the
          Jurkat-Tag cell line. Stimulation of the cells with an
          antibody directed against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD3</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">OKT3</TIMEX>, increased tyrosine
          phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). However, phosphorylation
          of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y420F</NUMEX> mutant was markedly reduced relative to WT
          Rlk-GFP. These results suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> can be
          phosphorylated on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y420</TIMEX> in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> stimulation,
          supporting a role for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> downstream of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> kinases in
          signaling from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>, analogous to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX>'s role in
          signaling from sIgM.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        By several criteria, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> appears to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of tyrosine kinases, yet significant differences
        exist between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and the other kinases in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. To
        elucidate functional similarities and differences between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tec</ENAMEX> kinases in signaling from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX>, we investigated the interactions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> with Src
        family kinases. Our data suggest that such interactions
        occur and that the phosphorylation events leading to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation of Rlk</ENAMEX> are analogous to those required for the
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases. However, our data also suggest
        that the regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> has distinct properties.
        First, we have observed an 
        in vitro interaction of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amino-terminus of Rlk</ENAMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SH3</NUMEX> domains of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, we have demonstrated interactions between
        these molecules in cells co-expressing both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and the Src
        family kinase, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fyn</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> can be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunoprecipitated</ENAMEX> when co-expressed. Moreover,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-expression with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX>, as well as other Src family kinases
        (data not shown), leads to increased phosphorylation of Rlk
        and activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> kinase, in agreement with
        observations made with other Tec family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
        It has been proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> kinases activate Btk
        through phosphorylation of a tyrosine, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y551</TIMEX> in the
        activation loop of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX>, leading to increased kinase
        activity and autophosphorylation of a tyrosine in the SH3
        domain. These patterns of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> have been
        observed upon cross-linking of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgM</ENAMEX>, arguing that this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> is functional in the signal transduction from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 37, 38</TIMEX>]. Our mutational analysis of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> supports a similar mechanism for activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> by
        Src family kinases downstream of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>. Rlk kinase
        activity is increased by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinase-mediated
        phosphorylation of a conserved tyrosine, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y420</TIMEX>, equivalent
        to Y551 in the activation loop of the kinase domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX>.
        Mutation of this site causes a reduction in tyrosine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> and kinase activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>, which is not
        substantially enhanced upon co-expression with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> or upon
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> stimulation. Thus, this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Src</ENAMEX> kinase phosphorylation site
        appears to be important for activation after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>
        stimulation. Mutation of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> tyrosine, equivalent to
        the putative autophosphorylation site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX>, slightly
        reduces tyrosine phosphorylation and kinase activity of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>. However, phosphorylation and kinase activity of this
        mutant still can be enhanced after co-expression with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX>.
        Thus, despite its unique amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">terminus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> utilizes a
        transphosphorylation activation mechanism similar to other
        Btk family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
        Although our original SH3 domain binding experiments
        suggested a specific interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tec</ENAMEX> kinases and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src kinases Fyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hck</ENAMEX>, we have been able to
        observe both activation by and co-precipitation with other
        Src family kinases including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293T</NUMEX> cells
        (data not shown). Thus, in vivo, interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> may
        not be restricted to a particular subset of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX>. Indeed, we have found that mutation of the
        proline-rich region did not abolish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> co-precipitation
        with either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fyn</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lck</ENAMEX> (data not shown), suggesting that
        interactions between these kinases may not occur solely
        through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an SH3</TIMEX> mediated interaction, at least in the 293T
        expression system. Nonetheless, whether there is a specific
        connection between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> in T
        cells remains an interesting question. Recent data suggests
        that phosphorylation of the T cell adaptor molecule SLP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>
        occurs after stimulation of T cells with altered peptide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligands</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX>-dependent manner that is independent of
        the adaptor molecule <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39, 40</TIMEX>]. Notably, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> has also
        been found to be capable of phosphorylating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SLP-76</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>].
        It will be of interest to determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX>
        participates in this novel activation pathway.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> is phosphorylated similarly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itk</ENAMEX>,
        there are marked differences between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these two kinases</TIMEX>.
        Perhaps the most obvious of these differences is the lack
        of the pleckstrin homology domain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rlk</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> suggest that
        membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Itk and Btk</ENAMEX> requires the
        interaction of their PH domains with products of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PI3K</TIMEX>,
        thereby facilitating phosphorylation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 28</TIMEX>]. In contrast, we have recently demonstrated that
        PI3K <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> do not alter activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX>,
        suggesting that the requirements for activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> by
        Src family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> are distinct from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tec</ENAMEX> kinases.
        It is also of note that we can reproducibly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co-immunoprecipitate Rlk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX>, perhaps due to their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>, whereas we have been unable to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co-precipitate Itk</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-expressed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293T</NUMEX> cells (data not shown), again
        demonstrating distinct properties of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> protein
        compared to certain other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Btk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The
        combination of similar and distinct features is further
        supported by the observation that 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TXK</ENAMEX> can rescue phospholipase C-γ
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> in BTK deficient DT40 cells, but fails to rescue
        a defect in apoptosis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>].
        Interestingly, we also find that the full-length form of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> has a higher basal level of tyrosine phosphorylation
        and kinase activity than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX> when expressed in heterologous
        cells, consistent with potentially different localizations
        and upstream interactions (unpublished observations). The
        full-length isoform of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> also exhibits higher tyrosine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> and kinase activity than the short isoform.
        This differential phosphorylation does not appear to result
        solely from a distinct phosphorylation site on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">full-length Rlk</ENAMEX>, since mutation of the only additional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tyrosine</ENAMEX> found in the full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y6</NUMEX>) does not greatly
        reduce the phosphorylation or activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> when
        expressed either alone or in conjunction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX>. Instead,
        the increased phosphorylation may result in part from
        distinct properties of full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>. Indeed, we report
        here that the palmitoylated cysteine-string is responsible
        for the targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> to RAFTs: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX>-insoluble,
        glycolipid-enriched membrane microdomains that contain many
        signaling molecules, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases. Our data
        may provide the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> demonstration that a cysteine-string
        motif can lead to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> association with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>. Of note,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> have been found to be associated with lipid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX> upon activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29, 35</TIMEX>].
        However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX> requires its PH
        domain and is dependent on the products of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PI3K</TIMEX>. Indeed, in
        Jurkat cells, which are deficient in the inositol
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phophatase PTEN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX> is constitutively associated with the
        membrane unless the cells are treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of
        PI3K or transfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTEN</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>]. In contrast, we have
        found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> association with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>, like its activation
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases, is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">PI3K</NUMEX> independent. Thus, although
        Rlk, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Btk</ENAMEX>, is activated by phosphorylation by
        Src family kinases and can be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>, its
        requirements for this activation may be unique.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fyn</ENAMEX> also led to a rapid
        disappearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX> soluble fraction as
        measured by pulse-chase analysis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). This phenomenon
        could result from either a change in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> location to a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX>-insoluble fraction or increased turnover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX>.
        Activation of tyrosine kinases and other signal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">transduction</ENAMEX> molecules is associated both with changes in
        subcellular distribution and with changes in protein
        stability. For example, crosslinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T-cell</ENAMEX> receptor
        results in a transition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> to a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX>-insoluble fraction [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43, 44, 45</TIMEX>], as well as to
        increased turnover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> components [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>]. Nonetheless,
        the decreased half-life of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX>-soluble
        and insoluble fractions argues that activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rlk</ENAMEX> leads
        to increased degradation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, similar to
        that observed for other components of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, but
        not previously reported for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> kinases. The
        dependence of this increased turnover on phosphorylation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> suggests that a phosphotyrosine-dependent association
        with another molecule may be required for this process,
        reminiscent of the increased degradation of the PDGF
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Syk</ENAMEX> caused by association with the ring-finger
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein Cbl</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47, 48, 49</TIMEX>] or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lck</ENAMEX>-dependent degradation
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>].
        Recent evidence from gene-targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> suggests that
        Rlk may synergize with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX> in signaling from the T cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> to activate phospholipase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-γ</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. The
        similarity of the phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> family
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> to that which activates other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tec</ENAMEX> kinases suggests
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> also functions downstream of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> kinases in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> transduction pathways. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itk</ENAMEX>, may therefore
        function together in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> signaling events in a
        fashion similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> in BCR signaling. Recent data argue
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itk</ENAMEX> interacts directly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slp-76</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Grb2</ENAMEX> to
        participate in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT-nucleated T</ENAMEX> cell signaling complex
        involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLC</ENAMEX>-γ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">activation</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5, 29</ENAMEX>]. It will be of
        interest to examine the interactions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> with other
        components of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the potential in vitro
        binding of the amino-terminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SH3</NUMEX> domain of
        Grb2 hints of similar protein interactions. Thus, although
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> appears to be distinct among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tec</ENAMEX> kinases in the
        lack of a PH domain, the presence of a palmitoylated
        cysteine string and the existence of a shorter isoform that
        can localize to the nucleus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> may contribute to similar
        signaling pathways. Indeed, our data suggest that the
        cysteine string may serve as a surrogate to the PH domain
        for targeting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX>. It is also notable that recent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Btk</ENAMEX> can translocate to the nucleus upon B
        cell activation, similar to the nuclear translocation we
        have reported for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 51</TIMEX>]. Nonetheless, the PI3K
        independence of the activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> activation and its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAFTs</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> may also have
        distinct contributions to these signaling pathways.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Culture and Reagents</ENAMEX>
          293T and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HeLa</ENAMEX> cells were maintained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modified Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium (DMEM) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          fetal calf serum, penicillin, streptomycin, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glutamine</ENAMEX>. Jurkat cells expressing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SV40</NUMEX> large T antigen
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat Tag</ENAMEX>) were a generous gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crabtree</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>) and were maintained in RPMI <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX>
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal calf serum, penicillin,
          streptomycin, glutamine, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 μM 2-mercaptoethanol</NUMEX>.
          Anti-murine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> was previously described. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fyn</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">FYN3</NUMEX>)
          was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>,
          CA); anti-phosphotyrosine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">(4G10</ENAMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upstate</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnologies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Placid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Transfections
          Constructs were introduced into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293T</NUMEX> cells by calcium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX> transfection in medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 </NUMEX>M
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chloroquine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-5 μg</NUMEX> of each plasmid was
          used for each transfection (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 × 10 6cells</ENAMEX>); the cells
          were harvested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 to 36 hours later</TIMEX>. Transfections into
          HeLa cells were performed identically, without the
          addition of chloroquine. Jurkat Tag cell lines (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          7cells) were transfected by electroporation using a
          Biorad electroporator at 250 V and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">960 μF</NUMEX> or by square
          wave electroporation on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BTX</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">830</ENAMEX> using settings of 300 V
          and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 ms. 24 hours later</TIMEX>, cells were stimulated with
          OKT3, lysed and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rlk</ENAMEX> analyzed as below.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constructs</ENAMEX> and Mutagenesis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Full-length Rlk</ENAMEX> cDNA expression constructs pCIR,
          pcDNA3Rlk and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk-GFP</ENAMEX> have been described previously [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>]. Point mutations were introduced into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk-GFP</ENAMEX> by a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> based strategy [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>] with oligonucleotides encoding
          the required mutations (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Mutated residues</ENAMEX> are in bold):
          Y420F (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGAC GAT GAA T</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC ATC AGT TCT TCT G</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y91F</TIMEX> (GTC AAG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT CTT T</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T T GAC TTC CTG CC</ENAMEX>). All mutations
          were confirmed by dideoxy sequencing. pLNCX-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FynT</ENAMEX> was a
          generous gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Lowell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USCF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>,
          CA). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glutathione S-Transferase</ENAMEX> (GST) fusion constructs
          were previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>].
        
        
          In vitro filter binding assays
          GST-Rlk fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were grown and induced as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacteria</ENAMEX> were sonicated in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX>-buffered saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ph7.4</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>
          X-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>, insoluble material removed by centrifugation for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> rpm and soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GST</ENAMEX> fusion proteins
          purified with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST-Sepharose</ENAMEX> beads (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>).
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 </TIMEX>g of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were separated
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE, transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nitrocellulose</ENAMEX> and probed
          with biotinylated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SH3</NUMEX>-GST fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> as previously
          described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>].
        
        
          Immunofluorescence
          HeLa cells were transfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rlk</ENAMEX> and Fyn
          expression constructs, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 hours later</TIMEX> passed onto
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coverslips</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12-24 hours</TIMEX> later fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          paraformaldehyde for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> at room temperature.
          Cells were stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fyn3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">antiserum</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1: 500</TIMEX>, washed
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Red</ENAMEX> conjugated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-Rabbit Goat</ENAMEX> serum (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cappel</ENAMEX>). Nuclei were
          counterstained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPI</ENAMEX>, cells were visualized on a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeiss Axioplan</ENAMEX> microscope with a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Charge Coupled Device</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCD</ENAMEX>) camera.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Blotting</ENAMEX> and Immunoprecipitation
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> following transfection cells were washed once
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and lysed in NP40 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lysis Buffer</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> Nonidet-P
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40, 50</TIMEX> mM HEPES pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM NaPO
          
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM sodium
          orthovanadate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AEBSF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 ug/ml aprotinin</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein extracts</ENAMEX> were directly
          mixed with 2X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> sample buffer (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1X: 50 mM</TIMEX> Tris
          pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.8</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> glycerol, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bromphenol Blue</ENAMEX> plus
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> B-mercaptoethanol). Alternatively, lysates were
          clarified by centrifugation and detergent-soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>
          was analyzed. Equivalent amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were boiled
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> sample buffer and separated by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE and
          transferred onto nitrocellulose (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schleicher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schuell</ENAMEX>).
          The membranes were blocked in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> Tween-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat dry milk</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">w/v</ENAMEX>). The membranes were incubated with the appropriate
          primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/2000</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Rlk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4G10</ENAMEX>,
          anti-phosphotyrosine) or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Fyn</ENAMEX>) dilution
          overnight at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4°C or 1-2 hours</TIMEX> at room temperature.
          Membranes were washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX>, incubated with the
          appropriate secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/10000</NUMEX> dilution
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehringer Mannheim</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was visualized
          by enhanced chemiluminescence (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham</ENAMEX>).
          For immunoprecipitation studies, equivalent amounts of
          detergent soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were incubated with affinity
          purified anti-Rlk sera for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2-4 hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. The
          complexes were recovered with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protein A-Sepharose</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>)
          and washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times with ice cold NP40 wash buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          NP40, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">orthovanadate</ENAMEX>) and analyzed by
          Western blotting using either anti-Rlk serum or anti-Fyn
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1000</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitro</ENAMEX> Kinase Assays
          Cell extracts were prepared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">NP40</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lysis Buffer</ENAMEX> and
          immunoprecipitated as described above. Complexes were
          recovered with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Protein A Sepharose</ENAMEX>, washed twice with ice
          cold NP40 wash buffer, washed twice with ice cold Rlk
          kinase buffer (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 mM HEPES</TIMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM MgCl
          
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM MnCl 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 , 100 μM sodium orthovanadate</ENAMEX>). The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> reaction was carried out in kinase buffer
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 </NUMEX>g <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid denatured enolase</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 </NUMEX>Ci
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[γ- 32P</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redivue, Amersham</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX> at room
          temperature. The reaction was quenched with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> sample
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX>, boiled and separated by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE.
          Phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were detected by autoradiography
          or quantified on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhosphoImager</ENAMEX>. The level of Rlk
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was analyzed by immunoblotting.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raft Isolation</ENAMEX>
          Jurkat Tag cells were transfected by square wave
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electroporation</ENAMEX> using the parameters of 300 V and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ms.
          For each condition <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> cuvettes containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 7cells</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>
          ml were electroporated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 μg</NUMEX> of the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>.
          Cells were grown over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RPMI</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> fetal
          calf serum. In some experiments, cells were pretreated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wortmannin</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100 nM</NUMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> hrs prior to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fractionation</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX> stimulation, cells for each
          condition were concentrated into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> ml, warmed to 37°C
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> and then treated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 μg</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OKT3</ENAMEX>. Ice cold
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> was added to the cells after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 minutes</TIMEX> OKT3 treatment
          and the cells were quickly pelleted and lysed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TENV</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 mM Tris 7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM Na 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> VO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ) containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>. The
          cells were homogenized with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> strokes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ml Dounce
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homogenizers</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> of incubation on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>.
          Homogenates were adjusted to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> sucrose by addition of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TENV</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> sucrose. The lysate was transferred
          to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TLS55</NUMEX> ultracentrifuge tube, over-layered
          sequentially with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30% and 5%</NUMEX> sucrose in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TENV</ENAMEX>. Sucrose
          gradients were centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> μl fractions were removed from the top of the
          gradient for analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Metabolic Labeling and Pulse Chase</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 × 106</ENAMEX> 293T cells were transfected with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 μg</NUMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indicated Rlk</ENAMEX> construct and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 μg</NUMEX> of empty vector or the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indicated Fyn</ENAMEX> construct. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> after
          transfection, the cells were split equally among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> plates and grown in complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 24</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. The cells were placed in serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cys</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-</ENAMEX>)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> prior to pulse labeling. Cells were pulse
          labeled with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 mCi</NUMEX> of Trans- [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35S</TIMEX>]-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Label</ENAMEX> (ICN) in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>
          ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-</ENAMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cys</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-</ENAMEX>) medium for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. After
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>, the monolayers were chased with complete DMEM
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM unlabeled methionine and cysteine
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. At the indicated chase time, the cells
          were lysed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml cold NP40 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lysis Buffer</ENAMEX> and the
          lysates were clarified by centrifugation. Rlk was
          immunoprecipitated with affinity purified anti-Rlk
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX> and immune <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> were
          recovered with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protein A-Sepharose</ENAMEX>, washed as described
          above, and boiled in SDS-sample buffer. Labeled proteins
          were separated by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> PAGE, and analyzed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorography</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PH</ENAMEX>, pleckstrin homology; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PI3K</TIMEX>, phosphoinositide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3-Kinase; SH2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Src homology-2</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SH3</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> homology-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XLA</ENAMEX>,
        X-linked agammaglobulinemia; 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xid</ENAMEX> ; x-linked immunodeficiency; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>; sIgM, surface immunoglobulin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>; (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAP</ENAMEX>),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTPase-Activating Protein; GST</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glutathione S-Transferase</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sodium Dodecyl Sulfate; PBS</ENAMEX>, phosphate buffered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saline</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">NP40</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonidet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-40</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PAGE</ENAMEX>, polyacrylamide gel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrophoresis</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
