
  
    
      
        Background
        Plasma membrane microparticles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>) of endothelial
        origin have been identified in normal human blood [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3</NUMEX> ]
        and increased counts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> carrying endothelial antigens
        were documented in the blood of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with lupus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anticoagulant</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] , acute coronary syndrome [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] ,
        thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] or in patients
        with exacerbated <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple sclerosis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . Similarly to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood platelets</ENAMEX>, endothelial cells release <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> which express
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphatidylserine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX>) on their surface. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX>-exposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> in
        blood appear to act as the catalytic surface for assembly
        of the prothrombinase complex [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Although circulating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> of various cellular origin in patient with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> were
        reported to be procoagulant through multiple mechanisms [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> ] , in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> they may have an anticoagulant
        function by promoting the generation of low amounts of
        thrombin that activate protein C [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] .
        The process of membrane vesiculation and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">platelets</ENAMEX> has been shown to require a calpain-dependent
        dissociation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">membrane proteins</ENAMEX> from the submembrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytoskeleton</ENAMEX> and most likely involves intracellular
        signaling by platelet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinases</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . Besides
        platelets stimulated by various agonists such as thrombin
        with collagen or the complement complex <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C5b-9</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7 11</ENAMEX> ] , a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">release of PS-containing</ENAMEX> membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> was demonstrated in
        other cell types such as endotoxin-stimulated monocytes [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> ] , polymorphonuclear leucocytes stimulated with the
        chemotactic peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FMLP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] or apoptotic T-lymphocytes
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . The normal restriction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX> to the inner surface
        of the plasma membrane becomes perturbed in apoptotic cells
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] . When exposed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX> is a determinant for phagocyte
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> of cells to be cleared. Plasma membrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blebbing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release are generally accepted as typical
        signs of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> apoptosis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        In addition to a possible pathophysiological role of
        circulating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>, analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> derived from endothelial
        cells may be a valuable diagnostic marker of vessel wall
        injury. The phospholipid-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> annexin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX> has a
        high affinity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PS</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] and is utilized in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> detection
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and in cell supernatants [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Since very little
        is known about the mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release from endothelial
        cell, it is difficult to judge the type and extent of
        endothelial injury represented by increased plasma counts
        of endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>. We used flow cytometry to study the
        release of annexin V-binding membrane microparticles from
        stimulated by various agonists. We further focused our
        study on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> after proapoptotic
        stimulation with the topoisomerase I inhibitor camptothecin
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>). Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> analogues become one of the most promising
        new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of antineoplastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> introduced into the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] , activity of camptothecin on
        endothelial cells may be of great interest.
      
      
        Results
        
          With the exception of high concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ionophore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A23187</ENAMEX>, rapid stimulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> with various
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agonists</ENAMEX> did not result in a release of annexin V-binding
          microparticles
          Flow cytometry analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> culture supernatant
          demonstrated that a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> ionophore
          A23187 caused the release of low counts of annexin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX>-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). Similar short-time activation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> with phorbol myristate acetate (PMA) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/mL</ENAMEX>),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼mol/L</ENAMEX>, human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thrombin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THR</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Unit/mL</ENAMEX>, human
          tissue plasminogen activator (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TPA</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX> kU/mL or human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">angiotensin II</ENAMEX> (AGTII) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼mol/L</ENAMEX> did not cause any
          significant increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). All of the
          agonists applied induced morphological changes in HUVEC
          seen by phase contrast light microscopy, which confirmed
          the cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> (not shown).
        
        
          Proapoptotic, but not proinflammatory, stimulation
          induced a release of annexin V-binding microparticles
          from HUVEC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> count increased overnight in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> of
          unstimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> culture, but this was not enhanced by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ mL</ENAMEX>) or by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 Î¼g/mL</ENAMEX>). However, when
          cells were activated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> in the presence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cycloheximide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 Î¼g/mL</ENAMEX>) to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apoptosis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , a
          dramatic increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> count was observed, as compared
          to TNFÎ± or cycloheximide treatment alone (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B).
          Similarly, induction of apoptosis with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>, a
          topoisomerase I inhibitor [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] , led to a release of
          annexin V-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> which was prevented by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZVAD</ENAMEX>. ZVAD
          also inhibited a release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> from unstimulated cells,
          which probably represents spontaneous apoptosis of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cultured HUVEC (Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release did not correlate with the level of cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in HUVEC stimulated with camptothecin
          Phase contrast microscopy showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> culture
          treated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼M</NUMEX> CPT (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C) lost
          confluence with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 30-40%</NUMEX> cells remaining adherent.
          The level of apoptosis of adherent cells was assessed by
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> and annexin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-FITC/</ENAMEX> propidium iodide assays
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fig 3</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one third</NUMEX> of the remaining
          adherent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> showed annexin V-binding (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3B) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-fragmentation (TUNEL-positivity) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3C).
          Interestingly, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times lower concentration of CPT
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">500 nM</NUMEX>) also induced significant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 4</NUMEX>
          hrs of treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A) and after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hrs</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM
          camptothecin induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release comparable to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î¼M CPT
          treatment, but without any significant increase in
          annexin V-binding to the cells or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-fragmentation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3B,3C). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> culture was still confluent (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B)
          with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20-30%</NUMEX> lower cell density as compared with
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMSO</ENAMEX> treated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HUVEC (Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A). This result indicates
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release is not related to cell desquamation. To
          investigate whether maturation of the cell culture
          influences the degree of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> in
          response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>, we compared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release from subconfluent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of confluence) at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs in culture, HUVEC
          reaching confluence at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> hrs in culture and overgrown
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> hrs in culture. Our results showed that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> declined with culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">maturation</ENAMEX>. There was also a change of the sensitivity of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overgrown HUVEC</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CPT</ENAMEX> treatment in confluent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> hrs old
          culture resulting in the higher concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼M</ENAMEX>) releasing higher levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). In growing
          culture at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM CPT caused even higher
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>. In confluent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">HUVEC 48 hrs old</NUMEX>,
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release induced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼M</NUMEX> CPT was not
          significantly different (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Endothelial antigens CD 105 and CD <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> were both
          expressed on living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>, apoptotic bodies and other
          cell fragments in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CPT</ENAMEX> treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> culture but CD 105
          was absent on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of annexin V-binding membrane
          microparticles
          Using flow cytometry, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSC</ENAMEX> plot we gated
          homogeneous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of single living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G1</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          5A), which appeared negative in propidium iodide staining
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B). Living cells from control cultures as well as
          from cultures treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> were strongly positive for
          both antigens CD 105 and CD <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5C). Expression of
          CD59 on endothelial cells was not influenced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs
          incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">500nM</ENAMEX> or 5Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> as compared with control
          cells incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>. Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD105</ENAMEX> was
          only slightly decreased on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CPT</ENAMEX> treated cells. Cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fragments > 4 Î¼m</ENAMEX> in size as compared with standard
          beads were gated separately (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G2</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A). Larger cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragments</ENAMEX> appeared positive in propidium iodide staining
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B). All analyzed cell fragments were positive for
          CD59 and also expressed CD 105 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5D). Comparison of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> under the different peaks on the histogram (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          5C,5<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>) indicates that the portion of cell fragments
          corresponding to apoptotic bodies and necrotic cells was
          significantly higher in culture treated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼M</NUMEX> CPT as
          compared to culture treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> or with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX> alone. In a separate protocol we analyzed the
          expression of CD <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX> and CD <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> on membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>. Comparison
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSC</ENAMEX> values of standard beads and analyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> showed
          that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> of annexin V-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> released from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">< 1 Î¼m</ENAMEX> in size (range <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX> Î¼m). Analyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> were
          free of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleic acids</ENAMEX> as they were not stained with
          propidium iodide (not shown). Double-labeling flow
          cytometry assay showed that all annexin V-binding
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">membrane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> expressed CD59 but only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 50%</NUMEX> of
          these expressed CD 105 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Our previous study demonstrated that cultured HUVEC
        released annexin V-binding membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> in response to
        proapoptotic stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . In the present
        study, we investigated whether endothelial cells release
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">membrane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> after rapid stimulation with Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-mobilizing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> or after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> stimulation with proinflammatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, or only after induction of apoptosis.
        Our negative results with thrombin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRAP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TPA</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AGTII</ENAMEX> indicate that rapid Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-mobilization, despite
        dramatic morphological changes of the cells, does not
        result in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). The only report
        showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release after rapid stimulation with a
        physiologic agonist is the study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamilton</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] that demonstrated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> with the complement complex C5b-9.
        This membrane-attack complex may destabilize cell membrane
        by generating pores in phospholipid bilayer. We observed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> after short-time treatment only with
        high concentrations (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX>) of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A23187</TIMEX>. In this experiment,
        a direct destabilizing effect of the Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ionophore</NUMEX> A23187
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> membrane resulting in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> formation is also likely.
        Another question is relation of plasma membrane blebbing
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> study documented peroxide-induced
        membrane blebbing after a short time stimulation of
        endothelial cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release was not
        investigated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> showed micrographs of stimulated
        cells with membrane blebs of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 3 Î¼m</NUMEX> in diameter. Size
        of majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> produced in our experiments is less than
        1Î¼m. This difference indicates that the mechanism of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release may be different from membrane blebbing visually
        observed on cells by conventional light microscopy.
        We did not find any significant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release from HUVEC
        after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B) although
        stimulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> culture was confirmed by
        upregulation of CD <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> on cell surface (not shown). In
        comparison, Combes 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] recorded a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> fold
        increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP count</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> culture stimulated overnight
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> when compared to control cells. These discrepant
        results may stem from differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> culture
        conditions and the flow cytometric assay. In our study, the
        proapoptotic stimulation was the only efficient way to
        release membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release from
        endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> after proapoptotic stimulation was not
        studied before, we focused on its characterization. We used
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>, an inhibitor of topoisomerase I, that is a well
        defined apoptogenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> belonging to a promising class of
        antineoplastic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . In contrast to more
        physiological stimuli (i.e, oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>) induction of
        apoptosis by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> is less complex and thus is a better model
        for study of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release phenomenon. Our results showed that
        the growth stage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> culture influenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> release in
        response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). It is difficult to understand why
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM CPT caused higher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subconfluent HUVEC</ENAMEX>. This difference is small and may be
        influenced by error of analysis. It is evident, however,
        that cell culture maturation increased resistance to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">camptothecin</ENAMEX> treatment. This may be related to decreased
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX> in mature confluent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX>.
        Size distribution of annexin V-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> released from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> after proapoptotic stimulation was similar to that of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">endothelial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> found in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . The small size and
        the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleic acids</ENAMEX> indicate that the analyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>
        are different from apoptotic bodies formed in the terminal
        stage of apoptosis. Our finding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD59</NUMEX>+ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD105</NUMEX>+ and
        CD59+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD105</NUMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) suggests that HUVEC
        can release different types of annexin V-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> with
        respect to their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> expression. This observation
        cautions against the use of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> for detection
        of endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. The presence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD59</TIMEX> on all
        annexin V-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP corresponds</ENAMEX> to the high expression of
        this glycosylphosphatidylinositol anchored glycoprotein on
        endothelial cells. The homodimeric transmembrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glycoprotein</ENAMEX> CD 105 (endoglin) is relatively specific for
        endothelial cells and is abundant with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 500,000</NUMEX>
        copies per <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . It is not clear, however,
        why they are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD59</NUMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> that express CD105 and some
        that do not (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). Although CD 105 was shown to be an
        endothelial cell proliferation marker [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] , its
        expression was only slightly decreased on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CPT</ENAMEX> treated cells
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5C) and was stable on overgrown confluent HUVEC up to
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> hrs in culture (not shown). We also found this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>
        on cell fragments, including apoptotic bodies (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5D).
        Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD59</TIMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with an important complement
        regulatory function, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD105</ENAMEX> is a component of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGFÎ²</ENAMEX>, there may be functional and/or
        diagnostic differences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP populations</ENAMEX>.
        It is generally accepted that appearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX> on the
        outside of the plasma membrane is an early sign of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in many cell types after different treatments [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chan</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] showed that exposure of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX> on the cell surface preceded DNA strand breaks in
        apoptosis of different cell lines. Cell membrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vesiculation</ENAMEX> and release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> is considered to belong to
        the execution stage of apoptosis where the fate of the cell
        is sealed. To our surprise, in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CPT</ENAMEX> treated HUVEC the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release did not correlate with the extent cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">desquamation</ENAMEX> and apoptosis or remaining adherent cells
        characterized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX> exposure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell membrane</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-fragmentation (TUNEL) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). In contrast, Aupeix 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] reported that the
        release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS-containing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> was proportional to hypodiploid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">THP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">937</NUMEX> cells stimulated by various
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptotic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Our experiments with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CPT</ENAMEX> treated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HUVEC</ENAMEX> indicate that annexin V-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> may be released
        from adherent cells at initial phase of apoptosis before
        exposure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX> on cell surface or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA fragmentation</ENAMEX>. Cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">desquamation</ENAMEX> and massive formation of apoptotic bodies seen
        after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">¼M CPT</ENAMEX> treatment did not further enhance the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) thus supporting the hypothesis that
        annexin V-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release takes place in the initial
        phase of apoptosis. The essential step in plasma membrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">destabilization</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release very likely is a
        caspase-dependent sphingomyelin hydrolysis, which leads to
        the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramide</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29 30</NUMEX> ] . It is possible,
        however, that sphingomyelin hydrolysis and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release may
        be a consequence of the action of initiator caspases or
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZVAD</ENAMEX> sensitive proteases rather than only executioner
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caspases</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 31 32</NUMEX> ] . Our study was performed in HUVEC
        culture, which may have particular properties in respect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> release when compared with endothelial cells from other
        organs. Our finding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX> is not exposed on the cells
        treated with low concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> while they release
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS-containing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> may suggests that these cells release <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>
        to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX> from the cell surface as a protective
        mechanism that may counteract proapoptotic stimulation in
        the life/death decision process.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Our results demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> release different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of annexin V-binding membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> in response to
        proapoptotic stimulation. We showed that rapid stimulation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> with thrombin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TPA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AGT II</ENAMEX> or overnight
        stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> or LPS does not induce release of
        annexin V-binding membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>. Release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> after
        treatment with camptothecin very likely occurs at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early</TIMEX>
        stage prior to a "point of no return" in apoptosis. This
        phenomenon may represent a physiologic repair process
        rather then be a part of apoptotic cell death.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Monoclonal antibodies
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phycoerythrin</ENAMEX> (PE) conjugated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IgG2a</ENAMEX> isotype control
          (IgG-IC) was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Immunotech</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marseille</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mab</ENAMEX> to human CD59 (PE-conjugated, clone <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MEM 43</NUMEX>)
          was from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caltag Lab</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burlingame</ENAMEX>, CA), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mab</ENAMEX> to human CD105
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>-conjugated, clone <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">N1-3A1</ENAMEX>) was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancell/Alexis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, CA).
        
        
          Endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clonetics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cultured</ENAMEX> in endothelial cell growth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> EGM-2
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clonetics</ENAMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of fetal bovine serum and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supplements</ENAMEX>. Cells of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ndpassage were used in the
          experiments. Cells were seeded at a density of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cells/cm 2in</ENAMEX> polystyrene <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcon</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-well plates or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> mm
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dishes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson Labware</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Lakes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) and
          maintained at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> under an atmosphere of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> room air. Cells were used
          for experiments at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> hrs in culture when they reached
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confluence</ENAMEX>. For apoptotic assays, treated culture was
          washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>' balanced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt solution</ENAMEX> (HBSS) with
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.35%</NUMEX> bovine serum albumin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS/BSA</ENAMEX>) and adherent cells
          were harvested with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX> buffer with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>. After harvest, cells
          were centrifuged (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">300 g/5 min</ENAMEX>), washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS/BSA</ENAMEX> and
          used for analysis.
        
        
          Phase contrast microscopy
          HUVEC cultures in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well plates were photographed
          using CK40 <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Olympus</ENAMEX> culture microscope (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>)
          with a SPOT camera and software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostic Instruments</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Phase contrast at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200Ã—</NUMEX> magnification was
          used. The culture cell density was estimated by visual
          counting of cells in a standard area on the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">micrographs</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Overnight stimulation of HUVEC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confluent HUVEC</ENAMEX> were washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> and incubated
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> with various agonists in the medium:
          MEDIUM only; DMSO <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5 %</NUMEX> (vehicle for camptothecin); tumor
          necrosis <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-Î±</ENAMEX> (TNF) from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Biochemicals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/mL</ENAMEX>; cycloheximide (CHX) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/mL</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1000 U/</ENAMEX>mL with cycloheximide <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼g/mL
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF/CHX</ENAMEX>); lipopolysaccharide (LPS) 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">055:B5</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calbiochem</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> Î¼g/mL; camptothecin (CPT) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5 Î¼mol/L</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 nmol</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/L</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> with caspase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">inhibitor Z</ENAMEX>-Val-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>-Asp-fluoromethyl ketone (ZVAD) from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calbiochem</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼mol</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/L</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ZVAD 50 Î¼mol/L</ENAMEX>
          alone. After incubation, media and cells were harvested
          for analysis.
          In a study of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>-release in subconfluent, confluent
          and overgrown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> culture, the cells at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24 hrs</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confluence</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> hrs (reaching confluence) or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> hrs
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">overgrown</NUMEX>) in culture were incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">% DMSO</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 nM or 5 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> in medium. After incubation
          supernatant from cell culture was harvested and annexin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX>-FITC-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> were counted.
          In a study of expression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD59 and CD105</TIMEX> on
          endothelial cells, apoptotic bodies and other cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragments</ENAMEX>, the confluent HUVEC at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> hrs in culture were
          treated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 nM or 5 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> in
          medium. After treatment the cell culture supernatant was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">separated</ENAMEX>, adherent cells were harvested with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM HEPES
          buffer with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>,
          and pooled with culture supernatant. This mixture of
          cells, apoptotic bodies and other cell fragments was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centrifuged</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">300 g/5 min</ENAMEX>), washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS/BSA</ENAMEX>, labeled
          in aliquots with saturating concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE-conjugated Mab</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD105</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD59</TIMEX>, washed again in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS/BSA</ENAMEX> and analyzed by flow cytometry.
        
        
          Short-time stimulation of HUVEC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confluent HUVEC</ENAMEX> were washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> and incubated
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> with various agonists in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> with
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.35%</NUMEX>BSA: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> alone; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5 %</NUMEX> dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO);
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ionophore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A23187 1-100 Î¼mol/L</ENAMEX>; phorbol myristate acetate
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/mL</ENAMEX>; human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thrombin</ENAMEX> receptor activating peptide
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFLLRNP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRAP</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-50 Î¼mol/L</ENAMEX>; human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thrombin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THR</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US FDA</ENAMEX>
          standard lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Unit/mL</ENAMEX>; human
          tissue plasminogen activator (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TPA</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX> kU/mL or human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">angiotensin II</ENAMEX> (AGTII) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼mol/L.</ENAMEX> All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> were from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calbiochem</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) unless otherwise stated. After
          incubation, cell cultures were observed by phase contrast
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microscopy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell supernatants</ENAMEX> were collected for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>
          analysis.
        
        
          Annexin V-labeling of microparticles
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One hundred</NUMEX> Î¼L of medium or cell culture supernatant
          were incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 Î¼L</NUMEX> of annexin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-FITC</ENAMEX> from BD
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PharMingen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> at room temperature
          with or without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> to estimate the non-specific
          binding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fifty Î¼L</ENAMEX> of labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> were added to TruCount
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tubes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>) containing standard beads in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX>
          Î¼L of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS/BSA</ENAMEX> solution. Samples were immediately
          analyzed with flow cytometry.
        
        
          Immunolabeling of annexin V-binding
          microparticles
          Medium or cell supernatant containing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> were
          centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">g for 5 min</ENAMEX>, and the sediment was
          discarded. Supernatant was further centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,800</NUMEX>
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10Â°C</TIMEX>, and sedimented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> were resuspended
          in the original volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS/BSA</ENAMEX>. Aliquots of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼L
          were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> at room temperature with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î</NUMEX>¼L
          of annexin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-FITC</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD Pharmingen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) and
          saturating concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE-conjugated Mab</ENAMEX>. After
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubation</ENAMEX> and washing with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mL <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS/BSA</ENAMEX> (centrifuged at
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">19,800 g</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10Â°C</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were diluted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼L HBSS/BSA</ENAMEX> and analyzed by flow cytometry.
        
        
          Flow cytometry of endothelial cells and cell
          fragments
          Cell samples were analyzed by a FACScan flow cytometer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) equipped with CELLQUEST
          software with forward scatter (FSC) and side scatter
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>) in linear mode setting. Samples were analyzed using
          forward scatter (FSC) vs. side scatter (SSC) plot and
          propidium iodide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>) fluorescence vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSC</ENAMEX> plot. Single
          cells were gated separately in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">gate G1</ENAMEX> and apoptotic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> and other cell fragment in gate G2 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). Count
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> gated particles was analyzed for each sample.
          Apoptotic status of cells was assayed using Annexin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-FITC Apoptosis Detection Kit</ENAMEX> for annexin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V/</ENAMEX> propidium
          iodide cell labeling and using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apo-Direct Kit</ENAMEX> for
          labeling (TUNEL) according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instruction
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD Pharmingen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA). Percentages of propidium
          iodide-negative cells binding annexin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX> and
          TUNEL-positive cells were evaluated. In a study of the
          expression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD59 and CD105</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX>, histograms showing
          expression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD105 and CD59</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">G1</NUMEX>) and cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragments</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">G2</NUMEX>) are presented. Binding of the IgG2a
          isotype control (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG-IC</ENAMEX>) corresponded to the fluorescence
          of nonlabeled cells and cell fragments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Quantum</ENAMEX>
          TM24 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beads</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flow Cytometry Standards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Juan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>) were
          run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> as a separate sample to standardize
          fluorescence readings.
        
        
          Flow cytometry analysis of endothelial cell
          membrane microparticles
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> were analyzed in a separate protocol [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] using a
          modified method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combes et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Annexin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX>-FITC-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> were gated in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX> vs. fluorescence
          logarithmic plot. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP quantitation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TruCount</ENAMEX> beads
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) were used in each
          sample as an internal standard. TruCount beads were gated
          in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSC</ENAMEX> logarithmic plot and analysis was
          stopped when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> beads were counted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> count released
          by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 3cells</TIMEX> was calculated for each sample. TetraSpeck
          fluorescent microsphere standards of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.2</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.0 Î¼m</NUMEX> in diameter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR)
          were used to estimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> size based on comparison of FSC
          values. Antigen expression on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> was analyzed by
          double-labeling with annexin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V-FITC</ENAMEX> and PE-conjugated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabs</ENAMEX>. The annexin V-FITC-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX> were gated, and
          their binding of PE-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabs</ENAMEX> was evaluated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX> vs.
          PE - fluorescence logarithmic plots.
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGTII</ENAMEX>, angiotensin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, bovine serum albumin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHX</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cycloheximide; CPT</ENAMEX>, camptothecin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>, dimethyl sulfoxide;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX>, fluorescein isothiocyanate; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>' balanced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt</ENAMEX> solution; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX>, human umbilical vein endothelial
        cells; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC-IgG, IgG</ENAMEX> isotype control; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mab</ENAMEX>, monoclonal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MP</ENAMEX>, microparticles; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>, phycoerythrin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>,
        propidium iodide; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">phorbol-myristate</ENAMEX>-acetate; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphatidylserine; TRAP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thrombin</ENAMEX> receptor activating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX> (SFLLRNP); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>, tumor necrosis factor; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TPA</ENAMEX>, tissue
        plasminogen activator; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX>, terminal
        deoxynucleotidyltransferase dUTP nick end labeling; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZVAD</ENAMEX>,
        Z-Val-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>-Asp-fluoromethyl ketone.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Author JÅ</ENAMEX>  participated in the design of the study and
        carried out tissue culture and flow cytometry experiments.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author KH</ENAMEX> participated in flow cytometry experiments and in
        the design of the study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author JGV</ENAMEX> participated in the
        design of the study and in its coordination.
      
    
  
