
  
    
      
        Background
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Medicare</ENAMEX> &
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> Services (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX>) announced plans for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Quality Initiative</ENAMEX>, a new strategy to improve the
        quality of care in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. This
        Initiative is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-pronged effort. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX> and state
        survey and certification <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> continue their existing
        regulatory enforcement efforts. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX> promotes
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' access to new information about the quality of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> in specific nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, in the form of
        publicly-reported Quality Measures available on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX>'s
        website for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">medicare</ENAMEX>.gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third</ENAMEX>,
        nursing home stakeholders collaborate to promote and
        support efforts to improve nursing home quality of care.
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Improvement Organizations</ENAMEX> (QIOs) offer
        community-based quality improvement assistance programs to
        nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> seeking to improve their performance
        on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX>.
        Before national implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Initiative</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX> conducted a pilot
        in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. QIO quality improvement activities
        during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> included collaborating with nursing home
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX> on all aspects of the initiative, educating
        all nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX>, and
        offering quality improvement assistance to nursing home
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home Quality Initiative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> built
        on nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>' desire and enthusiasm to deliver
        high quality care by adding another incentive to improve
        (the public release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measure</ENAMEX> data) and by
        providing consultative services, clinical education, and
        technical support from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> in that
        improvement.
        Releasing performance outcome information (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality</ENAMEX>
        Measures data) gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> additional information to
        consider when selecting a nursing home, and consequently,
        may also spur efforts to improve the quality of care
        provided in nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> overall [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . These efforts to
        improve quality may result from increased consumer
        consciousness due to public reporting, and, consequently,
        heightened competition in the nursing home market based on
        relative quality of care, or may be a response to the
        incentive to compare favourably with other individual
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> based on publicly-reported data [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] . There
        may remain other motivating factors, but still open to
        debate is which effect has the greatest impact on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">healthcare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>' efforts to improve [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
        In a report on the appropriateness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality</ENAMEX>
        Measures chosen for publicly reporting during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Quality Initiative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
        Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>) questioned the reliability,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">validity</ENAMEX>, and risk adjustment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX>
        selected for public reporting, expressed concerns about the
        accuracy of data that are used to calculate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality</ENAMEX>
        Measures, and indicated that the format in which Quality
        Measure data were published on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home Compare</ENAMEX> may not
        be understandable by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . However, these
        potential limitations do not seem to have reduced the
        impact of public reporting on nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>'
        interest in quality improvement and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> assistance, as
        experienced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Furthermore,
        according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX>'s own data, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52%</NUMEX> of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> states requested technical assistance on quality
        improvement from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX>, and most nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in these
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88%</NUMEX>) had heard of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home Quality</ENAMEX>
        Initiative to publicly report quality of care information [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ] .
        This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports the lessons that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
        pilot states learned with regard to the impact that this
        Initiative has on nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>' interest in
        quality improvement, on the relationship among stakeholders
        in the nursing home setting, and on the provision of
        quality improvement assistance to nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. We present
        recommendations based on these lessons learned in order to
        inform and facilitate future quality improvement efforts in
        nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> serve as external facilitators of quality
        improvement projects among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. In the
        pilot, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> provided quality improvement assistance related
        to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the clinical topics covered by the publicly
        reported Quality Measures, pain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and pressure
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ulcer</ENAMEX> prevention and treatment. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> topics were
        selected from the entire set of publicly reported measures
        because nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> regard improvement in these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> as a high priority, and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the pilot
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> wanted to test and refine methods and materials for
        quality improvement assistance on just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> topics before
        developing them for all topics associated with the publicly
        reported Quality Measures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> convened volunteer nursing
        home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> to facilitate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of ideas and
        strategies among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> for improving care processes
        related to these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> clinical topics, as well as visited
        nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> to work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> on an individual basis
        to provide quality improvement assistance. Additionally,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> provided to these nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> clinical materials and
        educational workshops on pain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and pressure ulcer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prevention</ENAMEX> and treatment, as well as education on quality
        improvement strategies such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> building,
        brainstorming, root-cause analysis, and rapid-cycle
        improvement. While we can identify the types of assistance
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> provided to participating nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, we did
        not have a tracking system in place during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> to
        quantify the amount of assistance provided by state, and
        each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> utilized a unique combination of these strategies
        to assist nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Therefore,
        the activities as they are described here should be viewed
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> examples of approaches used in nursing
        home quality improvement.
        Throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> states
        met on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one-hour</TIMEX> teleconference calls to share
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lessons</ENAMEX> learned about each stage of implementing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>.
        During these calls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> Quality Partners
        (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> and the lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> for the pilot)
        collected lessons learned and comments from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX>, national
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX>. The lessons learned were
        entered into an Access database and categorized by state,
        category of intervention (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recruitment</ENAMEX>, workshops, quality improvement assistance,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>) and clinical topic (e.g., pain, pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ulcers</ENAMEX>,
        restraints, etc.). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> reviewed the database
        entries and analysed the recorded lessons learned to
        identify common themes in order to summarize the following
        experience-based recommended approaches to assisting
        nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> with quality improvement.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Forming Partnerships</ENAMEX>
          In order to raise awareness about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home</ENAMEX>
          Quality Initiative among nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> pilot
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> found it effective to work together in promoting
          the availability of nursing home data for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> in
          the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX>, as well as to guide the
          improvement activities related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stakeholders</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> included nursing home trade
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> (the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Health</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Association</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Association of Homes</ENAMEX>
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aged</ENAMEX>), nursing home professional
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> (such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College of Health</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Administrators</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Association of Nurse</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment Coordinators</ENAMEX>), state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> (such as the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments of Health</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Survey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Certification</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elderly Affairs</ENAMEX>), long-term care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ombudsman offices</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> discharge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resident Council</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>, and senior citizen advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
          Based on the experiences of the pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the
          recommended approaches to facilitating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> are
          to: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) form an advisory or steering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of partners
          that meets regularly (e.g., <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) maintain
          regular contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, even when no new
          information is available.
          Benefits of creating a steering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of nursing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home stakeholders</ENAMEX> include: easing communication among all
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, facilitating updates, discussing issues facing
          nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, and brainstorming possible solutions. For
          this reason, nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> in each state
          expressed a preference to work together, even in states
          where there has traditionally been tension between
          certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. Partnerships result in practical
          coordination of resources, such as scheduling training
          sessions to nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> at pre-existing conferences
          sponsored by other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, or sharing address lists,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">newsletters</ENAMEX>, and meeting space. Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> also
          allow for the development of a consistent, positive
          message about nursing home issues to all outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>.
          For example, it was noted in the pilot that when the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> received a consistent message about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Quality Initiative</ENAMEX> from all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, media
          coverage tended to be more supportive of nursing homes
          than when stakeholders were divided.
          Since frequent contact with all nursing home
          stakeholders increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> and collaboration among the
          different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, timely communication with all potential
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> is a recommended approach to building
          partnerships. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> sent out a weekly
          newsletter by email to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>. This newsletter
          conveyed information about upcoming training sessions,
          legislative updates and answers to frequently asked
          questions.
        
        
          Establishing a relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Survey</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> states identified the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Survey Agency</ENAMEX> (SSA) as one of the most important and
          influential stakeholders with whom to establish a
          relationship. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason for this is that nursing home
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX> often want to know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> has been made
          aware of quality improvement material or recommended
          clinical interventions. It is also important to highlight
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> has no regulatory
          responsibilities and is distinctly different from the SSA
          in its work with nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.
          As is true with any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>, regular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> is essential to success. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> found that
          they should regularly communicate to the SSA the kinds of
          quality improvement assistance they were planning to
          offer to nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, and if possible, obtain
          an endorsement of that assistance. An assurance of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Survey Agency</ENAMEX>'s awareness of quality improvement
          activities is essential in gaining nursing home
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> and in increasing their willingness to
          work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> (or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>), especially given
          the central role of the regulatory process in the current
          culture of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Survey Agencies</ENAMEX> in most pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, such as surveyors,
          State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDS Coordinators</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>,
          participated on the steering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of nursing home
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, and made individual contact with QIOs
          during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX>
          Nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> need to understand the origin
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX> in order to make use of them in
          quality improvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> states offered
          educational workshops about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX> to all
          nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The workshops focused on the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Minimum Data Set</ENAMEX> (MDS) items that are the source of the
          Quality Measures, as well as methods used to risk adjust
          the measures. While large workshops prove useful in
          introducing concepts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, ongoing consultation in
          smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> were most helpful in
          increasing understanding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX> for
          nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> found that it was imperative to
          have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> (e.g., an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> or the state
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>) participate in the training sessions to
          clarify questions about appropriate coding for some of
          the MDS items, as there is tremendous variation in how
          nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> code the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDS</ENAMEX> for the same MDS
          items.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engaging Physicians</ENAMEX> and the Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Improvement</ENAMEX>
          Once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> began to provide quality
          improvement assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> nursing home
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>, they received requests for assistance in
          involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> in quality improvement efforts. Most
          of the requests came from nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of nursing.
          The involvement of medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> is
          vital in the attempt to change facility rates on certain
          Quality Measures, such as pain, which often depends on
          changes in prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> to improve pain
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>. However, engaging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> and
          medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> to become directly involved in quality
          improvement projects at their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> is often a
          challenge. Current regulations require that the medical
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>'s quality assurance
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>, but the intensity of their involvement in
          quality improvement efforts is highly variable. Even when
          actively involved, most medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> lack training
          in quality improvement processes. Historically, quality
          improvement has not been part of medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>'
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">curricula</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> found several strategies to overcome
          noninvolvement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> or medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> that
          could be implemented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> or the nursing home, as
          described in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teaching Quality Improvement</ENAMEX>
          Teaching the principles of quality improvement to all
          nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, including direct care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, is
          another common challenge to implementing quality
          improvement projects in nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Certified Nursing</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assistants</ENAMEX> (CNAs) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>-tested <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nursing Assistants</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STNAs</ENAMEX>) provide the majority of direct patient care in
          nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, but are often not included by the nursing
          home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> in quality improvement efforts.
          Moreover, quality improvement training is often presented
          at a college-education level, even though <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">fewer than 5%</NUMEX>
          of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> have had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or more years</TIMEX> of
          college [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . The lack of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>'
          involvement in quality improvement is unfortunate, as
          they are often best situated to contribute ideas to
          quality improvement efforts.
          To reach all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> in the nursing home setting,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> found that training to nursing
          home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> on quality improvement was most effective when
          presenters integrated the principles of rapid-cycle
          quality improvement into examples of small-scale
          improvements that could be made in care processes common
          to the nursing home setting. Quality improvement theory
          was not well understood by nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> when
          general quality improvement concepts and terms (such as
          flow-charting and root-cause analysis) were presented
          without using nursing home care processes as examples, or
          were presented only with examples from manufacturing or
          other health care settings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> were more successful
          when they used language common to the nursing home
          setting, rather than quality improvement jargon (i.e.,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX>) in their training and communications.
          Relating quality improvement to the clinical method of
          careful observation, followed by intervention (i.e., some
          change in the care process), and then again careful
          observation to monitor the effect, was also well received
          by nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. Another successful approach is to
          teach one concept, such as data collection, at a time,
          allowing time in between for nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to apply
          the concept in either a mock workshop exercise, or as a
          real-life exercise at their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>.
          While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> challenge in providing education on quality
          improvement principles is the content of the curriculum,
          another challenge consists of presenting information
          differently from the usual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">didactic</TIMEX> seminars that nursing
          home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> attend, which are not always effective. To
          overcome this barrier, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> used
          both teleconferences and interactive sessions to
          facilitate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> in sharing
          their experiences in quality improvement and in
          implementing changes in processes of care. For example,
          when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at these interactive sessions asked
          nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> to explain in detail the change in
          process that they planned to make, other nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> usually had experience in attempting the same
          change. It was apparent in the pilot that nursing homes
          have many practical tips to share about the effective
          application of widely accepted guidelines and protocols,
          and that the activity of sharing experiences is useful in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inspiring</ENAMEX> and guiding nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in making
          changes to improve their processes of care. Examples of
          these practical tips are given in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>.
          One barrier that nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> face in doing
          quality improvement is lack of time for planning and
          evaluation. Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> found that some time at
          workshops was best allocated as time for nursing home
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to identify a change they could make in one process
          of care. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> then set a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-week</TIMEX> deadline for nursing
          home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to implement and measure a change they
          designed, in order to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to break down large
          systems changes into manageable steps. At subsequent
          workshops, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> facilitated productive discussions with
          nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to help them analyse of the results of
          the change, as measured by simple data collected by
          nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.
          Finally, nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> appreciated meetings
          or workshops that were arranged as a series, between
          which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were assigned simple tasks relevant to
          what they had learned as "homework". Nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
          were then held accountable to present a report of the
          results of their activities at the next meeting. When
          QIOs integrated nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>' reports of their
          experiences into the workshops, the application of
          quality improvement strategies at participating
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> increased, because this reporting was valuable
          in identifying for all nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> the
          tangible process changes that proved effective in
          improving care.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Providing One-on-One Assistance to Nursing</ENAMEX>
          Homes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> states that worked with
          nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> on improving processes of care
          related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Measures</ENAMEX> found that nursing home
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> were eager to begin a quality improvement effort in
          their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Collaboration was most successful when
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> had nursing home experience themselves, and
          could lend a sympathetic and experienced ear to barriers
          that faced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> found that nursing home
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> were more receptive to materials and advice when
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> was spent early in the project to assess the nursing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">home</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> needs. This led to the development of
          detailed forms (or "checklists") that nursing home staff
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> could use to assess whether or not
          recommended care processes for the clinical topic of
          focus were in place at the nursing home.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> found that working with nursing home providers
          demands an approach that is as simple and
          straight-forward as possible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> collection tools, for
          example, should be pared down to include only the
          information critical to the project. Rather than building
          a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and a new set of inservices separate from what
          the nursing home already does, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> can coordinate with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and meetings that already exist within the nursing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> visits to nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> were more effective
          when an agenda was provided in advance, the meeting was
          limited to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately one hour</TIMEX>, and handouts were
          provided to focus the meeting.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convert Regulatory Compliance Culture</ENAMEX> to Quality
          Improvement Culture
          Nursing home care is highly regulated by state and
          federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Failure to comply with regulations can
          result in stiff penalties, such as fines or exclusion
          from participation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> reimbursement.
          Some nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, particularly those seeking managed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> and other insurance contracts, have begun to seek
          certification from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Commission on Accreditation</ENAMEX>
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Healthcare Organizations</ENAMEX> (JCAHO) for both long term
          and sub-acute care, which adds additional layers of
          requirements for the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. In addition, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 50%</NUMEX>
          of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> or are affiliated
          with one [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . Corporate rules and protocols add
          another type of regulation with which nursing home staff
          must comply. Such externally imposed requirements, rules,
          or protocols often hinder the ability of nursing home
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> quality improvement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to implement creative
          solutions that may lie outside of the established rule or
          protocol. For example, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain organizations</ENAMEX> prohibit
          the use of "standing orders" in any form. Others require
          corporate pre-approval for changes in programs, for the
          sake of internal corporate consistency.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> working in quality improvement
          need to acknowledge nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>' requirements
          for regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adherence</ENAMEX>, but also must be aware of the
          regulations and clarify questions from nursing home staff
          about any 
          perceived conflicts between
          regulations and quality improvement strategies (for
          examples of such conflicts, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>). To assure
          quality improvement strategies are consistent with
          government regulations, frequent QIO consultation with
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Survey Agency</ENAMEX> is needed. Moreover, nursing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> may be more interested in quality improvement
          interventions that are related to salient
          regulations.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the greatest challenges to the national
          implementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home Quality Initiative</ENAMEX> may
          be in changing the nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> mindset from one
          of compliance with regulation through a system of quality
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurance</ENAMEX> (focused on retroactively examining outcomes)
          to a mindset of quality improvement (focused on
          proactively improving processes and systems). For
          example, nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> are accustomed to
          designing a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty-day</TIMEX> plan of correction" in response
          to citations given by surveyors, in which the cited
          system of care is quickly revised to comply with the
          regulation. The plan of correction is then "re-inserted'
          into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> without any testing of the actual
          effect of the changes, but no proof of effectiveness is
          required. Quality improvement, however, is based on a
          process of making change iteratively, and demands testing
          prior to implementation to determine whether a change
          will actually result in an improvement.
          Nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> correctly perceive the
          government in an oversight role, enforcing regulations
          with punitive actions. Convincing nursing home providers
          that working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> on quality improvement
          initiatives is a voluntary, collaborative endeavor that
          is independent of the survey (inspection) process is a
          barrier that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> must overcome in order to be
          effective.
        
        
          Addressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staffing</ENAMEX> Issues
          Turnover and vacancies make the formation and function
          of quality improvement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> more difficult, resulting in
          a low likelihood that any improvement will be adequately
          monitored or fully implemented. Workforce instability at
          the nursing home unavoidably impacts the relationship
          that the nursing home has with any outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>,
          including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX>. Even in the short duration of the
          pilot, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> staff witnessed turnover and vacancy in all
          positions. The challenge is not limited to working with
          ever-changing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> on a quality improvement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>,
          but also in accommodating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality Improvement Nurse</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of Nursing who is covering a short-staffed unit
          rather than championing a quality improvement project. In
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> instance, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>, uninformed about the
          pilot program and its objectives and methods, immediately
          withdrew the nursing home from the program, stating that
          it "was too time-consuming."
          Having multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact persons</ENAMEX> at each nursing home
          helped the QIOs overcome a break in the nursing home's
          involvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> developed relationships with the
          entire quality improvement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> rather than just the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Administrator</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing</ENAMEX>. Given the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing</ENAMEX>'s many responsibilities, it is advised that
          someone other than him/her is designated as the quality
          improvement project's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>. Finally, frequent contact
          with all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> was necessary to be aware of and
          offset staff changes.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Publicly reporting nursing home quality of care, and
        quality improvement projects in nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, have existed
        independently of one another prior to this new federal
        initiative. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care</ENAMEX>
        Commission began reporting on a set of quality indicators
        for nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> in
        response to a legislative mandate [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10</ENAMEX> ] . Additionally,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS Nursing Home</ENAMEX> Compare web site (at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">medicare</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>) reported a set of quality 
        indicators for all nursing homes
        nationally from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 to November 2002</TIMEX>, when the new set of
        quality 
        measures became available. In both of
        the initiatives above, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> reporting of nursing home
        quality indicators stood alone, without related support to
        nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> for quality improvement. The impact of public
        reporting on nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>' interest in quality
        improvement has not previously been evaluated.
        Prior nursing home quality improvement projects have
        been initiated in the absence of public reporting, by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">external</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Survey Agencies</ENAMEX>,
        research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. Results
        indicate that these external groups have had success in
        improving processes of care (i.e., improved pain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, pressure sore prevention and treatment, and
        rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">influenza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia immunizations</ENAMEX> among
        nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] .) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home Quality</ENAMEX>
        Initiative is a logical next step in creating a long-term
        commitment to quality improvement approaches driven by
        public reporting.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> found several key outcomes
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home Quality Initiative</ENAMEX> that help to
        maximize the potential of public reporting to leverage
        effective improvement in nursing home quality of care.
        First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> reporting focuses the attention of all
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX> in the nursing home industry on achieving good
        quality outcomes on a defined set of measures, and creates
        an incentive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> formation. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, publicly
        reported quality measures motivate nursing home providers
        to improve in certain key clinical areas, and in particular
        to seek out new ways of changing processes of care, such as
        engaging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> and the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> more directly.
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, the lessons learned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> of this
        Initiative indicate that certain approaches to providing
        quality improvement assistance are key to guiding nursing
        home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>' desire and enthusiasm to improve towards a
        using a systematic approach to quality improvement.
      
      
        Conclusions
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home Quality Initiative</ENAMEX> has already
        demonstrated the potential of public reporting to foster
        collaboration and coordination among nursing home
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX> and to heighten interest of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in
        quality improvement techniques. Through this Initiative,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX> are identifying key lessons learned about approaches
        to providing quality improvement assistance to nursing home
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">providers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIOs</ENAMEX>' work in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Home Quality</ENAMEX>
        Initiative will greatly contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of knowledge
        about facilitating quality improvement efforts in the
        nursing home setting, although it remains to be seen
        whether these efforts lead to improved quality of care in
        nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> nationwide.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SK</ENAMEX> contributed to the analysis of lessons learned and
        drafted the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DG</ENAMEX> conceived of the study,
        contributed to the analysis of lessons learned, and drafted
        the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PP</ENAMEX> conceived of the study, contributed to
        the analysis of lessons learned, and drafted the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASP</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LB</ENAMEX> contributed lessons
        learned and their analysis. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved
        the final manuscript.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMDA - American Medical Directors Associations</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMS - Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNA - Certified Nursing</ENAMEX> Assistant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizations</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDS - Minimum Data Set</ENAMEX>
        PDSA - Plan Do Study Act
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIO - Quality Improvement Organization</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAI - Resident Assessment Instrument</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA - State Survey Agency</ENAMEX>
        STNA - <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State</ENAMEX>-tested Nursing Assistant
      
    
  
