
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psoriasis</ENAMEX> is a common skin disorder affecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 to 3</NUMEX>
        percent of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] Treatment of the
        disease results in costs that range <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 0.7</NUMEX> to more
        than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 billion dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> alone [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . One
        of the most cost-effective forms of potential treatment for
        the disease is the use of antithyroid thioureylenes such a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">propylthiouracil</ENAMEX>. We previously reported the effectiveness
        of thioureylene treatment in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with plaque psoriasis
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] , a finding since confirmed by others [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] .
        The mechanism of action of antithyroid thioureylenes in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psoriasis</ENAMEX> remains unclear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> have been studied with
        relation to their effect in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX>' hyperthyroidism which,
        like psoriasis, is an autoimmune disorder [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10 11 12</ENAMEX> ]
        Antithyroid thioureylenes, of which propylthiouracil,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methimazole</ENAMEX> and carbimazole are used in clinical practice,
        have known immunomodulatory properties [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] and, in
        the case of psoriasis, also have antiproliferative effects
        as demonstrated by their ability to produce a decline in
        markers of cellular proliferation such as proliferative
        cell nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> (PCNA) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
        Skin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen-presenting cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langerhans</ENAMEX> cells) appear
        to play an important role in the initiating events that
        lead to the cytokine cascade that results in keratinocyte
        proliferation and development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">psoriatic lesions</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> ] . Effective therapeutic approaches to psoriasis
        treatment, such as psoralen UV-A therapy (PUVA), which
        result in depletion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APCs</ENAMEX> in the skin [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> ] , and
        UV-B [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] , lead to one of the most sustained improvement
        in psoriasis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX>, a product of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Langerhans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> and skin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monocytes</ENAMEX> plays a pivotal role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">T-cell</ENAMEX> activation that
        leads to formation of the psoriatic plaque [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
        levels are also significantly raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX>' hyperthyroidism and are reduced following treatment
        with propylthiouracil [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        CD1a is expressed in differentiated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-presenting
        cells and monocytes and is used as a marker for the
        presence of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the skin [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25 26</NUMEX> ] . The CD1
        molecules are the products of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> CD1 genes located on
        chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The genes are closely related to the mixed
        histocompatibilty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (MHC) genes indicating origin
        from a common precursor [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . CD1 molecules, however,
        have limited sequence homology to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> class <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">I and II</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">molecules</ENAMEX>, and unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MHC</ENAMEX> molecules are also capable of
        binding non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein antigens</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] .
        The present study was performed to examine the effect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">propylthiouracil</ENAMEX> treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with plaque
        psoriasis on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD1a</TIMEX> expression in their psoriatic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> in
        order to determine whether this form of therapy resulted in
        depletion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APCs</ENAMEX> from affected skin, that could account
        for the therapeutic benefit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTU</ENAMEX> in this disorder.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4M, 2F</ENAMEX>) with stable plaque psoriasis
          were recruited for study. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> ranged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> from
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 to 63 years</TIMEX>, mean ± <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44 ± 16 years</TIMEX>. None of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was taking any form of topical or systemic
          treatment, other than emollients, for psoriasis for at
          least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> prior to entry into the study. Pregnant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with thyroid dysfunction determined by
          pre-enrollment screening thyroid function tests were
          excluded from the study. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Review Board</ENAMEX>
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irvine</ENAMEX>, approved the
          study.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clinical Scoring</ENAMEX>
          Clinical evaluation was performed by the same
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dermatologist</ENAMEX> (VSN) at the time of patient entry into the
          study and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> intervals until completion of the
          study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scoring</ENAMEX> was based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PASI</ENAMEX> scoring system [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biopsy Samples</ENAMEX>
          Biopsy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were taken from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at the start
          and after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 months</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PTU</ENAMEX> treatment from the same
          psoriatic lesion. Skin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were obtained using a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mm
          punch biopsy under aseptic conditions with local
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anesthesia</ENAMEX>. The biopsies were frozen and stored at -70°C
          until processed. Indirect immunoperoxidase staining was
          used to identify <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD1a</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Histological</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scoring</ENAMEX>
          Biopsy specimens were viewed by a dermatopathologist
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJB</ENAMEX>). Histological scoring was made with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-point
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">scoring</ENAMEX> system graded from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0 to 4</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> = normal, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX> =
          slight, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - moderate, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3</TIMEX> = severe, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX> = very severe) based
          on criteria noted below after examination of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
          consecutive high-power fields. Histological scoring took
          into account hypogranulosis, parakeratosis and the
          inflammatory infiltrate in the epidermis and superficial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dermis</ENAMEX>. The total score reported was the sum of the
          individual parameters. Epidermal hyperplasia was measured
          with an oculomicrometer from top of the epidermis to the
          base of the ridges.
        
        
          Laboratory Tests
          Thyroid function tests were performed in all
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> prior to entry into the study and again at
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> intervals until study completion at twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>.
          The tests consisted of measurement of serum free T 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ) and thyroid-stimulating hormone
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSH</ENAMEX>). Complete blood counts (CBC) were also obtained at
          the same time intervals.
        
        
          Immunoperoxidase Staining
          Tissue samples from biopsy specimens stored at -70°C
          were taken and embedded in paraffin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4 μm</ENAMEX> sections were
          coated onto slides and allowed to dry <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55°C</TIMEX>.
          An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBC block</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.5 ml</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> ml <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX>) was applied for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 min</TIMEX> after which the slides were washed in tap water
          until clean. Following a series of washing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, the
          slides were washed with blocking serum (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> horse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">serum</ENAMEX>)
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> after which <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD1a</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:100 dilution</ENAMEX>)
          was applied for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>. The slides were washed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> after which anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:200</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dilution</ENAMEX>) was applied and the slides washed again in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX>. Tertiary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> kit) was added for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> and the slides were then washed for with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. DAB
          was applied in the dark (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>), the slides were washed
          in distilled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 min</ENAMEX>), counterstained with
          hematoxylin, washed with tap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, dehydrated and
          mounted.
        
        
          Quantification
          Results were expressed as the absolute number of
          positive staining dendritic cells counted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a 1</NUMEX> mm
          length of the epidermis. Only cells with clearly defined
          nuclei present in the suprabasal layers of the epidermis
          were counted.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          The results are expressed as mean ± <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX>
          analysis was performed using the t-test for paired
          observations. Level of significance was p < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinical Response</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PASI</ENAMEX> Scores
          All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> showed some improvement in their
          psoriasis with near-complete resolution in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PASI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> declined from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">21.40 ± 6.81</NUMEX> at baseline to
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.85 ± 4.35</NUMEX> at completion of the study (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.004</NUMEX>).
          Clinical improvement became apparent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three weeks</TIMEX>
          after therapy.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Histological</ENAMEX> Scores
          Histological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> also declined significantly from
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.17 ± 2.78</NUMEX> at baseline to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.00 ± 2.61</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 12</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">weeks PTU</ENAMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p < 002</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidermal</ENAMEX> thickness
          decreased from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.52 ± 0.17 mm</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.26 ± 1.11 mm</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.007</NUMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serum TSH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4and</NUMEX> CBC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBC</ENAMEX> remained normal (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.85 ± 0.53</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.05</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.31</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cells/μL</ENAMEX>, p = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ns</ENAMEX>) during the entire study with no patient
          demonstrating any leucopenia. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serum</ENAMEX> TSH concentrations
          remained within the euthyroid range with no patient
          exhibiting clinical signs or offering complaints
          suggestive of hypothyroidism. Serum free thyroxine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ) showed no significant change.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serum TSH</ENAMEX> slowed a slight rise in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> as a whole showing no significant elevation of TSH
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.72 ± 0.98</NUMEX> μU/ml vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.73 ± 1.43</NUMEX> μU/ml, p = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ns</ENAMEX>). The
          rise did not exceed the normal range, and all patients
          remained clinically euthyroid.
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD1a</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Psoriatic</ENAMEX> Plaques
          As expected, CD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1a</NUMEX> with characteristic stellate
          profiles typical for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langerhans</ENAMEX> cells were readily seen
          in the epidermis in all pre- and post-treatment biopsy
          samples. The number of CD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1a</NUMEX> staining cells showed an
          apparent increase after propylthiouracil therapy. The
          number of such cells rose from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5.67 ± 4.08</NUMEX> pretreatment
          to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10.00 ± 4.20 post-treatment</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.02</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fig 1,</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The efficacy of antithyroid thioureylenes as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in
        the treatment of plaque psoriasis is well established [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] The mechanism of action of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in psoriasis
        remains unclear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> can potentially act by reducing
        the cytokine signals that lead to keratinocyte
        proliferation or by reducing keratinocyte proliferation. A
        key element in the generation of the cytokine signals
        responsible for formation of a psoriatic plaque is the skin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antigen</ENAMEX>-presenting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> or Langerhans <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. Therapeutic
        modalities deplete such cells, that often lead to
        improvement in psoriasis. The best example of such an
        approach is treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UV</ENAMEX>-A and psoralens, as well as
        UV-B, which result in depletion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APCs</ENAMEX> and produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
        the most long-lasting remissions of the disease which might
        last in some instances for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long as 6 months</TIMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31 32</NUMEX> ] A
        key antigenic marker of skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">APCs</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD1a</TIMEX>. Langerhans cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">precursors</ENAMEX> arise from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD34</NUMEX> positive monocytes/macrophages
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34</NUMEX> ] . They circulate in the blood
        before localizing in the skin, primarily in dermal
        connective tissue. In the dermis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Langerhans</ENAMEX> precursors
        are strongly HLA-DR (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ia</ENAMEX>) positive, and are relatively
        non-phagocytic, "indeterminate cells." CD1a expression is
        not pronounced in the precursors and is not significantly
        expressed until the cells become differentiated. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36 37</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> ] Differentiated cells localize to the midepidermis,
        demonstrate characteristic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birbeck</ENAMEX> granules, and exhibit
        dendritic appendages. These differentiated cells, although
        usually stable, sometime exhibit proliferative activity and
        increase in many cutaneous immune response states [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 39</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> ] . The inability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTU</ENAMEX> to reduce CD1a expression in
        biopsy samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with psoriasis suggests that the
        mechanism of action of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is psoriasis is not due to
        any effect on skin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen-presenting cells</ENAMEX> or production
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX>, a motive cytokine that is responsible for
        initiation and maintenance of the cytokine stimulatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cascade</ENAMEX> that leads to formation of the psoriatic plaque [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> ] . In support of this argument is the fact that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">circulating IL-12</ENAMEX> did not show any significant change with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTU</ENAMEX> treatment (submitted). Additional studies are being
        performed which address whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTU</ENAMEX> treatment of patients
        with plaque psoriasis leads to reduced 
        in situ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX> expression, alters
        production of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-35</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-40</ENAMEX> components of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
        heterodimer, as well as exerts an effect by enhancing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in the proliferated keratinocytes that make up
        the psoriatic plaque which would result in clinical
        improvement.
      
      
        Competing Interests
        None declared.
      
    
  
