
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> have numerous functions depending upon the member
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in which they are expressed.
        Most are open under resting membrane potentials, and thus
        help maintain the voltage across the membrane near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +equilibrium potential. Specific functions include
        modulation of electrical activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac</ENAMEX> and neuronal
        cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX>, and epithelial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +transport [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ]
        . The crystal structure of the transmembrane region of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KcsA</ENAMEX>, from the bacteria 
        Streptomyces lividans has been
        determined [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA, Kir's</ENAMEX> are 2TM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that
        have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1 and M2</TIMEX>, that flank a P
        segment. The P <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> transverses only the outer portion
        of the transmembrane region. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of P dips into
        the transmembrane region as an α-helix and its latter
        portion returns to the surface in a relatively extended
        conformation that lies near the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-fold axis of the pore.
        Backbone oxygens from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> subunits of the latter
        portion of P form a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and thus
        determine the selectivity of the pore. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +selectivity
        filter region is the only portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX> that shares
        substantial sequence identity with eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir N</ENAMEX>-
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>termini <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> that precede and follow the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M1</NUMEX>-P-M2
        motif contain regions that are well conserved among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>'s
        (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), but that are not similar to sequences of any
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. In at least some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>, these
        cytoplasmic domains modulate the activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homology</ENAMEX> models [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1-P-M2</ENAMEX> portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>'s
        have been developed using the backbone structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX>.
        The validity of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> has been challenged by
        experiments [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] that were interpreted as indicating that
        the sequence alignment between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kir</ENAMEX> proposed
        originally by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doyle et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX> and used in these
        models is incorrect. Fortunately, the putative bacterial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX> reported here can be aligned unambiguously
        with the pore-forming P and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M2</NUMEX> segments of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KscA</ENAMEX> and
        the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>. This turns out to be the same
        alignment that was used in developing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX> homology
        models [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
      
      
        Results
        In analyzing evolutionary relationships among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and their homologs, we identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
        prokaryotic sequences that should code for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> whose
        closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>. The 
        Burkholderia pseudomallei (KirBac
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.1</NUMEX>) and 
        Burkholderia cepacia (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">KirBac 1.2</NUMEX>)
        sequences were determined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sequencing Group</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanger Centre</ENAMEX> and can be obtained from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sanger</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ac</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uk/Projects/Microbes/.</ENAMEX> The 
        Burkholderia <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fungorum</ENAMEX> LB400
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">KirBac1.3</NUMEX>), 
        Magentospirillum
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magnetotacticum</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">KirBac2.1</NUMEX>), 
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nostoc Punctiforme</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">KirBac3.1</NUMEX>)
        sequences are being determined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE Joint Genome</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> and can be found at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jgi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doe</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/.</ENAMEX>
        These sequences are preliminary and could contain errors.
        The eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> have been classified into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subfamilies</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir 1</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kir7</TIMEX>. We used several
        multisequence alignment methods (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PsiBlast</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clustal W</ENAMEX>
        1.74 [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pileup</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCG</ENAMEX> package [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] ) to initially
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">align KirBac</ENAMEX> with eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX> sequences accessible in
        public databases. The methods all predict essentially the
        same alignment with only minor differences in the locations
        of some insertions and deletions (indels); the final
        alignment shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1was adjusted manually for those
        few positions where discrepancies arose. Portions of the
        sequences at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>termini that are difficult to
        align because they are poorly conserved among the sequences
        were not included in the calculations or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1or</ENAMEX> the
        alignment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1shows</ENAMEX> the evolutionary
        distances calculated among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX>. These analyses support the phylogenetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> shown
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, in which the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> and prokaryotic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX>'s form <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of each family
        are more closely related to each other than to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
        the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. KirBac1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX> were placed in
        the same subfamily because of their high degree of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">similarity</ENAMEX>, as indicated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. The alignments used
        for the calculations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and</ENAMEX> illustrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1are
        rigorous because they consider many sequences and almost
        identical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alignments</ENAMEX> are obtained with a variety of methods
        that all take into account residue similarities as well as
        identities. However, for illustrative purposes it is more
        convenient to consider only identities for a few sequences.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1illustrates our alignment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> sequences
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir7.1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir2.1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX>. Kir2.1 was selected
        for the illustration because it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eukaroyte</ENAMEX> Kir
        studied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] and because it is closely
        related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Kir3</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kir5</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir6</ENAMEX> subfamilies
        (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Kir7 was selected because it is the Kir
        subfamily most distant from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kir</ENAMEX> subfamilies, as
        indicated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. Of the different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX> were found to be most similar to the Kir
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superfamily</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PsiBlast</ENAMEX> searches primarily because of
        the homology of their similar, relatively long C-terminal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the M2</TIMEX> segments. When the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M1</NUMEX>-P-M2
        regions of all of the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channels are
        compared, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> finds that the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> are the most
        divergent. Accordingly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the M1-P-M2</TIMEX> region of most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eukaryotic Kir's</ENAMEX> has numerous unique features that
        distinguish them from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. These
        features, which are numbered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Kir2</TIMEX>.1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX>, include in sequential order: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) A DxxTTxxDxxWR
        motif immediately preceding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a highly conserved
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tryptophan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) an insertion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the M1-P</TIMEX> loop that
        contains a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVxx</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX> or I) motif, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) the absence of an
        aromatic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> 'aromatic cuff position [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ]
        in the P segment helix, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) a glutamine near the end of the
        P helix, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) the absence of an aspartate at the end of the P
        segment signature sequence (TVGYGD) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RxxTxxCP</ENAMEX> motif in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-M2</ENAMEX> loop that is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> longer than in most
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) a glutamine in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S6</TIMEX>,
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) a hydrophilic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asn, Asp</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glu</ENAMEX>) near the
        mid region of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S6</TIMEX> that when negatively charged is involved
        in blockade of some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mg</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3shows that
        none of these features are present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX>. In
        fact, if only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-M2</ENAMEX> transmembrane pore-forming region is
        considered, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX> are more similar to some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> than to the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> (see below).
        This finding suggests that the common ancestor to KirBac
        and the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> did not have these features, and
        that they developed after the divergence of the eukaryotic
        Kir subfamilies.
        The intermediate nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-M2</ENAMEX> region
        between sequences of the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and several
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> can be analyzed several different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way is to perform a Blast search of the
        nonredundant database using only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-M2</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M1</NUMEX>-P-M2
        regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX>. When only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-M2</ENAMEX> region is used, the
        highest scores are with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the voltage-gated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kv</ENAMEX>), and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a bacterial
        family of putative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> that have transmembrane
        segments quite similar to those of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kv</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. We call
        this family <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">K-bac6tm1</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1-P-M2</ENAMEX> region is used, a
        Blast search also finds some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kir</ENAMEX> sequences among the
        highest scores. To analyze these relationships more
        quantitatively, we aligned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the M1-P-M2</TIMEX> regions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">224 Kv</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">11 K-bac6tm1</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">129 Kir</ENAMEX> sequences. We also aligned the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1-P-M2</ENAMEX> region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> bacterial sequences in
        the microbial sequence database that were most similar to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX> to produce a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KcsA</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. We then developed
        sequence profiles from each of these multisequence
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alignments</ENAMEX>. To identify the best alignments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX> and
        KirBac <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to the transmembrane segments of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, similarities of the sequence profiles were
        calculated as described in the Methods for different
        alignments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX> for both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the M1</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX>. The
        length of the hydrophobic region of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1</ENAMEX> is longer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>'s
        than for the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. To search for the best
        alignment between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>' or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>,
        longer M1 and M2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> sequence profile blocks
        where scanned through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">M2</ENAMEX> blocks indicated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>.
        3for the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. No indels were permitted in these
        calculations because they are unlikely to occur in
        transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX>. The P <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> was not included in
        this analysis due to the high number of identical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>
        indicating the obviously correct alignment between the
        different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Z scores (see Methods) for
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> alignments, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alignment A of Fig</ENAMEX>. 3and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alignment</ENAMEX> B
        proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] , are given in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. The
        Z value is the number of standard deviations the raw
        alignment score is from the mean of the normal distribution
        of scores obtained by random permutations of the alignment
        columns. The more positive the Z value, the less likely it
        is that the alignment occured by chance and that the two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protein families</ENAMEX> are not related. A Z value of zero
        indicates that the alignment is no more likely than a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> permutation of the sequence of amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alignment A</ENAMEX> was best for all comparisons. All Z values of
        Alignment A are greater than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.3</NUMEX> for all comparisons except
        when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is compared to the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>, for which
        the values range from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.9</NUMEX>. The finding that
        Alignment A is clearly the best for comparisons of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KirBac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to both the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and the Kir
        family, strengthens the argument that it is the proper
        alignment for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirs</ENAMEX> with the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>. Alignment A is also
        predicted to be best by all of the other methods that we
        used. (Except that for some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> sequences the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhiBlast</ENAMEX> approach predicted that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> indel near
        the beginning of S6 occurred within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S6</TIMEX> instead of in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-S6</ENAMEX> loop. We favor the loop location predicted by Clustal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX> because indels are more likely to occur in loops than
        within transmembrane helices.) Furthermore, when Z values
        were calculated for alignments of the different family
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">profiles</ENAMEX>, this alignment was found to score quite highly
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>'s even without considering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KirBac</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
        The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX>'s score are more similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kv</ENAMEX> and
        Kbac6TM1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX> but as more similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>'s
        for the remaining portions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> illustrates their
        intermediate nature.
        The best alignment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1</TIMEX> is less apparent. Alignment A
        produces high Z scores when the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M1</NUMEX> profiles of nonKir
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are compared to each other and when the KirBac
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The Z scores of
        Alignment A for comparisons of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to the other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are also reasonably high (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.9</NUMEX>). However, the Z
        scores for comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> to the non-Kir of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
        are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only between 1.2</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX>; and some other alignments
        scored higher for comparisons of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KirBac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kv</ENAMEX> and Kbac6tm1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alignment A</ENAMEX> can be
        inferred to be the best because it scores highest for
        comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> and for comparisons of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> to the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. M1 lies on the exterior of the
        KscA crystal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> where it should be very exposed to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lipids</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is in a membrane (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4a).
        This relatively exposed peripheral location explains why it
        tends to be poorly conserved when different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are
        compared.
        We favor Alignment A for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1</TIMEX> for several additional
        reasons. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) This alignment does not require any indels for
        alignment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX> with most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kv</ENAMEX> and
        KcsA-like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> for the entire <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M1</NUMEX>-P-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX>. Indel
        penalties were not included in our profile calculations. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> site suppressor experiments on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir2.1</ENAMEX> strongly
        suggest that a serine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1</TIMEX> forms a H bond with a
        glutamine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . This can occur when
        Alignment A is used to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">homology models</ENAMEX> based on the
        KcsA <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>. Futhermore, when a homology <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> (to be
        presented elsewhere) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KirBac1.1</ENAMEX> was developed, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">analogous glutamate residue</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX>, which is absolutely
        conserved among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX>, can form H-Bonds to the two
        adjacent asparagines <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1</TIMEX>; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of these is
        analogous to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir2.1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">serine</ENAMEX> mentioned above and the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is absolutely conserved among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX>. This
        interaction between the most polar conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> on M1
        (the glutamate) and the most polar conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> on M2
        (the asparagine) cannot occur with most other alignments of
        M1 when the strongly predicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alignment A</ENAMEX> is used for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alignment A</ENAMEX> is used to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">homology models</ENAMEX>,
        most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> that are highly conserved both within and
        between the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> of
        other transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX>. This point is illustrated in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helical</ENAMEX> wheel representations shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4of the
        M1-P-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M2</NUMEX> segments for the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Note that both
        M1 and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M2</NUMEX> display patterns that we call unilateral
        conservation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] in which <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> that are exposed to
        lipid on the outer surface are poorly conserved and very
        hydrophobic, whereas those that interact with other protein
        residues tend to be more highly conserved. These patterns
        would not be expected to be the same in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kv</ENAMEX> and Kbac6tm1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> because they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> additional transmembrane
        segments per subunit that should surround their core
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S5-P-S6</ENAMEX> region. In these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> that are
        conserved among the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> tend to cluster
        together, either near the center of the pore, where they
        determine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +selectivity, or at the region where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">M1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>,
        and M2 interact within the subunit. In the latter case,
        most of the very highly conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> are small
        (glycine, alanine, serine, threonine, or cysteine). Small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> are common where axes of adjacent transmembrane α
        helices come close together [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . Although there is
        little sequence similarity for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the M1 and M2</TIMEX> sequences when
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX> sequences are compared to those of the other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, the patterns of sequence conservation of the Kir
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">KirBac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are remarkably similar to those of the
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alignment A</ENAMEX> is used. Also note that
        many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> that are highly conserved within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each</TIMEX>
        family are identical or very similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> that are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conserved</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KirBac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, as indicated by the red
        and orange dashed lines that encircle some of the side
        chains.
        The patterns of sequence conservation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4are
        complemented nicely by mutagenesis studies that have been
        performed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> as shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. For example, note
        how well the poorly conserved (black) and highly conserved
        (red, orange and yellow) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">M1</ENAMEX> for the Kbac6TM1
        family of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4fcorrespond to the tolerant (blue) and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intolerant</ENAMEX> (red) Kir <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">M1</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5a, that was
        developed from the screening experiments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor et al</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
        ] ; and note how well the poorly conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> (black,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blue</ENAMEX>, cyan, and green) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> and highly conserved
        residue positions (magenta, red, and orange) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4b) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KcsA</ENAMEX>-like (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4d) families
        correspond to the tolerant (blue) and intolerant (red) M2
        Kir resiude positions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5b, that were colored
        according to results of alanine and tryptophan scanning
        experiments [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . These similarities of residue
        conservation patterns between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
        do not match as well for most other alignments between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4</NUMEX> ] have used Alignment A for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX> and the eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>. However, based on the
        results from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> mutant screens that identify <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> site
        suppressor mutations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M2</NUMEX> segments in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir2.1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor</ENAMEX>
        et al. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alignment B</ENAMEX> in which the Kir
        sequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3would be shifted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> positions to the
        left relative to the other sequences for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M1</TIMEX>, while those
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX> would be shifted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> positions to the right. They
        proposed a model to explain their data in which the Kir2.1
        has a structure different from that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX> in which M1
        interacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1</ENAMEX> helices of adjacent subunits throughout
        the entire transmembrane region. We are skeptical about the
        validity of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> because our three-dimensional
        modeling efforts indicate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor et al.</ENAMEX> model
        requires exclusion of the P <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> from the transmembrane
        region. It is highly unlikely that the only portion of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with substantial sequence identity between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>'s
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX> and that determines the selectivity of the
        channels for potassium would have entirely different
        structures and/or exist in different locations in these two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>. Our calculations indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alignment B</ENAMEX> is
        clearly inferior to Alignment A for both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2 and M1</TIMEX>; in
        fact, the Z values in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2of Alignment B</ENAMEX> average <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>,
        as expected for an incorrect alignment. Futhermore,
        Alignment A requires no indels for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the M1-P-M2</TIMEX> regions for
        most sequences, which were not included in the
        calculations, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alignment</ENAMEX> B requires <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. Finally, in
        our hands homology <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX> developed with
        Alignment A satisfy the mutagenesis data on which Alignment
        B is based as do models using alignment B, and models using
        Alignment A are more consistent with mutagenesis studies of
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3 13</ENAMEX> ] . No single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> in which the P
        segment has the structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcsA</ENAMEX> can satisfy all of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> site suppressor data of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] .
        However, their data are from an open conformation and the
        KcsA <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> is probably a closed conformation. Most of
        their data can be satisfied by a combination of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        conformations by dramatically altering the position of M1
        and the inner portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">M2</ENAMEX> for the open conformation
        (personal observation). It is also conceivable that some of
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> site suppressor data are due to an essential
        intermediate stage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein folding</ENAMEX> that differs from the
        final structure.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Gene transfer between <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> often complicates the
        interpretation of their evolution. There are now three
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of eukaryotic ion channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> for which only a
        few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homologs</ENAMEX> have been identified in prokaryotes: the first
        family is a glutamate-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GluR0</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ]
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synechocystis PCC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6803</TIMEX>, that is homologous to
        eukaryotic ionotrophic glutamate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>; the second
        family is a Na +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NaChBac</ENAMEX>, from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus halodurans</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] , [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ]
        and homologous sequences from 
        Thermobifida fusca and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magnetococcus sp</ENAMEX>. MC1 (personal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">observation, http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jgi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doe</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/</ENAMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> 6TM
        motif per subunit that is homologous to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CatSper</ENAMEX> Ca
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm cells</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] and to each of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">homologous 6TM</ENAMEX> motifs of the pore-forming subunit of
        eukaryotic Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+channels; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
        In each case, the nature of the prokaryotic sequence
        supports the hypothesis that the gene evolved <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prokaryotes</ENAMEX> rather than being transferred to the prokaryote
        from a eukaryote. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mutagenesis</ENAMEX> experiments [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> ] suggests that the ion selective region of eukaryotic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glutamate</ENAMEX> receptor pores have a gross structure similar to
        that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channels; however, only GluR0 has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel
        signature sequence and forms a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +selective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. This
        is consistent with the hypothesis that glutamate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
        evolved <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and then lost
        their selectivity in eukaryotes. Similarly, the fact that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaChBac</ENAMEX> is about equidistant from consensus sequences of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> 6TM motifs of eukaryotic Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] is
        consistent with the hypothesis that Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> initially
        evolved <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in prokaryotes as homotetramers from 6TM
        Kv-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and then underwent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> consecutive gene
        duplication events to evolve into the eukaryotic Ca
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> that have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> pore-forming subunit that
        contains <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four consecutive 6TM</TIMEX> motifs. Likewise, the
        hypothesis that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> evolved after transfer of a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eukaryotic Kir</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> is inconsistent with several
        findings: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) all eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> are more closely related
        to each other than to any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-M2</ENAMEX> region of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX> is more similar to that of some other bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +channels than it is to that of eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1-P-M2</ENAMEX> region of eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> have numerous
        features that occur in no other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX>. Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>'s probably evolved <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in
        prokaryotes as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX>. This finding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suggests KirBac</ENAMEX> has diverged less from the common ancestor
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> and eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>'s than have the eukaryotic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX> and supports the hypothesis that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir</ENAMEX>'s evolved first
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>.
        The utility of bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> in structural studies
        has been made abundantly clear by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">KcsA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>.
        Currently little is known about the three-dimensional
        structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of the structure of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac</ENAMEX> would be a major breakthrough in understanding the
        structure and functional mechanisms of this important
        family of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. Also, it would be interesting to
        compare the functional properties of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX> to those of
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kir's</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chimeric</ENAMEX> experiments in which <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are
        generated that combine part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KirBac</ENAMEX> with part of a Kir
        could be useful in identifying the role of features that
        are conserved among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eukaryotic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kir</ENAMEX>'s but that are not
        present in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KirBac's</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        Sequence searches were performed with the web-based
        programs Blast and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PsiBlast</ENAMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www3.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ncbi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nlm</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nih</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/BLAST/</ENAMEX>for sequences that were
        deposited in data bases and by tblastn at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ncbi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nlm</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nih</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/MicrobJ3last/unfinishedgenome.</ENAMEX>htmlfor
        unpublished microbial sequences. The default matrix
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">BLOSUM62</NUMEX>) and gap cost were used but a filter was not used
        in these searches. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Package Version 10.2</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetics Computer Group</ENAMEX> (GCG), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisc</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>. was used
        to align and edit multiple sequences and to calculated the
        distance matrices. Clustal W1.74 [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] was also used to
        make multisequence alignments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1-P-M2</ENAMEX> region for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of each <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Kir subfamily</NUMEX> plus the other sequences
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illustrated</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
        Quantification of the similarity of the transmembrane
        segments of the different channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> was accomplished
        by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> transforming the multiple sequence alignments into
        log-odds residue profile matrices. This was done by the
        method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henikoff & Henikoff</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] , as previously
        described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . In summary, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step was to weight
        each sequence in a multiple sequence alignment block
        according to its degree of similarity to the other
        sequences, which has the effect of minimizing the influence
        of highly redundant sequences in the final profile. These
        weights were calculated according to the method of Henikoff
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Henikoff</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] , which is based on the residue
        diversity at each position of the alignment. Next, the
        sequence-weighted counts were used to calculate the
        observed occurrence frequency of amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid residues</ENAMEX> at
        each column of the alignment block. To these real residue
        counts, pseudo-counts were added to better approximate the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> set of related sequences in nature (of which only an
        incomplete, non-random sample is known). Calculation of the
        pseudo-counts was based on the degree of diversity and
        statistical substitution probabilities for the specific
        residues occurring in each of the alignment columns. The
        recommended value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX> times the residue diversity was
        used for the total number of pseudo-counts, and the amino
        acid substitution probabilities were taken from the BLOSUM
        62 matrix [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . A substitution matrix based on
        transmembrane helices [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] was also used in some cases,
        however, the results were not altered substantially.
        Finally, the log-odds of occurrence of a specific residue
        is obtained from the logarithm of the sum of real and
        pseudo-counts divided by the background frequency that
        would occur in a random sequence by chance. The latter was
        calculated from the relative occurrence of all amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWISS-PROT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> sequence database [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . The
        final profiles were then constructed as matrices of
        dimension <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> by the number of positions in the multiple
        sequence alignment, where the column vectors provide the
        log-odds of occurrence of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> different amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> at
        each position.
        Having numerically represented the distribution of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple sequence alignments</ENAMEX>, the
        similarity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> profiles was calculated according to the
        method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pietrokovski</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . Specifically, the standard
        Pearson correlation coefficient was calculated for each
        aligned pair of column vectors and summed over the length
        of the alignment to provide a raw score. This was then
        converted to a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Z-score</ENAMEX>, which is the number of standard
        deviations the raw score is from the mean of the normal
        distribution of scores that would occur by chance. This
        distribution was estimated from the scores obtained by
        randomly permuting the columns of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the two profiles
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 40 thousand</NUMEX> times. In contrast to our previous method
        of calculating the chance distribution from the Blocks
        database [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] , using the profiles corrects for the
        specific composition of amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX>. The
        Z-score provides a measure of the statistical significance
        that can be compared among pairs of aligned profiles. More
        positive scores are less likely to occur by chance, and
        thus indicate a greater probability that the two protein
        segments are homologous.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        Kir: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inward rectifying K</ENAMEX> +channel
        KirBac: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inward rectifying K</ENAMEX> +channel homolog from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bacteria</ENAMEX>
        Kv: Voltage-gated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel
        Kbac6TM1: a family of prokaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> whose closest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kv</ENAMEX> channels.
        2TM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> transmembrane
        segments per subunit
        6TM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> transmembrane segments
        per subunit.
      
    
  
