
  
    
      
        Background
        Resistance to acyclovir (ACV) or penciclovir (PCV)
        generally arises by a single base mutation in either the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX> thymidine kinase (TK) or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol</ENAMEX>) gene [for
        a review, see reference [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] ]. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TK</ENAMEX> is not
        essential for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus replication</ENAMEX> in cell culture [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] ,
        although 
        in vivo analyses implicate it in HSV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virulence</ENAMEX>, pathogenicity and reactivation from latency [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 16 22</NUMEX> ] . Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> are dependent upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV TK</ENAMEX> for
        monophosphorylation, an event obligatory for the formation
        of the active triphosphate inhibitor [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> risolates
        often exhibit high levels of cross-resistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX>
        ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Viral populations</ENAMEX> are naturally heterogeneous; there are
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 to 8</TIMEX> TK deficient variants per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        4plaque-forming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> (PFU) of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HSV-1</TIMEX> (laboratory strains
        and clinical isolates) that have never been exposed to
        antiviral selection [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 13 15 17</ENAMEX> ] . Resistance to
        nucleoside <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX> arises readily in tissue
        culture probably by selection of pre-existing mutants [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 18</NUMEX> ] . Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Field</ENAMEX> 
        et al. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] demonstrated sequential
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX> inoculation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> to mouse receiving sub-optimal
        ACV therapy led to the selection and amplification of
        resistant virus 
        in vivo. After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> serial passages
        in the immunocompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, the infection became
        completely refractory to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ACV</ENAMEX> treatment.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acyclovir</ENAMEX> has been in part superceded by the oral
        prodrugs valaciclovir (VCV) and famciclovir (FCV), the
        latter being the oral version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 24</NUMEX> ] . No
        comparative studies of the emergence of resistance
        following sub-optimal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> or FCV have been reported and
        therefore set out to to select for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HSV-1</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-2</ENAMEX> isolates
        resistant to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> after using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prodrug</ENAMEX> selection.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Cell lines and virus strains
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MRC-5</ENAMEX> (pass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-25</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vero</ENAMEX> were grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modified Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium (DMEM) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          fetal calf serum (FCS) and incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . Vero cells were utilized for virus
          plaque purification and protein lysate preparations and
          MRC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells were used for PRA and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">PEA</ENAMEX>. TK-negative (TK -)
          human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">osteosarcoma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">143</ENAMEX>) cells were propagated in the
          medium described above and utilized for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-thymidine
          kinase enzymatic assay.
          Virus stocks were prepared by inoculating cells at
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plaque-forming units</ENAMEX> per MRC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> (PFU/<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>).
          Laboratory virus strains utilized were <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">HSV-1 SC16</NUMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-2 SB5</ENAMEX>. SC16 was kindly provided by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Safrin</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilead Sciences</ENAMEX>, CA). SB5 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">VR-2546</ENAMEX>) was
          plaque-purified from HSV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 333</NUMEX> kindly provided by Dr.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Priscilla Schaffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>) at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">passage 6</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Antiviral agents
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCV</ENAMEX> were synthesized at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GlaxoSmithKline</ENAMEX>. VCV
          was extracted from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valtrexâ„</ENAMEX>¢ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tablets</ENAMEX> and purity was
          confirmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPLC</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animal inoculation</ENAMEX> and treatment
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Female BALB/c</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Charles River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>) were infected intradermally in both ear pinnae with
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼l</NUMEX> of virus suspension containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 5PFU</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX> as
          previously described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . The same viral challenge was
          used for each subsequent in vivo passage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> or FCV were
          administered via drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> at either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml (a dose
          previously shown to be a highly effective [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] ; and D
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutton</ENAMEX>, unpublished observations) or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">suboptimal</ENAMEX> treatment) from the time of infection until
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 4</TIMEX> post-infection. No significant difference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>
          consumption between either of the treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> or the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">placebo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (drug-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>) was observed. Daily drug
          intake equated to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kg or 15 mg/kg</NUMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mg/ml</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml doses, respectively.
          To facilitate processing of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blinded samples</ENAMEX>, a coding
          system using sample number-passage number was applied.
          Virus sample numbers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HSV-1</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
          through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSV-2</ENAMEX>. The ears from one mouse were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pooled</ENAMEX> (passage number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> inoculation) and used to
          inoculate the ear pinnae of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> mouse (passage number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
          There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">replicate mice</ENAMEX> per treatment group
          (either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">suboptimally</ENAMEX> treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> or
          placebo-treated) and isolates from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> serial 
          in vivo passages examined. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five</TIMEX>
          individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaques</ENAMEX> were purified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times to
          homogeneity from the single drug-resistant virus mixture
          identified after 
          in vivo passage, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> (sample <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">passage 4</ENAMEX>). The clonal purified isolates from this sample
          were designated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-P4A<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-E</ENAMEX>.
          The 
          in vivo pathogenicity of selected
          virus preparations was assessed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> by monitoring
          lesion severity for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 days</TIMEX> following inoculation of the
          left ear pinna with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Ã— 10 5PFU</NUMEX>. Cumulative lesion scores
          (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day 0-14</TIMEX>) were then calculated from the individual daily
          scores.
        
        
          Virus isolation and in vitro assays
          Virus stocks were prepared as described previously [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> ] , titrated and characterized by PRA and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">PEA</ENAMEX>. On day
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> post-infection, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were euthanized, and both ear
          pinnae removed and pooled in coded tubes, one tube per
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>. The code was not broken until all tissue culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assays</ENAMEX> had been completed. The tissue was homogenized and
          virus stocks were prepared in MRC-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells from cell-free
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatants</ENAMEX>. Following virus adsorption onto the MRC-5
          monolayer, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> washes with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">phosphate-buffered</NUMEX> saline were
          performed to remove any residual antiviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cell-free</ENAMEX> virus was harvested, titrated and characterized
          by PRA and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEA</ENAMEX> prior to use in subsequent passage
          experiments (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). All PRA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEA</ENAMEX> and in vivo studies
          were carried out using virus that had undergone a single
          in vitro passage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRAs</ENAMEX> were performed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MRC-5 cells</ENAMEX> as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . The plating efficiency of
          the virus preparations generated 
          in vivo was determined according to
          the method developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">et al.</ENAMEX> with minor modifications [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> ] as reported previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> serial
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-fold</NUMEX> dilutions of virus were inoculated onto MRC-5
          cells in the absence of antiviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> or in the presence
          of either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACV</ENAMEX> or PCV at a concentration of antiviral <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          times higher than the average IC 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> for wild type parental <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-1</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSV-2</ENAMEX>, respectively. The mutation frequency was
          calculated as follows: mutation frequency = (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> titer
          in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>)/(<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus titer</ENAMEX> in the absence of
          drug). The frequency is often expressed as a plating
          efficiency, or percentage of viruses that are resistant,
          which is calculated as percent resistant = (mutation
          frequency) Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Antibodies</ENAMEX> and biochemical assays
          Western blot analysis was performed as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viral TK</ENAMEX> activity was determined by a
          modification of the method utilized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coen</ENAMEX> and Schaffer
          [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] as described in [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . Primers utilized for TK
          sequencing were described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Virus yield after antiviral treatment
          To evaluate efficacy of prodrug treatment in this
          model, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCV</ENAMEX> were provided in the drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> at
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml or at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml (sub-optimal treatment) for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> infected with either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-1 SC16</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-2 SB5</ENAMEX>. Titers
          (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 4</TIMEX> post-infection) of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 4.5</NUMEX> log 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> virus per ear were recovered from
          placebo-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, regardless of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus type</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
          As expected, a significant reduction in virus yield
          (greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX> log 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> decrease) was noted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          treated with either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VCV</ENAMEX> or FCV at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml following
          infection with either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-1</ENAMEX> or HSV-2.
          In the same experiment, virus yield from
          suboptimally-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> was reduced approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6</NUMEX> log 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> compared to placebo-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>,
          and these data are consistent with a previous report in
          which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> was administered at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/ml</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml, viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">replication</ENAMEX>, albeit
          reduced, was still ongoing, a prerequisite for the 
          in vivo selection of resistant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX>.
          A reproducible difference in virus yield between the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> antiviral treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> at the suboptimal
          concentration was evident, regardless of virus type. For
          HSV-1, the difference in titer between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX>-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.45</NUMEX> log 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 PFU/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FCV-</ENAMEX>treated (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.92</NUMEX> log 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 PFU/ml</ENAMEX>) was statistically
          significant (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.049</NUMEX>). Similarly for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSV-2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/ml</ENAMEX> was significantly more effective than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCV</ENAMEX> in this
          mouse model. Titers from VCV- or FCV-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.06</NUMEX> log 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 PFU/ml</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.55</NUMEX> log 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 PFU</TIMEX>/ml, respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.001</NUMEX>).
          Similar trends were noted when the antivirals were
          compared at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml for both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSV-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSV-2</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
          These observations can not be accounted for by
          differences in exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> since oral
          administration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCV</ENAMEX> results in almost identical
          blood concentration-time curves for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] .
          A more probable explanation is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> is approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-fold more potent than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> in murine cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ]
          .
          To select and amplify drug-resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, a
          total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> consecutive passages were performed, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">progeny</ENAMEX> virus from each passage was characterized 
          in vitro by PRA and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">PEA</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          PRA susceptibility
          
            Drug-selected HSV-1 SC16
            Mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> susceptiblities of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">HSV-1</NUMEX> isolates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> =
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX>) from passages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> are listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>.
            All isolates from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> treated with either placebo or
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCV</ENAMEX> remained sensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> (IC 
            50 s ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.28</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.50</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>)
            and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> (results not shown) according to the
            standard resistance breakpoint criteria, whereas
            isolates from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> had PCV IC 
            50 s ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.31</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.3</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml.</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> isolate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4th</ENAMEX> passage; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX>) in this treatment
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> was confirmed as resistant to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> (IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.3</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> (IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>). Generally, test
            sample IC 
            50 s varied within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold of the
            non-passaged control virus IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> , within each particular assay
            (data not shown); however, isolate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> was clearly
            different, with an IC 
            50 greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-fold</NUMEX> over the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> virus IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX>.
            Interestingly, although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> was resistant, the
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> pass isolate for this sample was completely
            sensitive to both antiviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agents</ENAMEX> (ACV IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.16</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml; PCV IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.53</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>). Therefore, the PRA
            provided no early indication at pass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> of potentially
            increasing resistant variants upon subsequent passage.
            Furthermore, the resulting virus preparation from
            subsequent passaging of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> reverted to a sensitive
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenotype</ENAMEX> (ACV IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.74</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml; PCV IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.74</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>), although
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">suboptimal</ENAMEX> treatment was still utilized.
          
          
            Drug-selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-2</ENAMEX> SB5
            Mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> susceptiblities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-2</ENAMEX> isolates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> =
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX>) from passages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> are listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>.
            No resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSV-2</ENAMEX> emerged among the total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> HSV-2
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">isolates</ENAMEX> tested from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (PCV IC
            
            50 s ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.66</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.85</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
            across treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>). These results were confirmed
            when the same isolates were tested for susceptibility
            to ACV (results not shown) and all the IC 
            50 s were sensitive over a similar
            range as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX>. As with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HSV-1</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-2</ENAMEX> test samples
            were generally within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold of the control virus IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> (data not shown).
          
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEA</ENAMEX> profiling
          
            Drug-selected HSV-1 SC16
            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">HSV-1</NUMEX> control virus preparation contained
            between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.002</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.02%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> rvirus and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.004</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.009%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> r,
            which equates to an average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.6 ACV rand 6.0</NUMEX> PCV
            rresistant viruses per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 5PFU</NUMEX>. Generally, the
            proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> rvirus varied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>-fold between
            tests when compared to the control virus, ranging from
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.004 to 0.009%</NUMEX> (data not shown); however, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> serial
            samples in the VCV-treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P3</TIMEX> and
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX>, clearly showed a substantial increase in the
            proportion of resistant virus relative to the wild type
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, specifically an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">and 8800</NUMEX>-fold
            increase, respectively (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P2</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.002%</NUMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P3</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>; and
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV r</ENAMEX>). Although passage 3 preparation
            contains a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> log increase in resistant virus compared
            to passage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, this level is insufficient to
            significantly increase the IC 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> . Consistent with the failure to
            establish an infection refractory to treatment, the
            proportion of resistant virus decreased to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.08%</NUMEX> PCV
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rand</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> rby passage 5.
          
          
            Drug-selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-2</ENAMEX> SB5
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-2</ENAMEX> control virus preparation contained
            between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.24</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.40%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> rand <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.13</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.40%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> rvirus,
            which equates to an average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.1 ACV rand</NUMEX> PCV
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rviruses</ENAMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 3PFU</NUMEX>. Generally, the proportion of
            resistant virus varied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX>-fold between tests
            when compared to the control virus (data not shown),
            however a continual increase in the proportion of
            resistant virus was seen with the sample <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> passages
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>). The proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> rvirus in
            sample <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> increased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.40% to 2.8% to 12.2%</NUMEX>
            throughout serial passages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> and declined to
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> by passage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>. All of these isolates were
            susceptible to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> by the PRA (IC 
            50 s for sample <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, passage 2
            through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>, were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.79</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.90</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml,</ENAMEX>
            respectively).
          
        
        
          Analysis of drug-resistant isolate
          Of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210</NUMEX> HSV isolates from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> treated sub-optimally
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCV</ENAMEX> or VCV, or with placebo, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> HSV-1 isolate,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> was identified in the PRA as an antiviral-resistant
          isolate. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> single plaques from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> were isolated
          after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> rounds of plaque purification and
          characterized. The clonal isolates were tested for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">susceptibility</ENAMEX> to using the PRA and were found to be
          highly resistant to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> (ACV IC 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 s > 25 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>;
          PCV IC 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 s > 25 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>), although
          susceptible to foscarnet.
          Western blot analysis showed that each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clonal</ENAMEX> isolate
          produced a truncated TK polypeptide compared to the wild
          type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TK protein product</ENAMEX> of approximately <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">43 kD</NUMEX> (Figure
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Moreover, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> clones were defective for TK
          activity compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-1 SC16</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-thymidine
          kinase assay (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>). Sequence analysis of the TK
          coding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> plaque isolates identified a
          G nucleotide insertion in the homopolymeric hot-spot G7
          tract at nucleotide <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">435</NUMEX>, a common mutation present in
          other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> rHSV isolates [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19</NUMEX> ] . This base insertion
          produced a frame shift in the coding sequence, resulting
          in a loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP / nucleoside</ENAMEX>-binding site and the
          creation of a premature stop codon at amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid 228</ENAMEX> to
          encode a truncated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> kD TK polypeptide.
          Lastly, the 
          in vivo pathogenicities of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-P4
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its clonal isolates (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4E</TIMEX>) were compared
          with the control virus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-1 SC16</ENAMEX>. Isolate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-P4
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX> resistant virus caused significant
          clinical disease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, only marginally less severe
          than that observed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-1 SC16</ENAMEX>. In marked contrast,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice inoculated</ENAMEX> with the plaque-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purified</ENAMEX> isolate, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4E</TIMEX>,
          developed a mild infection. The cumulative disease scores
          for parental virus control HSV-1 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SC16</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-P4E
          were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96 and 15</TIMEX>, respectively.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        HSV-1 or HSV-2 isolates were passaged serially <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
        times in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice inoculated</ENAMEX> in the ear pinnae and treated with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suboptimal</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kg</NUMEX> per day) concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCV</ENAMEX> or VCV
        to select resistant virus. Despite ongoing, albeit reduced,
        viral replication in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, selection of resistant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX> with the prodrugs proved difficult. Interestingly, the
        single drug-resistant isolate identified from this study
        reverted to a sensitive phenotype upon reinfection, even
        with suboptimal antiviral treatment.
        Although virus recovered at passage 4 from one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX>) was clearly resistant in the
        PRA (IC 
        50 s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.3 and 9.5</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX>,
        respectively), the preceding and the subsequent isolates
        were sensitive according to the criteria for defining
        resistance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEA</ENAMEX> identified a gradual increase in the
        proportion of resistant virus from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P2</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.002%</NUMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-P3
        (~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>) to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44%</NUMEX>). However, for the most part, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> did not correlate with the eventual appearance of
        drug-resistant virus as defined by the PRA. Consistent with
        this, an earlier studied showed that the proportion of
        drug-resistant virus in a preparation needs to be
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 50%</NUMEX> before resulting in a signficant change
        in IC 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        Biochemical characterization of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> isolate
        confirmed that impaired TK activity was most likely
        responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> phenotype. Sequence analysis
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these clonal isolates (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4E</TIMEX>) revealed insertion
        of an extra <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> homopolymeric region of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TK</ENAMEX> coding
        region. This mutation has also been detected in clinical
        isolates from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> immunocompromised [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] or with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] as well as resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX> selected in tissue
        culture [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 18</NUMEX> ] . Interestingly, this mutation was
        present in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> rclinical isolates obtained during
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivation</ENAMEX> in the absence of drug pressure, as well as in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> rstrains which evolved during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX> therapy and were
        followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX>-susceptible isolates at the next
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] .
        It was surprising to find that the ACV-resistant virus
        selected 
        in vivo was not retained or amplified
        in subsequent passages despite continued suboptimal
        treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX>. This result appears to be in direct
        contrast to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Field</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] who found that following
        selection of ACV-resistant virus 
        in vivo, such <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">viruses</ENAMEX> remained
        refractory to treatment upon subsequent passage using
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">suboptimal</ENAMEX> treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX>. The reason for this
        difference is unclear. However, the failure to maintain the
        resistant virus on subsequent passage suggests that the
        pathogenicity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> may have been only partially
        attenuated relative to the sensitive virus and indeed the
        pathogenicity of the clonal virus isolate, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4E</TIMEX>, was
        severely attenuated. Further studies on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-P4</TIMEX> clonal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">isolates</ENAMEX> and the clinical significance of their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attentuation</ENAMEX> should be explored.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Sub-optimal therapy of immunocompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with either
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCV</ENAMEX> or FCV did not readily select for HSV-mutants resistant
        to either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACV</ENAMEX> or PCV, suggesting that selection of
        resistance with either prodrug remains difficult using this
        system. All the virus isolates from each serial passage
        were examined by both PRA and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">PEA</ENAMEX>. The former is widely
        accepted as the gold standard for susceptibility testing of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX>, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACV</ENAMEX>, a correlation between PRA 
        in vitro IC 
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> and clinical outcome has been
        established. In spite of this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEA</ENAMEX> appears to have
        potential as an adjunct to the PRA by providing earlier
        detection of the emergence of resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSV</ENAMEX>. However, it is
        important to note that although an increase in the number
        resistant variants within isolates was readily detected by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">PEA</ENAMEX>, clinically-resistant virus did not develop in the
        immunocompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Therefore, the presence of resistant
        virus within an isolate, even at levels substantially above
        background, does not in itself indicate that increased
        resistance will follow, nor does it necessarily predict
        clinical resistance. It would be of interest to apply the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">PEA</ENAMEX> to an extensive series of clinical isolates,
        particularly isolates obtained from severely
        immunocompromised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, in order to evaluate the
        proportions of resistant virus that occur within different
        clinical isolates.
      
      
        Competing Interests
        None declared.
      
    
  
