
  
    
      
        Background
        Proteins recognizing specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequences play an
        important role in the regulation of gene expression and in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX>. Nearly all eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> transcribed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RNA Polymerase II</ENAMEX> for instance, contain the conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TATA</ENAMEX>
        box which is present upstream of the transcription start
        site. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TATA</ENAMEX>-box binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~30 kDa</NUMEX> component of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TFIID</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> binds specifically to the heptanucleotide
        A and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] and forms the core of the
        transcription initiation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. Additionally, many
        specific transcription factors bind to the upstream
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> in a sequence specific manner and regulate gene
        expression. For example in 
        Drosophila , a heat-shock
        transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (HSTF) can bind to consensus
        heat-shock response elements [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] and regulates expression
        of heat/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> inducible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. Promoter activity in later
        branching eukaryotes is greatly modulated by enhancer and
        repressor sequences which have no activity of their own but
        are the targets of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA biding proteins</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> complexes
        which can remodel the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">promoter chromatin</ENAMEX> to make it more or
        less accessible to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA polymerase</ENAMEX>. Biochemical assays have
        shown that the action of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>-dependent chromatin
        remodelling activities increase the accessibility of DNA
        within chromatin templates. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> cerevisiae <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWI/SNF</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , Ino80
        complex [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila NURF</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] are examples of
        some high molecular weight chromatin remodelling factors
        which can facilitate transcription by binding to
        chromatinized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA templates</ENAMEX>. However, none of the above
        chromatin remodelling factors binds to specific DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX>.
        Unlike transcription, the role of sequence specific DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding proteins</ENAMEX> in eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX> is not well
        characterized. In higher eukaryotes finding of specific DNA
        sequences essential for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX> has been elusive so
        far. In yeast 
        Saccharomyces cerevisiae , a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-protein origin recognition complex binds to ARS
        consensus sequence (ACS) in a sequence specific manner [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
        ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individual ORC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subunits</ENAMEX> have not been demonstrated to
        show DNA binding activity 
        in vitro . Recently, in an 
        in vitro study ScCdc6 has been shown
        to bind double stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . The minimal requirement
        for the binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Cdc6</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> has been mapped within its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>-amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid sequence</ENAMEX>. 
        Saccharomyces pombe <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ORC4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">subunit</ENAMEX> has
        been reported to contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity by using its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal AT hook <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . Neither ScCdc6 nor SpORC4
        showed any sequence specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity.
        Recombinant <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> protein 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila ORC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DmORC</ENAMEX>) binds to ACE
        region of the 
        Drosophila chorion gene [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . 
        In vivo , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DmORC</ENAMEX> co-localized with the
        amplified chorion gene locus. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Xenopus</ENAMEX>, biochemical
        analysis of replication and cell cycle events using egg
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extracts</ENAMEX> has helped to understand the mechanism of
        eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . However, two
        dimensional gel electrophoresis analysis of the rDNA locus
        showed that replication initiated at all sites tested [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
        ] . All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> human homologs of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila ORC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subunits</ENAMEX> have been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cloned</ENAMEX> and characterized [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . Other replication
        proteins like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cdc6</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cdt1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCMs</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cdc45</TIMEX> that are essential
        for initiation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX> have also been reported [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> ] . Conservation of replication factors among higher
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eukaryotes</ENAMEX> suggests that functionally they may play similar
        roles.
        In an attempt to identify DNA binding activity of human
        Cdc6, it was expressed and purified as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-Cdc6</ENAMEX> fusion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> from baculovirus infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sf9</ENAMEX> insect cells.
        Partially purified fractions (reduced glutathione eluate)
        containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GSTCdc6</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> showed an ACS binding activity in
        an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> dependent manner. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GSTCdc6 protein</ENAMEX> fraction
        contained both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the GSTCdc6</TIMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> KDa 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> frugiperda <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. The DNA
        binding activity was confined to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> kDa polypeptide. It
        was latter found that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p35</TIMEX> has an intrinsic affinity to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX>. This polypeptide bound to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast ACS</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in
        the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> matches to ARS consensus sequence
        were found to be essential for this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity
        both by gel shift assay as well as by in vitro foot
        printing assay. A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA fragment</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> matches from
        human c-myc replication origin <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> also showed p35
        binding activity suggesting that this polypeptide has
        intrinsic DNA binding activity. The implications of this
        DNA binding activity are discussed here.
      
      
        Results
        
          Partially purified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein fractions</ENAMEX> containing
          GSTCdc6 or GST contain an ACS binding activity
          We infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sf9</ENAMEX> insect cells with the baculovirus
          expressing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GSTCdc6</TIMEX>. Cells were harvested <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> post
          infection and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were extracted according to
          the procedures described in materials and methods. The
          GSTCdc6 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was partially purified by pull down on
          glutathione beads (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). The partially purified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was used in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding assays with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX> bp DNA
          fragment containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three conserved</NUMEX> boxes (A, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B1</ENAMEX> and
          B2) of the ARS consensus sequences (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7A& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">7B</ENAMEX>). As
          a control, we used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> alone, which was purified using
          the same strategy used for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GSTCdc6</TIMEX> purification. A DNA
          protein complex was formed in both the cases as evidenced
          by the retarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobility</ENAMEX> of the free 32P phosphate
          labelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 1B</ENAMEX>). The specificity of the DNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> was examined in a competition reaction by
          increasing the amount of unlabeled DNA fragment
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">containing ACS</ENAMEX> like elements. It was determined that the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA-Protein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> could be competed efficiently by
          increasing amount of unlabelled ACS like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">20×, 50×,</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100× and 200×</TIMEX> respectively) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fig 2</ENAMEX>). A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~350</NUMEX> bp DNA
          fragment from pBlueScript <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KS</ENAMEX> +( 
          Hin fI digested and subsequently
          gel purified) of similar base composition did not compete
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mobility Shift Assay</ENAMEX> when added at a similar
          concentration indicating a degree of specificity in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA-Protein complex</ENAMEX> formation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        
        
          An unidentified <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~35</NUMEX> kDa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> from baculovirus
          infected insect cells is responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding
          activity
          Partially purified fractions containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GSTCdc6</ENAMEX> or GST
          showed DNA binding activity. To further fractionate the
          proteins present in the partially purified GSTCdc6
          fraction the glutathione column was washed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> mM
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chloride</ENAMEX> prior to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GSTCdc6</NUMEX> elution with
          reduced glutathione. Western blot analysis using anti GST
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A) revealed that neither <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> mM nor 300
          mM fractions contained GSTCdc6 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A). GSTCdc6 protein
          was present only in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> eluted by reduced
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glutathione</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proteins</ENAMEX> released by different salt
          fractionation were separated on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE and
          visualized by silver stain (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3B</NUMEX>). A prominent band
          of molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mass</ENAMEX> ~<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> kDa was visualised both in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt eluate</ENAMEX>.
          To check whether the DNA binding activity was due to
          the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~35</NUMEX> kDa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GSTCdc6</ENAMEX> itself, gel shift
          assays were performed either using <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 ng ~35</NUMEX> kDa protein
          obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> wash or GSTCdc6 by itself (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3C). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eluate</ENAMEX> gave a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> shift which was
          identical with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> shift found with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GSTCdc6</ENAMEX> found in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. GSTCdc6 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eluted</ENAMEX> from the beads following high salt
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">wash</ENAMEX> failed to give any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> shift suggesting that the
          ~<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> kDa polypeptide was responsible for the DNA binding
          activity.
          To further test whether the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35</ENAMEX> is
          absolutely required for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt</ENAMEX> eluate was dialysed against low <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> buffer H<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/0.15</NUMEX>
          and then passed through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Superose</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> gel filtration
          column. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Each fraction</TIMEX> was checked for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding
          activity by gel <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX> assay using a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">32P</NUMEX> labelled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA fragment</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACS</ENAMEX> elements. DNA binding
          activity was found only in high molecular weight fraction
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~670 kDa</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A). Proteins present in the gel
          filtration fractions in the high molecular weight range
          (fractions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13-17</NUMEX>) were separated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE followed by
          silver stain. Surprisingly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX> was found to be present
          only in the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fraction 15</NUMEX> which contains the DNA binding
          activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B). The presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p35</ENAMEX> in the same
          fraction containing the DNA binding activity strongly
          suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35</ENAMEX> is responsible for the binding
          activity.
        
        
          DNA binding activity is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> dependent
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the hallmarks of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> ORC binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> ARS
          consensus sequences is its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> dependence [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . We were
          interested to see whether the DNA binding activity of the
          ~<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> kDa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> dependent or not. Gel shift assays
          were performed either in the absence or in the presence
          of increasing amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> in the reaction mixture (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). In the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, a very weak binding was
          observed whereas with increasing amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> strong
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> was detected. There is a threshold of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentration</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> mM and onwards) which stimulated the
          binding remarkably. A nonhydrolysable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> analog, ATPγS
          was used in the binding reaction to see whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hydrolysis</ENAMEX> is required for this binding. With increasing
          amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPγS</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> shift was completely inhibited
          suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> hydrolysis is required for this DNA
          binding activity. This was confirmed by adding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> back
          in the reaction mixture when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPγS</ENAMEX> was already present in
          the reaction. Under these reaction conditions, increasing
          amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> again stimulated the DNA binding activity
          even in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPγS</ENAMEX> suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPγS</ENAMEX> can
          be competed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> hydrolysis which
          is essential for this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, lanes
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 and 14</TIMEX>).
        
        
          p35 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">binds</ENAMEX> to A, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">B2</NUMEX> boxes of ARS consensus
          sequences as revealed by footprinting assay
          After establishing the fact that a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> kDa binds to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA fragment</ENAMEX> containing ARS
          consensus sequences, the exact site of binding of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was mapped by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>-phenanthroline
          footprinting assay. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNaseI</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,10-phenanthroline-cuprous</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is a small chemical
          probe which can demark the boundaries of the protected
          region clearly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was bound to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>' 32P
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">labelled 240 bp DNA fragment</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> ARS
          consensus sequence and separated from the free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> by gel
          shift assay. The gel was then treated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>-phenanthroline reagent as described in materials
          and methods. The bound and unbound <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was purified and
          allowed to run in a sequencing gel (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). On the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>-rich strand (bottom strand) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> protected regions were
          observed. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> region entirely covered the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A box</ENAMEX> of
          the ARS consensus sequence and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> region covered
          the overlapping regions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B1 and B2</TIMEX>. Therefore the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
          kDa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> has a strong affinity to bind to A, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B1</ENAMEX> and B2
          boxes of the ARS consensus sequences. The long stretch of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX> could be due to multimeric form of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35</ENAMEX> or
          could be due to the formation of a higher order
          nucleoprotein <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          p35 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">binds</ENAMEX> to A, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">B2</NUMEX> boxes and mutation in
          these boxes abolish DNA binding activity
          Previous studies of the structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ARS1</ENAMEX> in both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX> and chromosome contexts have shown that it
          contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> essential DNA element, A, that includes a
          perfect (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11/11</NUMEX>) match to the ARS consensus sequence (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7A), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> additional elements, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B2</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B3</ENAMEX>,
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> bases match to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> that are also
          important for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARS</ENAMEX> function [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . We were interested to
          see whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">B2</NUMEX> boxes were sufficient to allow
          p35 binding activity. We used the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p21N protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">terminal 150</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> of coding region of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">p21</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] as a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> when incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~35</NUMEX> kDa protein
          does not form a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA protein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 7D</ENAMEX>). The DNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragment</ENAMEX> was divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subfragments</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">(a</ENAMEX>, b, c and
          d; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7B) and subcloned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of p21N</TIMEX> fragment.
          Fragment 'a' does not contain any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> sequence whereas
          fragments b, c and d contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> like
          element. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACS</ENAMEX> containing sub fragments (b, c, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>)
          showed a mobility shift (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7D), which suggests that at
          least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> like element (either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/11</NUMEX> match or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX>
          match to ARS consensus sequence) is essential and
          sufficient for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX> binding activity. This was further
          confirmed by using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">subfragment</ENAMEX> d mutated at the ACS
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motif</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7C). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Subfragment</ENAMEX> d as shown if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig</ENAMEX> 7Dlane 10
          can bind strongly to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> kDa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, however mutation
          altering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ts</ENAMEX> of the core ACS sequence to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 7C</ENAMEX>) to generate the dmut oligonucleotide results
          in the abolition of its ability to bind <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX>. Therefore
          the ACS sequence is essential for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p35</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA protein</ENAMEX>
          complex formation.
        
        
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> kDa polypeptide binds to ARS consensus sequence
          found in c-myc origin of replication
          In 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. cerevisiae</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> have
          been implicated to be important both for ORC binding and
          origin function [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . We looked for the availability of
          such sequences in known human origins of replication like
          c-myc, lamin beta <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 and Dnmt1</TIMEX>. An origin of replication
          was mapped previously by nascent strand abundance
          analysis within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.0 kb</NUMEX> zone immediately upstream of c-myc
          gene [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . Detailed analysis of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.0 kb</NUMEX> upstream
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequences</ENAMEX> revealed the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ACS</ENAMEX> like elements
          separated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">148</NUMEX> nucleotides (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAAAGATAAAG</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAAAGAAAAAA</ENAMEX>). A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bp DNA fragment</ENAMEX> containing both the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> was amplified by polymerase chain reaction
          and the product was used subsequently for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX> binding
          studies.
          A strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> shift was observed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) which could
          be competed out using a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 bp</NUMEX> long double stranded oligo
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ACS</ENAMEX> like elements (oligo 'b', <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7B).
          Increasing amount of ~<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">65 bp</NUMEX> long unrelated (non specific)
          double stranded oligo did not have any effect on this
          binding activity suggesting that binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p35</NUMEX> to c-myc
          origin region is specific. Interestingly, analysis of
          Lamin beta 2 origin of replication <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> also revealed
          the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> match) like elements [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ]
          . Further studies are required to find out whether p35
          also binds to lamin beta 2 origin region.
        
        
          p35-ACS interaction is sensitive to high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>,
          temperature and EDTA
          The stability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-ACS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was further
          tested either by changing NaCl concentration in the
          reaction mixture, or by shifting reaction temperature or
          by adding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity was found to be
          sensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX> concentration (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>). Strong band
          shift was obtained <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to 0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M NaCl</ENAMEX>. NaCl concentration
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and above completely inhibited the binding
          activity. Higher temperature also showed a drastic effect
          on the binding activity. Normal DNA binding activity was
          observed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 42°C</TIMEX>. Temperature higher than 42°C
          completely abolished the binding activity suggesting that
          the off rate of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">p35</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> is much faster at higher
          temperature. Finally inclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> in the reaction
          mixture inhibited the binding reaction suggesting that
          the divalent cations are essential for this binding
          activity.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Few <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> have been reported in the literature, which
        are capable of binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> in a sequence specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
        dependent manner. Although transcription factors bind to
        specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequences</ENAMEX>, the binding activity is not
        dependent on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> hydrolysis. In contrast, chromatin
        remodelling factors like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWI/SNF</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ISW1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BRG1</TIMEX> facilitate
        transcription from chromatinised templates in the presence
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . However, these factors do not bind to
        specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequences</ENAMEX>. In eukaryotic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX>,
        sequence specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> dependent DNA binding activity has
        been demonstrated in yeast 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> cerevisiae where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORC</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six</NUMEX>
        polypeptide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> binds to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> ARS consensus sequence
        in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> dependent manner [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . The binding sites for
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORCs</ENAMEX> are not very clear at present. DmORC binds the
        critical elements of well-characterized, chromosome III
        amplification domain (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ACE3</ENAMEX> and ori-β, though the precise
        sequence recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DmORC</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ACE3</TIMEX> and ori-β have not
        been identified [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . Studies of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ScORC</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DmORC</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] indicate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> binding by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Orc1p</TIMEX> is required
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding. However <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> hydrolysis is not required for
        DNA binding for both the cases suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
        hydrolysis may be required for further downstream
        processes. Chromatin immunoprecipitation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ChIP</ENAMEX>) studies
        have demonstrated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpORC</ENAMEX> with 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pombe origins [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] and human ORC
        with the EBV 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ori P</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23 24</NUMEX> ] . Whether ORC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">binds</ENAMEX> to these sequences directly or indirectly with the
        help of other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are subject to in vitro DNA binding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assays</ENAMEX> using purified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ORC proteins</ENAMEX>.
        In this study, we report a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~35</NUMEX> kDa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baculovirus</ENAMEX> infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sf9</ENAMEX> insect cells that binds to yeast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> sequences in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> dependent fashion. p35 was purified
        as high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX>) eluate from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-Cdc6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beads</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-Cdc6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">eluted</ENAMEX> from the beads following high salt wash
        failed to show any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3C) whereas
        high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt eluate</ENAMEX> containing only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX> showed strong DNA
        binding activity suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p35</ENAMEX> not Cdc6 is
        responsible for the binding activity. This experiment was
        repeated several times and always the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> preparations
        containing p35 showed DNA binding activity.
        p35 has an intrinsic affinity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> moieties. Sf9
        insect cells were infected with baculovirus expressing GST
        alone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysate</ENAMEX> was allowed to bind to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> beads.
        High salt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">eluate</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> beads was tested
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity. Surprisingly, we observed a very
        similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> shift as obtained previously using high salt
        eluate from GSTCdc6 (data not shown). Further, high salt
        eluate from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GSTORC2 and GSTORC4</TIMEX> (GST fusion protein
        containing human origin recognition complex subunit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX>
        respectively) also showed DNA binding activity (data not
        shown). Therefore, it can be concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35</ENAMEX> interacts
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> and high salt concentration is required to disrupt
        this interaction. The nature and the specificity of the
        interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35</ENAMEX> are not clear at this
        moment. It is important to note that majority of the p35
        bound to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> or GST fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are released mostly at
        high salt concentration (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">300 mM</NUMEX>) allowing us to get rid of
        most of the impurities by stringent washing of the GST
        beads with buffer containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>.
        A weak DNA binding activity was found till <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). A strong stimulation was obtained
        at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> concentration. It is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35</ENAMEX> is
        purified as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> bound form but an associated weak ATPase
        activity does not allow it to give a strong binding
        activity. It is suggested that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> concentration may
        be sufficient to overcome this inhibitory effect. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hydrolysis</ENAMEX> is essential for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity of p35
        since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPγ S</ENAMEX>, a nonhydrolysable analog of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> completely
        inhibited the binding activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). It is possible
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> is required for strand opening which needs to be
        further explored. An insect cell factor, polyhedrin
        promoter binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> has been reported previously,
        capable of binding to AT rich DNA sequence [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
        However, the reported DNA binding activity was unusual in a
        sense that the activity was heat and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> concentration
        resistant. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">100 mM EDTA</TIMEX> concentration did not affect the DNA
        binding activity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding activity reported in this
        study was found to be temperature, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> and salt
        concentration sensitive (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) suggesting that this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polypeptide</ENAMEX> is completely different from the polyhedrin
        promoter binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
        p35 showed a strong DNA binding affinity towards ACS
        like elements. This was confirmed first by using unlabeled
        specific competitor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> which completely abolished the
        binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">32P</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">labelled probe</ENAMEX>. Competition using unrelated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> did not affect the DNA binding activity. We took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p21N</TIMEX>,
        which normally does not bind to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX>, to further test the
        binding specificity. Introduction of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ACS</ENAMEX> like
        element (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> match) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p21N</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSc</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSd</ENAMEX>) showed a
        strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> shift (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7D) suggesting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> ACS
        like element is sufficient for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX> binding. This was
        further confirmed by making mutations in the ARSd fragment.
        The resulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSdmut</ENAMEX> did not show any p35 binding activity
        suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> like element itself but not the
        adjacent sequences are essential for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p35</TIMEX> binding
        activity. However, a systematic mutational analysis of ACS
        like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> will be required to explore the exact binding
        specificity of p35 towards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> like elements. ACS elements
        are normally AT rich. However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX> did not bind to random
        AT rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX>. p35 did not bind to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p21N</NUMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSa</ENAMEX> which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contains ARSa</ENAMEX> oligo (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> AT rich) with no ACS like element.
        Surprisingly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX> showed strong binding activity in the
        presence of the oligo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSb</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64%</NUMEX> AT rich), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSc</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX> AT
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSd</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74%</NUMEX> AT rich) respectively (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7D</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSb</ENAMEX>, c and d contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> like element (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
        7B). Finally the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX> phenanthroline footprint analysis
        confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">binds</ENAMEX> to A and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B1-B2</ENAMEX> boxes of the ARS1
        DNA fragment. At this moment, the function of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35</ENAMEX> is not
        very clear. It may play major role(s) in the transcription
        of certain insect cell genes. It may as well be responsible
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX>. The fact that it binds to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> ACS
        and to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA fragment</ENAMEX> from c-myc origin of replication
        region containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast ACS</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
        dependent manner further strengthen the hypothesis. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> cerevisiae origin recognition
        complex (ORC) binds to ARS consensus sequences in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
        dependent fashion and this binding is essential for both
        origin function and activity. It is interesting to note
        that a huge <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> origin recognition complex binds to
        yeast ARS1 whereas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX>, a small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is showing same
        kind of protection as evidenced by foot print analysis
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). We believe that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p35</NUMEX> forms an oligomeric structure
        or it maintains a multimeric form which may explain the
        wide footprint over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ARS1</TIMEX> fragment. The presence of p35
        in high molecular weight fraction (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~670 kDa</NUMEX>) following
        superose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> gel filtration chromatography strengthen this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypothesis</ENAMEX> and clearly suggests that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p35</NUMEX> forms an
        oligomeric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>.
        ARS consensus sequence has been found near the vicinity
        of c-myc, lamin beta <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 and Dnmt1</TIMEX> replication origin [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ]
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> from insect cells and finding its human counterpart
        will greatly help in elucidating its possible function in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        The data presented here leads to the identification and
        characterization of a polypeptide from insect cells with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> dependent DNA binding activity. This is an important
        and unique observation. In 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. cerevisiae</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> have
        been reported to be essential for ORC binding and
        replication initiation. Yeast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> found in
        c-myc and lamin beta 2 origin region may play similar roles
        in replication initiation. However, it is also possible
        that p35 is a transcription factor which may facilitate
        transcription of some insect cell genes. Further
        characterization of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">p35</NUMEX> from insect cells and finding its
        human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">homolog</ENAMEX> will be very helpful to dissect its
        functional role in replication and/or transcription.
      
      
        
          Plasmid construction
          Cloning of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cdc6 cDNA</ENAMEX> is described elsewhere.
          Coding sequence of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cdc6</ENAMEX> was cloned in pFastBac-GST
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies, Inc.</ENAMEX>) to express GST fusion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bp DNA fragment</ENAMEX> from 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> cerevisiae <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ARS1 chromosomal DNA</ENAMEX>
          replication origin containing all the key elements
          including boxes A, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B2 and B3</TIMEX> was subcloned in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pBlueScript KS</ENAMEX>(+) between 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eco RI</ENAMEX> and 
          Hin dIII. Subsequently 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eco</ENAMEX> RI- 
          Hin dIII fragment was end labelled
          using γ <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">32P</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and used either for gel shift assay or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">copper</ENAMEX>-phenanthroline foot print assay. p21N, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> terminal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">~150 bp of p21</ENAMEX>) was previously cloned in pBlueScript
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KS</ENAMEX>(+) between 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eco RI</ENAMEX> and 
          Hin dIII sites.
          Complementary oligos corresponding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSa</ENAMEX>, b, c, d
          and dmut (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7B) were synthesized (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~50</NUMEX> bases in length)
          and subsequently annealed to get double stranded oligos.
          p21N<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/KS</ENAMEX>(+) construct contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only one</NUMEX> 
          Stu I site which is present within
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p21N</NUMEX> insert. All the annealed double stranded oligos
          were cloned into the 
          Stu I site using blunt end
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligation</ENAMEX>. The sequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARSa</ENAMEX>, b, c and d are
          followed:
          ARSa:
          ttagtttttcggtttactaaatcgtaatagaaatgtagaacaataaaatgt
          ARSb:
          tctaaaatacaaatctagaaaatacgaacgaaaagttttccggacgtccgt
          ARSc:
          cggacgtccgttcacgtgtttgttatgaatttatttatgatgagtcattat
          ARSd:
          tgagtcattattggataaagaatcgtaaaaactgctttaaacgataaaa
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Plasmid</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> kb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA fragment</ENAMEX> from c-myc
          origin region was a kind gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Leffak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>. Forward and reverse PCR primers
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gaagaaaaactctcttttc</NUMEX>-3' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">atttgctgggttgaaaaatg</NUMEX>-3'
          respectively) were used to amplify 300 bp region
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ACS</ENAMEX> like elements.
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GSTCdc6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> in insect cells and
          purification
          Baculoviruses were produced from the recombinant
          pFB-GST plasmid using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bac</ENAMEX>-to-Bac expression system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies Inc.</ENAMEX>). Sf9 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) were infected
          with the pFB-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GSTCdc6</NUMEX> or pFBGSTbaculovirus according to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>' recommendations. Cells were harvested
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> post-infection. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell pellet</ENAMEX> was washed once
          in cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphate-buffered saline</ENAMEX> and subsequently
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuspended</ENAMEX> in hypotonic lysis buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>.Cl, pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.9</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MgCl2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM phenylmethylsulfonyl
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fluoride, 2 μg/ml pepstatin, 2 μg/ml leupeptin, 5 μg/ml</ENAMEX>
          aprotinin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM dithiothreitol). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> suspension was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homogenized</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dounce</ENAMEX> homogenizer using a B-type pestle
          followed by centrifugation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX> rpm for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> min. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pellet</ENAMEX> containing the nuclei was lysed in buffer H<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/0.15</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES/KOH</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.02%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonidet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-40</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM magnesium acetate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          glycerol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM phenylmethylsulfonyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 μg/ml</ENAMEX>
          pepstatin, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 μg/ml leupeptin, 5 μg/ml aprotinin, 1</ENAMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dithiothreitol</ENAMEX>). The resulting suspension was subjected
          to ammonium sulphate precipitation (starting with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          followed by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> and finally <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>). The pellet after the
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> ammonium sulphate cut was resuspended in buffer H<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/0.0</NUMEX>
          (no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>) and then dialyzed overnight against buffer
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">/0.15</NUMEX>. The dialyzed sample was then bound to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> beads
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with buffer H<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">*/0.15</TIMEX>
          (containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NaCl</ENAMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM KCl). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proteins</ENAMEX>
          were eluted using reduced glutathione elution buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mM Tris</ENAMEX>.Cl, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM reduced glutathione, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonidet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-40</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunoblotting</ENAMEX> and Silver stain
          Anti-GST polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnologies</ENAMEX>. Western blotting technique
          was carried out using standard protocol. The silver stain
          protocol is described elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Gel <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX> assay
          Gel <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation assay</ENAMEX> was performed with slight
          modification of the protocol used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mukhopadhyay et al</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> fragments to be used for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">gel retardation</ENAMEX>
          assay were endlabeled with γ <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">32P</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>. The binding
          reactions were performed in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 μl</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM
          Tris-HCl, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">30 μg/ml</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">v/v</ENAMEX>) glycerol for
          most of the reactions. The mixture was incubated at 37°C
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> and loaded directly on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> polyacrylamide gel
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBE</ENAMEX> buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tris</ENAMEX> base, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">boric acid</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.3</NUMEX>). The gel was run at 150 V for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>,
          dried and autoradiographed.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Copper</ENAMEX>-phenanthroline footprint assay
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Copper</ENAMEX>-phenanthroline footprint assay was
          performed essentially by using the protocol described by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwabara et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA-protein gel</ENAMEX> is run in the
          absence of free radical scavengers as described in gel
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation assay</ENAMEX>. The gel is placed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM
          Tris-HCl, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>. The gel is further incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing equal volume of solution
          A (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> mM <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Phenanthroline</ENAMEX> monohydrate in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cupric</ENAMEX> sulphate mixed with equal volume followed by
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:10</TIMEX> dilution with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>) and solution B (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-Merceptopropionic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>). Finally the gel is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soaked</ENAMEX> in solution C (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">28 mM 2,9</NUMEX> Dimethyl-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phenanthroline</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> min. The gel is washed
          twice in deionised <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. After the pre-treatment of the
          gel, it is autoradiographed and the retarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> is cut
          from the gel and placed in an eppendorf tube. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> is
          eluted from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gel</ENAMEX> slice, denatured and loaded in a
          sequencing gel. The sequencing gel is fixed, dried and
          the bands were visualised by autoradiography.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        SKD designed, performed and co-ordinated the whole
        study. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NM</ENAMEX> participated in insect <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> culture and helped in
        making and amplification of baculovirus expressing GST-Cdc6
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RKS</ENAMEX> helped in making the figures and drafting the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> helped in analysing the data and critically
        reviewed the manuscript. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the
        final manuscript.
      
    
  
