
  
    
      
        Background
        Glucocorticoids influence a wide spectrum of cellular
        functions through their action on soluble intracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. In most cells, unliganded glucocorticoid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX> (GR) reside predominately in the cytoplasm, where
        they exist as a heteromeric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> comprised minimally of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>-kDa and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>-kDa heat shock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hsp90</ENAMEX> and
        hsp70). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p60/Hop, p23, hsp40, FKBP52,</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FKBP51</ENAMEX>) have been implicated in the
        assembly/stabilization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GR-hsp90-hsp70-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> in a
        form that has high affinity for agonist [for review, see
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Ref. 1, 2, 3</ENAMEX>]. Upon agonist binding, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> undergoes
        a transformation, and the ligand bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> translocates into
        to the nucleus in a manner that is determined by a nuclear
        localization sequence (NLS) contained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>].
        There the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> acts as a ligand-activated transcriptional
        stimulator or repressor of primary response genes by
        binding to glucocorticoid hormone-responsive elements (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRE</ENAMEX>)
        contained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid</ENAMEX>-responsive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and either facilitating or repressing the formation
        of an active transcriptional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
        Although little is known about the molecular machinery
        that regulates <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid</ENAMEX> receptor movement through the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytoplasm</ENAMEX> and into the nucleus, several studies suggest
        that movement is influenced by reversible phosphorylation.
        Evidence for this originated from the studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qi et</ENAMEX> al.
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5, 6</ENAMEX>], which revealed that the hormone insensitivity
        produced by cellular transformation with v-mos (a
        serine/threonine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> that acts as an oncogene)
        results from both a decrease in the nuclear retention of
        liganded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and a decrease in the reutilization of GR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> back into the cytoplasm. Subsequently,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeFranco et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>] reported that treatment with okadaic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, a potent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ser</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thr protein phosphatase inhibitor</ENAMEX>, also
        results in inefficient nuclear retention of agonist-bound
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> and the cytoplasmic "trapping" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> in a form that is
        unable to "recycle". Recent studies with okadaic acid
        suggest phosphorylation alters the high affinity binding of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> to hsp-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>, and that an intact cytoskeleton is required
        for ligand-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GR</ENAMEX> translocation through the cytoplasm
        to the nucleus [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>].
        The ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">okadaic acid</ENAMEX> to influence the
        intracellular partitioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> suggests that an okadaic
        acid sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ser</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thr protein phosphatase</ENAMEX> (PPase)
        participates in the regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>. In vitro,
        okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> acts as a potent inhibitor of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">serine</ENAMEX>/threonine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein phosphatases</ENAMEX> type 1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PP1</NUMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2A</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PP2A</NUMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9, 10</ENAMEX>].
        Accordingly, many of the effects produced by the treatment
        of cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">okadaic acid</ENAMEX> have been attributed to the
        inhibition of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> enzymes. However, due to toxicity
        and solubility constraints, in living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> it is difficult
        to distinguish the actions of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">PP2A</NUMEX> from those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP1</ENAMEX> using
        okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, it is now clear that
        there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> isoforms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP1</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP1Î±</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP1Î´</TIMEX>, PP1Î³ 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and PP1Î³ 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 12, 13</TIMEX>], <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> isoforms of PP2A
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP2A Î±</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP2AÎ²</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 15</TIMEX>]) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> structurally related
        phosphatases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP4</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 18</TIMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP6</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP7</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>]. Although detailed dose-response studies have not been
        reported for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native PP5</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP6 and PP7</TIMEX>, studies with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP4</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>] and recombinant PP5 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>] indicate they are also
        sensitive to okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">calcineurin</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PP2B</NUMEX>) and
        PP2C, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP7</ENAMEX> is apparently insensitive to inhibition by
        okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>].
        Recent studies indicate that PP5 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GR-hsp90</ENAMEX> complex [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 23</TIMEX>] suggesting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> may
        influence the actions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRs</ENAMEX>. However, studying the
        cellular roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5</ENAMEX> has proven difficult, in part,
        because no physiological substrates for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> have been
        identified. In addition, in crude <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell homogenates</ENAMEX> PP5
        resides predominately in an inactive state that represents
        <<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> of the measurable PPase activity. To characterize
        the cellular roles of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> we have, therefore, developed
        chimeric antisense <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX>'- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> -(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-methoxy</ENAMEX>) ethylphosphothioate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oligonucleotides</ENAMEX> capable of inhibiting the expression of
        human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5</ENAMEX> at nanomolar concentrations. Because the lead
        compound targeting PP5 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ISIS 15534</NUMEX>) acts via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAase H</ENAMEX>
        mediated degradation, studies with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15534</NUMEX> do not allow
        us to assess how rapid changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> activity affect
        cellular functions (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern</ENAMEX> analysis indicate that it
        takes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~ 6</NUMEX> for the mRNA degradation to occur and, due to the
        half-life of the preexisting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, it takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">~ 24 hours</TIMEX>
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels to fall [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. Nonetheless, ISIS
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15534</NUMEX> potently inhibits the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5</ENAMEX> in cultured
        cells for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">~ 48-72 hours</TIMEX> (IC 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><75 nm</NUMEX>), which affords a ~
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-48 hour</TIMEX> window in which the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> is
        essentially ablated [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 25</TIMEX>]. More importantly, because
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX> has no effect on the structurally related PPases
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>], it can be employed to specifically inhibit the
        actions of PP5 by suppressing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5 protein</ENAMEX> levels in
        cultured human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX>.
        To assess the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5</ENAMEX> in the regulation of
        GR-mediated events, binding studies were conducted with [
        3H]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">dexamethasone</ENAMEX> before and after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15534</NUMEX>-mediated
        suppression of PP5 expression. These studies revealed that
        the suppression of PP5 expression had no apparent effect on
        dexamethasone binding, suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> does not affect
        the formation of the high-affinity ligand binding complex
        or hormone binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. In contrast, mobility
        gel-shift analysis revealed that treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> 15534
        produces a marked increase in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRE</ENAMEX>-containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, and transient transfection studies
        employing a GR-responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmid revealed that
        the suppression of PP5 expression activates GR-dependent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. When A549
        cells were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX> and then dexamethasone,
        the effect was <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX>, with maximal dexamethasone induced
        luciferase activity ~ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times greater than the maximal
        dexamethasone-induced response attainable in the presence
        of PP5 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. Together, these studies indicate that PP5
        acts as a suppressor of GR-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">transcription</ENAMEX>.
        To further characterize the mechanism by which PP5
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affects GR</ENAMEX> function, in the present study we employed a
        GR-GFP fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and fluorescent microscopy to follow
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> in cells treated with dexamethasone and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX>. These studies indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> mediated
        suppression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>-function arises from the ability of PP5
        to suppress the nuclear accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRs</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        
          Inhibition of PP5 by okadaic acid
          Okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> is widely employed to inhibit PPase
          activity in eukaryotic cells, and the observed effects
          are often attributed to the inhibition of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP1 and PP2A</TIMEX>.
          However, as seen in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, the dephosphorylation of
          phosphohistone by the catalytic subunit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">purified</ENAMEX> PP5
          from bovine brain is also <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potently</ENAMEX> inhibited by okadaic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>. Okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> inhibits the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5</ENAMEX> in a
          dose-dependent manner, having an IC 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.58</NUMEX> +/- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.41</NUMEX> nM. Under
          identical assay conditions, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">okadaic acid</ENAMEX> is a more potent
          inhibitor of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP2A</TIMEX> (IC 
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 ~ 0.05 nM</NUMEX>) and weaker inhibitor of
          PP1 (IC 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 ~ 45 nM</TIMEX>). However, the activity of
          PP5 against histone (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">865 +/- 31 nMoles Pi/min/mg protein</ENAMEX>)
          is less than that of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP2A</TIMEX>. Therefore, whereas assays
          conducted with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP1 and PP2A</TIMEX> were conducted with a
          concentration of enzyme that is diluted below the
          titration endpoint (defined as the concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enzyme</ENAMEX> after which further dilution no longer affects the
          IC 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ; [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>]) because the activity of
          PP5 upon further dilution was below that necessary for
          accurate quantification, we could not establish a clear
          titration endpoint with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX>. Based on titration studies
          with microcystin-LR to estimate the actual amount of PP5
          in the reaction, an estimate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          i for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">okadaic acid</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.07</NUMEX> +/- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.16</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nM</ENAMEX>. Still, it should be kept in mind that the true <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          i may be slightly lower. Nonetheless,
          it is clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> is sensitive to inhibition by
          okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> at the concentrations that also affects the
          activity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP1 and PP2A</TIMEX>. Therefore, when okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> is
          employed to treat cells at a concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">>1-5 nM,</ENAMEX>
          the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> is also affected.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX> promotes nuclear localization of
          GR
          To determine whether the suppression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> activity
          influenced the subcellular distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>, plasmids
          expressing a GR-GFP fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were microinjected
          into cells that were previously treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> 15534.
          In these studies the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GR-GFP</ENAMEX> used was derived from the
          fusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> to a GR mutant that retained the ability to
          bind agonist, translocate to the nucleus, and bind <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>,
          but lacked transactivation activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. When plasmids
          expressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFP</ENAMEX> were injected into the nuclei of
          cells and the cells were grown in serum-containing
          medium, the majority of the expressed GR-GFP localized to
          the nuclei of the injected cells, as expected due to the
          presence of glucocorticoids in the serum. Thus, after
          microinjection, the cells were grown in medium
          supplemented with serum for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 to 6 hours</TIMEX> and then serum
          starved <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> to cause the redistribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFP</ENAMEX>.
          In the absence of serum, GR-GFP localized throughout the
          cells, with equal intensity in both the nucleus and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytoplasm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A). Upon treatment of these cells with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dexamethasone</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>) the GR-GFP
          efficiently translocated to the nucleus. To assess the
          role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5</ENAMEX> in the intracellular partitioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>,
          cells were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX> or a mismatched
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ISIS 15521</NUMEX>) at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM, which
          essentially ablates <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> expression in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 25</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 hours</TIMEX> after antisense
          treatment, the cells were microinjected with pGR(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>)-GFP
          and subjected to serum-starvation as described above. In
          cells treated with the mismatch control prior to
          microinjection, GR-GFP expression was indistinguishable
          from that in untreated cells: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFP</ENAMEX> was distributed
          evenly throughout the cytoplasm and nucleus (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX>).
          In contrast, following treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ISIS 15534, GR</ENAMEX>-GFP
          was localized in the nucleus without dexamethasone
          treatment. The percentage of cells displaying
          predominantly nuclear GR-GFP or cytoplasmic GR-GFP from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          independent experiments were tabulated and are presented
          in Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2B</TIMEX>. In control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the absence of
          dexamethasone, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of the cells showed
          nuclear>cytoplasmic localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFP</ENAMEX>. Similarly,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with mismatch oligonucleotide
          displayed greater nuclear than cytoplasmic localization
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFP</ENAMEX>. By contrast, the percentage of cells showing
          more nuclear than cytoplasmic distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFP</ENAMEX> was
          ~ <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">93%</NUMEX>, ~ <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88% and ~ 98%</NUMEX> in cells treated with either
          dexamethasone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ISIS 15534</NUMEX> and
          PP5 plays a role in the nucleo-cytoplasmic partitioning
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Inhibition of PP5 expression does not globally
          affect nuclear shuttling
          The ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX> treatment to induce the
          nuclear accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFP</ENAMEX> suggests that PP5
          influences the subcellular distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>.
          Alternatively, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> could have a more global role,
          possibly regulating entire nuclear transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX>. To
          test the latter, the effect of PP5 suppression on the
          nucleo-cytoplasmic shuttling of another transcription
          factor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFAT</ENAMEX>, was investigated. In these studies, a
          stable GFP-NFAT expressing HeLa cell line was employed [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>]. As seen in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, in the absence of any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, the
          GFP-NFAT <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is localized entirely within the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytoplasm</ENAMEX>. Upon treatment with the calcium ionophore
          ionomycin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-NFAT</ENAMEX> translocates rapidly to the nucleus.
          The fusion protein then relocates to the cytoplasm if the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is washed out of the cells for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hours</TIMEX>. When the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-NFAT HeLa</ENAMEX> cells were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX>, the
          distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-NFAT</ENAMEX> was indistinguishable from
          untreated cells or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with mismatched control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligonucleotides</ENAMEX>. Northern analysis confirmed the ability
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15534</NUMEX> to suppress PP5 expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hela</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>.
          Therefore, the results indicate that suppression of PP5
          expression does not have a global effect on all nuclear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shuttling proteins</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Like other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid hormone receptors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRs</ENAMEX> are
        phosphoproteins, and reversible phosphorylation of specific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ser/thr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> or associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> has been
        implicated in the regulation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) hormone binding to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytoplasmic</ENAMEX> GR-complex, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the translocation of the GR
        between the cytoplasm and the nucleus, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the binding of
        ligand activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GR</ENAMEX> to consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRE</ENAMEX> in the promoter
        regions of GR-responsive genes, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) the formation of an
        active transcriptional complex [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 5, 6, 7, 8, 28</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 31</TIMEX>]. Many of the kinases that catalyze the
        phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRs</ENAMEX> and associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> have been
        identified. However, little is known about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPases</ENAMEX> that
        must also participate in the regulation of GR-mediated
        signaling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>.
        Several recent studies indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> participates in
        the regulation of GR-induced gene expression. First,
        dexamethasone-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">transcription</ENAMEX> is markedly enhanced
        when the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> is suppressed by treatment with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, both co-immunoprecipitation
        studies and studies with mutant forms of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> indicate that
        PP5 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GR-hsp90</ENAMEX> complex [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 23</TIMEX>].
        However, binding assays revealed that the suppression of
        PP5 expression has no apparent effect on [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3H</TIMEX>]dexamethasone
        binding [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. Therefore, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> appears to act as a
        suppressor of GR-induced gene expression via a mechanism
        that does not alter receptor number or the binding of
        hormone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>. To further characterize the relationship
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between PP5</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>, in the present study we employed a
        GR-GFP fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> to track the movement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRs</ENAMEX> in A549
        cells following treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> or ISIS 15534.
        These studies revealed that in the absence of
        glucocorticoids, GR-GFP localized mainly in the cytoplasm.
        As expected, treatment with dexamethasone results in the
        efficient translocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFPs</ENAMEX> into the nucleus.
        Nuclear accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFP</ENAMEX> was also observed when the
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5</ENAMEX> was suppressed by treatment with ISIS
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15534</NUMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">~ 24 hours</TIMEX>. This translocation of GR-GFP
        occurred without the addition of glucocorticoids and in the
        presence of serum free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. Thus, in the absence of
        physiological concentrations of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRs</ENAMEX> accumulate in the
        nucleus of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells. This finding is consistent with data
        obtained from gel-shift analysis and transfection studies
        conducted with GR-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmids, where a decrease in
        PP5 levels facilitates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and
        produces an increase in GR-transactivation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. Together,
        these studies suggest that the increase in GR-induced
        transcriptional activity observed when the expression of
        PP5 is suppressed by treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX> results from
        the nuclear accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>.
        The mechanism by which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> suppresses the nuclear
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> is not clear. The current data is
        consistent with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> acting to suppress the nuclear import
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRs</ENAMEX>. Alternatively, the data is also consistent with PP5
        acting to promote the nuclear export of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRs</ENAMEX>. Because
        the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX> treatment are not readily
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reversible</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">washout</ENAMEX> experiments needed to distinguish
        between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possibilities cannot be conducted until a
        specific and reversible inhibitor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> is developed.
        Recent studies indicate that okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> inhibits
        nuclear transport mediated by import <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, importin Î²
        and transportin, suggesting that an okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> sensitive
        phosphatase participates in a mechanism that negatively
        regulates entire nuclear transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>]. Since
        PP5 is sensitive to inhibition by okadaic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, we tested
        the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> acted at a more global level by
        assessing the effect of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ISIS 15534</NUMEX> on the cellular
        distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFAT-GFP</ENAMEX>. In contrast to the findings
        obtained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR-GFP</ENAMEX>, the suppression of PP5 expression had
        no apparent effect on calcium induced nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">import</ENAMEX> or the
        subsequent export of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFAT-GFP</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Therefore, PP5
        does not appear to regulate entire nuclear transport
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        These studies indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> participates in the
        regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> nucleocytoplasmic shuttling, and that the
        suppression of PP5 expression results in the nuclear
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>. Therefore,
        the previously reported increase in GR-induced
        transcriptional activity that occurs after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> 15534
        induced suppression of PP5 expression likely results from
        the nuclear accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> in a form that is capable of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding DNA</ENAMEX> yet still requires agonist to elicit maximal
        transcriptional activation. Still, it is not yet clear if
        PP5 acts to suppress the nuclear accumulation or to
        facilitate the nuclear export of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRs</ENAMEX>. Thus, the precise
        molecular mechanism by which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP5</TIMEX> suppresses the nuclear
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> remains to be elucidated.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Reagents
          Tissue culture medium, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipofectin Â®and TRIzol</ENAMEX> Â®were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DECEprimeâ„¢ II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA labeling</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAXIscriptâ„</ENAMEX>¢ 
          in vitro transcription kits were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambion Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[Î±- 32P</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">dATP</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[Î±- 32P</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTP</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dupont NEN</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein kinase</ENAMEX> A (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>':<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-cyclic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMP</ENAMEX> dependent),
          phosphorylase b (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4.1.1</NUMEX>), crude <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">histone</ENAMEX> (type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2AS</ENAMEX>)
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p-nitrophenyl phosphate</ENAMEX> (PNPP) were obtained from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemical Company</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Cell Culture
          A549 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung</ENAMEX> carcinoma cells were obtained from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tissue Collection</ENAMEX>. A stable HeLa cell line
          expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-NFAT</ENAMEX> was generously provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Scripps Research Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HeLa</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells were grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 g</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>/liter (DMEM) and
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 %</NUMEX> heat-inactivated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>. All cell cultures were
          routinely passed when <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90-95%</NUMEX> confluent.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oligonucleotide Synthesis Assay</ENAMEX> for Oligonucleotide
          Inhibition of PP5 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expression</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX>'- 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> -(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-methoxy</ENAMEX>)ethylphosphothioate
          oligonucleotides were synthesized and purified as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>]. To suppress the expression of
          PP5, the indicated cells were plated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> mm dished and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cultured</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX>. When the cells were
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 70%</NUMEX> confluent, they were treated with
          oligonucleotides as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 25</TIMEX>].
          Briefly, cells were washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 ml</NUMEX>)
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing the oligonucleotides at the indicated
          concentration and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml DOTMA/DOPE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipofectin Â®</ENAMEX>;
          GIBCO-BRL) was then added. After incubating the cells at
          37Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX>, the cells were washed and cultured in
          fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17 hours</TIMEX>. The cells
          were then harvested, and total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIzol Reagent</ENAMEX> (GIBCO-BRL) according to the methods of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼g</NUMEX>) was fractionated on
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> agarose gels containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> and transferred
          to DURLON-UV (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>) nylon membranes. Following UV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-linking, the filters were hybridized with a [
          32P]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> for human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5</ENAMEX>. The human <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cDNA probe</ENAMEX> was
          generated from the full length coding region of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5</ENAMEX> and [
          32P]labeled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DECAprime Â®DNA Labeling Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambion</ENAMEX>)
          according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s protocol. Hybridization
          was performed in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> formamide at 42Â°C
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX>. Following hybridization, the membrane was
          subjected to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> low stringency washes (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã— SSC) at room
          temperature and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> high stringency washes (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.1</NUMEX> Ã—
          SSC<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/0</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55Â°C</TIMEX>. Hybridization was visualized by
          autoradiography, and the filters were then stripped and
          reprobed with a [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32P</TIMEX>]labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">glyceraldehyde-3-phosphate</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dehydrogenase</ENAMEX> (GAPDH) cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> to confirm equal
          loading. Quantification of hybridization signals was
          achieved by analysis of the scanned autoradiograms using
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Image program</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ImagePC</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Preparation of phosphoprotein substrates
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Histone</ENAMEX> (type 2AS from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) was phosphorylated with
          cAMP-dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase A) as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>]. Briefly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mg of histone was
          incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mg of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase A, in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM
          Tris-Cl buffer (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>) containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">1 mCi</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32P</TIMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">150</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼M ATP</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in a final volume of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ml. The
          reaction was allowed to continue for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5 to 4</NUMEX> hrs at 30Â°C
          and terminated by the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.3 ml of 100%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCA</ENAMEX>. The
          precipitated phosphohistone was collected by
          centrifugation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX> Ã— g for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min. The supernatant was
          discarded, and the pellet was redissolved in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
          Tris-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.2</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCA</ENAMEX> was added to precipitate the
          phosphohistone, and this precipitation-resuspension wash
          was repeated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> times. The pellet produced upon the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCA</ENAMEX> precipitation was washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> times with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ml of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethyl ether</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:4</ENAMEX>; v:v) and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> additional
          times with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acidified ethanol</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethyl ether</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:4</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCl</ENAMEX>). The washed histone was allowed to air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry</ENAMEX> and was
          then resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris-Cl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>). This procedure
          yields phosphohistone with a specific activity > <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX> Ã—
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 6CPM/nMole incorporated phosphate.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Determination of phosphatase activity
          Phosphatase activity against phosphohistone was
          determined by the quantification of [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32P</TIMEX>] liberation
          from phosphohistone as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>].
          Assays, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 Î</NUMEX>¼l total volume, containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX>, pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oleic acid</ENAMEX> (assay
          buffer) and [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32P</TIMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phosphoprotein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-2 Î¼M PO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ), were conducted at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>] using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PP5 purified</ENAMEX> from bovine
          brain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">serine</ENAMEX>/threonine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> phosphatase type 5
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PP5</NUMEX>) was purified from bovine brain according to the
          following procedure: a bovine brain was homogenized in ~
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> volumes of buffer A (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 mM HEPES</TIMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 mM PMSF</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-mercaptoethanol</TIMEX>) and subjected to
          centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> g for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> min. followed by a
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%-60%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ammonium sulfate</ENAMEX> fractionation of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatant</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ammonium</ENAMEX> sulfate
          fractionation were resuspended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> ml of buffer B (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HEPES pH 8.5 4Â°C</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2-mercaptoethanol</TIMEX>), desalted on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-25</ENAMEX> sephadex column
          equilibrated with buffer B, then subjected to sequential
          chromatography on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HiTrap Heparin</ENAMEX> column
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>), a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ml <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HiTrap Q</ENAMEX> column (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>) and a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HiTrap SP</ENAMEX> column (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>) respectively. The eluate
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> column was then diluted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-fold with buffer C
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM tris pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-mercaptoethanol</TIMEX>)
          and subjected to anion-exchange chromatography on a
          BioScale Q column (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 ml</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX>). All steps in the
          purification procedure were performed at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4Â°C</NUMEX> except for
          the last step which was performed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23Â°C</TIMEX>. PP5 activity
          was followed during the purification by assaying for
          trypsin-stimulated phosphohydrolase activity at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37Â°C</NUMEX> vs.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p-nitrophenyl phosphate</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> Î¼l reactions containing:
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM tris pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.3</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM p</ENAMEX>-nitrophenyl
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX>.
          Dephosphorylation reactions were routinely conducted
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> and initiated with the addition of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">substrate</ENAMEX>. The dephosphorylation of substrate was kept to
          less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 %</NUMEX> of the total phosphorylated substrate, and
          the reaction was linear with respect to enzyme
          concentration and time. [ 32P]phosphate liberated by the
          enzymes was extracted as a phosphomolybdate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> and
          measured according to the methods of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Killilea et al.</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>]. Inhibition of phosphatase activity by okadaic acid
          was determined by adding the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> to the enzyme
          mixture <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> prior to initiating the reaction with
          the addition of substrate.
        
        
          GR-GFP expression vectors
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mutant rat</ENAMEX> glucocorticoid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> that retained
          hormone binding, nuclear translocation activity, and
          specific DNA binding activity, but was incapable of
          transactivation was fused to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">S65T</NUMEX> mutant of green
          fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> to create pGR(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>)-GFP. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>)-GFP
          expression is driven by the CMV immediate early promoter
          and enhancer. All manipulations were performed as
          described, and all constructs were confirmed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequencing</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein</ENAMEX>-free plasmid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was purified
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX> maxiprep columns (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) and
          contained predominantly supercoiled plasmid with no
          contaminating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> or low molecular weight
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contaminants</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          GFP-GR translocation
          Cells were plated on etched coverslips and grown until
          the cultures were ~ <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 %</NUMEX> confluent. The cells were then
          either treated with oligonucleotides as described above
          or left untreated. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eighteen hours later</TIMEX>, purified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-free pGR(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>)-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> suspended in phosphate-buffered
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saline</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml) was microinjected into the nuclei of
          the cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>]. Typically, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> cells were injected
          for each condition. After microinjection the cells were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hours</TIMEX> at
          37Â°C. The cells were then washed several times with
          serum-free media and placed in serum deficient media for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14 hours</TIMEX> to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-GR</ENAMEX> translocation to the nucleus,
          prior to treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM dexamethasone (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 min.</NUMEX>) or
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> alone. The cells were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, fixed by incubation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 %</NUMEX>
          paraformaldehyde for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> and washed again <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> before mounting on slides with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DABCO/DAPI</ENAMEX> mounting
          solution. GR-GFP expression and localization were
          monitored by fluorescence microscopy. Nuclei were
          localized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPI</ENAMEX> staining. Images were captured with an
          Optronics cooled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCD</ENAMEX> camera and imported into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photoshop</ENAMEX>. The experiments were repeated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> times (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One-way ANOVA</ENAMEX> was performed to determine
          statistical significance of the results using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Instat</ENAMEX> 2.03
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GraphPad Software</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GFP-NFAT</ENAMEX> nuclear shuttling assay
          Stably-transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HeLa cells expressing GFP-NFAT</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>] were grown on glass coverslips to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 30%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">confluency</ENAMEX> and either left untreated or treated with,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ISIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">15534</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ISIS 15521</NUMEX> (a mismatched oligonucleotide
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ISIS 15534</NUMEX>) in the absence of serum as
          described above. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four hours later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> was added to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          and the cells were grown for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an additional 24 hours</TIMEX>. The
          cells were then treated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX> ionomycin for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>, after which time they were either fixed
          immediately or washed extensively with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and incubated
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hours</TIMEX> in medium lacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> ("washout").
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> cells were not incubated with ionomycin. GFP-NFAT
          and images were captured with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Optronics cooled CCD</ENAMEX>
          camera and imported into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe Photoshop</ENAMEX>.
        
      
    
  
