
  
    
      
        Background
        In this investigation, we explored the potential
        cytotoxic interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> using a murine
        macrophage cell line (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RAW264.7</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> is a monofunctional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analog</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur mustard</ENAMEX> (bis-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-(chloroethyl)sulfide) which
        a bifunctional vesicant and a chemical warfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. Both
        bis-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-(chloroethyl)sulfide) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> are known to provoke
        acute inflammatory responses in skin [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3</NUMEX> ] . The
        resulting skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">blistering</ENAMEX> is thought to involve the
        stimulation of specific protease(s) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apoptosis</ENAMEX> is
        now considered a possible molecular mechanism whereby CEES
        induces cytotoxicity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> is a major component of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell wall</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gram</ENAMEX>-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> and is known to trigger a variety of
        inflammatory reactions in macrophages and other cells
        having CD14 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] . In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> is known
        to stimulate the macrophage secretion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nitric oxide</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ]
        factor-alpha (TNF-alpha) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">interleukin-1</NUMEX>-beta (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-1-beta</ENAMEX>)
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . For this reason, we also determined if TNF-alpha
        or IL-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-beta were capable of enhancing the cytotoxic
        effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>.
        LPS stimulation of macrophages is known to involve the
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> phosphorylation by kinases as well as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-kappaB</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11 12 13</NUMEX> ] . The activation of protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> (PKC) by diacylglycerol is also a key event in LPS
        macrophage activation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . 
        In vitro experiments have shown that
        the secretion of TNF-alpha and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>-beta by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>-stimulated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monocytes</ENAMEX> is dependent upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] . In
        this study, we also determined if phorbol myristate acetate
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>) activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> also enhanced CEES toxicity.
        Evidence suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-alpha [
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX>. Our long-term goal is to understand the
        molecular mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur mustard toxicity</ENAMEX> and to
        determine if free radical production plays an important
        role in this toxicity.
        In our experiments, cytotoxicity was measured by a
        decrease in the optical density by the MTT
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bromide</ENAMEX>) assay or by an increase in the fluorescence of
        propidium iodide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assay is based on reduction
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> by actively growing cells to produce a blue formazan
        product with absorbance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">575</NUMEX> nm. A low MTT absorbance
        indicates cell death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PI assay differentiates</ENAMEX> between
        live and dead cells. Cells that have lost membrane
        integrity cannot exclude PI, which emits a red fluorescence
        after binding to cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> or double stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>. A
        high PI<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX> indicates cell death.
      
      
        Results
        
          Cytotoxic interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> as
          measured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assay
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RAW 264.7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">macrophages</ENAMEX> were incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) or both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> and
          cell viability then measured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assay. As shown
          in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, we found that LPS-stimulated RAW264.7
          macrophages were markedly more susceptible (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>)
          to CEES toxicity (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24 hr</NUMEX>) than resting macrophages as
          indicated by the dramatic drop in dehydrogenase activity.
          In the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> at a level of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 Î¼M</NUMEX> did not
          significantly affect cell viability as measured by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assay.
          The characteristics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> toxicity to LPS-stimulated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RAW 264.7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">macrophages</ENAMEX> were further characterized by
          varying the concentrations of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>. The MTT
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> in Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2show</TIMEX> that very low levels (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">25 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LPS</ENAMEX> dramatically enhanced the toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> (measured
          after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hr</TIMEX>) to macrophages at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">concentrations > 300</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼M.</ENAMEX> In general, LPS levels beyond <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml did not
          further enhance the toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>. However, LPS level
          at a level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml significantly increased the
          cytotoxicity of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 Î¼M</NUMEX> CEES compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> activated
          RAW265<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> cells not treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX>
          analyses indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼M</NUMEX> CEES
          were not significantly different from control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (not
          treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>) in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25 or 50 ng</TIMEX>/ml
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>. However, at a LPS level of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 ng/ml</ENAMEX>, cells
          treated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> showed a great MTT optical
          density than control cells. This might be due to a slight
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mitogenic</ENAMEX> response to low levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> course for the cytotoxic interaction between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> as measured by the propidium iodide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>)
          assay
          In order to insure that our results could be
          reproduced with an alternative assay for cell viability,
          we also utilized the propidium iodide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>) assay. In this
          assay, the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> fluorescence increase over the control
          cells (i.e., <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Ã—</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">treatment -PI</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> )/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> ) indicates cytotoxicity. For
          each experiment, the value for the control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> is zero
          and is not, therefore, shown. Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3indicates</TIMEX> that the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">PI assay</ENAMEX> provides the same qualitative results as the MTT
          assay, i.e., a synergistic toxic interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">20 ng/ml</ENAMEX>). Moreover, the cytotoxic
          interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> was noticeable after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>) and reached a maximum <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> after
          exposure. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) was significantly
          toxic to RAW <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">264.7</NUMEX> macrophages even in the absence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> alone was never significantly different than
          cells with no treatment, which always has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> percent
          PI<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX> increase.
        
        
          TNF-alpha and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> also enhance the cytotoxic
          effect of CEES
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gram</ENAMEX>-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> binds to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">CD14</NUMEX> and
          initiates a complex signal transduction pathway involving
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Toll</ENAMEX> receptor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, which eventually results in the
          synthesis of pro-inflammatory cytokines such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-alpha
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX>. We, therefore, investigated the potential
          roles of TNF-alpha and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> in enhancing CEES
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1shows</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) are significantly more cytotoxic (after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>) when administered together than when administered
          alone. In this experiment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">25 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼M</ENAMEX>) combined gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> values of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">120.8 Â± 2.3</NUMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.25 Â± 0.07</NUMEX>, respectively. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> data suggest that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml, is able to enhance the toxicity of CEES
          (an MTT value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.25 Â± 0.07</NUMEX>) to a greater extent (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.05</NUMEX>) than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml (an MTT value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.74</NUMEX> Â±
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.07</NUMEX>). The ternary mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">25 ng/ml</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-1beta
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) was not found to be more
          cytotoxic than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">25 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼M</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2shows</ENAMEX> completely analogous data with TNF-alpha,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX>, an amplification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> toxicity (after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>)
          in the presence of the inflammatory cytokine. In this
          experiment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml plus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> (at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) gave
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> values of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">62.6 Â± 1.4 and 0.32 Â± 0.05</NUMEX>,
          respectively. This indicates that TNF-alpha at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
          is not as potent at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml) in enhancing the
          cytotoxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼M.</ENAMEX> TNF-alpha combined with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>) was found to not exert any
          cytotoxic effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RAW264.7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">macrophages</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein kinase</ENAMEX> C is a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor serine</ENAMEX>/threonine
          kinase that is maximally active in the presence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diacylglycerol</ENAMEX> and calcium ions. 
          In vitro experiments by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffey et</ENAMEX>
          al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] have shown that TNF-alpha and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-1beta
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX> and mRNA accumulation by monocytes following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> treatment is dependent on PKC activity. Phorbol
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-myristate 13</NUMEX>-acetate (PMA) is a specific activator of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group A</ENAMEX> and group B <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase C. We wanted to
          determine, therefore, if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase C activation by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> would enhance the toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>. As shown in Table
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, the combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼M</ENAMEX>)
          was more cytotoxic (after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>) toward the RAW264.7
          macrophages than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> alone. However, as was the
          case with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> and TNF-alpha, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> was not as
          effective as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> in enhancing CEES toxicity.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        We have found that inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>,
        TNF-alpha, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> amplify the cytotoxicity of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RAW264.7 macrophages</NUMEX>. There is evidence suggesting
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> can modulate levels of inflammatory cytokines but
        this information is controversial and inconsistent.
        Cultured monocytes exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> show a transient
        increase in TNF-alpha [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Similarly, cultured normal
        human keratinocytes exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> show a transient
        increase in both TNF-alpha and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> ] . In
        contrast to the results of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arroyo et al.</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20</NUMEX> ] ,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricketts et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> or TNF-alpha
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> did not increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur mustard</ENAMEX>-exposed mouse
        skin. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blaha et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] , using an 
        in vitro human skin model, found that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> treatment resulted in a decreased level of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1alpha</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabourin et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] also addressed this issue and
        studied the 
        in vivo temporal sequence of
        inflammatory cytokine gene expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur mustard</ENAMEX>
        exposed mouse skin. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> found an increase
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> mRNA levels after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 hours</TIMEX> that dramatically
        increased <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 6-24 hours</TIMEX> post exposure [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] .
        Moreover, immunohistochemical studies showed an increase in
        tissue levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . The 
        in vitro results reported here
        support a role for inflammatory cytokines in the mechanism
        and kinetics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> toxicity. Our unique findings with
        regards to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> are significant because they demonstrate
        that this bacterial endotoxin enhances CEES toxicity even
        when present at extremely low levels, i.e., nanograms of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LPS</ENAMEX> per ml.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> is ubiquitous and is present in serum, tap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
        and dust. Military and civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> would, indeed,
        always have some degree of exposure to environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>,
        which could increase the toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur mustard</ENAMEX>. In
        exposure. Our primary future goals are to understand the
        general mechanism for the enhanced toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> in the
        presence of inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and use this information to
        develop effective countermeasures. Our experiments with PMA
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>) suggest that the activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase C
        may play a key role in molecular mechanism whereby LPS
        enhances the cytotoxic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>.
        In experiments that will be reported elsewhere, we have
        found the antioxidants such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RRR</ENAMEX>-alpha-tocopherol and
        N-acetylcysteine are effective in reducing the cytotoxic
        effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> on LPS-stimulated macrophages. We have also
        initiated experiments to distinguish the roles of apoptosis
        and necrosis in the observation reported here.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Our results suggest that that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LPS</ENAMEX> dramatically enhances
        the toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur mustard</ENAMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> is a ubiquitous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in the natural environment, its presence is likely to
        be an important variable influencing the cytotoxicity of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur mustard</ENAMEX> toxicity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> is known to stimulate the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monocytes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . We, therefore, also
        determined if these cytokines influenced the cytotoxicity
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>. The data in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tables 1and 2demonstrate</ENAMEX> that both
        these cytokines enhance the cytotoxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX> as
        measured by either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assay or the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PI assay</ENAMEX>.
        Inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase C is known to block the
        secretion of TNF-alpha and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] whereas
        stimulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase C promotes TNF-alpha and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1beta</ENAMEX> production [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . The data reported in Table
        3show that stimulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase C activity by PMA
        also enhances the cytotoxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEES</ENAMEX>. Collectively, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> reported here provide the basis for future experiments
        attempting to determine the signal transduction mechanisms
        whereby inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agents enhance sulfur mustard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Materials
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LPS (Escherichia Coli Serotype</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0111</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">B4</ENAMEX>) and PMA
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Phorbol 12-Myristate 13-Acetate</ENAMEX>) were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemical Co. St. Louis, MO. Murine IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-beta was
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Diagnostic Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flanders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>).
          r-TNF-alpha (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX>) was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega Co</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Cell culture and treatments
          RAW264<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> murine macrophage-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Culture Collection</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) were cultured at 37Â°C
          in a humidified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> air with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) in RPMI-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1640</NUMEX> medium with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal
          bovine serum, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml</ENAMEX> penicillin and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">streptomycin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">GiBcoBRL Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>). Adherent cells
          were subcultured over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96</TIMEX> well Costar tissue
          culture plates in serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> BSA
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of cell
          viability
          This assay for cell viability is based on the
          reduction of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bromide</ENAMEX> (MTT) by mitochondrial dehydrogenase in viable
          cells to produce a purple formazan product. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schweitzer et</ENAMEX>
          al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] have shown that this assay provides linearity
          between optical density and cell number. This assay was
          performed by a slight modification of the method
          described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wasserman et al.</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25</NUMEX> ] . Briefly, at the
          end of each experiment, cells cultured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96</TIMEX> well plates
          (with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of medium per well) were incubated with MTT
          (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> per well) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">formazan</ENAMEX> product was solubilized by addition of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of
          dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> (in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M HCl</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. The dehydrogenase activity
          was expressed as the absorbance (read with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular</ENAMEX>
          Devices microplate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>) of the formazan product at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">575</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nm</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Dye exclusion assay (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PI assay</ENAMEX>)
          This assay uses propidium iodide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>) dye to
          differentiate live and dead cell [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27 28</NUMEX> ] . Cells
          that have lost membrane integrity cannot exclude PI,
          which emits a red fluorescence after binding to cellular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> or double stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each</TIMEX> experiment, cells
          were washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î¼l</NUMEX> of RPMI
          medium with <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼g/ml PI</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> at room
          temperature. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PI fluorescence</ENAMEX> was measured using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fluostar Galaxy</ENAMEX> microplate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> using an excitation
          wavelength of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX> nm and an emission wavelength of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">650</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nm</ENAMEX>. We expressed the results as the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> increase in
          the fluorescence of treated cells over the fluorescence
          of control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (no treatments), i.e., <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Ã—</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">treatment -PI</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> )/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> )
        
        
          Statistical analyses
          Means among treatments were compared by one-way ANOVA
          followed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scheffe</ENAMEX> test with a significance level of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>. In both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tables</ENAMEX> and Figures, means not sharing a
          common letter are significantly different (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>).
          Means sharing a common letter are not significantly
          different. The means and standard deviations of three
          independent experiments are provided in both the Figures
          and Tables.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WLS</ENAMEX> drafted the manuscript and supervised the overall
        conduct of the research, which was performed in his
        laboratory. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MQ</ENAMEX> carried out all of the experimental work in
        this study and performed the statistical analyses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX>
        (along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WLS</ENAMEX>) conceived of the study, participated in
        the study design, and provided continuous evaluation of the
        experimental data. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
