
  
    
      
        Background
        It was originally thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> and tyrosine kinase
        receptors functioned independently to mediate different
        signaling events, but it has become clear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>
        that some functions and signaling pathways are shared (for
        reviews, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marinissen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutkind</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luttrell</ENAMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] ; and van <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biesen et al.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] ). For
        example, some classical neurotransmitters such as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT have
        short-term effects on ion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and other effectors such
        as adenylyl cyclase but also have growth factor-like
        effects in developing brain [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] and mitogenic effects on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> (reviewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gerhardt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Heerikhuizen</ENAMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] ). The peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones insulin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1</ENAMEX> have
        both short-term metabolic effects and long-term actions on
        cell growth and differentiation. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Insulin</ENAMEX> and IGF-I bind and
        stimulate tyrosine kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> which interact with a
        large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">effectors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] . Complex interactions
        occur between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types of signaling pathways that
        are the subject of intense investigation.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> displays a heterogeneous
        distribution in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNS</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] and is not found in
        peripheral tissues. It is abundant in choroid plexus where
        it modulates the production of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF),
        and in limbic regions and hypothalamus where it may play a
        role in motor behavior and appetite control. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> has been implicated in
        anxiety, migraine, movement disorders, eating disorders and
        neuroendocrine regulation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . The importance of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> in regulation of food intake
        is evident in a knockout mouse developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tecott et al.</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obesity</ENAMEX> found in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> is due to excessive
        food intake and this phenotype along with increased plasma
        levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> and leptin is analogous to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Type</ENAMEX> 2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knockout mouse</ENAMEX> is also susceptible to
        epileptic-like seizures - suggesting that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> has a role in tonic
        inhibition of neuronal excitability.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin/IGF-1 receptors</ENAMEX>
        share some functional roles; both have trophic effects in
        the brain and modulate appetite. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>/IGF-1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] co-localize in several areas in the brain
        including choroid plexus, olfactory bulb, cerebral cortex,
        hypothalamus, and hippocampus. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Interactions</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between insulin</TIMEX>
        and serotonergic pathways may have important consequences
        for their known roles in appetite modulation and trophic
        actions in the brain. We chose to look for these types of
        interactions in choroid plexus because both <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin/IGF-1 receptors</ENAMEX>
        are abundant in this tissue and because the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is the only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HT</ENAMEX> receptor
        present in these cells.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the GPCR
        family. GPCRs stimulate heterotrimeric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> which
        release activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GÎ²Î³</ENAMEX> subunits to interact with a
        variety of effectors. The function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> is tightly
        regulated by phosphorylation by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> messenger activated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase A and protein kinase <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coupled receptor</ENAMEX>-specific kinases (GRKs). Arrestins
        bind phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and further down-regulate
        receptor activity by inhibiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> protein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interaction</ENAMEX>. It
        is well-known that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> can regulate the activity of
        tyrosine <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kinase</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase pathways</ENAMEX>. However, there is
        little evidence for reciprocal regulation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> kinase
        effects on GPCR function. Here we report such evidence -
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin-mediated MAP</ENAMEX> kinase regulation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> activity.
      
      
        Results
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> signaling on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5HT</NUMEX> 2Creceptor
          function in choroid plexus cells
          We examined the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> signaling on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> function in isolated rat
          choroid plexus cells. Activation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in choroid plexus
          stimulates phosphoinositol hydrolysis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] and
          increases intracellular calcium [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . We measured
          changes in intracellular calcium in response to serotonin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-HT</ENAMEX>) with the calcium indicator, fura. A robust
          increase in intracellular calcium was seen in response to
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1aand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1c</ENAMEX>) and this response could be
          completely blocked with the selective <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor antagonist</ENAMEX>, mesulergine
          (data not shown). The response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT was significantly
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attenuated</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> inhibition) when choroid plexus cells
          were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> before superfusing serotonin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1band <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1c</ENAMEX>). Pretreatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">098059</ENAMEX>, a MEK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inhibitor</ENAMEX> blocked the inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1c) but had no effect on the serotonin response when used
          alone. These data indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> inhibits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> activity and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> is an
          obligatory component of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>'s action, implicating the
          involvement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase pathway</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Characterization of the mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>'s
          effect on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5HT 2Creceptor</TIMEX> function in Xenopus
          oocytes
          To delineate the mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>'s action on the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX>, we used the 
          Xenopus oocyte expression system.
          Oocytes contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endogenous insulin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1 receptors</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> ] . They also have many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAS</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase pathways</ENAMEX>, which have been implicated in cell
          cycle control and re-entry into meiosis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] .. We
          expressed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX>, a serotonin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-HT</ENAMEX> 
          2C ) and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1</ENAMEX> muscarinic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acetylcholine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ach</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> utilize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> for signaling; they stimulate phosphoinositide
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hydrolysis</ENAMEX> and increased phospholipase C activity which
          leads to transient activation of a Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-dependent Cl
          -current in the oocytes. Activation of either receptor
          can cross-desensitize the other, suggesting that they
          share the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> protein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pathway</ENAMEX>.
          To determine the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin receptor</ENAMEX> or IGF-1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor activation</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX>'s, cells were treated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cl</ENAMEX> -currents elicited by subsequent
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-HT</TIMEX> or Ach stimulation were compared with those without
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">insulin/IGF-1</ENAMEX> treatment. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, treatment
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> or IGF-1 resulted in a significant reduction
          of the peak Cl -current in response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT, but did not
          affect the response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ach</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Insulin</ENAMEX> alone did not induce
          an ionic current under these conditions (data not shown).
          Insulin treatment did not affect the general
          characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cl</ENAMEX> -current induced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT or
          Ach, i.e., a depolarizing current with a rapid transient
          peak and slower oscillatory phase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2aand 2b</ENAMEX>, top).
          Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> specifically reduced the peak Cl
          -current in response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83%</NUMEX> compared to untreated
          controls (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1513 Â± 138</ENAMEX> nA vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">261</NUMEX> Â± 78 nA, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a, middle)
          with no change in the magnitude of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cl</ENAMEX> -current in
          response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ach</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2681 Â± 281 nA vs. 2785 Â± 186</ENAMEX> nA, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2b, middle). Similar to the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, IGF-1
          treatment specifically reduced the magnitude of the Cl
          -current in response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1665 Â± 222</ENAMEX> nA vs.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">737 Â± 181</ENAMEX> nA, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a, bottom), without affecting the
          response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ach</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1275 Â± 272 nA vs. 1220 Â± 243, Fig</ENAMEX>. 2b,
          bottom). These data indicate that the inhibitory effect
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF-1</ENAMEX> is specific for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Insulin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1 receptors</ENAMEX> activate several different
          regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX>, PI3
          kinase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">kinase</ENAMEX> and protein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tyrosine phosphatase</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> ] . Initiation of this transduction cascade requires
          the intrinsic tyrosine kinase activity of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">insulin/IGF-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. To determine whether or not
          tyrosine kinase activity was required for the action of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">insulin/IGF-1</ENAMEX>, the tyrosine kinase inhibitor genistein
          was used. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3a, in oocytes pretreated with
          genistein before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGF-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, the reduction in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cl</ENAMEX> -current was abolished, whereas genistein
          treatment alone had no effect on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT response in
          oocytes not treated with IGF-1.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF-1</ENAMEX> pathway diverges into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAS</ENAMEX>-dependent
          and -independent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX>. To identify which path is
          involved, an anti-RAS <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> that can neutralize RAS
          activity was injected into oocytes before IGF-1
          treatment. This <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RAS antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Y13-259</ENAMEX>) has been shown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oocytes</ENAMEX> to block the re-entry into meiosis or germinal
          vesicle breakdown induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Antibody
          injection blocked the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT
          response (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3b), demonstrating that the inhibitory
          effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF-1</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAS-dependent.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAS</ENAMEX> activates a cascade of kinases, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAF</ENAMEX>, MAP
          kinase kinase (MEK) and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX>. The involvement of
          this pathway in regulation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HT</ENAMEX> receptor function was
          examined. Pretreating cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">098059</ENAMEX>, a specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> kinase inhibitor [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] , blocked the effect of IGF-1
          on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT response, whereas inhibition of protein
          kinase C did not (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4a). These results suggest that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> is involved in mediating the inhibitory effect of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">insulin/IGF-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX>'s primary role is activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX> through
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">threonine</ENAMEX> and tyrosine phosphorylation of MAP kinase
          which in turn phosphorylates and regulates the function
          of several nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, such as transcription
          factors, as well as cytosolic and membrane-associated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">EGF receptors</ENAMEX>. To
          determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX> is involved in mediating the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">insulin/IGF-1</ENAMEX> effect, activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] was
          injected into oocytes before testing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT response.
          Active MAP kinase reduced the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT response by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX>
          compared to untreated controls (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4b), demonstrating
          that active <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX> is capable of mimicking the
          inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF-1</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX>.
          The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> contains a putative MAP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> site [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">serine 159 in the second</TIMEX>
          intracellular loop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the 3rd and 4th</TIMEX> transmembrane
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">domains</ENAMEX>. To ascertain whether MAP kinase directly
          modulates the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> function, this amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> was
          changed to alanine by site-directed mutagenesis. As shown
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4c, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> no longer inhibited the peak Cl
          -current activated by the mutant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor S159A</ENAMEX>,
          indicating that serine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">159</ENAMEX> is likely the site of MAP
          kinase modulation.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coupled receptor superfamily</ENAMEX> and one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 30</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloned serotonin receptors</ENAMEX>. Except for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> receptor which is an oligomeric ion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serotonin receptors</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> and are divided
        into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> subfamilies based on sequence homology, gene
        structure, and signaling pathways [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX>, like other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, stimulates phospholipase C,
        and increases IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAG</ENAMEX> which leads to increased
        intracellular calcium and mediates many cellular processes.
        In general <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> receptor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> are growth-regulatory
        and stimulate cell division. However, unlike the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2A [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2B [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is not known to activate MAP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> activates multiple signal
        transduction cascades 
        in vivo and in heterologous
        expression systems (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raymond et al 2001</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] ; and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerhardt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Heerikhuizen</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> ( [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] , for reviews).
        In choroid plexus, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor stimulates PI</ENAMEX> turnover,
        increases <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cGMP</ENAMEX> formation and activates Cl -channels. In
        heterologous expression systems, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] and in some cases either activation or
        inactivation of adenylyl cyclase has been demonstrated in
        addition to the well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> of phospholipase C
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX> turnover.
        The regulation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> has been the focus of
        several studies, but the results have been difficult to
        interpret for several reasons including the complex
        pharmacology of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. The presence of spare <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] in choroid plexus
        has also complicated the study of desensitization 
        in vivo . However, it has been
        demonstrated that denervation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT neurons
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">supersensitizes 5-HT</ENAMEX> 
        2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] in choroid plexus,
        suggesting that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are under tonic control by
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-HT</TIMEX>. In primary cultures of choroid plexus cells, repeated
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HT</ENAMEX> application desensitizes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT induced increases in
        intracellular calcium [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . Down-regulation of receptor
        binding sites in choroid plexus cells is seen after agonist
        treatment [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . However, inverse agonists can either
        down- [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] or up-regulate [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> binding sites dependent upon
        cellular context. The mechanisms underlying desensitization
        or down-regulation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> are unknown but these
        reports suggest finely tuned control of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> function and density.
        Several studies have utilized heterologous expression
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> to identify mechanisms of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> regulation. Phosphorylation
        most likely has a prominent role in regulation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westphal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> ] demonstrated that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> exhibits basal
        phosphorylation, and that agonist treatment was associated
        with increased phosphorylation and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> desensitization
        in transfected cells. The expressed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> exhibits homologous and
        heterologous desensitization in oocytes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] mediated by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> C [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34 35</NUMEX> ] . A calmodulin-dependent
        kinase may also be involved in homologous desensitization [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> ] . In contrast, a recent study indicates that neither
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> nor calmodulin-dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> are
        involved, instead desensitization of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is dependent on GRK activity
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] . Interestingly, tyrosine kinase involvement in the
        agonist-mediated phosphorylation of the rat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> has also been reported [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>
        ] , although as yet no report has shown that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> directly activates tyrosine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX>.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are subject to another form
        of regulation by means of mRNA editing [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> editing
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] is a type of posttranscriptional modification that
        occurs when double-stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA deaminase</ENAMEX> converts
        genomically coded adenosines to inosines, thereby changing
        the coding sequence of specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA transcripts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
        editing of the rat <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> was first described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>
        et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] and editing at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> nucleotide sites alters
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> within the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> intracellular loop. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
        editing of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is conserved among species [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> ] and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 7</NUMEX> major isoforms with tissue-specific
        expression patterns have been described in rat brain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ]
        suggesting a functional importance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> cDNA clone
        used in our study codes for the fully edited form
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Val157-Ser159-Val161</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. The putative MAP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> site (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Ser159</NUMEX>) we identified and mutated in this
        study is also a site of mRNA editing in this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>; i.e.
        Ser159 is only present in edited forms. The fully edited
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rat 5-HT</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> exhibits reduced agonist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">efficacy</ENAMEX> or ability to interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> proteins compared to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">unedited receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ile157-Asn159-Ile161</ENAMEX>) in transfected
        cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . Interestingly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT elicits a larger
        response (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4c) in cells expressing the mutant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S159A</NUMEX>) compared to the fully edited mouse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, and the mutant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> is not regulated by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>. Binding of radiolabelled mesulergine was similar
        in the edited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2C and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">S159A mutant receptors</ENAMEX> in
        transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (data not shown). These results suggest
        some intriguing possibilities. Either the mutant receptor
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S159A</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> more readily to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> proteins compared to the
        fully edited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX>, or the edited (Ser159
        containing) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> may be phosphorylated to some extent
        in the basal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. We hypothesize that the phosphorylated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> may couple less efficiently to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, but
        this hypothesis remain to be tested. Our results indirectly
        suggest that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ser159</ENAMEX> may be
        subject to yet another form of regulation; i.e.,
        phosphorylation by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX>.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is very abundant in choroid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plexus</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 42</ENAMEX> ] , and is the only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HT</ENAMEX> receptor present on
        these cells. Choroid plexus cells line the cerebral
        ventricles, form the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>-CSF barrier, and are responsible
        for the production of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] .
        Although the mechanisms have not been delineated, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is thought to regulate CSF
        production and the expression of transferrin. For example,
        upon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intraventricular</ENAMEX> injection, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        2C <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">agonists</TIMEX> decrease the production of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSF</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] and in primary cultures of choroid plexus, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT
        agonists increase the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transferrin</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45 46</NUMEX> ] ,
        an iron carrier <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> which has trophic effects on the
        brain. In addition, choroid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plexus expresses insulin</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-I</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 47</NUMEX> ] ., as well as large
        amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> that is secreted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSF</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CSF</ENAMEX> contains <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGFs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-HT</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] in concentrations
        high enough to activate their respective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in
        choroid plexus, suggesting that this signaling mechanism
        may occur 
        in vivo . It has been suggested that
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-5HT 
        2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in choroid plexus may be
        tonically activated, due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSF</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT concentrations near
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> , thus tonically inhibiting CSF
        production. Our data suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> may reduce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> activity, thereby increasing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSF</ENAMEX> production and decreasing transferrin production. As a
        consequence, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> inhibition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> activity may change the
        volume and composition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSF</ENAMEX> and indirectly may alter the
        concentrations of many potentially important signaling
        molecules in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSF</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> kinase regulation is potentially an important
        mechanism of modulating GPCR function, however the
        prevalence of this type of modulation is unknown. Our
        results suggest that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase substrate</ENAMEX>,
        whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M1 Ach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> is not. The optimal consensus
        site for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase phosphorylation isPro</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser/Thr</ENAMEX>)-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro</ENAMEX>,
        however in some cases the upstream <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro</ENAMEX> is not required and
        a minimal sequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ser-Pro or Thr-Pro</ENAMEX> is phosphorylated
        (for review, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] ). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> site is just such a minimal
        sequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ser-Pro</ENAMEX> and it is the only MAP kinase site we
        identified within the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>'s presumed intracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">domains</ENAMEX>. This site is not conserved within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the M1</TIMEX> Ach
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> or other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. Although all of these
        receptors contain <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ser-Pro or Thr-Pro</ENAMEX> sequences within
        intracellular domains it is difficult to determine the
        importance of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. For example, despite the fact
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> did not inhibit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ach</ENAMEX> receptor signaling in our
        experiment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> M1 Ach <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> contains several MAP
        kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thr-Pro sequence</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        ndintracellular loop and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ser-Pro and one Thr-Pro</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        rdintracellular loop. The reason for this apparent
        discrepancy is unclear but may be related to a "spare
        receptor" phenomenon in the oocyte expression system.
        Alternatively, additional sequence or regulatory elements,
        which have not been identified, may be required for MAP
        kinase phosphorylation. Determining the prevalence and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specificity of MAP</ENAMEX> kinase modulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX>'s will await
        future studies.
      
      
        Conclusions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">insulin/IGF-1</ENAMEX> signaling down-regulates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> function in choroid plexus
        and 
        Xenopus oocytes via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> kinase, and
        that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> is a substrate for MAP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> kinase regulation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX> and suggests that this form
        of regulation may be more wide-spread than has been
        previously recognized. Furthermore, since some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> can
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modulate MAP</ENAMEX> kinase activity, MAP kinase regulation of GPCR
        function may then serve as a form of negative feedback
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> in much the same way that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase A, protein
        kinase C and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coupled receptor kinases</ENAMEX> (GRKs)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regulate GPCRs</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chemicals</ENAMEX> and Reagents
          Cell culture reagents and enzymes including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAM</ENAMEX>'s
          F12, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-valine, dialyzed fetal calf serum, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pronase</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>)
          except as noted. All other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) except as noted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">098059</ENAMEX> was kindly provided
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. R. Saltiel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parke-Davis Pharmaceutical</ENAMEX>
          Research, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann Arbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purified</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ERK2</ENAMEX> was kindly
          provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. H. Cobb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Pharmacology</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT Southwestern Medical Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Choroid plexus cell isolation and culture
          All animal experiments in this work have been carried
          out in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide for the Care</ENAMEX> and Use of
          Laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> as required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. National</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutes of Health</ENAMEX>. Choroid plexus cells were isolated
          as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, choroid plexus from adult
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">male Sprague</ENAMEX>-Dawley <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">175-200 g</ENAMEX>) were dissected into
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cold Locke</ENAMEX>'s buffer, rinsed and enzymatically dissociated
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37Â° C</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Balanced Salt Solution</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">330</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ug</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Pronase I and 260</ENAMEX> ug/ml DNase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.</ENAMEX> The cells were pelleted and choroid plexus cells were
          released after an additional digest with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ug</ENAMEX>/ ml DNase
          I in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX>. The cells were resuspended in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MEM</ENAMEX> containing
          D-valine and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> dialyzed fetal calf serum and plated on
          concavalin A-coated round glass coverslips. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four days</TIMEX>
          later the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> was replaced with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ham's</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">F12</NUMEX> medium.
        
        
          Intracellular calcium measurements
          After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX> in culture, cells were loaded with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 Î</NUMEX>¼M
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fura-2 AM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/ml</ENAMEX> bovine serum albumin (BSA) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at 22Â°C
          and washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22Â°C</TIMEX>. Cells were
          continuously superperfused with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HBSS</ENAMEX> containing the
          indicated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Insulin</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 or 20 Î¼M</NUMEX>) was diluted into
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HBSS</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mg/ml BSA</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 uM</ENAMEX>) was diluted
          into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX>. Some cells were pretreated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼M</NUMEX> PD
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">098059</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> before intracellular calcium
          measurements. Fura imaging was done using software kindly
          provided by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Gruenstein</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> and was carried out as previously described [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> ] . Peak intracellular calcium responses were measured
          from individual cells and pooled for statistical
          analysis.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Oocyte</ENAMEX> injection and drug treatment
          Oocytes were injected with 
          in vitro <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transcribed RNA</ENAMEX> for the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mouse 5-HT</ENAMEX> 
          2C [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M1</NUMEX> acetylcholine
          (kindly provided by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. Bonner</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for the
          experiment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> alone for all other
          experiments. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> injection, oocytes were
          stimulated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ach</ENAMEX>, and the chloride current was
          measured using a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-electrode voltage-clamp
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Axoclamp-2A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axon Instruments, Foster City</ENAMEX>, CA). Oocytes
          were subjected to different treatments as follows. For
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1</ENAMEX> treatment, oocytes were treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ND96</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.6</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX>, then rinsed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ND96</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 minutes</TIMEX>
          before stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼M 5-HT</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ach</ENAMEX>. For the
          experiments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oocytes</ENAMEX> were pretreated with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Î¼M genistein for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 minutes</TIMEX> or were injected with RAS
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.65 Î¼g/50 nl</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes before</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-HT</ENAMEX>
          stimulation or treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1</ENAMEX> followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT
          stimulation. For the experiments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4a, some oocytes
          were pretreated with either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PD 098059</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼M for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase C inhibitor, myristoylated
          EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calbiochem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA), (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î¼M for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>)
          before <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT stimulation or treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1</ENAMEX> followed
          by stimulation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4b, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oocytes</ENAMEX> were
          injected with active <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ERK2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>) or MAP
          kinase buffer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes before 5-HT</TIMEX> stimulation or
          treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF-1</ENAMEX> followed by stimulation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT.
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4c, oocytes were injected with 
          in vitro <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transcribed RNA</ENAMEX> for the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX> or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          2C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">S149A mutant receptor</ENAMEX>. The oocytes
          were stimulated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT or treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          followed by stimulation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT.
        
        
          Site-directed mutagenesis
          The putative MAP kinase site on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX>, serine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">159</NUMEX>, was mutated
          to alanine by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> with primers containing an alanine
          codon at the place for serine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">159</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product was
          subcloned into the same vector as the wild-type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2C receptor</ENAMEX>, and the mutation
          confirmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequencing</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">JH</ENAMEX> carried out fura imaging and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oocyte</ENAMEX> experiments and
        drafted the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SZ</ENAMEX> participated in fura imaging and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oocyte</ENAMEX> experiments and carried out the site-directed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutagenesis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LB</ENAMEX> participated in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oocyte</ENAMEX> experiments. MM
        participated in the design of the study and generated the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RAS antibody</ENAMEX>. AD purified the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX> and participated
        in the design of the study. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KG</ENAMEX> participated in the design
        of the study. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AF</ENAMEX> participated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fura</ENAMEX> experiments and
        in the design of the study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LY</ENAMEX> conceived of the study and
        participated in its design and coordination. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
