
  
    
      
        Background
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health Consensus</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development Conference</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] concluded that breast
        conserving surgery (BCS) followed by radiation is an
        appropriate method of primary treatment for the majority of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with early stage breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> (AJCC stages [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] I,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIB</ENAMEX>). Numerous clinical studies have shown that
        survival after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> followed by radiation therapy is
        equivalent to survival following mastectomy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
        these stages [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5</NUMEX> ] . Some absolute indicators for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mastectomy</ENAMEX> remain [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] , in particular widespread
        malignant-type microcalcifications, previous radiotherapy,
        and a relation of tumor size to breast size that would not
        allow a cosmetically satisfactory result. Although there
        has been an increase in the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> since the early
        1990s, an apparent under-utilization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for
        whom such treatment was not contraindicated has been
        documented [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . Geographic location, type of hospital
        and health plan, and personal preferences have been
        investigated as possible factors to explain the continued
        use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mastectomy</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10 11 12</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comorbidity</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] has
        been found to be an important predictor among older
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> registries do not collect sufficient detail to
        examine some of these issues and medical records reviews
        are time consuming. Insurance claims data are a
        cost-effective alternative; they have already been
        collected and put into an electronic format by the
        insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>. They cover large segments of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, allow follow-up, use standardized codes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15</NUMEX>
        ] , and do not rely on subject recall. In <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> research,
        insurance claims data have been used to estimate the
        effectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cervical cancer</ENAMEX> screening [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , to
        assess the role of screening practices in the incidence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] , and to estimate mammography
        participation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> enrollees in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> who received care from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Maintenance</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> (HMO) were found to receive more BCS than
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fee-For-Service</ENAMEX> (FFS) plans [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] . Whereas a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare/SEER</ENAMEX> registry linked data set has been used
        extensively to examine treatment and screening issues in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years</TIMEX> and older [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , linking of
        insurance claims data from private health plans in younger
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX> has been more difficult because of the large
        number of health plans in most geographic areas. However,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> provides unique opportunities for insurance claims
        research because the majority of medical care is received
        within the state and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 90%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ]
        are covered by a limited number of health plans. As a pilot
        project, we were able to link data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii Tumor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registry</ENAMEX> and from a health plan in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>. The objectives
        of this analysis were to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> treatment
        and comorbid conditions using the insurance claims data and
        to examine possible determinants of BCS 
        vs. mastectomy for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with stage I and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">II disease</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Sources</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> has maintained a database of all cases of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of Hawaii</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> and
          became part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SEER</ENAMEX> program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> record
          contains demographic characteristics such as age,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ethnicity</ENAMEX>, marital status, island of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>, as well
          as information on tumor size, extent of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, lymph
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">node</ENAMEX> involvement, and tumor grade. From medical records
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, information is
          collected on the initial course (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tumor Registry</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>-directed treatment following
          diagnosis. Quality control reviews have shown that
          case-ascertainment through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> has been virtually
          complete [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . Over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases reported to
          the registry are histologically confirmed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> also
          maintains a link with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii Department of Health</ENAMEX>, which
          allows for death information to be captured in the HTR
          database.
        
        
          Linking
          The insurance claims for this study were obtained from
          a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX> who was a party to the memorandum of
          agreement. The linked data set contained <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases
          diagnosed from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 through 1998</TIMEX>. During the linking
          process, a list of health plan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who had at least
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cancer diagnostic codes in their claims history were
          matched against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> using a probabilistic method. For
          each matched record, the health plan furnished all claims
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>. They also indicated whether the
          individual was enrolled in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fee-For-Service</ENAMEX> (FFS) or a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capitated</ENAMEX> (HMO) plan, a choice provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX>.
          However, the majority of linked <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases belonged to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFS</ENAMEX> plan and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> plan provided by this insurer
          differs considerably from a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> aged
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years and older</TIMEX> were included only if they were still
          working and had primary coverage through the health plan
          or if they were covered under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> but also had
          secondary coverage through the health plan. The dataset
          furnished by the health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX> contained all claims
          processed for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in this study. The data
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> included: date of service, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classification of Disease</ENAMEX>, version 9 (ICD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) diagnosis
          codes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Procedural Terminology</ENAMEX> (CPT) codes
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> specialty code. The dataset
          contained claims for services from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laboratories</ENAMEX>, freestanding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, as well as
          outpatient services provided by hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> set
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Breast cancer</ENAMEX> cases accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16.6%</NUMEX> of all cancer
          cases recorded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> during the period from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> to
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. In the linked dataset, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27.7%</NUMEX> of the cases were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cases. Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ICD-9-CM</ENAMEX> code range [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ]
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">174.0 to 174.9</NUMEX>), we identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,377</NUMEX>
          female breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases. We then excluded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">265</NUMEX> cases
          diagnosed after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 1998</TIMEX> because we would not have a
          complete history of claims data covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of treatment. We also identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had
          been recorded twice in the linked dataset because breast
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> was diagnosed in both breasts, as identified by
          the laterality codes. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the diagnosis date
          was identical, in which case we considered the two
          diagnoses as one case. For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> cases with different
          diagnoses dates, we retained both records because there
          was a separate completed course of treatment for the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in each breast. We eliminated one case that was in
          the linked dataset and had inpatient data but no
          outpatient data, resulting in a dataset containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,088</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cases.
        
        
          Staging
          We used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> information in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extent of Disease</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EOD-10</ENAMEX>) field [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] to determine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Joint</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Cancer</ENAMEX> (AJCC) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNM</ENAMEX> stage [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] , where T
          represents the primary tumor size, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> refers to lymph node
          involvement, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> refers to presence of metastases. In
          cases where the tumor size was unknown, we assigned a
          stage only if the size was not a determinant in the TNM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grouping</ENAMEX>. If the extension was unknown, we equated it to
          extension <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> (confinement to breast tissue and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX>). For
          the small number of cases (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) for whom lymph node
          involvement code was unknown, we considered this the same
          as no lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">node</ENAMEX> involvement because the tumor size was
          so small for these cases that a lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">node dissection</ENAMEX> was
          not considered necessary at the time of this study. The
          results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNM</ENAMEX> staging agreed well with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEER</ENAMEX>
          summary stage codes.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer</ENAMEX> treatment
          We used the CPT codes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] in the claims dataset to
          identify the type of surgery performed. For mastectomies,
          we included codes for simple and subcutaneous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mastectomies</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19180 and 19182</NUMEX>), radical mastectomies
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19200 and 19220</NUMEX>) and modified radical mastectomy
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">19240</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> was identified by the CPT codes for partial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mastectomies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">19160, 19162</ENAMEX>). We also included codes for
          excision of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cysts</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19120 and 19125</NUMEX>) as
          these codes meet the definition of a lumpectomy, although
          we recognize that some surgeons may have billed these
          codes for excisional biopsies as a diagnostic procedure.
          If BCS was initially performed, but followed by a
          subsequent mastectomy, the subject was classified in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mastectomy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. This situation would have occurred when
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> code was actually used for a diagnostic biopsy
          and the subsequent surgical treatment was a mastectomy or
          in situations where a lumpectomy was first selected, but
          a mastectomy became necessary because pathological
          examination revealed cancerous cells in the margins of
          the excised tissue. CPT codes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77261 to 77799</TIMEX> were
          selected to determine whether radiation therapy was
          received. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> codes and also a number of other
          codes used by the health plan for billing were considered
          evidence of chemotherapy treatment.
        
        
          Comorbidities
          Information on the existence of comorbidities was
          extracted from the claims data using the occurrence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ICD-9</ENAMEX> codes associated with comorbid conditions included
          in the Charlson Index [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . We also analyzed data for
          conditions that were not included in that index, but
          occurred at a high enough frequency to warrant
          examination as possible comorbidities, in particular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lipid disorders</ENAMEX>. We included the
          following twelve comorbid conditions into our index:
          diabetes with complications, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes w</ENAMEX>/o complications,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hypertension</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cerebrovascular disease</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chronic pulmonary disease</ENAMEX>, peripheral vascular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney disease</ENAMEX>, liver <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, rheumatological <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>,
          hypothyroidism, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lipid metabolism disorders</ENAMEX>.
          Comorbidities were based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>' claims with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">respective ICD-9</ENAMEX> code [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 12-months</TIMEX> period
          preceding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> was diagnosed.
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The month</TIMEX> of diagnosis was excluded to avoid identifying
          as comorbidities any complications or conditions directly
          resulting from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> treatment. Laboratory, radiology,
          and other diagnostic services were excluded from the
          comorbidity identification process because tests may have
          been done to rule out the condition. Each subject was
          assigned a comorbidity score of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0</NUMEX> (no <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">condition</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (one
          condition), or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or more</NUMEX> conditions).
        
        
          Other variables
          In addition to stage at diagnosis and size of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX>,
          we examined several other variables that were possible
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">determinants</ENAMEX> in the utilization of BCS 
          vs. mastectomy in early stage
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, including <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at diagnosis, ethnicity,
          island of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>, and marital status. For ethnicity,
          we used the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>,
          Caucasian, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Filipino</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>). All other
          ethnicities were grouped into an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other</ENAMEX>" category. The
          specific island of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> was coded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX>, but
          since close to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> resides on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
          ] , we classified <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> as either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Oahu</ENAMEX> or non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oahu</ENAMEX>.
          For marital status, we grouped all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who were
          identified as single, separate, divorced or widowed in
          the unmarried category. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under age 50</TIMEX> were
          considered pre-menopausal and women <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> and older
          were classified as postmenopausal. Tumor grade
          information from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> record was grouped into grade I
          (well-differentiated cells) 
          vs. all other grades (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX>
          and unknown).
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          All analyses were performed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX> version <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.00</NUMEX> for
          Windows (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>). Simple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kappa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">statistics (κ</ENAMEX>) was calculated to validate the treatment
          information from the insurance claims and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27</NUMEX>
          ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> was used as reference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> throughout the
          analysis. It was defined as the dependent (outcome)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variable</ENAMEX> and coded as a dichotomous variable, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          indicating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> received and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> indicating mastectomy
          received. Age was entered in units of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and tumor
          size was grouped into units of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> millimeters (one
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centimeter</ENAMEX>). For analyses of ethnicity as a predictor of
          treatment selection, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caucasian</ENAMEX> was used as the control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> and indicator variables for all other ethnic groups
          were created. Logistic regression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] was used to
          explore the influence of each variable on the use of BCS 
          vs. mastectomy. First, we
          considered each independent variable by itself in a model
          and then we entered all variables simultaneously in a
          logistic regression model. Odds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ratios</ENAMEX> (OR) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] with
          corresponding <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> Confidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intervals</ENAMEX> (CI) were
          calculated to measure the degree of influence of
          variables on the utilization of BCS 
          vs. mastectomy.
        
      
      
        Results
        Based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNM</ENAMEX> stages, we identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">722</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">stage I, IIA</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">IIB breast cancer</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66.4%</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,088</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cases in the linked data set). These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">722</NUMEX>
        cases represented <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32.8%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">722</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,203</NUMEX> cases) of all early
        stage breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases recorded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> during the
        study period. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the
        study population (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>) were diagnosed in stage I of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 24% and 12%</NUMEX> in stage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIB</ENAMEX>,
        respectively. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately 30%</NUMEX> of the study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> were
        aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than 50 years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close to half</NUMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> to 64 years
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years and older</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> resided on the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX>. Overall, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52.8%</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX>. Of the cases diagnosed at stage I,
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> had received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47%</NUMEX> a mastectomy.
        This decreased to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> for stage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIA</ENAMEX> and to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34%</NUMEX> for stage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIB</ENAMEX>. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years</TIMEX> and older, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX>, compared
        to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 50 years of age</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-64</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. While <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX> underwent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 43%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> residing on the outer islands
        received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX>. We observed no statistically significant
        differences between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> and mastectomy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in terms
        of ethnicity, comorbidity count, menopausal status, marital
        status, and insurance plan. We found very high agreement
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> data and claims data in identifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BCS [κ</ENAMEX> =
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.91</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.88</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.94</NUMEX>)], <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 32</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misclassified</ENAMEX>. For the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who received BCS
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92.1%</NUMEX>), the lumpectomy was followed by radiation therapy.
        Additional chemotherapy was given to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34.1% and 42.5%</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had a lumpectomy or a mastectomy,
        respectively.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the univariate</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>), we found that tumor
        size and grade, island of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>, age, and stage at
        diagnosis were predictors of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> treatment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>
        residing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX> were considerably more likely to have BCS
        than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> living on all other islands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. For
        each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one-centimeter</NUMEX> increase in tumor size, there was a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>
        lesser chance of undergoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX>. Since size of tumor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">correlates</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> stage, this also decreased the
        likelihood for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in stage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIB</ENAMEX> to receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> with well-differentiated tumor grades were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> more
        likely to undergo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> as compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with all other
        grades. We found that for each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year</TIMEX> increment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>,
        the chances of having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>. We also observed
        that average tumor size was inversely related to age. Mean
        tumor sizes (in cm) with standard deviations were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.82</NUMEX> ±
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.59 ± 1.2</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.39 ± 0.94</NUMEX> for women younger than 50
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 to 64 years</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years</TIMEX> and older,
        respectively. Therefore, the smaller tumor sizes may
        account for the greater likelihood of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> among older
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
        In a combined model with all independent variables in a
        logistic regression, island of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> remained the only
        significant predictor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>
        living on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> more likely to have BCS than women
        on the outer islands. Although all other variables lost
        their statistical significance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> for age, TNM
        stage, tumor size, and tumor grade remained similar in
        magnitude as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the univariate</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>. Although none of the
        ethnicity variables was significant, it appeared that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Filipino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were less likely to receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> than women
        from all other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Residence on outer islands did not
        explain this observation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNM</ENAMEX> stage of IIB
        were still <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> less likely to receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> than women
        diagnosed at stage I, but the relation lost its statistical
        significance due to the small number of cases. Menopausal
        or marital status, type of health plan, or the number of
        comorbidities were not related to the type of surgery.
      
      
        Discussion
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX> of residence at the time of diagnosis was the
        most important predictor for receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BCS</ENAMEX> in this dataset
        of health plan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> with early stage breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> living on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> more likely to have BCS than
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> living on outer islands. Age at diagnosis and tumor
        size were also related to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> treatment although
        they were not statistically significant in the combined
        model. Contrary to our expectation and a previous
        publication [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] , the number of comorbid conditions did
        not effect treatment in this analysis. The importance of
        geographic location can be explained by the availability of
        radiation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> on the different <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>.
        Whereas on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Oahu</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> can be reached within
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX>, distances on the outer islands are much farther.
        Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Island</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maui</ENAMEX> have a radiation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facility</ENAMEX>, but they are hard to reach from many parts of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">islands</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> residing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kauai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Molokai</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanai</ENAMEX> have
        to fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to receive the course of treatment
        or they have to remain there temporarily. Because this may
        be not be economically feasible for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, as well as
        physically and psychologically challenging, it is possible
        that many women choose to undergo a mastectomy instead.
        Alternatively, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> in rural areas may
        favor mastectomy because of differences in education or
        cultural attitudes toward medical advances. We do not have
        information to explain why a small proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underwent BCS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.9%</NUMEX>) did not receive radiation. However,
        compared to other reports [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 30 31</NUMEX> ] , the proportion of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who received radiation is very high. An interview
        study with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] showed that some patients
        decide against their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>' recommendation for
        radiation because they fear the treatment or hold certain
        beliefs about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. For other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, radiation may
        have been contraindicated due to comorbid conditions.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, a national BCS rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42.6%</NUMEX> was reported [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>
        ] with a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46.7%</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific region</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>). Our results
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 to 1998</TIMEX> indicate a slightly higher rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52.8%</NUMEX>). Geographic differences in BCS use have repeatedly
        been described in the literature. In western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> residing outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> area were less
        likely to have BCS than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> residing inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>,
        in particular if radiation therapy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> were not
        available in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>. Comparing rates across the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> was much more common in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . Low BCS rates were
        also found in rural areas, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South Carolina</ENAMEX>
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . An
        analysis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991-1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SEER</ENAMEX> data [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] demonstrated a
        strong association between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> and distance to the next
        radiotherapy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. The likelihood of undergoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> was
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> lower among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> living <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than 15 miles</NUMEX> from the
        next radiotherapy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>.
        In contrast to our results, a number of studies have
        shown that the likelihood of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> decreases with increasing
        age [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 30 33</NUMEX> ] , possibly due to less concern about
        cosmetic results. Because of the relatively small
        proportion (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX>) of women <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years and older</TIMEX> and the fact
        that the women <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years</TIMEX> and older in our study had a health
        plan other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, they were not directly comparable
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in the published literature. Therefore,
        our ability to observe an effect among older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX>. In particular, we were not able to examine the
        treatment of women <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years</TIMEX> and older who have been
        described as receiving more BCS than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 65 to 79</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . Our findings of lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> in smaller and
        well differentiated tumors agree with previous studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>
        ] , but the absence of an effect of comorbid conditions
        disagrees with a study in older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] that showed a
        higher rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with comorbidities. Type of
        health plan did not predict type of treatment in our study
        probably because the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in this data set had
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFS</ENAMEX> plan. In previous analyses with a larger variety of
        health plans, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were considerably more likely to
        receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> received more BCS in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . However, a study using
        administrative data [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] described lower BCS use among
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and treatment was similar by health plan
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern California</ENAMEX>.
        Our study had several limitations, including the
        possibility of incomplete claims histories if patients
        changed health plans during the course of treatment, but
        the high agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HTR</ENAMEX> information indicates that the
        validity of insurance claims information was high.
        Continuing efforts by the health plan through feedback
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loops</ENAMEX> has improved diagnostic coding [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, but
        as documented for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> claims, problems remain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] .
        As discussed above, our study sample of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> does not represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
        excluding in particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>, and the relatively small number
        of uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. The exclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> claims
        lead to a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, whereas the lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>
        claims biased the cases toward a higher socioeconomic
        status. On the other hand, the study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> represented
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> quite well in terms of ethnicity (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of Business <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1998 1705 /id</ENAMEX>). Because our data set
        included <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42.4%</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cases under 65 years
        diagnosed during the study period, the results represents
        this population much better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of older
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Also, we were unable to measure some factors that
        have been found to be important in other reports, in
        particular, influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] , physician
        specialty [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] , type of hospital (teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> with radiation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, private, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36 38 39 43</NUMEX> ] , socio-economic status and
        education [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] , tumor-breast ratio and the expected
        cosmetic results [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 9</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> interactions
        before surgery [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] , and psychological factors, such as
        fear of radiation or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . The strengths of using
        of insurance claims data for this analysis were twofold.
        First, we had more detailed treatment information available
        than collected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor registry</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the
        diagnostic codes in the claims data allowed us to estimate
        the number of comorbid conditions before the cancer
        diagnosis.
        The results of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> study combining tumor registry
        and insurance claims data raises an important issue for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> practice in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of Hawaii</ENAMEX> and elsewhere.
        Health care providers and insurance plans need to work with
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to develop viable solutions to facilitate
        access to radiation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for women residing in remote
        locations, such as islands with no radiation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>.
        Attitudes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> living in rural areas
        may be important in the choice of treatment, but could not
        be investigated in this project. Future research that
        includes interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> may
        investigate attitudes toward certain types of treatment and
        identify additional barriers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCS</ENAMEX>, such as psychological
        problems. In order to understand how treatment decisions
        were made in practice, qualitative information from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicians</ENAMEX> and breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> should be collected
        and examined in detail. Further validation of treatment and
        comorbidity from insurance claims data would strengthen
        this type of research in the future. The inclusion of a
        larger proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cases is needed to
        establish the validity of our findings for the population
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">at-large</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
    
  
