
  
    
      
        Background
        Cellulose acetate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phthalate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAP</ENAMEX>) is a promising
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microbicide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for prevention of infection by
        sexually transmitted <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> (STD) pathogens, including
        HIV-1 [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAP inactivates HIV-1</ENAMEX> and blocks
        the coreceptor binding site on the virus envelope
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glycoprotein</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX>, while leaving the site for the primary
        cellular receptor CD4 accessible [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] Soluble CD4 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sCD4</NUMEX>)
        was shown to inhibit HIV-1 infection by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mechanisms:
        reversible blockage of virus binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, and
        irreversible inactivation of virus infectivity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] .
        Since CAP and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> bind to distinct domains on the HIV-1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">envelope</ENAMEX>, it was of interest to determine whether or not
        these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ligands affect virus infectivity synergistically
        as do other combinations of anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">HIV-1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Binding</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sCD4</ENAMEX> leads to conformational changes in
        gp120 [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14 15 16 17</NUMEX> ] . Binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp120</NUMEX> to coreceptors
        CXCR4 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX>, respectively, triggers additional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conformational</ENAMEX> changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> envelope glycoproteins [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> ] For these reasons it was of interest to determine
        whether a) pretreatment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sCD4</TIMEX> would affect
        subsequent binding of CAP to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus particles</ENAMEX>, and b) CAP
        binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus particles</ENAMEX> in the presence or absence of
        sCD4 would elicit conformational changes which could affect
        HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infectivity</ENAMEX>. Such studies were expected to elucidate
        further the mechanisms involved in the antiviral/virucidal
        activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and to contribute to the potential
        development of microbicides combining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more
        anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">HIV-1</NUMEX> compounds with distinct target sites.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Reagents
          The following monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (mAbs) were used:
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NC-1</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> mAb raised against the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix
          bundle from HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] ; and anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p24</NUMEX> mAb
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ImmunoDiagnostics, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woburn, MA</ENAMEX>). Rabbit antibodies
          against the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle were prepared as
          described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . Rabbit antiserum against HIV-1 IIIB
          gp120 was prepared as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] and shown to
          cross-react with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX> (own unpublished data).
          Recombinant soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD4</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sCD4</NUMEX>) was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genentech Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South San Francisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CA. Recombinant HIV-1 IIIB gp120</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biotinylated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> and biotinylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sCD4</ENAMEX> were from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ImmunoDiagnostics, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woburn, MA</ENAMEX>. Purified recombinant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protein A/G</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>. Pelletted,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>-fold concentrates of HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.8</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 10virus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">particles/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.47</NUMEX> × <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 10virus particles/ml</ENAMEX>) [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> ] were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Biotechnologies, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MD. Biotin</ENAMEX> labeled goat anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgG</ENAMEX> and anti-rabbit
          IgG were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche Diagnostics Corporation</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IN. Chicken</ENAMEX> serum was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM Concepts</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toms River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiserum</ENAMEX> to phthalate was prepared by
          immunization of rabbits with phthalic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anhydride</ENAMEX> treated
          rabbit serum albumin [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . Horseradish peroxidase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX>) labeled streptavidin was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zymed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CA. HRP</ENAMEX> was quantitated using a kit from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkegaard & Perry Laboratories, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MD. Enzyme</ENAMEX> linked immunosorbent assay (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>) kits for
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">HIV-1</NUMEX> p24 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckman Coulter, Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>. The tyrosine-sulfated peptide from CCR5 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ]
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">; {S</ENAMEX>-peptide; MDYQVSSPI 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y DIN</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y YTSEPSQK</ENAMEX>; ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sulfotyrosine</ENAMEX>)} was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
          Peptide, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvale</ENAMEX>, CA. The corresponding control peptide
          with tyrosines instead of sulfotyrosines, and N36
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGIVQQQNNLLRAIEAQQHLLQLTVWGIKQLQARVL</ENAMEX>) and C34
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIEWDREINNYTSIIYSLIEESQNQQEKNEQELL</ENAMEX>) peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>
          of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> core [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] of HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX> were from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AnaSpec, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CA. CAP</ENAMEX> was a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastman</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical Company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingsport</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>. H9 cells chronically
          infected with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PM1</NUMEX> cells were obtained
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIDS Research and Reference Reagent Program</ENAMEX>
          contributed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drs. R. Gallo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. Lusso and M. Reitz</ENAMEX>,
          respectively.
        
        
          Inhibition of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> infection
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 TCID</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ) in the presence or absence of
          graded concentrations of virus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX>,
          respectively, in RPMI-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1640</NUMEX> medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal
          bovine serum (FBS) were mixed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MT-2 cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          4cells/well) and placed into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well polystyrene plates.
          The mixtures were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">37°C overnight</TIMEX>. On the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          ndday, culture supernatants were removed from each well
          and fresh medium was added. On the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> thday, culture
          supernatants were collected and tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p24 antigen</ENAMEX> by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX>. Similar experiments were done with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">× 10 5virus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">particles</ENAMEX>), except that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PM1</NUMEX> cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] were
          used instead of MT-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cells.
          The inhibitory activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> in
          combination, against HIV-1 infection was determined as
          described above. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>:sCD4 weight ratios in the
          combinations were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:1 and 2:1</TIMEX> for HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> and HIV-1
          BaL, respectively. The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> inhibitory concentrations (IC 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ) and the combination index values
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>) were calculated as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] using
          a computer program (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CalcuSyn</ENAMEX>) kindly provided by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. Chou</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>). A CI
          value < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> indicates synergy and that of > <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          indicates antagonism. The compound dose reductions were
          calculated based on the IC 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> value for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sCD4</ENAMEX> used alone
          or in combination [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
          To measure the virucidal activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CAP</ENAMEX>/sCD4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">combinations</ENAMEX>, treated and untreated purified <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HIV-1</ENAMEX> IIIB
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.4 × 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8virus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">particles</ENAMEX>) (unlike in the experiments
          described in an earlier report [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] where infectious
          tissue culture medium was used instead), were serially
          diluted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2- to 256</NUMEX>-fold in RPMI-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1640</NUMEX> medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>, mixed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MT-2 cells</ENAMEX> and placed into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well
          polystyrene plates. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Virus replication</ENAMEX> was monitored by
          measuring p24 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> as described above. Similar
          experiments were done with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.5</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 8virus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">particles</ENAMEX>), except that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PM1</NUMEX> cells were used instead of
          MT-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cells. The percentage of residual infectivity after
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CAP/sCD4</ENAMEX> treatment was calculated from calibration curves
          relating absorbance to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> dilutions of untreated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">viruses</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>)
          For virus capture assays, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well polystyrene
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immulon II; Dynatech Laboratories Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chantilly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>) were coated either with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μg/well</ENAMEX>).
          or with mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NC-1</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] . For coating with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, a
          solution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100 μl; 10 μg/</ENAMEX>ml in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> acetate pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.0</NUMEX>) was added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>. After incubation overnight
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed and postcoated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at
          20°C with bovine serum albumin (BSA) and gelatin (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> acetate pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>). For coating with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were first coated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> A/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">μg</ENAMEX>/well) in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M Tris</ENAMEX> buffer, pH <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.8</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20°C</TIMEX>,
          followed by mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NC-1</ENAMEX> or normal mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> (= control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wells</ENAMEX>) {<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> μg/well; diluted in phosphate buffered saline
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>)} for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20°C</TIMEX>. Coating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">N36/C34 peptide</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complexes</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.01 to 10 μM</NUMEX>) was done under conditions
          described for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> A<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/G. Subsequently</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">washed</ENAMEX> and postcoated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> and gelatin as described
          above, except that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were dissolved in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.14</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.0</NUMEX> (TS). Chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serum</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>) in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ch-PBS</ENAMEX>) was used instead in experiments with HIV-1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX> to suppress binding of this virus to control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX> and stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. HIV-1
          virus particles suspended in diluents and treated as
          indicated in legends to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Figs. 2</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3, 5were</TIMEX> added to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wells</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. Subsequently the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10×</NUMEX> with ice cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:50</TIMEX> anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p24</NUMEX> mAb in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ch</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> for
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX> to minimize the contribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p24 antigen</ENAMEX> not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> particles to absorbance readings
          corresponding to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p24 antigen</ENAMEX> released from detergent
          treated virus. The washed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> with bound virus
          particles were then treated with lysis buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> Nonidet
          P40 {NP40}, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 μg/ml BSA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. The
          supernatants were removed and tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p24 antigen</ENAMEX>
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELISA kits</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckman Coulter, Inc.</ENAMEX> following the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s protocol.
          To measure the binding of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">biotinyl-sCD4</TIMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">biotinyl-gp120</ENAMEX> (in the presence and absence of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sCD4</NUMEX>),
          respectively, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, the biotinylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were
          added to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and control postcoated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> without CAP,
          respectively, at dilutions shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The binding
          of these biotinylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>, after
          washing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX>, was determined by adding
          HRP-streptavidin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μg/ml</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> gelatin
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05 %</NUMEX> Tween 20 for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">washed</ENAMEX> and bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX> was detected using the test kit from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirkegaard & Perry</ENAMEX> following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protocol</ENAMEX>, and the absorbance was read at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> nm.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich ELISA</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle was
          performed as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . Treated and control virus
          preparations were incubated with lysis buffer for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> min
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20°C</TIMEX> and then added to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> coated with rabbit
          polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> core. In control
          experiments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> alone (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 mg/ml</ENAMEX> in lysis buffer) was
          added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>. After incubation at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4°C overnight</TIMEX>,
          binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles was determined from
          subsequent binding of mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NC-1</ENAMEX>, which was added at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">μg/ml</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">/1% BSA/1%</NUMEX> gelatin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 μl/well</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at
          37°C. Subsequently the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/0</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.05%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tween 20</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biotin</ENAMEX> labeled anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">μl</ENAMEX>/well; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">125 ng/ml</ENAMEX> diluted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> dry
          fat-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>) was added. After incubation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at
          37°C, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed as described above and
          HRP-streptavidin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">125 ng/ml</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> goat
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 μl/well</ENAMEX>) was added. After incubation for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/0</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.05%</NUMEX>
          Tween <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX> was quantitated as described above.
          To exclude the remote possibility that mAb NC-1
          reacted with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold dilutions (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25 to 8</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">μg/ml</ENAMEX>) of the mAb and of control mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX>, respectively
          (each at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> μg/ml in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>-BG) were added to CAP coated or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAP-gp120</ENAMEX> coated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">washed</ENAMEX> and bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> was quantitated as described above
          for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich ELISA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were prepared by
          coating first with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> under conditions
          described above for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> A/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, except that the pH was
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.8</NUMEX>. Subsequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> was added to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wells</ENAMEX> as described above. In control experiments, serial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dilutions</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/200 to 1/1,600</NUMEX>) of rabbit anti-phthalate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiserum</ENAMEX> and of normal rabbit serum, respectively (each
          diluted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-fold in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>-BG) were added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>.
          Bound rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> was quantitated using biotinylated goat
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-rabbit IgG</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Shedding of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gp120</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> particles
          Preparations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">purified</ENAMEX> HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX>,
          respectively, were incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 min at 37°C</NUMEX> in the
          presence or absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> (final concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 mg/ml</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> preparations were not exposed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. Virus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">particles</ENAMEX> and released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> were separated by
          centrifugation as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . The virus containing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pellets</ENAMEX> and supernatant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> were assayed by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          allowing gp120 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> of polystyrene plates were coated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> A/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>,
          followed by polyclonal rabbit anti-gp120 (diluted
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>-fold) under conditions described above for virus
          capture assays. Serial twofold dilutions in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>-BG of
          preparations containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp120</ENAMEX> were added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>.
          After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20°C</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed and bound gp120
          was detected by addition of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">biotinyl-sCD4</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μg</ENAMEX>) followed
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX>-streptavidin as described above. The amount of
          gp120 in the virus <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> and the supernatant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> was
          calculated from calibration curves relating absorbance
          readings to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp120</NUMEX> dilutions. All determinations were done
          in triplicate.
        
        
          Molecular modeling: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Docking of CAP</ENAMEX> on the gp41core
          structure
          The acetylated and phthaloylated cellotetraose unit
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX>) composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four 1,4</NUMEX>-linked β-D-glucose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>,
          which is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">part of CAP</ENAMEX> was created in
          Quanta <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] as described before [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> was
          minimized by the steepest descent method followed by the
          adopted basis <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton-Raphson</ENAMEX> (ABNR) method. The energy
          difference of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> Kcal/mol between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> successive
          structures during both minimization steps was used as the
          termination criterion.
          The docking simulations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> were performed using
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DockVision</ENAMEX> program [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] on the entire surface of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> core structure {The X-ray crystal structure of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> core, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1aik</TIMEX>, was retrieved from the protein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">databank http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rcsb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org}.</ENAMEX> A grid box (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">125 × 125 Å ×</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">125 Å</NUMEX>) was created to cover the entire gp41 core surface
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> to dock. The default forcefield (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX>
          Potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Function</ENAMEX>) was used to perform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monte Carlo</ENAMEX>
          runs for docking simulations. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the gp41</TIMEX> core
          structure were kept rigid during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">docking</TIMEX>. Intermolecular
          energy criteria were used to select the lowest energy
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">docked CTAP</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Electrostatic potential maps of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp120</ENAMEX> and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120-CD4</ENAMEX> complex
          Electrostatic potentials were calculated using a
          Poisson-Boltzmann solver included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GRASP</ENAMEX> program [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> ] . All default parameters were used. The
          electrostatic potential maps are shown on the accessible
          surface of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120 and the gp120-CD4</TIMEX> complex.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Enhancement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAP-HIV-1</ENAMEX> binding by CD4
          Earlier studies [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] indicated that CAP binding to
          the envelope glycoprotein <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> and to HIV-1 virus
          particles, respectively, did not interfere with their
          subsequent association with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sCD4</TIMEX>. Thus, it would be
          expected that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> would not inhibit the attachment of
          HIV-1 to target cells and would block only subsequent
          steps obligatory for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> infection initiated by
          engagement of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CXCR4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">coreceptors</ENAMEX>, respectively.
          The latter event was shown to be blocked by CAP [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] and
          has been considered the basis for the virus inhibitory
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus inactivating</ENAMEX> properties of CAP at neutral pH.
          However, it has not been determined whether or not
          occupancy of CD4 binding sites within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> would affect
          subsequent interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>. To answer this
          question, the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp120</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120-sCD4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>,
          respectively, to immobilized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> was studied. Results
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1indicated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that sCD4</TIMEX> enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gp120-CAP</ENAMEX>
          binding. Maximum enhancement was observed at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sCD4/</ENAMEX>gp120
          weight ratios of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">≥ 0.6</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1insert), corresponding to a
          molar ratio of ≥ 1.2 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] , in agreement with the
          observation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120-CD4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> consist of one
          molecule each of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Biotinyl-sCD4</ENAMEX> in
          the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> did not bind to CAP. Similarly,
          pretreatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HIV-1 with sCD4</ENAMEX> resulted in subsequent
          increased binding of virus with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, the effect being
          much more pronounced with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX> in comparison with
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Synergism between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> in inhibiting HIV-1
          infection
          Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> can bind CAP and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> simultaneously, and
          the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> is enhanced in the presence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sCD4</TIMEX>,
          it was of interest to determine whether these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ligands
          act on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> cooperatively, resulting in synergism of
          their antiviral effects. This indeed was observed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          1and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sCD4 synergistically</ENAMEX> inhibited
          infection by HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>) and HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). A similar synergism was observed for virucidal
          activity against HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) but only additive
          effects were found for HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX> (in the absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sCD4</TIMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> for CAP = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.49</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml; in the
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 μg/ml</ENAMEX>], which caused an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.85</NUMEX>-fold
          decrease of infectivity, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.39</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml for residual
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infectivity</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Treatment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> leads to induction of
          gp41 <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles
          Earlier studies [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] , in which the binding of CAP
          treated and untreated virus with antibodies specific for
          distinct regions on the envelope glycoproteins <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> and
          gp41 was studied, indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> had either no effect
          or caused decreased binding with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against
          several peptides from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> but only against a single
          peptide, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">557-586</ENAMEX>, from gp41 (see Discussion). It was
          intended to expand these studies to mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NC-1</ENAMEX>, specific
          for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . Results of
          preliminary studies indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> did not interfere
          with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle formation from constituent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX> derived from near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C-terminus</ENAMEX> of the
          gp41 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ectodomain</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] ; (own unpublished data).
          Surprisingly, and unlike with mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2F5</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] specific for
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal region of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> ectodomain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] , CAP
          treatment enhanced the binding of both HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> and
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX> to mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NC-1</ENAMEX>, reacting with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41 six</NUMEX>-helix
          bundles from both HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), suggesting
          the formation of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> within virus particles
          as a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CAP</ENAMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). Treatment with
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> further enhanced the expression of the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles in the case of HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 5B</ENAMEX>), but
          not in the case of HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 5A</ENAMEX>). sCD4 alone was
          less effective in enhancing the expression of the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles. Treatment of neither recombinant gp160
          or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp41 C-</ENAMEX>peptide with CAP resulted in generation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epitopes</ENAMEX> recognized by mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NC-1</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
          To exclude the remote possibility that mAb NC-1
          reacted with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-bound CAP, and that this,
          rather than binding to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles, would lead to
          results shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, the binding of the mAb to CAP
          coated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> was investigated. No significant binding of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mAb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-1</ENAMEX> and of control mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX>, respectively, to wells
          coated by CAP directly or to CAP bound to HIV-1 IIIB
          gp120 was observed. On the other hand, anti-phthalate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> reacted with both forms of immobilized CAP
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). These results support the conclusions from
          results in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
          Engagement of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp120</NUMEX> coreceptor binding site with a
          tyrosine sulfated peptide from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus</ENAMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coreceptor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] , shown to inhibit infection by
          CCR5-dependent, but not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR4-dependent</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">HIV-1 isolates,</ENAMEX>
          was sufficient to increase the expression of the gp41
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> BaL <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus particles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>).
          A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CCR5</NUMEX> control peptide the tyrosines of which were not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sulfated</ENAMEX> did not have this effect. Analogous experiments
          with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> were not performed since there are no
          published data concerning the biological properties of
          tyrosine sulfated peptides from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus of</ENAMEX>
          CXCR4.
          In the experiments described above evidence for the
          formation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41 six</NUMEX>-helix bundles was obtained from
          capture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5 S-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptide</ENAMEX> treated virus
          particles, respectively, onto wells coated with mAb NC-1.
          This assay is equivalent to an immunoprecipitation assay
          with solid phase mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NC-1</ENAMEX>. In order to provide further
          evidence for the induction of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles
          by the distinct ligands binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> envelope, the
          newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> in virus lysates were also
          quantitated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich ELISA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . The results not
          only unequivocally confirmed the induction of gp41
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sCD4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>-peptide from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>, but also provided evidence that
          these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> were undetectable in untreated virus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">particles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.078 to 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml) in the
          absence of virus particles provided negative results in
          this assay. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CCR5</NUMEX> peptide lacking sulfated tyrosines
          did not induce the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles. Thus, it seems
          likely that the detection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41 six</NUMEX>-helix bundles in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">untreated HIV-1</ENAMEX> using the virion capture assay was due to
          their spontaneous formation during prolonged incubation
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1</ENAMEX> in these tests. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles were also
          induced by heating (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 min at 60°C</NUMEX>) HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> particles
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>).
          In summary, blocking by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> of the coreceptor binding
          sites on the virus envelope glycoprotein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp120</ENAMEX> within
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus particles</ENAMEX> appears to induce conformational
          changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp41</TIMEX> leading to the formation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix
          bundle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Shedding of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gp120</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> particles
          It was reported that treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">HIV-1 gp120/</ENAMEX>gp41
          envelope glycoprotein oligomers with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sCD4</NUMEX> lead to
          shedding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120-sCD4</ENAMEX> complexes concomitant with
          increased exposure of some cryptic epitopes on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX> ] . Therefore, it was of interest to determine
          whether or not shedding of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gp120</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus particles</ENAMEX> was
          required for the CAP induced exposure of binding sites
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mAb NC-1</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp41</TIMEX>. Treatment of HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> and BaL
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> did not decrease the level of virus-associated
          gp120 in comparison with control virus preparations
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>). The results agree with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> life of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> h
          for virus associated gp120 in the course of spontaneous
          gp120 shedding from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1 HXB3</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37°C</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] and the
          small sCD4 induced release of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp120</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at 37°C
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] . Thus gp120 shedding was not a prerequisite for
          the formation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41 six</NUMEX>-helix bundles.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Earlier studies [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] indicated that CAP treated HIV-1
        particles have their coreceptor, i.e. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR4 and CCR5</TIMEX>,
        binding sites obstructed, while sites involved in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> appeared unaffected. This suggested
        that HIV-1 could bind <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD4</ENAMEX> and CAP at the same time,
        independently. Since association with CD4 induces
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conformational</ENAMEX> changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the HIV-1</TIMEX> envelope glycoprotein
        gp120 [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 16 17</NUMEX> ] , it was of interest to determine: (a)
        whether CD4 binding to HIV-1 would affect subsequent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of the virus with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and (b) the consequences
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">both CD4</TIMEX> and CAP binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus particles</ENAMEX>. First, it
        was found that pretreatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120 with sCD4</ENAMEX> enhanced
        subsequent binding with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). This could be
        ascribed to conformational changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX>, to the
        concealment of surface areas with the greatest negative
        charge on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>), which could
        diminish the electrostatic attraction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between gp120</TIMEX> and
        negatively charged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, or to additional CAP binding sites
        on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120-sCD4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>. The binding of
        HIV-1 with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> was similarly enhanced by pretreatment with
        sCD4 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), the effect being much more pronounced with
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">R5</NUMEX> virus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV-1 BaL</ENAMEX>, in comparison with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">X4</NUMEX> virus,
        HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX>. These observations may be related to the
        recognized role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD4</ENAMEX> in inducing conformational changes
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> that contribute to the exposure of binding sites
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR4</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17 38</NUMEX> ] .
        Furthermore, it seemed important to determine whether
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">simultaneous CD4</ENAMEX> and enhanced CAP binding to HIV-1 would
        result in synergistic effects for inhibition of HIV-1
        infection. Evidence for such synergism was indeed
        established (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        Earlier studies [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] , in which the binding of CAP
        treated and untreated virus to antibodies specific for
        distinct regions on the envelope glycoproteins <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> and
        gp41 was studied, indicated that CAP caused decreased
        binding with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against several peptides from gp120
        but only with a single <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> against peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">557-586</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from gp41</TIMEX> (for numbering of amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid residues</ENAMEX> see our
        earlier publication [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] ). Thus, there are fewer binding
        sites for CAP on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp41</TIMEX> than on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX>. Interestingly,
        molecular docking studies revealed that phthalic and acetic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid anhydride modified cellotetratose</ENAMEX>, a subunit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">docked</ENAMEX> to a single site on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the gp41</TIMEX> core structure
        overlapping the peptide <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">557</NUMEX>-586 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>). This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> is
        in the vicinity of the most prominent positively charged
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> on the surface of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> core which has an overall
        negative charge. Since CAP blocks coreceptor binding sites
        on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp120</NUMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] it was of interest to determine whether this
        blockade would lead to conformational changes in HIV-1
        gp41, similar to those elicited by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD4</TIMEX> or coreceptor
        binding to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX>.
        The occupancy of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD4</ENAMEX> and coreceptor binding sites by
        their respective ligands elicits downstream conformational
        changes in the envelope glycoprotein <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp41</TIMEX>, rendering it
        competent for fusion between virus and target cell
        membranes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 40 41 42 43</NUMEX> ] . Shedding of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gp120</NUMEX> from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus particles</ENAMEX> is not required for subsequent membrane
        fusion events [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] . The induction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41 six</NUMEX>-helix
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bundles</ENAMEX>, detectable by mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NC-1</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> in the absence of
        gp120 shedding is consistent with this conclusion. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conformational</ENAMEX> changes lead to the formation of a
        coiled-coil in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp41</TIMEX>, consisting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 -terminal leucine/isoleucine zipper</ENAMEX>
        regions, each contributed by one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> subunits of
        the envelope glycoprotein trimer. In the presence of target
        cell membranes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -terminal fusion peptide is displaced
        in the direction of the target cell membrane, into which it
        inserts. Thus, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the HIV-1</TIMEX> envelope glycoprotein <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp41</ENAMEX> becomes
        an integral component of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> membranes, the viral membrane
        and the cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">membrane</ENAMEX>. The outer surface of the
        coiled-coil contains grooves into which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> heptad repeat
        regions from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal part of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> ectodomain
        pack, resulting in a stable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 45 46 47</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48 49 50 51 52 53 54</NUMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> can
        be detected by specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 20 43 55</NUMEX> ] .
        Results presented here indicate that purified HIV-1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">particles</ENAMEX> do not contain detectable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle
        structures. Their expression is induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CAP</ENAMEX> treatment of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Prior</TIMEX> engagement of CD4 binding
        sites is not required for the induction of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix
        bundles by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, but increases their expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>). The apparent cooperativity between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> in
        induction of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> may
        possibly be related to the observed synergism between these
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ligands for inhibition of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> infection (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX> 1and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The hypothesis that engagement of coreceptor
        binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> leads to the expression of
        gp41 <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> is supported by the
        finding that a tyrosine sulfated S-peptide, but not the
        non-sulfated peptide, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 56</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> ] has an effect similar to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). The
        helix-bundles were also induced by heating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1</ENAMEX> virus
        particles at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60°C</TIMEX>, in agreement with the irreversible
        induction of the fusogenic conformation in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">influenza</ENAMEX> virus
        hemagglutinin by heat [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58 59</NUMEX> ]
        In summary, the results presented here suggest that
        treatment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> leads to conformational changes
        in the envelope glycoproteins, ultimately resulting, in the
        absence of target cell membranes, in the formation of gp41
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundles. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> are extremely stable
        and represent a terminal, functionally inactive viral
        constituent [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54 60</NUMEX> ] ; (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>), analogous to that of
        inactivated <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">influenza virus hemagglutinin</ENAMEX> HA2 exposed to
        low pH in the absence of cell membranes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59 61 62 63 64</NUMEX> ]
        .
      
      
        Conclusions
        Earlier studies describing the underlying molecular
        mechanisms involved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the HIV-1</TIMEX> inhibitory effect of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate microbicide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> indicated that this compound
        remains bound to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">impairing</ENAMEX> virus infectivity by
        blockade of binding sites for cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coreceptors</ENAMEX> CXCR4
        and CCR5 [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . Results reported here further extend these
        findings and show that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) there is synergism between sCD4
        and CAP for inhibition of virus infectivity; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) CAP binding
        to HIV-1 leads to conformational changes in viral envelope
        glycoproteins resulting in the expression of functionally
        inert <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-helix bundle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>.
        To the best of our knowledge, results reported here and
        earlier [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] represent the most detailed study on the
        mechanism of action of a polymeric anti-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> compound and
        offer new opportunities for microbicide research, including
        the design of combined microbicides with distinct target
        sites on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> and acting synergistically.
      
      
        List of abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, cellulose acetate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phthalate</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STD</ENAMEX>, sexually
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">transmitted disease</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX>, enzyme-linked immunosorbent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX>; mAbs, monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>, fetal bovine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum; PEG</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polyethylene</ENAMEX> glycol <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX>, human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immunodeficiency</ENAMEX> virus type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, bovine serum albumin;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, phosphate buffered saline; Ch-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken serum</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>)
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS-BG</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1% BSA/1%</NUMEX> gelatin in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX>, horseradish
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peroxidase</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sCD4</TIMEX>, soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD4</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
        Tris, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX>, cellotetraose acetate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phthalate</ENAMEX>; pdb,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protein Data Bank; ED</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> , effective dose for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 %</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibition</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Author 1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ARN</ENAMEX> developed the concepts representing the
        basis of the manuscript and designed most experiments.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author 2 NS</ENAMEX> carried out most experiments and contributed to
        the development of experimental techniques. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author 3 SJ</ENAMEX>
        developed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibody NC-1</ENAMEX> and was involved in
        studies on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> helix bundles and on synergism
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> for inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HIV-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">infectivity</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author 4</ENAMEX> YYL did most tissue culture work and infectivity
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assays</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author 5</ENAMEX> AKD did all the molecular modeling
        studies.
      
    
  
