
  
    
      
        Background
        With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one million</NUMEX> new cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> is
        the most common <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and is the leading cause
        of death in women <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 to 70 years of age</TIMEX> in the world.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Breast cancer</ENAMEX> results from genetic and environmental
        factors including diet, radiation and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5</NUMEX>
        ] . The molecular events involved in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carcinogenesis</ENAMEX>,
        however, remain to be elucidated.
        Numerous studies have shown that polypeptide growth
        factors such as insulin-like growth factors (IGFs) are
        mitogens for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7 8 9</NUMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-I</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> signal through a common tyrosine kinase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, the insulin-like growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor 1</ENAMEX> receptor
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IGF1R</NUMEX>), and have mitogenic and cell survival actions that
        may promote tumor development. Modulation of this mitogenic
        pathway occurs in part via the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX>, which functions
        in the internalization and degradation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> is also important in activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-Î², a
        potent growth inhibitor for most cell types, and in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX>, transport and activation of lysosomal enzymes,
        such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cathepsins</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . It has been shown that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> expression is significantly reduced in both rat
        and human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hepatocellular carcinomas</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . Loss of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hetorozygosity</ENAMEX> (LOH) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF2 receptor gene</ENAMEX> locus on
        6q26-27 coupled with somatic point mutations in the
        remaining allele has recently been demonstrated in liver
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancers</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23</NUMEX> ] . In
        addition, somatic mutations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2R gene were also
        found in prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carcinoma</ENAMEX>, and genetically
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">unstable cancers</ENAMEX> of the endometrium, brain, stomach and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">colorectum</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25 26 27 28 29</NUMEX> ] . The findings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOH</ENAMEX> and
        mutations of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> in a wide variety of tumor types
        have led to the proposition that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> is a tumor
        suppressor gene. In addition to genetic data, a tumor
        suppressor gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> has to meet functional criteria.
        The functional characteristics of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor gene
        have not been well established for <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R.</ENAMEX> Thus, further
        studies that address the relationship between the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">functional M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> level and cell growth activity are
        needed.
        To verify whether decreased levels of functional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> can provide a growth advantage for cancer cells,
        we used viral and ribozyme strategies to reduce the
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> in human breast cancer cells and
        then examined the effect on growth and apoptosis of these
        cells.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Construction of a recombinant adenoviral vector
          containing the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R-ribozyme</ENAMEX>
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">49 bp M6P/IGF2R ribozyme oligonucleotide,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAATTCTCCACACTGATGAGCCGCTTCGGCGGCGAAACATTCAACGCGT-3</ENAMEX>'
          and the corresponding reverse complementary strand were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synthesized</ENAMEX>. The fragments were subcloned into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pRz951</TIMEX> to
          produce a plasmid (designated as pRz-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IGF2R</NUMEX>) containing a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribozyme</ENAMEX> targeted against the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R.</ENAMEX> For construction
          of the recombinant adenovirus containing the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R-ribozyme</ENAMEX> (pAd-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX>), the segments
          containing the ribozymes were amplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> and cloned
          into a pAdTrack-CMV vector and then recombined
          homologously with an adenoviral backbone pAdEasy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> vector
          to generate pAd-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX>, following the protocol
          described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">He et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . The pAd-GFP/Rz-IGF2R
          carries both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>) genes,
          each under the control of separate cytomegalovirus (CMV)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX>. Another viral vector, pAd-GFP, which carries
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> gene only under the control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>,
          was generated and used as a control vector. The
          adenoviral vector <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> were linerized with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Pac I and</ENAMEX>
          transfected into the replication-permissive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E1A</ENAMEX> transcomplementing cell line) using Lipofectamine
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies</ENAMEX>) to produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">E1</NUMEX>-deleted,
          replication-defective recombinant adenovirus as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . Large-scale amplification of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recombinant</ENAMEX> adenovirus in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells was followed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purification</ENAMEX> using a discontinuous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CsCl</ENAMEX> gradient. The
          constructs were confirmed by enzymatic digestion and DNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequencing</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transcription</ENAMEX> and cleavage reaction of the ribozyme
          in vitro
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Plasmids</ENAMEX> containing the ribozyme or the substrate
          (either <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 bp</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R mRNA</ENAMEX> or an unmatched sequence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATATTGTCCAGTGC-3</ENAMEX>') were linearized with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mlu I. All</ENAMEX>
          transcripts were generated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T7 RNA</ENAMEX> polymerase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>). Substrate transcripts were labeled by
          incorporation of [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32P</TIMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTP</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼Ci/ml; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nen Life Science</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Products, Inc.</ENAMEX>). Specific activity of the [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32P</TIMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTP</ENAMEX> and
          the base composition of each substrate molecule were used
          to calculate substrate concentration. Ribozyme
          transcripts were quantified spectrophotometrically.
          Cleavage reactions contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substrate RNA</ENAMEX>,
          increasing amounts (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60 nM</NUMEX>) of ribozyme, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 20</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼l
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼l <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA inhibitor</ENAMEX> in a final volume of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼l</NUMEX>.
          Cleavage reactions were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> hrs.
          Reactions were stopped by addition of loading buffer: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX>
          formamide, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM Na 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">bromophenol</ENAMEX> blue and xylene cyanol. Cleavage products
          were analyzed on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> polyacrylamide and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8 M</ENAMEX> urea
          denaturing gels. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Imager</ENAMEX> was used to quantitate
          product and substrate fragments.
        
        
          Cell cultures and infection with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF2R</ENAMEX>-Rz
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>-GFP
          MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells were cultured in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> medium containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in a tissue culture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX> relative humidity. Cells
          were used for experiments after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-3 days</TIMEX> in culture.
          Viral infections were carried out by adding viral
          particles at various concentrations (usually, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8virus particles/ml</ENAMEX>) to culture medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>.
          Initially, optimal viral concentration was determined by
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX> to achieve an optimal balance of high gene
          expression and low viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX> to minimize cytotoxicity.
          After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs of incubation, the infection medium was
          replaced with normal (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>) culture medium. For
          treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX>, cells were incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> after infection with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF2R-Rz</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX>.
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventy two hrs</TIMEX> post infection, cells were used for
          analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2R gene expression and its effect on
          cell growth.
        
        
          Analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2R gene expression in MCF-7
          cells
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> transcripts were determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX>-PCR
          using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneAmp EZ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rTt RNA PCR</ENAMEX> kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX>). Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          was extracted from cultured cells using an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> transcripts were amplified using primers
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GACAGGCTTGTCCTGAGTTA-3</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-TTCTGCTCTGGTTCTGCATG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>', specific to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF2R receptor</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> assay
          was performed in triplicate. Primers specific for human
          Î²-actin cDNA were added to a parallel reaction to
          standardize for variations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> between samples. PCR
          products were resolved on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0 %</NUMEX> agarose gel, visualized
          under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">UV</ENAMEX> light and quantitated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Imager</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Measurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">125I -IGF-II</ENAMEX> internalization
          Cells were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> hrs in serum-free
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing 125I-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml) with or
          without excess unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>). Following the
          incubation, the cells were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with
          ice-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>-associated radioactivity was
          determined by a Î³-counter. Specific internalized
          125I-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> was calculated by subtracting the counts of
          samples with excessive unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> from that without
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">unlabeled IGF-II</ENAMEX>, and normalized to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> content.
        
        
          Beta-glucuronidase binding assay
          Binding of Î²-glucuronidase was assayed as described
          previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31 32</NUMEX> ] . Briefly, cells were permeabilized
          with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> saponin in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hepes</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM Î²-glycerophosphate, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> human serum albumin, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mM mannose-6-phosphate</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">M6P</NUMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. The
          cells were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> saponin. They were incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX>
          units/ml Î²-glucuronidase from bovine liver (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mM Hepes</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM
          Î²-glycerophosphate, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> human serum albumin, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          saponin with or without <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 mM M6P overnight</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. Cells
          were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saponin</ENAMEX> and sonicated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM sodium acetate (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.6</NUMEX>).
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> concentration of solubilized <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> extract was
          measured and enzyme activity was assayed as follows: for
          each reaction <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼l cell extract were added to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 Î¼l</NUMEX> of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM sodium acetate (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paranitrophenyl</ENAMEX> (PNP)<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-Î²-glucuronide</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) as substrate.
          After an incubation period of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">500 Î¼l 1 M</ENAMEX>
          Na 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> were added to each reaction and the
          absorbance was measured at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> nm. Experimental values
          were compared to a standard curve that was constructed
          using <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-100 nM</TIMEX> solutions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PNP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">500 Î¼l 100</ENAMEX> mM
          sodium acetate and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">500 Î¼l 1 M Na</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> . Specific activity was calculated
          as nM of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PNP</ENAMEX> produced/hour/mg of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Beta-glucuronidase endocytosis assay
          Beta-glucuronidase endocytosis assay was carried out
          as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, confluent cell
          cultures were washed twice with pre-warmed serum-free
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> followed by incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 mg/ml</ENAMEX>
          human serum albumin and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>.
          Following incubation cells were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with
          pre-warmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>. Cells were then incubated in DMEM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">containing 5 mg/ml</ENAMEX> human serum albumin alone or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4000</TIMEX>
          units Î²-glucuronidase with or without <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. Following the incubation, the cells were
          washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and subjected to enzyme
          activity assay as described above.
        
        
          Cell proliferation assay (MTT assay and cell
          counting)
          MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells were grown in culture plates (tissue
          culture grade, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>, flat bottom) in a final volume
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml serum-containing culture medium per well, in a
          humidified atmosphere at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX>. After infection with
          Ad-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF2R-Rz</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX>, cells were incubated with or
          without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100 Î¼l MTT</ENAMEX> labelling
          reagent were added to each well and incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> hrs,
          followed by addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml solubilization solution into
          each well. The cells were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">37Â°C overnight</TIMEX>.
          Spectrophotometrical absorbency of the samples was
          measured using an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UV-visible Recording</ENAMEX> Spectrophotometer
          with wavelength of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">550-690</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nm</ENAMEX>. In addition, the total
          number of viable cells in each treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was
          counted by a trypan blue exclusion method using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hemocytometer</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> apoptosis
          MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells were infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX> or
          Ad-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventy two hrs</TIMEX> post infection, cells
          were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hrs.</TIMEX> Apoptotic
          cells were identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX> staining using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vybrantâ„¢ Apoptosis Kit</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#5</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>) according to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s protocol. In addition, after infection
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX> and treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>,
          cell viability was assessed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assay Kit
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche Molecular Biochemicals</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell apoptosis</ENAMEX> was
          determined using the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cell Death Detection ELISA Kit</ENAMEX> assay
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche Molecular Biochemicals</ENAMEX>) according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s protocol.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>'s t-test was used to evaluate the difference
          between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> values. Each experiment was repeated at least
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times. Statistical significance was accepted at the
          level of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleavage</ENAMEX> reaction of the ribozyme in vitro
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> ribozyme we constructed has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>-bp
          binding arms complementary to the target site of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> mRNA, and a catalytic core (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). To
          evaluate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bioactivity</ENAMEX>/specificity of the ribozyme and
          the accessibility of the target site, a cleavage reaction
          
          in vitro was performed. The
          substrates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[Î±- 32P</ENAMEX>] labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA transcripts</ENAMEX> containing
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 bp</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R mRNA</ENAMEX> or an unmatched sequence, were
          incubated with the ribozyme as described (see Materials
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methods</ENAMEX>). The ribozyme cleaved only the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2R
          mRNA into the expected products. In this assay, the
          hammerhead ribozyme was able to cleave <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50%</NUMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> target within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 hr</NUMEX> of incubation, and by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
          hrs, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 90%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> target was converted
          to the expected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B). These results
          indicate a high efficiency and specificity of the
          ribozyme 
          in vitro. 
        
        
          Expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R-ribozyme</ENAMEX> in cultured
          MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells
          To test whether infection of cultured cells with the
          Ad-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX> can induce the expression of the ribozyme
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX>), total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted from cells infected
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF2R-Rz</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX>, and subjected to RT-PCR
          using ribozyme-specific primers. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2,</ENAMEX>
          infection of MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX> resulted in
          positive expression of the ribozyme as determined by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>. As expected, the ribozyme sequence-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> produced a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">430-bp</NUMEX> PCR fragment only in cells
          infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX>, but not in cell infected
          with the control viral vector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Ribozyme</ENAMEX> treatment reduces <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> expression in
          MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells
          To examine the ability of the ribozyme to reduce
          levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> mRNA in MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells, total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was
          extracted from cells infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF2R-Rz</ENAMEX> or
          Ad-GFP, and subjected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX>-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX>. A primer specific for human Î²-actin was added to
          a parallel reaction to serve as an internal standard.
          Cells were used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> hrs post infection with average
          infection efficiency of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50-60%</NUMEX> (for which a viral dose
          used had minimal cytotoxicity). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> product of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">730 bp</NUMEX>, and the Î²-actin product was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">285 bp</NUMEX>.
          As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX>-infected cells
          exhibit a significantly lower level of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R mRNA</ENAMEX>
          than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>-GFP-infected cells, with a reduction of about
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> mRNA between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad</ENAMEX>-GFP-infected cells and
          uninfected cells (data not shown); indicating that
          infection with the adenovirus itself did not alter the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">endogenous M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> mRNA level. These results
          demonstrate that the ribozyme was highly effective in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">suppressing M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> expression in cultured MCF-7
          cells.
        
        
          Effect of ribozyme expression on the functional
          activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2R
          To determine the effect of the ribozyme on the
          functional activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX>, the binding and
          internalization of exogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">125I-IGF-II</ENAMEX> was measured in
          cells infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX>. As shown
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A, cells infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX> had a
          corresponding reduction of ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">125I-IGF-II</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internalization</ENAMEX> when compared with control cells
          (infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX>). We also examined the effect of
          the ribozyme on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M6P</NUMEX>-binding activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2R
          using the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M6P</NUMEX>-bearing lysosomal enzyme, Î²-glucuronidase,
          as a probe. The results showed that the maximal
          M6P-binding capacity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCF-7 cells</ENAMEX> treated with the
          ribozyme was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 39%</NUMEX> less than that of controls (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          4B). Furthermore, we assessed the ability of MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells
          to internalize exogenous Î²-glucuronidase after treatment
          with ribozyme. Similarly, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M6P</NUMEX>-inhibitable endocytosis
          of Î²-glucuronidase by ribozyme-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCF-7 cells</ENAMEX> was
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 38%</NUMEX> less than that of control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4C).
          These results confirm that the number of functional
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> in ribozyme-treated cells was reduced.
        
        
          Effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX>-ribozyme expression on
          proliferation of MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells
          We examined the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ribozyme-induced M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2R
          down-regulation on the growth of cultured MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells. We
          did not observe any difference in cell growth between
          GFP-only infected and non-infected cells (data not
          shown). Thus, all subsequent experiments were performed
          using GFP-only infected cells as control. Assessment of
          cell proliferative activity by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assay and counting of
          viable cells (data not shown) indicated that the number
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCF-7 cells</ENAMEX> in ribozyme-expressing cultures was
          significantly higher than that in control cultures (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). These differences in growth pattern and cell number
          were even more significant when the cultures were treated
          with exogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml, supplemented to culture
          medium) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). These results suggest that decreasing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> expression by the ribozyme can enhance
          proliferation of human breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells via an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX>-related mechanism.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX>-ribozyme expression on
          apoptosis of MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells
          We examined the effects of ribozyme expression on
          apoptosis of cultured MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells. After treatment with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>, as shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, a large number of control cells
          underwent apoptosis, as indicated by morphological
          changes (small round shape) and bright blue nuclear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staining</ENAMEX>. There were significantly more apoptotic cells
          in control cultures than in cultures expressing the
          Ad-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF2R-Rz</ENAMEX>. Accordingly, the number of viable cells,
          as measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> analysis, in cultures infected with
          Ad-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF2R-Rz</ENAMEX> was significantly (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40%</NUMEX>) higher than
          in cultures infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7A). The number of
          apoptotic cells, as measured by the cell death ELISA
          assay, in cultures infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/IGF2R-Rz</ENAMEX> was
          significantly (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 36%</NUMEX>) lower than in cultures infected
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7B). These results are consistent with
          the hypothesis that decreasing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> expression by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ribozyme</ENAMEX> treatment can reduce cell apoptosis.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        A growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of genetic evidence suggests that the
        M6P/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF2 receptor</ENAMEX> is involved in carcinogenesis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29</NUMEX> ] . However, direct
        evidence of a growth-regulatory activity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> is
        lacking. In this study, using ribozyme technology, we
        demonstrate an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of decreased expression and
        function of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> with increased cell proliferation
        and decreased susceptibility to TNF-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in
        human breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells. Expression of the ribozyme
        targeted against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF2 receptor</ENAMEX> in MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells
        resulted in down-regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> expression, as
        measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> function, indicated by a
        decrease in internalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">125I-IGF-II</ENAMEX>, and
        Î²-glucuronidase binding and endocytosis. Although we have
        not ruled out a RNAi effect in cells, the observed effects
        are likely the consequence of the specific cleavage of
        IGF2R mRNA by the ribozyme we used.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> analysis and viable cell counts showed that
        ribozyme-mediated down-regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> also
        resulted in increased cell proliferation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noticeably</ENAMEX>, the
        effect of ribozyme expression on cell growth was more
        apparent in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-</ENAMEX>II. This result suggests
        that the proliferative effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> down-regulation
        is likely the result of unchecked <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> stimulation.
        Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> is believed to sequester and degrade
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] , a decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> could result in
        decreased degradation and hence increased bioavailability
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-I</ENAMEX> receptor, which mediates the
        growth-promoting effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-</ENAMEX>II. Supporting evidence for
        the involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> in the proliferative effect
        resulting from loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> function comes from
        studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> knock-out <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R-null mice</ENAMEX>
        display global hyperplasia that coincides with elevated
        levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-</ENAMEX>II. Most importantly, however, the lethal
        nature of an <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX>-null phenotype is reversed in an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX>-null background [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . Although we did not measure
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extracellular</ENAMEX> levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX>, our results show that
        ribozyme-mediated down-regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> leads to a
        decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> internalization, supporting the above
        possibility.
        Our results also showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> down-regulation
        resulted in decreased sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCF-7 cells</ENAMEX> to
        TNF-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apoptosis</ENAMEX>. Although we do not rule out the
        potential contribution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX> pathway to this
        effect, we would like to consider other potential
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX>-dependent mechanisms, such as lysosomal proteases
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-Î² signaling, that may directly affect cell
        sensitivity to apoptosis. Recent evidence suggests that
        lysosomal enzymes, such as cathepsins B and D contribute to
        TNF-induced apoptosis 
        in vitro [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36 37 38</NUMEX> ] and 
        in vivo [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX> has been shown to be involved in binding,
        transport and activation of lysosomal enzymes, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathepsins</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . Therefore, it is possible that
        down-regulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> results in improper
        trafficking and activation of cathepsins. This, in turn
        would eliminate the apoptotic cascades triggered by these
        enzymes under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TNF</ENAMEX> stimulation and result in decreased
        sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCF-7 cells</ENAMEX> to apoptosis.
        It has also been shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> stimulation involves the
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-Î² [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 41 42</NUMEX> ] , a potent growth
        inhibitor for many cell types and a ligand of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R.</ENAMEX> In
        fact, activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TGF-Î²</ENAMEX> requires the binding of latent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-Î² to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IGF2 receptor</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . Therefore,
        down-regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> expression could also lead to
        a decreased bioavailability of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TGF</ENAMEX>-Î², thereby
        decreasing the sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCF-7 cells</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-Î²
        apoptotic pathway. A detailed mechanism of the observed
        effect is currently under investigation.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Our findings that ribozyme-mediated decrease in
        expression and functional activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R result</ENAMEX>
        in a growth advantage for MCF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells indicate that this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">receptor</ENAMEX> acts as a negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> of cell growth. This
        is consistent with previous observations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2R
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knockout mice</ENAMEX> displayed generalized increased growth and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cardiomygaly</ENAMEX> (resulting from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac myocyte hyperplasia</ENAMEX>) [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> ] , and that antisense-mediated reduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/</ENAMEX>IGF2R
        expression enhances tumorigenicity in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">JEG-3 cells</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] .
        Thus, loss or mutation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> may contribute to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> and progression of tumors via different
        pathways: by increasing the mitogenic activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IGF-II</ENAMEX>
        and decreasing the apoptotic signaling of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-Î² and
        lysosomal proteases. Further studies using various cell
        types or using <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are needed to address this issue.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ribozyme</ENAMEX> technology, as we show here, is a useful tool for
        these studies.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        Ad-GFP, adenovirus carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GFP gene</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad-GFP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Rz-IGF2R</ENAMEX>,
        adenovirus carrying both ribozyme against <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX> and GFP
        gene; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX>, green fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IGF-II</ENAMEX>, insulin-like
        growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">M6P/IGF2R</ENAMEX>, mannose
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6-phosphate/</ENAMEX>insulin-like growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor II receptor</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rz</ENAMEX>,
        ribozyme, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-Î² transforming growth factor beta.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ZC</ENAMEX> carried out ribozyme construction and functional
        assays, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YG</ENAMEX> carried out virus construction, infection and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NL</ENAMEX> drafted the manuscript, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JXK</ENAMEX> conceived the study,
        participated in its design and coordination. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        read and approved the manuscript.
      
    
  
