
  
    
      
        Background
        The mitogen-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> (MAPK) family
        consists of three commonly recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX>: the
        c-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">jun</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal kinase (JNK), also known as the stress
        activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> (SAPK) and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p38</NUMEX> kinase. While
        many actions have been associated with activation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> particular functions of interest to our
        laboratory are mitogen-stimulated growth [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] and smooth
        muscle cell contraction [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> pathways,
        activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway and the intracellular
        signaling pathways associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation are the
        best delineated. Known activators include reactive oxygen
        species [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] , growth factors [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] , and agonists of
        G-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein coupled receptors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other MAPK
        pathways, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX>, have been implicated in
        a variety of similar cellular functions. Known activators
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> in vascular smooth muscle cells
        include reactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> species [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] , mechanical strain
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX> ] , hypoxia [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] and a variety of cytokines and
        growth factors. The mechanisms of many cellular functions
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> are not yet clearly defined.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathway is involved in apoptosis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] , arginine
        vasopressin-induced increases in smooth muscle Î±-actin in
        vascular smooth muscle cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] as well as in
        phosphorylation of transcription factors c-jun, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATF-2</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELK-1</ENAMEX> and phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Na-K-2CI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cotransporter</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ]
        . The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p38</NUMEX> pathway has been implicated in apoptosis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] ,
        neointimal hyperplasia after vascular injury [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] as well
        as angiotensin ll-induced contraction in vascular smooth
        muscle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        Recently, it has been noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and p38
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX> can be activated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein coupled</ENAMEX> receptor
        agonists, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">angiotensin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>, in vascular smooth muscle
        cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> ] . In cardiac myocytes, both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p38</TIMEX> and JNK
        pathways have been activated by endothelin-1 (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) and the
        Î± 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adrenergic</ENAMEX> receptor agonist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenylephrine</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . The ability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and p38
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX> to be activated by the same agonists of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-protein
        coupled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> which activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX> led to the
        investigation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT as a possible activator of the JNK
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT, acting 
        via the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2A receptor</ENAMEX>, is a known activator of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway in vascular smooth muscle cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2 22</ENAMEX> ] . In
        these studies we tested the hypothesis that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HT</ENAMEX> would
        activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat aortic</ENAMEX> vascular
        smooth muscle cells.
      
      
        Results
        
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway
          In agreement with previously published studies from
          our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT caused a concentration-dependent activation
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway (figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). This activation occurs
          maximally at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> of stimulation and returns to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">basal</ENAMEX> levels by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . This time course
          of activation is consistent with that of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-protein
          coupled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p38</NUMEX> pathway
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p38</NUMEX> pathway has demonstrated a different time
          course of activation 
          via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein coupled receptors</ENAMEX>
          than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . Using the time point (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX>) at which angiotensin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX> demonstrates maximal
          stimulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathway we performed a
          concentration response curve (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -9-</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 -5M</TIMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT in
          vascular smooth muscle cells. Western analysis using
          phosphospecific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> was used to measure activation
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p38</NUMEX> pathway. A total or non-phosphospecific antibody
          was used to ensure equal loading of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p38 protein</ENAMEX>. After
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">thirty-minutes</TIMEX> of incubation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -9-</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 -5M</TIMEX>),
          there was no enhanced phosphorylation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p38</TIMEX> (figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>,
          bottom). In contrast, incubation with anisomycin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml</ENAMEX>) induced significant phosphorylation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p38</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-fold
          above basal). These data suggest that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT does not
          activate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p38</TIMEX> pathway in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> vascular smooth muscle
          cells despite the ability of other agonists to activate
          the pathway in these cells.
        
        
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathway
          Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3shows</TIMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of incubation with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -9-</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 -5M</TIMEX>) resulted in a trend towards a modest
          increase in phosphorylation of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p46</NUMEX> JNK isoform. This
          trend, however, was not statistically significant. In
          contrast, anisomycin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) induced significant
          phosphorylation of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p46</NUMEX> JNK isoform (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-7</ENAMEX> fold above
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">basal</ENAMEX>). Both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p54 and p46</TIMEX> bands were analyzed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">densitometry</ENAMEX> (data for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p54</TIMEX> not shown). However,
          incubation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT did not produce statistically
          significant activation in either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> when compared to
          vehicle. These data suggest that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT does not
          substantially activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathway in vascular smooth
          muscle cells. However, the data obtained with anisomycin
          provides evidence that this pathway can be activated in
          these cells.
          To confirm that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> was an optimal time
          point for observing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX>,
          we next performed a time course of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> phosphorylation
          after exposure to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> vascular smooth muscle
          cells. At no time point (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 min, 15 min, 30 min</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX>) did <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-HT</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -5M) enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> phosphorylation above
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">basal</ENAMEX> levels (figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). These data fail to support a
          role for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathway in
          vascular smooth muscle cells.
          To demonstrate that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein coupled</ENAMEX> receptor
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agonist</ENAMEX> could activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathway in our vascular
          smooth muscle cells, we incubated the cells with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">angiotensin II</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -9-</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 -5M</TIMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Angiotensin II</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -8-</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 -5M</TIMEX>) produced a significant
          increase in the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> phosphorylation (figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>).
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> speculate that the differences in the level
          of phosphorylation of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p46</NUMEX> JNK isoform in the vehicle
          treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> maybe due to differences in the JNK
          expression over time in cultured cells. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> used in
          these experiments were of a later passage than those used
          for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT incubation studies. These data, in addition
          to that obtained with anisomycin, demonstrate that in
          these vascular smooth muscle cells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathway can be
          activated.
          Due to the trend toward increased phosphorylation of
          both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p46 and p54</TIMEX> JNK isoforms by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT, we next
          performed JNK activity assays to determine whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT
          had any significant effect on kinase activity. This assay
          was chosen to ensure that the western analyses used were
          sufficiently sensitive to detect changes in the
          activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathway. There was no significant
          difference in the levels of activity at any concentration
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -9-</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 -5M</TIMEX>) after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubation</ENAMEX> in vascular smooth muscle cells (figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). In
          contrast, anisomycin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 ng/ml, 30 min</ENAMEX>) produced a
          significant increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> activation (approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-fold above basal). These data, in combination with the
          above findings, do not support a role for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT in the
          activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathway in vascular smooth muscle
          cells.
        
      
      
        Conclusions
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HT</ENAMEX> is an activator of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway in vascular
        smooth muscle cells. In contrast, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HT</ENAMEX> appears to be unable
        to activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> in vascular smooth
        muscle cells. No observable changes in activation, as
        measured by phosphorylation status, were seen at any of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT concentrations (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -9-</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 -5M</TIMEX>) or time points (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 min,</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min, 60 min and 2 hr</TIMEX>) examined. The data from the kinase
        activity assay also demonstrated no activation of the JNK
        pathway by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT.
        The mitogen-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with many cellular functions. The ability of
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-HT</TIMEX> to activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway is consistent with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HT</ENAMEX>'s
        role as a mitogenic stimulus and vasoconstrictor. Several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vasoactive G</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein coupled agonists</ENAMEX>, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angiotensin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and endothelin, have also been shown to
        activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway in vascular smooth muscle cells [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 21</NUMEX> ] . These same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> also activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and p38
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX>. These agonists have different time course and
        concentration profiles for activation of the different MAPK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation by angiotensin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT occurs
        at relatively lower agonist concentrations and within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of stimulation (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19,23</NUMEX>). The activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p38</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathways by angiotensin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and endothelin occurs at
        higher concentrations of agonist and requires a longer
        incubation with the stimulus [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 25</NUMEX> ] . There are data
        which also suggest that different signal transduction
        pathways are utilized for the different pathways [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26 27</NUMEX>
        ] . This differential activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> pathways is most
        likely due to the role that each plays in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. The ERK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> is associated with growth where as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p38</TIMEX> and JNK
        pathways are "stress response" pathways.
        In light of data for the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-protein coupled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor agonists</ENAMEX>, the inability of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT, also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-protein
        coupled receptor, was initially surprising. While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HT</ENAMEX> has
        never been shown to increase activation of either the p38
        or JNK pathways, it has been linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation. The
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2A receptor</ENAMEX> is the primary serotonergic
        receptor which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> to activation the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway in
        vascular smooth muscle cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HT</ENAMEX>'s inability to
        activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> pathways may be due to a lack of
        coupling of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2A receptor signaling pathway</ENAMEX> to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">components</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX>.
        It has recently been suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-protein coupled
        receptors with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDZ</ENAMEX> domains, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SH2-containing</TIMEX> domains and PTB
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">domains</ENAMEX> participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-protein</ENAMEX> interactions with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G-proteins</ENAMEX>, such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Grb2 and JAK2</TIMEX>,
        which may allow these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> to bypass the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-proteins
        and utilize other signaling cascades (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">29</NUMEX>). This ability of
        G-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein coupled receptors</ENAMEX> to modulate the signal cascade
        used, independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-proteins, suggests a broader range
        of interaction with signaling components. This may provide
        one explanation for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> and its
        lack of effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX>.
        Another possible explanation for the differential
        activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> pathways by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT may relate to the
        varied roles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT in different cell types and the multiple
        receptors which mediate these roles. When examining the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physiological</ENAMEX> role of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT in other cell types, in regards
        to apoptosis and cellular responses to stress, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HT</ENAMEX> is
        generally <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-apoptotic</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31 32</NUMEX> ] . In particular, in
        neuronal cells the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">1A receptor</ENAMEX> is upregulated under
        conditions of cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> and is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-apoptotic</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34</NUMEX>
        ] . The anti-apoptotic effects of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT maybe due to
        scavenging of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reactive oxygen</ENAMEX> species [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] as well as
        stimulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway which results in inhibition
        of a caspase-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-like enzyme [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . There are no currently
        published studies examining the role of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT as an
        anti-apoptotic factor in vascular smooth muscle cells. It
        may be that under stressful conditions, such as a disease
        state or a loss of nutrients which occurs in a state of
        ischemia, the smooth muscle cells upregulate a new
        complement of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34 35</NUMEX> ] . These new
        receptors maybe involved in activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK</ENAMEX> pathways, but the studies presented here do not
        directly address this issue. They do, however, support the
        conclusion that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2A receptor</ENAMEX> does not activate the p38
        orJNK pathways in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> vascular smooth muscle cells.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Aortic smooth muscle cell culture
          Vascular smooth muscle cells were derived from the
          aorta of male Sprague-Dawley <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> by an explant method
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . The smooth muscle cells
          were plated on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-100</ENAMEX>'s and grown to confluence. The
          cells were used between passages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 9</NUMEX>. The cells were
          positively stained for smooth muscle <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î±-actin</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oncogene</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Products</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA; Fluorescein</ENAMEX> labeled goat
          anti-mouse secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>,
          OR) with each new isolation.
        
        
          Aortic smooth muscle cells experiments
          Cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-100</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plates</ENAMEX>) were switched to physiological
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt</ENAMEX> solution (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 ml</NUMEX>) [consisting of (in mmol<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/L</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCI</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.7</NUMEX>; KH 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 PO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.18</NUMEX>; MgSO 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 â€¢</ENAMEX> 7H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.17</NUMEX>; CaCl 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 â€¢</ENAMEX> 2H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX>; NaHCO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.9</NUMEX>; dextrose, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX>; and CaNa 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.03</NUMEX>] for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> prior to
          addition of agonist. At this time, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">okadaic acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>),
          sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">orthovanadate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PD098059</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX>) or
          vehicle (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.5 %</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>) was added and allowed to
          equilibrate for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX>. PD098059, an inhibitor of MEK
          activation, was included in all experiments, except the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">activation</ENAMEX> experiments, to increase the specificity
          of the phospho-JNK <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> which recognizes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> and
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">42 kDa ERK</TIMEX> bands as well as bands at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54 and 46</NUMEX> kDa. In
          the presence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PD098059</TIMEX>, the bands at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 and 44</NUMEX> kDa were
          significantly reduced. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> was incubated with one
          agonist concentration [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-HT (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -9-</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 -5M</TIMEX>), angiotensin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -9-</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 -5M</TIMEX>) or anisomycin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 ng/ml</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] )] for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thirty minutes.</ENAMEX> Plates were placed on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and incubation
          buffer aspirated. Plates were washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold
          as a tyrosine phosphatase inhibitor (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM sodium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM Na 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> VO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five hundred</NUMEX> microliters
          of supplemented RIPA lysis buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-HCI</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ug/ml aprotinin, 10 ug/ml leupeptin, 1</ENAMEX> mM sodium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orthovanadate</ENAMEX>) were added to each dish and cells were
          harvested with a rubber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>. Lysates were
          centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Protein</ENAMEX>
          concentrations of the resulting supernatant were measured
          using the BSA method (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA). The gels
          were also stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gel Code Blue Â®</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) to validate equal loading of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Immunoblotting protocol
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supernatant</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4:1</ENAMEX> in denaturing loading buffer, boiled
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX>) was loaded, separated on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> denaturing
          SDS-polyacrylamide gels, and transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immobilon</ENAMEX>-P
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">membranes</ENAMEX>. Membranes were blocked for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3-4 hours</TIMEX> in Tris
          buffer saline + <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tween-20</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS-T</ENAMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>
          chick <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ovalbulmin</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.025%</NUMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">azide</ENAMEX>. Rabbit
          anti-phospho <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erk MAPK</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:5000</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wl</ENAMEX>),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">rabbit anti-phospho</ENAMEX> JNK MAPK (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:5000</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wl</ENAMEX>), rabbit anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">phospho</NUMEX> p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1000</ENAMEX>, Cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Signaling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>), mouse anti-total Erk (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:5000,</ENAMEX>
          Zymed, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, CA) rabbit anti-total JNK MAPK
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:5000</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz BioTechnologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA) or
          rabbit anti-total p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1000</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cell Signaling</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) were incubated with blots <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4Â°C</NUMEX>).
          Following washes, secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> linked to
          horseradish peroxidase [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anti-rabbit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:2000</ENAMEX>, Zymed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S. San Francisco</ENAMEX>, CA) or anti-mouse
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:7500</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amersham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Heights IL</ENAMEX>)] was added for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> and incubated with blots at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. Enhanced
          chemiluminescence was performed using standard reagents
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Kinase activity assay protocol
          Primary vascular smooth muscle cell preparations were
          treated with agonists as described above. They were then
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysed</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase lysis buffer [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MgCI2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM sodium
          vanadate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM
          beta-glycerophosphate, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">vol/vol</ENAMEX>) glycerol, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">vol/vol</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>, and protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 ug/ml pepstatin A1, 1 ug/ml</ENAMEX> leupeptin, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ug/ml aprotinin</ENAMEX>]. Equal protein amounts of each cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysate</ENAMEX> (usually <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">100 ug</TIMEX>) were incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 h at 4Â°C</NUMEX> in
          the presence of purified GST-c-Jun-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-79</ENAMEX>) bound to
          glutathione-agarose beads (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.8</NUMEX> ug GST-c-Jun/ul beads) as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . Beads were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> times
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNTG</ENAMEX> buffer (HEPES <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pH7.5</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">150</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>
          X-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.10%</NUMEX>, glycerol <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>) followed by an additional
          washing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNTG</ENAMEX> buffer + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> bovine serum albumin (BSA).
          Samples were then centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,000</NUMEX> rpm for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 min and</TIMEX>
          the supernatant was discarded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> were washed 2
          times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNTG</ENAMEX> buffer and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JKAW</ENAMEX> buffer
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">HEPES 25 mM</NUMEX>, glycerol <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>, MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 20</NUMEX> mM, Na 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> VO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 0.1</NUMEX> mM, beta-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">glycerophosphate 12.5</NUMEX>
          mM, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">EGTA 0.5 mM</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NaF 0.5 mM</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> were then
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuspended</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50.5</NUMEX> Î¼l <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JKAW</ENAMEX> reaction buffer containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Î¼Ci [- 32P</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼M unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at
          37Â°C, reactions were terminated by the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> ul
          SDS loading buffer, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were boiled and separated by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Proteins</ENAMEX> were transferred to stabilized
          nitrocellulose membranes and the bands corresponding to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">phosporylated c-Jun</ENAMEX> were counted by a phosphorimager
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Storm</ENAMEX> model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">860</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvale CA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> analysis
          Cell experiments were performed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times
          with each repetition of the experiment being performed in
          cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">explants</ENAMEX> derived from different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. Thus,
          experiments are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of responses of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unpaired Student</ENAMEX>'s t tests were used
          where appropriate in comparing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> responses and a
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> way <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ANOVA</ENAMEX> test was used when comparing responses of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> considered
          statistically significant). Phosphorimager data was
          captured using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Image Quant 5.1</ENAMEX> software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SunnyVale</ENAMEX>, CA). Quantitation of all band
          densities was performed using the public domain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Image</ENAMEX>
          (v.<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.62</NUMEX>).
        
      
    
  
