
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hypertension</ENAMEX> is a common medical problem in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, occurring in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 43 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
        ] . While end-stage renal failure represents the second
        most common cause of end-stage <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal disease</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] ,
        perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,500</NUMEX> hypertensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> develops
        clinically important hypertensive nephrosclerosis. This low
        frequency of end-organ renal damage suggests a potential
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">predisposition</ENAMEX> to this complication. The inbred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahl</ENAMEX>/Rapp
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rat</ENAMEX> is a genetic model of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt-sensitive hypertension</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX>
        ] . On a diet containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX>, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahl</ENAMEX>/Rapp
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt-sensitive</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) rats rapidly and uniformly manifest
        low-renin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> and die from hypertensive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nephrosclerosis</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> of the
        high-salt diet [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . The pathology is identical to human
        hypertensive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal disease</ENAMEX> and consists of
        arteriolosclerosis, glomerulosclerosis, and interstitial
        scarring with tubular cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropout</ENAMEX>. While other animal
        models of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> can be employed to study the
        pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>, because of the rapid and
        reproducible development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal failure</ENAMEX>, S rats provide a
        unique means to investigate the pathogenesis of
        hypertensive nephrosclerosis. In this respect, this model
        is very useful in understanding hypertensive
        nephrosclerosis that occurs in human low-renin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hypertension</ENAMEX>, especially in defined, more homogeneous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> such as the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grim</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] .
        Recent studies have shown that apoptosis was accentuated
        in kidneys of S rats during development of nephrosclerosis
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . These studies demonstrated increased numbers of
        TUNEL-positive cells, increased cytoplasmic nucleosome
        content and caspase-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> activation in kidneys of hypertensive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">S rats</ENAMEX>, compared to normotensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sprague-Dawley</ENAMEX> control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on the same high-salt diet. An increase in apoptosis
        rates in glomeruli and tubules was observed, confirming a
        process that involved several different cell types in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney</ENAMEX>. Apoptotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> were noted particularly in areas
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">glomerular sclerosis</ENAMEX> and in dilated tubules. An increase
        in the number of PCNA-stained cells was also demonstrated
        during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21-day</TIMEX> time frame, but because renal function
        deteriorated, renal failure correlated therefore positively
        with apoptosis and inversely with proliferation rates.
        Thus, the apoptotic process appeared to be a strong
        determinant of outcome in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> system transmits apoptotic signals from the
        surrounding environment into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fas</ENAMEX> contains a
        single transmembrane domain and belongs to the tumor
        necrosis <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (TNF)/nerve growth factor family [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FasL</ENAMEX> contains a single transmembrane domain and is also a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the same TNF <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . A soluble form of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> has been described, but appears to be less capable of
        inducing apoptosis, when compared with the bound form [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> ] . The binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FasL with Fas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">initiates</ENAMEX> receptor
        oligomerization, which recruits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX>-associated death domain
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FADD</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FADD</ENAMEX> binds <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">procaspase-8</ENAMEX> and permits
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-8</ENAMEX> through self-cleavage [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] .
        Caspase-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> activates the effector caspases, which commits
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> to the orderly process of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apoptosis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15</NUMEX> ] . In
        addition, caspase-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cleaves</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-2-</ENAMEX>interactive-death-agonist
        (Bid) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . Truncated Bid localizes to the mitochondria
        and promotes cytochrome c release; this process also serves
        as a major apoptotic-signaling pathway for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17 18</NUMEX> ]
        . Depending upon the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-8</ENAMEX> that is activated,
        the predominant pathway can be either Bid cleavage with
        subsequent mitochondrial release of cytochrome c or
        activation of the effector caspase pathway [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        Resident cells of the kidney express both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> signaling is functional in these cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23 24</NUMEX> ] . A recent review by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ]
        noted that the combined literature demonstrating
        participation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> pathway in renal injury
        essentially fulfilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX>'s postulates.
        In kidneys of S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, associated with apoptosis was a
        temporal increase in expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX>, which was
        demonstrated using <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> analysis of lysates of kidney
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cortex</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . The purpose of the present study was to
        demonstrate the site of expression and potential functional
        significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> in the kidneys of S rats
        during development of hypertensive nephrosclerosis.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Animal preparation
          Studies were conducted using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahl</ENAMEX>/Rapp
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt-sensitive</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS/Jr</ENAMEX>, termed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> male
          Sprague-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawley</ENAMEX> (SD) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, initially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28 days of age</TIMEX>,
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlan Sprague Dawley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IN.</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were housed under standard conditions and given
          a formulated diet (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIN-76A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dyets, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethlehem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>)
          that contained either <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3% or 8.0%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX>. These diets were
          prepared specifically to be identical in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and
          electrolyte composition and differed only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NaCl</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sucrose</ENAMEX> content. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groups of S</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SD rats</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3% and 8.0%</NUMEX>
          NaCl were maintained contemporaneously for each of the
          experiments performed. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 7 and 21</TIMEX> of study, rats
          from all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were anesthetized by intraperitoneal
          injection of sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pentobarbital</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbott Laboratories</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kg</NUMEX>. Laparotomy was performed
          and the kidneys were perfused 
          in situ through the aorta with cold
          heparinized <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.9%</NUMEX> NaCl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> until blanching occurred,
          which generally required infusion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 to 60</NUMEX> ml saline
          over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> min. Both kidneys were harvested under sterile
          conditions to obtain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> analysis and for
          light microscopy and histochemistry after fixation in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paraformaldehyde</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          In situdetection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> fragmentation using
          TUNEL
          
          In situ detection of DNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragmentation</ENAMEX> was performed by incorporation of
          fluorescein-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-dUTP at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'-OH ends of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> using
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apoptosis Detection System</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluorescein, Promega</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>), as performed previously by this laboratory
          [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7 26</ENAMEX> ] . Nuclei were counterstained using propidium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iodide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemical Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). For
          fluorescein, the excitation and barrier filters were set
          at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">450-490 and 515-560 nm</TIMEX>, respectively. Red fluorescence
          of propidium iodide was observed using excitation and
          barrier filters of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">515-560</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">580</NUMEX> nm, respectively.
        
        
          Immunohistochemistry
          After embedding in paraffin, sections <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼m</NUMEX> in
          thickness were immersed twice into xylene for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min each</TIMEX>,
          followed by immersion twice for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 min</TIMEX> each in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> and then <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>. Slides were rinsed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sec</ENAMEX> using deionized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and then immersed twice in
          deionized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min. To detect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fas</ENAMEX>, tissue sections
          were initially treated with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM
          Tris-HCl, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">138</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> mM KCl) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at
          room temperature, followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> 5-min <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">washes</ENAMEX> in TBS
          alone. Slides were covered in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0%</NUMEX> H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at room temperature and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in goat serum for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at room
          temperature. Slides were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at room
          temperature in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monoclonal</ENAMEX> mouse anti-human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fas/CD95/APO-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transduction Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> goat serum. Slides were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rinsed</ENAMEX> and covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> rat serum and
          peroxidase-labeled polymer conjugated to goat anti-mouse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAKO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EnVisionâ„¢+ System</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAKO Corporation</ENAMEX>,
          Carpinteria, CA) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at room temperature and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> was developed using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,3</NUMEX>'-diaminobenzidine (DAB)
          Chromogen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> (DAKO). Cells were counterstained
          using hematoxylin and the slides were mounted in standard
          fashion. As a negative control, the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was
          omitted from the reaction. As an additional control, the
          anti-Fas <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was pre-incubated with recombinant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soluble human Fas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PharMingen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml,</ENAMEX>
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at room temperature prior to use as the primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to stain the specimens. To detect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FasL</ENAMEX>,
          paraffin-embedded sections were initially heated twice at
          95Â°C for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 min</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-mM</ENAMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">citrate</ENAMEX> buffer, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staining</ENAMEX> then proceeded in standard fashion using goat
          polyclonal anti-FasL <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (goat polyclonal antibody
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> raised against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FasL</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-20</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-4 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>, followed by
          biotinylated donkey <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-goat</ENAMEX> IgG. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX> was developed
          using the avidin-biotin detection system (ImmunoCruz
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staining Systems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnology, Inc.</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunoenzyme</ENAMEX> double staining of kidney tissue was
          performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAKO EnVision Doublestain System</ENAMEX> (DAKO).
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were initially heated twice at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-mM</ENAMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">citrate</ENAMEX> buffer, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>, and then
          incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> min with the mouse anti-Fas IgG
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transduction Laboratories</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:500</ENAMEX> dilution in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were incubated in
          horseradish peroxidase-conjugated goat anti-rabbit and
          goat anti-mouse immunoglobulins for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> and developed
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,3</NUMEX>'-diaminobenzidine (DAB) Chromogen solution
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAKO</ENAMEX>). After incubation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> in the Doublestain
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX> (DAKO) at room temperature, the specimens were
          incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> min with the goat anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FasL IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruz Biotechnology, Inc.</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:50</TIMEX> dilution in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were then incubated with
          alkaline phosphatase-conjugated goat anti-rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> and
          goat anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgG</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min. The slides were developed
          using alkaline-phosphatase substrate to produce the red
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were then counterstained using
          hematoxylin before study.
          The specimens were examined using a light microscope
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>) equipped with a digital camera (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX>
          C5810, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamamatsu Photonics K.K.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Semi-</ENAMEX>quantification of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stained</ENAMEX> tubular epithelial cells was determined at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ã—20</NUMEX>
          magnification by projecting the image and counting the
          number of positive cells; a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different fields
          were analyzed for each kidney and the results were
          averaged to produce a final count for each kidney.
          Quantification of staining of glomerular compartment was
          determined at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ã—20</NUMEX> magnification by counting the number of
          stained <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-five glomeruli.</TIMEX>
        
        
          Immunoblot analysis
          Samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal cortex</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SD rats</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl diets for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 and 21 days</TIMEX> were diced into
          small pieces and chilled in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RIPA</ENAMEX> buffer
          per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX> of tissue, then homogenized (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omni-Mixer</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17105</NUMEX>;
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omni</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waterbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CT</ENAMEX>) in standard fashion. Reagents were
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemical Co.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> were mixed gently
          and incubated on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, then homogenized by
          passage through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>-gauge needle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirty Î¼l</ENAMEX> of
          phenylmethylsulfonyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX> (PMSF), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml, was added
          per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX> of tissue and incubated on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min.
          Samples were centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> and the
          supernatant was harvested. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of each sample
          was determined using a kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro BCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> assay
          reagent kit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>.). For each experiment
          that examined a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of interest, all samples were
          processed simultaneously. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Samples</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 Î¼g</NUMEX> of
          total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were mixed with an equal volume of 2x
          SDS-Laemmli sample buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.8</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>
          glycerol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> mM dithiothreitol, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">bromphenol</ENAMEX> blue) and boiled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX>, then resolved
          using either <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> SDS-polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Proteins</ENAMEX> were transferred on to nitrocellulose membrane
          using an electroblotting apparatus (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>,
          CA). Following incubation in blocking buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM
          Tris-HCl, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> non-fat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry milk</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM
          NaCl, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> Tween <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>), the membranes were probed with
          an affinity-purified rabbit polyclonal IgG directed
          against caspase-8 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caspase-8 p20</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>
          Biotechnology, Inc., <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:200</ENAMEX> dilution in
          blocking buffer, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. The membranes were
          then washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS-Tween</ENAMEX> and were incubated
          with horseradish peroxidase-conjugated donkey anti-rabbit
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:5,000 dilution. After
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> additional washes using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS-Tween</ENAMEX>, the membrane was
          developed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECL</ENAMEX> Western blotting system and Hyperfilm
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Pharmacia Biotech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>). The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> used in these studies recognized bands of the
          expected size for pro-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">caspase</NUMEX>-8 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 55 kDa</NUMEX>) and active
          caspase-8 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 20 kDa</NUMEX>). In other experiments, samples
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 Î</NUMEX>¼g total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> underwent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE using
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> polyacrylamide gels. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were transferred on
          to nitrocellulose membranes, which were incubated in
          blocking buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> dried milk
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> Tween-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>) and then rabbit anti-Bid antiserum (BD
          PharMingen, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:2000</ENAMEX> dilution in the same
          blocking buffer, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. Following incubation
          with donkey anti-rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> conjugated with horseradish
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peroxidase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnology Inc.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>,
          CA), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:6000</ENAMEX> dilution, for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at room temperature, the
          membrane was developed as described above.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          All data were presented as mean Â± standard error.
          Significant differences were determined using one-way
          analysis of variance with standard post-hoc testing
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statview</ENAMEX>, version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>). A P
          value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX> assigned statistical significance.
        
      
      
        Results
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidneys of S</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SD rats</ENAMEX> on both <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3% and 8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl
        diets were examined on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 7 and 21</TIMEX>. The blood pressure
        responses to dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> intake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dahl/Rapp S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>, an
        experimental model of hypertensive nephrosclerosis, and of
        the SD strain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> have been published. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX>
        on the high salt diet, S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were hypertensive (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">146 Â± 2</ENAMEX> mm
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hg</ENAMEX>) but had preserved <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal morphology</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 21</TIMEX> on
        the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl diet, the mean blood pressure increased to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">169 Â± 7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hg</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7 27 28</ENAMEX> ] . Mean blood pressures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> rats
        were not influenced by intake of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> over this time frame
        of study (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">118 Â± 4 mm</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hg</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl diet, compared to
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">115 Â± 4 mm</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hg</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX> NaCl diet). In addition, SD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> were healthy, the intake of either diet was
        similar, and they demonstrated no <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal abnormalities</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] . In the present study, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 21</TIMEX> the kidneys of S
        rats demonstrated significant vascular, glomerular and
        tubulo-interstitial injury. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> demonstrated apoptosis in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glomerular</ENAMEX> and tubular compartments (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fig 1</ENAMEX>). SD <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on
        both diets and S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX> NaCl diet demonstrated by
        light microscopy no <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal morphological</ENAMEX> alterations over
        the same period of study. These findings were similar to
        previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> from this laboratory [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 7</NUMEX> ] .
        Using immunohistochemistry, expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> was
        increased specifically in kidneys of S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl
        diet by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 7</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Staining was inhibited when the
        anti-Fas <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was pre-incubated with recombinant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soluble Fas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2Eand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">2J</ENAMEX>). Quantification analysis
        comparing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> groups of rats in the study showed that
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> in glomerular and tubular cells was
        greatest (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.05</ENAMEX>) in kidneys of S rats exposed to the
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl diet for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 and 21 days</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Comparing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> diets for the same duration, dietary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt</ENAMEX> did not alter Fas expression in kidneys of SD <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>.
        The increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fas</ENAMEX> expression in kidneys of S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on the
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl diet was observed in cells in the glomeruli,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tubules</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arteries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A,B,C). Cytoplasmic staining
        was particularly apparent in these samples.
        Over the same time period, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> expression was also
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">examined</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A,B,C,D,E,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>,H,I,<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>). The anti-FasL
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody labeled cells</ENAMEX> in both glomerular and tubular
        compartments, but expression was more subtle than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fas</ENAMEX>,
        particularly in the glomeruli. Quantification of these
        observations showed an increase in expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> in
        both glomerular and tubular compartments of kidneys of S
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl diet, compared with the other three
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). Again, dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> did not alter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glomerular</ENAMEX> and tubular expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> in kidneys of SD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. Tubular epithelial cell expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> appeared
        to be predominantly apical (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4Dand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4E</ENAMEX>), although
        cytoplasmic staining was also observed, particularly in
        cells of S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl diet. In addition, some
        tubular epithelial cells of kidneys from S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX>
        NaCl diet for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 days</TIMEX> appeared to express both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and FasL
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4F,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4H</ENAMEX>).
        To determine whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> apoptotic pathway was
        active, Western blotting of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal cortical lysates</ENAMEX> was
        performed using an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> that recognized both
        procaspase-8 and the active form of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-8</ENAMEX>. In these
        experiments, active <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-8</ENAMEX> was demonstrated in lysates
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal cortex</ENAMEX> of S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl diet for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). Active <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-8</ENAMEX> was not demonstrated in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on the diet for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX> (data not shown).
        Tissue was also examined for cleavage of Bid, which was
        identified specifically in lysates from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal</ENAMEX> cortex
        obtained from S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> NaCl diet for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>).
      
      
        Discussion
        Recent evidence suggests that apoptosis is involved in
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pathological</ENAMEX> processes in the lung [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31 32</NUMEX> ] and
        kidney [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34 35 36 37</NUMEX> ] . Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahl</ENAMEX>/Rapp
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt-sensitive</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>, which develops hypertensive
        nephrosclerosis that resembles the human disease process [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ] , this laboratory demonstrated an early and
        inappropriate apoptotic process that occurred in both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glomerular</ENAMEX> and tubular compartments of the kidneys and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apoptosis</ENAMEX> can be significant particularly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> into
        the course of hypertensive nephrosclerosis in this model
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). A previous study used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNase</ENAMEX> protection assay
        and Western blotting to demonstrate an increase in Fas
        expression in kidney cortex of hypertensive S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. These
        findings were observed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> of study [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . The
        present series of experiments demonstrated the diffuse
        sites of expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> in the kidney and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">explored</ENAMEX> further the possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> pathway
        was active during the development of hypertensive renal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> in this rodent model of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>. Expression of
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FasL</ENAMEX> was observed in kidneys of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and S
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, but specifically increased over time in hypertensive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">S rats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated</ENAMEX> with the increased expression was
        cleavage of procaspase-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> to produce the active enzyme and
        cleavage of Bid, indicating activation of the Fas/FasL
        apoptotic pathway in the course of progressive renal
        failure. These data, along with the previous studies that
        confirmed morphological evidence of apoptosis and
        biochemical evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-3</ENAMEX> activation in these
        kidneys [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , showed a role for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> pathway in
        promoting the loss of kidney function that develops in the
        setting of hypertensive nephrosclerosis in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.
        The mechanism of augmented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> expression in
        kidneys of hypertensive S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> is uncertain. In addition to
        apoptotic signaling, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> may also be
        involved in proliferation. Hueber, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, showed that Fas
        might promote <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">T-cell</ENAMEX> proliferation by modulating release of
        calcium from intracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> is
        anti-proliferative by regulating cell-cycle progression [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> ] . Previous studies demonstrated an increase in cell
        proliferation rates in kidneys of S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> on the high-salt
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">diet</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , so it is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> may play a
        role in control of proliferation. Another potential
        explanation is tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hypoxia</ENAMEX>, which has been suggested to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upregulate Fas</ENAMEX> in the kidney [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36 37</NUMEX> ] . MDCK cells in
        culture demonstrated increased expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas, FasL</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FADD</ENAMEX> in response to partial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> depletion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and
        FasL expression in the kidney may serve as indicators of
        cellular stress. Tissue hypoxia therefore remains a
        possible mechanism of increased expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FasL</ENAMEX>,
        although it seems less likely that the arteriolosclerosis
        that developed in S kidneys was severe enough to produce
        hypoxic conditions sufficient to up-regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fas</ENAMEX>, until the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> week of study.
        Increased expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FasL</ENAMEX> appeared to
        increase the propensity to undergo apoptosis, but was not
        the sole determinant of this process. Despite the increase
        in expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> of study, caspase-8
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> and Bid cleavage were not observed.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX>-mediated apoptotic signaling is modulated by other
        intracellular factors. Induction of inhibitor of apoptosis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> (IAP) is one such mechanism [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41 42 43</NUMEX> ] . In
        vascular smooth muscle cells, surface expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> ] and molecules involved in signaling the apoptotic
        process, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-8</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-3</ENAMEX>, appear to be
        regulated and provide another level of cellular control of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . However, the potential anti-apoptotic
        mechanisms present early in the course were ineffective by
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 21</TIMEX>, when caspase-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> activation was evident. A previous
        study suggested that the apoptotic process occurred early
        in the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> in this model [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] ,
        so the data suggested that an apoptotic mechanism in
        addition to activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> pathway is also
        involved in development of hypertensive nephrosclerosis in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">S rats</ENAMEX>.
        In conclusion, kidneys of S <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> have been shown to be
        very sensitive to hypertensive injury, which is mediated at
        least in part by the apoptotic mechanism controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX>.
        Augmented expression of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> by glomerular and
        tubular cells resulted in caspase-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> activation. The
        pronounced increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FasL</ENAMEX> expression and
        activation of this pathway by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third week</TIMEX> of study also
        correlated with previous evidence that documented
        irreversibility of the renal injury if the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> was
        not corrected by this time [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . These data supported the
        view that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> pathway promoted nephrosclerosis in
        this model. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Activation of the Fas</ENAMEX>/FasL pathway may also
        serve as a mechanism of tubular epithelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> loss and
        interstitial fibrosis, which are also prominent renal
        features of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>. The role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/FasL</ENAMEX> pathway
        in human hypertensive nephrosclerosis remains to be
        determined.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sprague</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dawley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahl</ENAMEX>/Rapp <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX>-sensitive rat
        Fas, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD95</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APO-1</ENAMEX>)
        FasL, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen ligand</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD95L</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APO-1L</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, phosphate-buffered saline
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIPA</ENAMEX>, radioimmunoprecipitation assay
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dodecyl</ENAMEX> sulfate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tris</ENAMEX>-buffered saline
        Bid, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bcl</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-interactive-death-agonist.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared
      
    
  
