
  
    
      
        Background
        Microglia are leukocytes derived outside the central
        nervous system in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone marrow</ENAMEX>, from where they enter
        the circulation as monocytes and migrate into the brain
        during late embryonic life establishing permanent residency
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> different phenotypic forms of microglia are
        known: the activated but nonphagocytic microglia, which
        play a role in inflammatory pathologies, and the reactive
        or phagocytic microglia which participate actively in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trauma</ENAMEX>, infection and neuronal degeneration [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] .
        
        In vivo as well as 
        in vitro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of LPS
        rapidly and potently <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">activates rat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> and neonatal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX> (for review see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ref.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] ). Accompanying both
        adult and neonatal microglia activation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] is a
        concomitant release of numerous secretory products (for
        review see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ref.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] ) that include tissue plasminogen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activator</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] , reactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen species</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] , cytokines like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX>
        ] and proteases, in particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-9</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 9</NUMEX> ] , in a time-
        and concentration-dependent manner. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> have
        been implicated in sublethal and lethal neuronal and glial
        injury [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] , neuronal degeneration [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3 11 12</ENAMEX> ] that
        could potentially affect neurodevelopment in the immature
        brain.
        Exposure to the marine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin domoic acid</ENAMEX>, an excitotoxic
        amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> structurally similar to kainic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and to the
        neurotransmitter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glutamic acid</ENAMEX>, has been shown to lead to
        amnesic shellfish poisoning in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, a condition that can
        lead to death in extreme cases [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . Currently, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety and Applied Nutrition</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Administration</ENAMEX> has included amnesic shellfish
        poisoning as one of the " 
        ...<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> recognized fish poisoning
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">syndromes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>... ", together with
        paralytic, neurotoxic, diarrhetic and ciguatera fish
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poisoning</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> website:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://vm.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cfsan</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fda</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/~dms/haccp-2f.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . Recent
        behavioral toxicity studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX>, have confirmed that
        domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> is a very rapid and potent neurotoxin in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">newborn rats</ENAMEX>, at doses far lower than in adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ] . Even though hippocampal pyramidal neurons and
        mossy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX> appear to be selectively targeted 
        in vivo by domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ]
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cynomolgus monkey</ENAMEX> brain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] , recently domoic acid
        was shown to affect glutamate uptake by astrocytes 
        in vitro and " 
        ...thus produced neurotoxicity... " [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ] . Of interest is the fact that no studies to our
        brain microglia to neonatal neurotoxicity after a
        short-term exposure to domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] .
        The possibility that domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> may activate neonatal
        microglia both 
        in vitro and 
        in vivo is suggested by recent
        observations with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kainic acid</ENAMEX>, a domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and glutamate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analog</ENAMEX> that can induce upregulation of neonatal microglia
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">scavenger receptor mRNA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] and tissue plasminogen
        activator release [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . The putative molecular
        explanation for these observations has been that kainic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> activates the ionotropic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AMPA glutamate GluR4</ENAMEX> subunit
        which has recently been shown to be expressed by activated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX> following transient forebrain ischemia 
        in vivo [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . Because this subunit
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glutamate receptor</ENAMEX> has affinity for domoic acid
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26 27</NUMEX> ] , we hypothesized that domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> might
        activate neonatal microglia 
        in vitro and lead to concomitant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> release [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] .
        The purpose of this investigation was to determine if a
        short-term 
        in vitro exposure to domoic acid
        might activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia and cause <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX>
        release. Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, which we have previously shown is a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rapid</ENAMEX> and potent 
        in vitro activator of neonatal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] as our positive control, we focused our
        investigation on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">microglia mediators</ENAMEX> which are
        released upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> activation, namely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Our present study
        demonstrates that in contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, during a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 hour</NUMEX> 
        in vitro exposure to domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">neonatal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> microglia release small, but statistically
        significant amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX>. Furthermore our
        observations suggest that 
        in vivo, brain microglia as well as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> released by this cell type in brain tissue,
        would appear to play a limited role in the rapid and potent
        domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid neurotoxicity</ENAMEX> observed in neonatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> after a
        short-term administration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        
          Determination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> by electrospray mass
          spectrometry
          The presence of undegraded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> in both stock
          solution (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.5 mM</NUMEX>) and dilutions prepared with LPS-free
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was confirmed by electrospray mass spectrometry
          prior to the experiments. As shown for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.5</NUMEX> mM domoic
          acid stock solution in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A, the dominate ion in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectrum</ENAMEX> was 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">m/z 312.2</ENAMEX> which is the
          pseudomolecular ion [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M+H</ENAMEX>] +of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX>. Also present
          in the spectrum were 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">m/z 334.2</ENAMEX>, the sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adduct</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M+Na</ENAMEX>]
          +of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX>, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">m/z 623.3</ENAMEX>, the dimer [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2M</NUMEX>+H] +of
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">m/z 645.4</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2M</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Na</ENAMEX>] +, the sodium
          adduct of the dimer. The dimer was formed in the gas
          phase due to the high concentration of the sample. Mass
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectra</ENAMEX> for dilution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.025</NUMEX> mM also
          showed as the dominate ion 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">m/z 312</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M+H</ENAMEX>] +(data
          not shown). As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B, for the lowest domoic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid concentration</ENAMEX> used in our studies, namely <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0025</NUMEX> mM
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, although background noise dominated the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sample,</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">m/z 312.2</ENAMEX>, the domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M+H</ENAMEX>]
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">+</ENAMEX>was clearly seen in the spectrum.
        
        
          Immunofluorescent visualization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD11b/c</ENAMEX> and
          glutamate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor subunit GluR4</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
          microglia
          It has recently been reported that transient forebrain
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ischemia</ENAMEX> leads to the expression of the inotropic AMPA
          glutamate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor GluR4</ENAMEX> subunit 
          in vivo [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX>. In order to ascertain that under our
          experimental conditions rat neonatal microglia expressed
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GluR4</NUMEX> subunit, we studied the expression of the AMPA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor GluR4</ENAMEX> by immunohistochemistry. The top left
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2shows a bright <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>, phase contrast view
          of microglia that were incubated in the absence of the
          primary antibodies against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GluR4 and CD11b</TIMEX>/c. Note that
          the microglia are irregular in shape and show numerous
          elongated processes extending from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of the
          cells. In addition, numerous vesicular structures are
          present in the cytoplasm of the microglia. The top right
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX> shows the same microglia when viewed using the FITC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">filter</ENAMEX> configuration. Note that the vesicular structures
          exhibit an intense autofluorescence, but that little or
          no fluorescence is evident over most of the microglia
          cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> or in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">elongated</ENAMEX> processes. Interestingly,
          this same pattern of autofluorescence was evident when
          the microglia were viewed with the TRITC filter
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">configuration</ENAMEX> (not shown). The middle left photo shows a
          bright <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>, phase contrast view of microglia that had
          been labeled with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against the glutamate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor GluR4 subunit</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">leukocyte marker CD11b/c.</ENAMEX>
          Again, the microglia are irregular in shape, with
          elongated processes extending from the cell bodies and
          numerous vesicles present in the cytoplasm. The middle
          right photo (green) shows this same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> when viewed
          using the FITC filter configuration. As evident, the
          microglia not only contain fluorescent vesicles, but also
          exhibit a prominent speckled pattern of fluorescence over
          the cell bodies and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">elongated</ENAMEX> processes. The fact
          that this speckled pattern of labeling is not present in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> that were incubated without the primary GluR4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (compare with top right photo) strongly
          indicates that the speckled pattern represents specific
          labeling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GluR4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">subunit</ENAMEX>. The lower left photo shows
          that these same microglia exhibited intense labeling of
          CD11b/c (red), which confirms that the microglia are of
          leukocytic origin. In the bottom right photo the images
          showing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the GluR4 and the CD11b</TIMEX>/c labeling have been
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superimposed</ENAMEX> (yellow). Together, these results indicate
          that GluR4 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glutamate receptor subunits</ENAMEX> are present on the
          cell surface and that these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> are, in fact,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> on cerebellar granule cell
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia viability
          Domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> has been reported to be neurotoxic to
          neuronal tissue 
          in vitro in concentrations ranging
          from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼M to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29 30 31 32 33</NUMEX> ] . In order to
          determine a concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> that was
          neurotoxic 
          in vitro during a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hour</TIMEX> exposure,
          we investigated the concentration-dependent effect of
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> on cerebellar granule neurons using the WST-1
          viability assay. This assay measures cell viability as a
          function of cleavage of the tetrazolium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt WST-1</ENAMEX> by
          mitochondrial dehydrogenases in viable cells to formazan.
          As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3Cand 3Dthe viability of primary
          cerebellar granule cells exposed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 6 hours</TIMEX> to
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">¼M-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX>] was significantly affected (P
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). In contrast to our observations with
          cerebellar granule neurons, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> even at the
          highest neurotoxic concentration tested in our 
          in vitro study, namely [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX>] did
          not affect microglia viability during a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hour</TIMEX> exposure
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 3Aand 3B</ENAMEX>). Because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> was clearly
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurotoxic</ENAMEX> in our studies, this concentration was
          selected for all 
          in vitro experiments with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) did not affect microglia
          viability 
          in vitro during a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hour</TIMEX> exposure
          (data not shown).
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> on TNF-Î± mRNA
          expression from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia
          Activation of microglia has been shown to cause the
          release of cytokines such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] . As shown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A, stimulation of microglia with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ml</ENAMEX>]
          resulted in a time-dependent increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA
          expression relative to controls as determined by
          semi-quantitative RT-PCR at the linear range of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amplification</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX>). Without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> treatment
          (control), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA expression was undetectable. As
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, the relative levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± expression
          increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX> fold by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> and remained elevated
          throughout the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hour</TIMEX> observation period. In contrast to
          the marked increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± expression induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>,
          as shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX>] induced a less
          potent yet time-dependent increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA
          expression as determined by semi-quantitative RT-PCR over
          the linear range of amplification (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX>). As shown
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, although not statistically significant, the
          relative levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± expression increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold by
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> and remained elevated during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next two</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
          microglia release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±
          In order to determine if the increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA
          after a short term stimulation with either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM</ENAMEX>] or LPS [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mL</ENAMEX>] led to a concomitant production of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF-Î± protein</ENAMEX>, the cell-free media corresponding to the
          same microglia used for TNF-Î± mRNA analysis were assayed
          with an ultrasensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELISA</ENAMEX>. As expected
          and shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mL</ENAMEX>] stimulated microglia
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time-dependent TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± release: by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> TNF-Î± levels
          increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2,233 %</NUMEX> and were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">298.7 Â± 3.9</NUMEX> pg/mL
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>-treated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.8 Â± 2.6</NUMEX> pg/mL (untreated
          controls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.01</ENAMEX>. In contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, levels
          of immunoreactive TNF-Î± in the tissue culture media
          increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53.3 %</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 hours</TIMEX> after microglia were treated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX>] and were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">28.2 Â± 3.6</NUMEX> pg/mL (domoic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid-</ENAMEX>treated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18.4 Â± 1.99</NUMEX> pg/mL (untreated
          controls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.01</ENAMEX>. Interestingly, the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hour</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> point corresponded to the highest level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±
          mRNA expression shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
          microglia release of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> and MMP-9
          We have recently shown that a stimulation of microglia
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> will lead to both TNF-Î± <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and MMP-9
          production, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> that has been reported to be toxic
          to neuronal tissue [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, when
          microglia were stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mL</ENAMEX>], an
          increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-2</ENAMEX> release was observed: by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> MMP-9 inverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.D.</ENAMEX> levels increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2,100 %</NUMEX> and
          were respectively <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.198 Â± 0.009</NUMEX> (LPS-treated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) vs.
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.009 Â± 0.001</NUMEX> (untreated controls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>.
          In contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">757 %</NUMEX> increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> levels was
          observed in the tissue culture media <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> after
          microglia were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX>]: inverse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.D.</ENAMEX> levels were respectively <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.06 Â± 0.01</NUMEX> (domoic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid-</ENAMEX>treated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.007 Â± 0.001</NUMEX> (untreated
          controls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.01</ENAMEX>. Domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX>] had no
          effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> release.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
          microglia release of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O 2-</ENAMEX>
          We have shown that while unprimed naive microglia
          release low levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 -</TIMEX>, pretreatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> results in
          an increase of PMA-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . As is depicted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8A,
          when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">microglia</ENAMEX> were pretreated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hours</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/mL</ENAMEX>], there was, as expected, an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼M</ENAMEX>]-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - production: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.9 nmoles/2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> (LPS-pretreated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.07 nmoles/2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> (untreated controls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.01</ENAMEX>. In
          contrast, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 hour</NUMEX> pretreatment of microglia with domoic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX>], yielded no statistically significant
          increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>]-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.97</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.44 nmoles/2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid pretreated</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.07</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nmoles/2 hours</TIMEX> (untreated controls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Furthermore,
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> did not affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>]-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - generation from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 hour</NUMEX>
          LPS-pretreated microglia: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.9</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nmoles/2 hours</TIMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>-pretreated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.26</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nmoles/2 hours</TIMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid pretreated</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Finally, as shown
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8B, though not statistically significant, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          hour stimulation with increasing concentrations of domoic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>], reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - generation from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hours</TIMEX>
          LPS-pretreated microglia: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.16</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.58</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nmoles/2 hours</TIMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX>] + <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) vs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nmoles/2 hours</TIMEX> (untreated controls, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Although domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>'s excitotoxicity to 
        adult neuronal tissue in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and monkeys is well documented (for review see
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ref.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] ), a growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of research also suggests
        that there might be increased vulnerability during the 
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">neonatal</TIMEX> period [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17</NUMEX> ] . The
        fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>-brain barrier is incomplete [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] ,
        provides a putative explanation as to why neonates and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fetal mice</ENAMEX> 
        in utero appear to be more sensitive
        to neurotoxins like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> than adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> ] . Although <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">microglia</ENAMEX> contribute to circa <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of the
        total glial cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in the central nervous system
        (For review see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ref.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] ), to our knowledge, no
        previous studies have investigated the potential role of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX> in mediating the neurotoxic effects of domoic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> in the developing rat brain. We have recently
        hypothesized that the marine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin domoic acid</ENAMEX> might affect
        the developing brain by directly activating neonatal rat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX> and causing a subsequent release of potentially
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">neurotoxic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] .
        Prior to testing our hypothesis experimentally, and
        determining whether <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> had the potential to
        directly activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia 
        in vitro, we thought that it was of
        critical importance to establish that: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the domoic acid
        preparation used in these experiments was stable, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) rat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neonatal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">microglia</ENAMEX> isolated by our methodology expressed
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glutamate receptor GluR4 subunit</ENAMEX> which has been
        observed in activated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> microglia 
        in vivo [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] and, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) to confirm
        that the domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> concentration selected for our 
        in vitro studies with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
        microglia was one that was clearly toxic to neuronal cells 
        in vitro after a short-term
        exposure.
        Although it has been reported that the solubility of
        domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 7.6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g/L</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24.4 mM</NUMEX>) [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> ] , rapid and complete dissolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> was
        only consistently observed in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> when preparing
        a stock domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid solution</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.5</NUMEX> mM in certified
        LPS-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. To rule out the possibility that domoic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> might have degraded as a consequence of either our
        preparative method or the subsequent freezing (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-80Â°C</ENAMEX>) and
        thawing of the domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> stock solution, electrospray
        mass spectrometry was run on both the domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> stock
        solution (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.5 mM</NUMEX>) and the dilutions prepared prior to the
        experiments. Our electrospray mass spectrometry results
        clearly showed that undegraded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> was present,
        demonstrating the stability of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> in the aqueous
        solutions that had been frozen at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-80Â°C</TIMEX> and thawed prior to
        use in the experiments. Interestingly, our observations
        complement those recently reported on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX>'s
        stability in saline <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] .
        The ionotropic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AMPA glutamate receptor GluR4 subunit</ENAMEX> has
        been shown to be expressed by activated rat adult microglia
        
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vivo</TIMEX> following transient forebrain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ischemia</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] and also 
        in vitro by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> ] . Because it is well established that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMPA</ENAMEX> glutamate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors bind domoic acid</ENAMEX> with high affinity in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nanomolar</ENAMEX> range [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] , we investigated the presence of
        GluR4 in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia used in our 
        in vitro experiments by a
        dual-labeling indirect immunofluorescence technique. Our
        results clearly confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GluR4</ENAMEX> was present in the rat
        neonatal microglia used in our 
        in vitro studies with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX>,
        demonstrating that the protocol used in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> to
        isolate microglia did not appear to affect the presence of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glutamate receptor GluR4 subunits</ENAMEX> and their
        colocalization with the CD <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">b/c</ENAMEX> integrin.
        The cytotoxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> to neuronal tissue 
        in vitro has been investigated over a
        wide range of concentrations, namely at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> Î¼M with primary
        cultures of cerebellar neurons [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31</NUMEX> ] as well as
        hippocampal slices [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] , at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î¼M with cultured
        prenatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat hippocampal</ENAMEX> neurons [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] and at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat lumbar spinal interneurons</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . In order to
        determine a concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> for our 
        in vitro studies that was toxic to
        cerebellar granule cells after a short-term exposure in our
        experimental conditions, we completed a viability study
        using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WST-1</ENAMEX> method. The results of this study
        demonstrated that even though the highest concentration of
        domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> tested, namely <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM, did 
        not affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia
        viability 
        in vitro, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> concentrations
        as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">low as 10</NUMEX> Î¼M were clearly cytotoxic to cerebellar
        granule neurons after a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hour</TIMEX> exposure. Because cerebellar
        granule <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> appear to be inherently resistant to the
        cytotoxic effects of excitatory amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurotoxicity</ENAMEX> appears to be " 
        ...facilitated when cellular energy is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX> in cultured cerebellar neurons... " [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] ,
        perhaps manipulating the experimental conditions (e.g.
        lowering the temperature to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">22Â°C</NUMEX>) might have enhanced the
        intensity of the observed cytotoxicity to cerebellar
        neurons even further, as was reported recently when
        cerebellar granule cells were exposed to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> domoic acid
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 24 hours</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] . Future work is necessary to
        determine if similar changes in the experimental conditions
        might also increase the toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> to rat
        neonatal microglia 
        in vitro. It is interesting to note,
        however, that in newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> a brief local application of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> to the exposed cortical surface led to a
        massive degeneration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMPA/KA GluR</ENAMEX> receptor positive
        Cajal-Retzius neurons [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] , severe impairment of
        cortical neuronal migration 
        in vivo and malformation of the
        domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid-</ENAMEX>treated neocortex [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] . Thus, because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM
        domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> was clearly toxic to cerebellar granule neurons
        both 
        in vitro (our current study) and 
        in vivo [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] , we selected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM
        domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> for the experiments with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia
        reported herein.
        Having determined that our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> preparation was
        stable and undegraded, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia
        expressed GluR4 
        in vitro and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM domoic acid
        was toxic to cerebellar granule neurons 
        in vitro but did not affect the
        viability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia, we then investigated
        whether a short term <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-6 hour</TIMEX> exposure to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM domoic acid
        would activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia 
        in vitro. In all our experiments we
        compared domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>'s effect with that of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, a
        potent and rapid microglia activator [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , to clearly
        show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia were able to become
        rapidly activated and release <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX>, i.e. TNF-Î±, MMP-9
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - upon short-term 
        in vitro treatment. We have recently
        reported on the kinetics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX> and the concomitant release of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF-Î± protein</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> microglia
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> are currently thought to participate in neuronal
        and glial injury 
        in vivo [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 45</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± is a cytokine that can mediate myelin and
        oligodendrocyte damage in vitro [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] and thought to play
        a key role in central nervous system pathologies [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . 
        In vitro <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli LPS</ENAMEX> can trigger rat
        neonatal microglia to rapidly activate TNF-Î± gene
        expression and subsequent protein release [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] in a
        concentration- and time-dependent manner. Although 
        in vitro exposure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microglia</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml LPS resulted, as expected, in a rapid
        elevation of both TNF-Î± gene expression and protein
        release, we observed only a small effect of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM domoic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> on TNF-Î± gene expression. Interestingly, the slight
        rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± expression yielded a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 %</NUMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>)
        increase of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF-Î± protein</ENAMEX> release <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> after stimulation
        with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX>. Although we feel it may be premature
        to speculate on the putative pathophysiological
        significance of this increase in immunoreactive TNF-Î±, the
        fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± can induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> expression in macrophages
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX> ] , suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± may play an as yet
        undetermined role in the mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> release
        observed in our studies. Futhermore immuno-PCR techniques,
        which have allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> to study the kinetics of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± release at the femtomolar range [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] , might help
        to study the kinetics of picomolar microglia TNF-Î± release
        triggered by a short-term exposure to domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>. These
        proposed studies might be of considerable significance in
        view of the fact that similar amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± release have
        
        also been observed after a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 hour</NUMEX>
        stimulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kainic acid</ENAMEX>, a
        domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and glutamate analog [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] . Taken together,
        our results with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> as well as those of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noda et</ENAMEX>
        al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kainic acid</ENAMEX> support the recently proposed
        notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX> might not be neurotoxic in some
        situations when the release of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> is low, and
        therefore might not be a necessary requirement for neuronal
        death involving excitatory amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] .
        Proteases such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-9</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] , which have been
        implicated in sublethal and lethal neuronal and glial
        injury 
        in vivo in " 
        ...central nervous system
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>... " [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] are released by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>-activated rat
        neonatal microglia 
        in vitro [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , by a mechanism that
        may involve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47 51</NUMEX> ] . Clearly because in our
        studies <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> stimulated both an increase in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± release, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX>, further investigation of a
        possible relationship between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> events may be
        important. Furthermore, though the magnitude of MMP-9
        secretion stimulated by domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> was lower than the one
        observed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, this is the first observation to our
        knowledge that an excitatory amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> is
        able to trigger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> release 
        in vitro. Although at the present
        time it is difficult to comment on the pathophysiological
        significance of increased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> release, it is perhaps
        noteworthy that increased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> expression has been
        correlated with increased apoptosis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] and increased
        microvascular permeability [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX> ] , events possibly
        involved in the opening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>-brain barrier [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX> ]
        and potential injury to the brain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Microglia</ENAMEX> constitute the main leukocyte-dependent source
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX> in the central nervous system [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> ] . Since microglia were first shown to release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] numerous investigations have
        been undertaken over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 14 years</TIMEX> to characterize
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> than can either prime and/or trigger the microglia <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
        
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - generating system (for review see
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ref.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] ). In our current experiments, we observed that
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> did not prime <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia for
        PMA-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - release, again in marked contrast
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>. Interestingly though, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> appeared to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modulate LPS</ENAMEX>-primed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - release, suggesting that domoic acid
        might potentially play a role in the 
        in vivo modulation of activated rat
        neonatal microglia, and perhaps other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leukocytes</ENAMEX> capable of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">releasing O</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 -</TIMEX>.
        In summary, in our experiments the 
        in vitro effect of a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-6 hour</TIMEX>
        exposure to domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> and concomitant TNF-Î±, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - release was clearly 
        distinct in its magnitude from that
        observed after exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> involved in
        endotoxic shock and other central nervous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologies</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ]
        . Even though this present study was limited to the study
        of the 
        in vitro effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> on
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">microglia mediators</ENAMEX>, namely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 -</TIMEX>, it provides the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> experimental
        evidence to our knowledge that domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, at 
        in vitro concentrations that are
        toxic to neuronal cells, can trigger a limited activation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia and the concomitant release of
        modest though statistically significant amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±
        and MMP-9.
        Our investigation does not exclude the possibility that 
        in vitro domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> may affect
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> that might support
        survival of neuronal cells. Several lines of evidence
        appear to support this possibility. Thus, in a recent
        report ionotropic AMPA glutamate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> were shown to " 
        ...function not only as ion channels but
        also as cell-surface transducers by means of their
        interaction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Src</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor protein</ENAMEX> kinase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyn</ENAMEX>... ", ultimately leading to " 
        neurotrophic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (BDNF) messenger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> " in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">cerebellar</ENAMEX> primary culture neurons [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX> ] . In another
        study, basic fibroblast growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (bFGF) was shown to
        significantly protect cerebellar granule neurons in culture
        from the neurotoxicity by domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, perhaps " 
        ...through a direct interaction of bFGF
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bFGF receptors</ENAMEX> on the neuronal surface... " [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ]
        . Interestingly, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia have been
        shown to express <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BDNF</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX> ] and bFGF [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX> ] , and in view
        of the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> can affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BDNF</ENAMEX> gene expression in rat
        neonatal microglia cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX> ] , experiments are currently
        underway in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> to determine if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> may
        affect neonatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> microglia expression of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BDNF</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bFGF</ENAMEX>. However, we do not rule out the possibility that
        growth factors other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BDNF</ENAMEX> and bFGF could be released
        by domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-stimulated neonatal microglia cells and play
        a role in neuroprotection from excitotoxic injury.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Our present results provide the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> experimental
        evidence to support the hypothesis that a 
        direct interaction of domoic acid
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia 
        in vitro, leads to the release of
        small but statistically significant amounts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        potentially neurotoxic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX>, namely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± and MMP-9
        after a short-term 
        in vitro exposure. These observations
        are of considerable significance if future research
        demonstrates that higher levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> are
        generated by neonatal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> microglia as a result of either
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a synergistic interaction between domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> " 
        ...when in association with subtoxic
        concentrations of excitatory amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>... " a
        combination that has been shown to increase the
        neurotoxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> to primary cultures of
        cerebellar neurons [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) an increase in the time of
        exposure to domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, as we have reported is the case
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . The fact that domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> has been shown
        to activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> microglia <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> after 
        in vivo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> ] clearly
        raises this latter possibility.
        An understanding of the potential neurotoxic and/or
        neuroprotective effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> in neonatal rats
        will ultimately lead to a better understanding of domoic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acid</ENAMEX>'s effect in neonatal human development. This concept
        is supported by the established fact that glutamate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are highly conserved between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mammals</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] .
        Ultimately studies contributing to the characterization of
        the early biochemical as well as cellular events subsequent
        to an intoxication with the marine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin domoic acid</ENAMEX> will
        yield new insights for the rationale development of novel
        of amnesic shellfish poisoning.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Reagents
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> B (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Escherichia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coli</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">026:B6</TIMEX>) was obtained from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Difco Laboratories</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>); crystalline lyophilized
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostics Chemicals Ltd.</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CT</ENAMEX>) and was dissolved in LPS-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> obtained
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIBCO-BRL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>) to prepare a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.5</NUMEX> mM
          stock [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] and stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-80Â°C</TIMEX>; goat anti-mouse IgG
          conjugated with tetramethylrhodamine isothiocyanate
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRITC</ENAMEX>) and goat anti-rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> conjugated with
          fluorescein isothiocyanate (FITC) were obtained from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemical Co.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> was maintained at
          -80Â°C as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM stock solution in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modified Eagle</ENAMEX> medium (DMEM) with high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,500</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/l</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neurobasal</ENAMEX>-A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-27</ENAMEX> supplement.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX>'s balanced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt solution</ENAMEX> (HBSS), penicillin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">streptomycin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>), trypsin (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX>)-EDTA (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 mM</NUMEX>) and trypan
          blue were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIBCO-BRL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>);
          certified heat-inactivated fetal bovine serum (FBS) was
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyclone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX>); mouse anti-rat <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CD11b/c</ENAMEX>
          monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OX-42</ENAMEX>) and rabbit anti-glutamate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">GluR4</NUMEX>) polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA). A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> stock of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml was
          prepared in a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.9%</NUMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chloride</ENAMEX> nonpyrogenic solution
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baxter Healthcare Corp.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ONT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>) and
          then diluted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> plus P and S to the
          appropriate concentration used in our experiments. Both
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> stock solution [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ml</ENAMEX>] and dilutions were
          stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-80Â°C</TIMEX>, thawed prior to each experiment and
          discarded after use.
        
        
          LPS containment
          To inactivate extraneous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, all glassware and metal
          spatulas were baked for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">180Â°C</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sterile</ENAMEX> and
          LPS-free <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75-and 162-cm</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2vented</ENAMEX> cell culture flasks,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well flat-bottom culture clusters, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well cell
          culture clusters and disposable serological pipettes were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costar Corporation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>), while
          polystyrene cell culture dishes (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60 Ã 15 mm</NUMEX>) were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corning Glass Works</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>). Sterile
          and pyrogen-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eppendorf Biopur</ENAMEX> pipette tips were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brinkmann Instruments, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westbury</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electrospray</ENAMEX> mass spectrometry of domoic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">acid</ENAMEX>
          The presence of undegraded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> in the stock
          solution (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.5 mM</NUMEX>) and dilutions prepared with LPS-free
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was confirmed by electrospray mass spectrometry
          prior to the experiments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electrospray</ENAMEX> mass spectrometry
          was performed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectrometry Laboratory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical Sciences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX>. All
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrospray</ENAMEX> mass spectrometry spectra were acquired on a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micromass Quattro</ENAMEX> triple quadruple mass spectrometer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>) employing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Megaflow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> and ion
          source. The data were acquired in the continuum mode. All
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solvents</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher Optima</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burdick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson</ENAMEX>
          Distilled-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> grade. Deionized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was obtained
          from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barstead NANOpure</ENAMEX> system. Domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid samples</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼l</ENAMEX>) were diluted with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50/50</NUMEX> H 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 O/AcN</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> formic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> as the
          mobile flow phase. An aliquot (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼l</NUMEX>) was injected using
          a model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7125 Rheodyne</ENAMEX> valve with a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼l loop. The sample
          was nebulized with dry nitrogen at a flow of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> l/hr and
          the nitrogen bath gas flow as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">300 l/h. The</ENAMEX> electrospray
          mass spectrometry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> was typically operated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX>
          kV on the electrospray mass spectrometry <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX>
          volts on the counter electrode at a temperature of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65Â°C</TIMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cone voltage</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> volts. Normal electrospray mass
          spectrometry spectra were acquired employing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MS 1</ENAMEX> over
          the desired mass range in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> - 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">s at</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> resolution (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> valley).
          The mass scale of the instrument was calibrated employing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CsI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 mg/ml</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50/50</NUMEX> H 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 O/AcN</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Immunofluorescent labeling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GluR4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD11b/c</ENAMEX> on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (AMPA) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glutamate-4</ENAMEX> receptor subunit (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">GluR4</NUMEX>) and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD11b/c</ENAMEX> were visualized by indirect
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunofluorescence</ENAMEX> using a dual labeling procedure. Rat
          neonatal microglia on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass coverslips</ENAMEX> were fixed and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">permeabilized</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-20Â°C methanol</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>, and then
          blocked with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> goat serum in phosphate buffered saline
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were incubated for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing the primary antibodies,
          a rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> GluR4 at a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:50 dilution</TIMEX>, and a mouse
          anti-rat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD11b/c</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OX-42</ENAMEX>) at a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:100</ENAMEX> dilution. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>
          samples were incubated in the same manner except the
          primary antibodies were omitted from the solution. The
          samples were rinsed quickly in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and then incubated for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing the secondary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX>, a FITC-conjugated goat anti-rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> at a
          dilution of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:50</TIMEX> and a TRITC-conjugated goat anti-mouse
          IgG at a dilution of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:400.</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were rinsed
          successively in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and deionized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and then were
          mounted on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> slides in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aqua Polymount</ENAMEX> from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polysciences, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warrington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were
          allowed to dry in the dark and were viewed using a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Ã
          objective lens on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Eclipse E400</ENAMEX> epifluorescence
          microscope from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Melville, NY</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital</ENAMEX> images
          of the cells were captured with a Spot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> digital camera
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostic Instruments, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sterling Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>)
          and processed by using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Image-Pro Plus</ENAMEX> image analysis
          computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Cybernetics, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Isolation and culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
          microglia
          All experiments were performed with adherence to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> guidelines on the use of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">experimental animals</ENAMEX> and with protocols approved by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwestern University's Research</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Animal Care</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>. To isolate <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia, cerebral
          cortices of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">day-old</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sprague-Dawley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> purchased
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN) were surgically removed
          and placed in cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml P</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼g/ml S</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meninges</ENAMEX> carefully removed, and brain tissue
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">minced</ENAMEX> and dissociated with trypsin-EDTA at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-5
          min. The mixed glial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> suspension was plated in either
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75- or 162-cm</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2vented</ENAMEX> cell culture flasks with DMEM
          medium supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml P</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml S
          and grown in a humidified <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-14 days</TIMEX>. On
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 14 and every 3-4 days</TIMEX> thereafter, microglia were
          detached using an orbital shaker (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> rpm, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">0.5 hours</TIMEX>,
          36Â°C, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ), centrifuged (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">400 Ã g, 25 min,</ENAMEX>
          4Â°C), and microglia number and viability assessed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">trypan</ENAMEX> blue exclusion. Microglia were characterized as
          described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Depending on the particular
          experimental protocol (see below), microglia averaging
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">> than 95%</NUMEX> viability were plated in either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> mm Ã <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mm</ENAMEX> polystyrene cell culture dishes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well cell culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clusters</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well cell culture clusters, with DMEM
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml P</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml S, and
          placed in a humidified <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">36Â°C 18-24 hours</TIMEX> prior
          to the experiments.
        
        
          Primary culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat cerebellar</ENAMEX> granule
          neurons
          Primary cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat cerebellar</ENAMEX> granule neurons
          were prepared from the cerebella of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-day-old</TIMEX>
          Sprague-Dawley <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. Cerebella were dissected and
          processed as described elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX> ] . The dissociated
          cells were grown in a serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Neurobasal</ENAMEX>-A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> with
          B27 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supplement</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 ml/500 ml</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX> ] , and in the
          presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). The cells were maintained
          in poly-L-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">lysine</NUMEX>-treated (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ug</ENAMEX>/ml; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60,000</NUMEX> cells<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">/0.1 ml</NUMEX> Neurobasal A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>/well), at 37Â°C
          in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> air<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">/5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . This method results in a culture
          consisting of neuronal precursors that differentiate into
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurons</ENAMEX>; the differentiated cultures were used for
          experiments after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Experimental protocol to determine the viability of
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid-</ENAMEX>treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia or cerebellar
          granule neurons
          A colorimetric assay for the quantitation of cell
          viability, based on the cleavage of the tetrazolium salt
          WST-1
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-[<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-Iodophenyl</ENAMEX>)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-nitrophenyl</ENAMEX>)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2H</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tetrazolio</ENAMEX>]<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,3</NUMEX>-benzene
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disulfonate</ENAMEX>) (slightly red) to formazan (red) by
          mitochondrial dehydrogenases in viable cells was utilized
          for these studies. Briefly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia or
          cerebellar granule cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60,000</NUMEX> cells / well) were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plated</ENAMEX> in LPS-free <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well cell culture clusters <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>
          prior to the experiments in either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> ml DMEM
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml P</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml S
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">microglia</NUMEX>), or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> ml serum-free Neurobasal A medium
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">B27 supplement</ENAMEX> (cerebellar granule neurons).
          Thereafter each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Î¼l of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Î¼M - 1</ENAMEX> mM final concentration) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> (LPS-free
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">water</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼l</NUMEX> of the tetrazolium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> WST-obtained
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche Diagnostics Gmbh</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannheim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>). Plates
          were incubated in a humidified <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36Â°C</TIMEX> and the reduction
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WST-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">reagent</ENAMEX> to formazan was measured repeatedly
          after the addition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WST-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">reagent</ENAMEX>, at either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">415</NUMEX> nM
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">neurons</NUMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">450 nM</NUMEX> (microglia), with a microtiter plate
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Experimental protocol to determine the effect of
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia release of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-
          To study the time-dependent effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> on the generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX>, rat
          neonatal microglia (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.8</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Ã <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 6cells/60</NUMEX> mm Ã <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> mm
          polystyrene cell culture dish) were treated with (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) LPS-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> used as a vehicle for
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> in a final volume of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ml
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml P</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and incubated in a humidified <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 to 6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h. Upon</ENAMEX>
          termination of the experiments, cell-free supernatants
          from each culture dish were assayed for TNF-Î±, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia were processed for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolation and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 - assay</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> cells/ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well cell culture clusters) were
          treated with (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) LPS-free water
          used as a vehicle for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX> or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> in
          a final volume of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> FBS
          + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml P</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml S and incubated in a humidified
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 to 6 hours</TIMEX>.
          Thereafter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> was removed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ml</ENAMEX> warm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> was
          added, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia were stimulated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>] for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">120 min</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - production was assayed as
          described below.
        
        
          Experimental protocol to determine the effect of
          domoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia TNF-Î±
          expression: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolation and semiquantitative RT-PCR
          analysis
          Total rat neonatal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microglia RNA</ENAMEX> was isolated with TRI
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reagent</ENAMEX> purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Research Center, Inc.</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> were performed in the same
          sample tube using gene-specific primers obtained from IDT
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coralville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IA</ENAMEX>), as described below, and the Superscript
          one-step kit obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco-BRL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>).
          Briefly, first strand cDNA was made using <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.25 Î¼g</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superscript</ENAMEX> II H-reverse transcriptase, antisense
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>-specific primers and conditions of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 min at 50Â°C</NUMEX>.
          Samples were denatured at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 min</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was
          performed for various cycle numbers to ensure linear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amplification</ENAMEX>. The PCR cycling conditions consisted of a
          denaturation step at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> s, an annealing step at
          54Â°C (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S12</NUMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">60Â°C</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX>), an extension step at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>, and a final extension step at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min. The
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼l samples contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> mM of each dNTP, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> mM
          magnesium sulfate. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Platinum Â®taq DNA polymerase</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>
          Î¼M of each gene specific primer. The primers for rat
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, were designed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNASTAR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lasergene</ENAMEX> software
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat TNF-Î± cDNA sequence</ENAMEX> (GenBank
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">accession</ENAMEX> number <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NM 012675</NUMEX>), and are sense (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bp 127 -</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>):<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GCC ACC ACG CTC TTC TGT CTA-3</ENAMEX>' and antisense
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bp 285 - 307</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCG CTT GGT TTG CTA CG-3</ENAMEX>', and
          generate <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a 181 bp</NUMEX> cDNA product. The primers for rat
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constitutively</ENAMEX> expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal S12</ENAMEX>, were sense:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-ACG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ACA CTG CTC TAC A-3</ENAMEX>' and antisense:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TGC CAT</ENAMEX> AGT
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TAA C-3</ENAMEX>' and generate <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a 303 bp</NUMEX> cDNA product as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63</TIMEX> ] . Controls for RT-PCR
          included samples without the enzyme reverse transcriptase
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> without template. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reactions were
          analyzed by electrophoresis using <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5 %</NUMEX> agarose gels,
          visualized with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SYBR</ENAMEX> Â®Gold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleic acid</ENAMEX> staining
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR), photographed, scanned and
          digitized with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN-SCAN-ITâ</ENAMEX>¢ gel automated digitizing
          system from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silk Scientific</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX>). The relative
          amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± expression as determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">normalized</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S12</TIMEX> levels using methods similar to those
          previously described by others [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">64</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TNF-Î± and O 2-</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunoreactive TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± in cell-free media supernates was
          determined using an ultrasensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELISA</ENAMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX> purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosource International</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camarillo</ENAMEX>,
          CA) with a detection limit of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.7</NUMEX> pg/ml. Results are
          expressed as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pg</ENAMEX>/ml. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 - : O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> was determined by the
          SOD-inhibitable reduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Briefly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - release from microglia was
          measured in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼M</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX>, with or
          without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOD</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Units</ENAMEX>). All experimental treatments were
          run in triplicate and in a final volume of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml. Changes
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> absorbance were measured at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX> nm using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckman</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DU-650</ENAMEX> spectrophotometer and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> expressed in nmol by
          employing the molecular extinction coefficient of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21.0</NUMEX> Ã
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 3M -1cm -1</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE gelatinase zymography for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> and MMP-9
          analysis
          Following incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid</ENAMEX>, MMP
          expression was analyzed in the harvested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">cultured</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat neonatal</ENAMEX> microglia. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> neonatal
          microglia cultures were normalized for cell number, equal
          volumes of harvested media obtained from each condition
          were analyzed. Briefly, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼l</NUMEX> of each sample were
          electrophoresed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> and under non-denaturing
          conditions using a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> polyacrylamide gel containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> gelatin. The gels were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> in a
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> solution and then washed twice with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min each</TIMEX>). The gels were then incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> buffer, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">containing 5 mM CaCl</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . A duplicate negative control gel
          was incubated as described above but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX>,
          pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">EDTA</ENAMEX> instead of CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . The gels were fixed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> in
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40% methanol /7%</NUMEX> acetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and then stained in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coomassie Blue Solution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), followed by destaining
          in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> acetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>. MMP activity was
          visualized as clear bands against a blue background.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gelatin-containing</ENAMEX> zymograms are typically used to detect
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">72 kDa</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">92 kDa</NUMEX>) and their
          identification is based on molecular weight. Relative
          clearing of each sample was quantitated by determining
          the inverse optical density <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Image</ENAMEX>
          software package (version <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.60</NUMEX>). Values are represented
          as the mean Â± <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> and are presented as inverse optical
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">density</ENAMEX>. The value corresponding to background, a region
          of equal area as that used to measure the cleared bands
          and of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> in which no sample was loaded, was
          subtracted from each sample value.
        
        
          Statistical analysis of the data
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were analyzed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prism Rsoftware</ENAMEX> package
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GraphPad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CA.</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way
          analysis of variance followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunnett</ENAMEX>'s test was
          performed on all sets of data. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">domoic acid-</ENAMEX>treated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were compared with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
          shown as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> or control in the corresponding figures.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p < 0.05</ENAMEX> and reported in each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> legend.
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î±-amino-3-hydroxy-5-methyl-4-isoxazole propionic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> medium; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>, fetal
        bovine serum certified; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>, ferricytochrome c type III;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX>'s balanced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt solution</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lipopolysaccharide</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-9</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">matrix metalloproteinase-9</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 -</TIMEX>, superoxide; P, penicillin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX> buffered saline; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-myristate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reaction; S</ENAMEX>, streptomycin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOD</ENAMEX>, superoxide dismutase;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, tumor necrosis factor.
      
    
  
