
  
    
      
        Background
        Chemokines are a large superfamily of small,
        structurally-related <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">peptides</ENAMEX> originally discovered as
        neutrophil attractants. Interleukin-8 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>) is a potent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the supergene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokines with ELR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motif</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELR</ENAMEX>+). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELR</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokines are potent angiogenic
        factors, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELR -CXC</ENAMEX> chemokines are potent angiostatic
        factors. Studies have shown that these angiogenesis-related
        activities are correlated with tumorigenesis in many tumor
        types and are distinct from their ability to recruit
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neutrophils</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] .
        Interleukin-8 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>) is inducible in a wide range of
        cells including lymphocytes, monocytes, endothelial cells,
        fibroblasts, hepatocytes, and keratinocytes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> is also found to be constitutively expressed in
        several tumor tissues including bronchogenic carcinoma,
        non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, colorectal carcinoma, breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, melanoma, prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, gastric carcinoma, and
        ovarian <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> has been implicated in
        growth-potentiation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] , angiogenesis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , metastasis
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 8</NUMEX> ] , and tumorigenesis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 6</NUMEX> ] of various tumors, its
        specific role remains unclear. Several observations support
        the assertion that a complex interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> and
        several other growth factors, cytokines, or other proteins
        is responsible for these tumor-related events [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 9 10 11</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . Growth regulated protein alpha (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRO-α</ENAMEX>), beta
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRO-β</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ENA-78</ENAMEX> have been reported to be co-induced
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells stimulated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> proinflammatory
        cytokines, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1β</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNF-α</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . This result is
        consistent with the presence of nuclear factor kappa B
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-κB</ENAMEX>) consensus binding sites in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> regions of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 15</ENAMEX> ] . In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-α</ENAMEX> and -β are
        also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELR</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> cytokine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that are
        reported to be important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> of tumorigenesis through
        their angiogenic properties [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2 16</ENAMEX> ] . They both share one
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8 receptors</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR2</TIMEX>, which has been postulated to
        regulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELR</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokine-mediated angiogenesis and
        resulting-tumorigenesis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . These observations suggest
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-α</ENAMEX> and -β may exhibit expression profiles similar
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>. Coordinated expression of these and other factors
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in certain tumor tissues suggests that they may
        be functionally associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in these tumors. In
        order to fully understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>'s role in these events, it
        is important to investigate these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinately</ENAMEX> expressed
        genes. A systematic, unbiased approach to identification
        and ranking of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>'s expression in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor tissues</ENAMEX>/cells may help to define the scope of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>'s
        role in tumorigenicity and important related interactions
        with other factors.
        There are over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 million</NUMEX> human <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Expressed Sequence Tag</ENAMEX>
        (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>) records in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GenBank</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>), which is still growing
        rapidly. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> sequences in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GenBank</ENAMEX> are derived from cDNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libraries</ENAMEX> generated from a vast array of tissue types
        including normal, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>-state, and variously treated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tissues</ENAMEX>. The number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> clones is reported to be
        proportional to the abundance of cognate transcripts in the
        tissue or cell type used to make the cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and thus
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the EST</TIMEX> distribution can provide a quantitative assessment
        of differential expression of a gene [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . The expanding
        tissue diversity and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> coverage have increased the
        statistical power of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>-distribution based expression
        analysis. An approach using <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> expression data as a binary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variable</ENAMEX> (present or absent in a cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>) has
        previously identified prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>-associated genes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
        ] . We are reporting here a novel 
        in silico approach for identification
        of genes whose mRNA are enriched in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8</ENAMEX> is
        represented. We focused on ESTs from cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> in
        which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> has been sequenced at least once and analyzed
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the EST</TIMEX> frequency of occurrence for all other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8</ENAMEX> related cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>. Those cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>
        were further catalogued into tumor and non-tumor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>,
        which allowed us to identify genes whose expression profile
        is closely related to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8</ENAMEX> in tumor tissues.
        Additional File 1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libraries List</ENAMEX> of all cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> in which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> has been sequenced at least once.
        Click here for file
      
      
        Results
        
          Genes co-expressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>
          We found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> has been sequenced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX> dbEST cDNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">libraries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and Additional file 1</ENAMEX>). Using these
          cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> (referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> tissue), we generated
          a reference database for all the genes and their
          expression profile relationship (measure by Z-score) with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>. The complete list of genes is provided in
          additional file <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, along with a distribution table based
          on contig size and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Z</ENAMEX>-score (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). A gene could be
          represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple contigs</ENAMEX> which represent splice
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">variants</ENAMEX> and sequencing errors. In this database, we
          provide the statistics for each contig, including the
          number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> clones, cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> clones in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>
          tissue, and cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> tissue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First we</ENAMEX>
          evaluated the performance of this search using the
          distribution analysis results for some known genes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The co-expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8 with IL-6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-α</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRO</ENAMEX>-β
          in many tissues has been well documented [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5 14 19</ENAMEX> ] ,
          and those genes are identified here as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> related genes
          with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8 Z-score ></ENAMEX>= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GRO-γ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ENA-78</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ]
          also show a high <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> Z-score, although the available <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">clone</ENAMEX> number for these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> is much smaller.
          Successful identification of these genes demonstrates the
          value of our 
          in silico approach. Besides
          Z-score, this database can be sorted in many different
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. For example, we can adjust the stringency of
          correlation by using the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> as
          a cutoff parameter.
          Additional File 2
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contigs</ENAMEX> identified in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL8</TIMEX> tissue List of contigs that
          have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL8</TIMEX> tissue.
          Click here for file
          Additional File 3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contigs</ENAMEX> identified in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL8</NUMEX>-tumor tissue List of contigs
          that have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL8</NUMEX>-tumor tissue
          Click here for file
          The significance of this study lies in the generation
          of a complete reference database for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> co-expressed
          genes. We present here a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> with high <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>
          clone count (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">>= 100</ENAMEX>) and high Z-score (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">>= 3</ENAMEX>)
          (referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8 genes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-2</ENAMEX>, ..., <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-36</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) to illustrate the usage of this reference database. A
          high <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> clone count is used to ensure the statistic
          significance of the data mining results. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> tissues
          represent both <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor tissues</ENAMEX>/cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-8-tumor</ENAMEX>) and
          non-tumor tissues/cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and Additional file 1</ENAMEX>).
          To generate a tumor expression profile, the percentage of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor clones versus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> clones (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> 
          tumor ) was calculated for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>
          genes. The resulting graph is shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The R 
          tumor profile reveals a bimodal
          distribution. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, tumor clones account
          for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 17%</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> clones (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> 
          tumor = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> genes
          exhibit a R 
          tumor of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">greater than 80%</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of
          these being greater than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> (kruppel-like factor 2
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">KLF2</NUMEX>), presenilin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PS1</NUMEX>), neural proliferation and
          differentiation control protein-1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NPDC1</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GW112</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">claudin-3</ENAMEX>). On the other hand, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> were not found
          in any <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>-tumor related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> 
          tumor = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>).
          For comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-α</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-β</ENAMEX>, the ratios of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> clones, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRO-α</ENAMEX> clones and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRO-β</ENAMEX> clones to total
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clones</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> 
          il8 , R 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-α</ENAMEX> and R 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRO-β</ENAMEX> ) for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> gene were
          analyzed. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> genes show
          similar correlation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> chemokines. As an
          example, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GW112</TIMEX> exhibits high correlation with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">IL-8, GRO</ENAMEX>-α
          and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-β</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> 
          il8 = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69%</NUMEX>, R 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-α</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX>, R 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-β</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68%</NUMEX>). On the other hand, KLF2
          (R 
          il8 = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX>, R 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-α</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16%</NUMEX>, R 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-β</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PS1</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> 
          il8 = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX>, R 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-α</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>, R 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-β</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>) show high correlation with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> and only slight association with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">GRO-α</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">GRO-β</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Genes co-expressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in tumor tissues or
          cell lines
          A set of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> is
          expressed (a subset of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cDNA libraries</ENAMEX>),
          was generated and is referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>-tumor tissue.
          This virtual tissue consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">171,521 cDNA</NUMEX> clones) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and Additional file 1</ENAMEX>). An
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor gene database was established based on these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">libraries</ENAMEX>. The complete list of genes is provided in
          additional file <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, along with a distribution table based
          on contig size and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Z</ENAMEX>-score (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). We present here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>
          candidate genes with relatively high levels of expression
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor tissue (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> clone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">count ></ENAMEX>= <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-8-tumor Z-score >= 3</ENAMEX>) (referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>-tumor
          genes, IT-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, IT-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, ..., IT-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>). To determine
          whether these genes are specifically related to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor tissue or whether they are also commonly found
          in tumors lacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> expression, the ratio between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor clones and general tumor clones (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> 
          il8tumor ) was plotted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor
          genes (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The R 
          il8tumor for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> tumor genes are
          greater than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38%</NUMEX>, which is much higher than the expected
          background ratio between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor clones (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">171521, Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) and general tumor clones (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">864428</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). A few of
          these genes are highly specific to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor tissues.
          Most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GW</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">112</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PS1</TIMEX>, and KLF2 show R 
          il8tumor values of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81% and 76%</NUMEX>
          respectively.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The vast amount of available <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> data allows expression
        analysis based solely on computational methods. It is
        possible to construct a "virtual tissue" based on the
        expression pattern of a particular gene or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of genes
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">e.g. tumor marker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>). It is also possible to group
        genes by tissue type through combining <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> from the same
        source tissue (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">e.g. tumor</ENAMEX>, brain, etc.). In this study we
        have generated "virtual tissues" based on (a) expression of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in all tissues and (b) expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8</ENAMEX> in tumor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tissues</ENAMEX>. Next we generated lists of genes that are most
        highly co-expressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> virtual tissues.
        Since the method is not limited to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> previously
        correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> expression nor to known genes, we have
        the opportunity to identify previously overlooked
        correlations with known or novel genes. In addition, the
        relative strength of the correlations is measured by a
        Z-score based on the number of clones representing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor tissue compared with the total number of clones.
        Assuming that co-expression is related to function, these
        Z-scores provide a basis for ranking genes according to
        potential involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>'s function. This reference
        database for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> co-expressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> can be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-referenced with other large scale expression
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analyses</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microarray</ENAMEX> experiments, to help decipher
        the regulation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and the functions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8 and IL-8</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-expressed genes.
        Among the genes most highly correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in
        tumor tissues are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KLF2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PS1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX>, and tumor necrosis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor receptor-1</ENAMEX> (TNFR-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), lumican (keratin sulfate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteoglycan</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">claudin-3</ENAMEX>, and perlecan. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytokines</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-2</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-7</ENAMEX>) induce the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">KLF2</ENAMEX> in activated T cells
        which correlates with their survival [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . They suggest
        that KLF2 may be involved in avoiding activation-induced
        cell death. It is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> may also mediate
        similar actions. This type of action could increase the
        ability of tumor cells to survive under conditions where
        cells normally apoptose.
        Lumican expression has previously been correlated with
        higher tumor grade, lower estrogen levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> and
        younger age of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in human breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . In
        addition, lumican is structurally related to both biglycan
        which is among the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor related genes and the
        human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">embryonal carcinoma marker antigen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TRA-1-60</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] .
        These relationships support the hypothesis that lumican may
        be a tumor related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>'s tumorigenic
        function.
        PS1 was also found to be highly correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in
        both the entire list of tissues and specifically in tumor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tissues</ENAMEX>. Based on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> distribution, presenilin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PS2</NUMEX>) is
        less related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Z</ENAMEX>-score = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-8-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor clone</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Total Clone</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast tumor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microarray</ENAMEX> experiments, unlike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PS1</TIMEX>, the peak level of
        expression for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PS2</TIMEX> is not in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BT-549</ENAMEX>. PS1 is a gene involved
        in early-onset familial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX>. There is
        accumulating evidence that mutations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PS1</TIMEX> accelerate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurodegeneration</ENAMEX> and facilitate apoptosis, and some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] suggest an association with the p53
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> transduction pathway. It was suggested that
        down-regulation of PS1 by wildtype <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> and also p21
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">WAF-1may</ENAMEX> be independent mechanisms leading to apoptosis and
        tumor suppression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . Our data correlating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PS1</TIMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor related tissue also suggest a potential
        a potent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> of angiogenesis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> has been shown to
        regulate angiogenesis and metastasis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">bladder cancer</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
        ] and several recent studies have reported correlations
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in several cell types including bladder cancer
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCC</ENAMEX>), non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> (NSCLC) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27</NUMEX> ] , human
        brain microvascular endothelial cells (HBMECS) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monocytes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . These data collectively demonstrate the
        correlation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in tumor tissues.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α is a well-characterized, potent inducer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-apoptotic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31 32</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roebuck</ENAMEX> provides a detailed analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> promoter
        structure including a promoter recruitment mechanism which
        involves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and the cooperativity of NF-kB and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-IL-6</ENAMEX>
        binding sites [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 32</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α exerts many of its effects
        through <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFR-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFR-2 receptors</ENAMEX>, thus co-expression of
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> might be anticipated. Our
        analysis does reveal a correlation between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFR-1 and IL-8</ENAMEX>
        expression. Using another bioinformatic approach, Eidelman
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX> report a close relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> secretion
        in cystic fibrosis cells and expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR-1/NFkB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX>. As is the case for several other genes
        found in this study, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR-1/NFkB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX> is associated
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53/p21 WAF-1tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor systems [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34 35 36 37</NUMEX>
        ] .
        Our analysis identified several interesting genes
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-expressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in tumor tissues which have not
        previously been associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>. Along with lumican,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">claudin-3, KLF2</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PS1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR-1</ENAMEX> mentioned above,
        these include several secreted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (secreted apoptosis
        related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein 1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NPDC1</ENAMEX>) which are also likely to
        function in coordination with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>; several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> from the
        well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of complement factors (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">esterase</ENAMEX>, human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">complement C4A</ENAMEX> and complement factor B); and several
        unknown or hypothetical genes. Interestingly, several of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> correlate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53/p21 WAF-1tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor
        network. We expect that some of these genes may present
        important therapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more levels in the
        network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> mediated interactions related to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tumorigenesis</ENAMEX>.
        Like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all EST</TIMEX>-based expression analysis, there are
        limitations for this 
        in silico method. First, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>-based
        expression analysis is not suitable for transcripts with
        low abundance (no or few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> ESTs in the
        database), which precludes statistical analysis. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>-based expression analysis can only indicate the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-expression of genes, but can not accurately measure the
        expression level. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, to generate a comprehensive
        reference database, we decided not to exclude cDNA
        libraries based on the sequence depth or special
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manipulation</ENAMEX> (e.g. subtraction and normalization). The
        depth of sequencing and special manipulation are not
        consistent across cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>, which could also
        influence the sensitivity of the analysis.
        The computational expression analysis methods developed
        here are not limited to the identification of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> related
        genes, but can also be applied to many other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> of
        interest. This method is complementary to other large-scale
        expression analysis methods (e.g. microarray) in that it is
        not limited by the physical presence of a gene on
        microarray, thus it offers an unique approach to
        discovering potential functional links between genes
        through expression profiling.
      
      
        Methods
        
          In silicoexpression analysis
          All non-commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">software</ENAMEX> used in these studies was
          written in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PERL 5.0</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Human EST</TIMEX> sequence and cDNA library
          information were retrieved from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GenBank</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Release 120</ENAMEX>) and
          an in-house relational database model (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sybase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SQL Server</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Release 11.0</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sybase Inc.</ENAMEX>) was created to mirror the
          public human <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> database (dbEST). <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The EST</TIMEX> sequences were
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> binned into clusters if they share <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same 21</TIMEX> mer
          tag beginning with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATG</ENAMEX> or CTG. Next, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESTs</ENAMEX> in each cluster
          were assembled into contigs using the PHRAP sequence
          assembly software (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Green</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Unpublished</ENAMEX>). Based on the
          ESTs corresponding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in its cognate contig, we
          generated a set of cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> is
          represented. This set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> is referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>
          tissue and can be considered as a virtual tissue
          consisting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">306,888 cDNA</NUMEX> clones)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and Additional file 1</ENAMEX>). We chose contigs
          consisting of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least 5 EST</TIMEX> clones and present in at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">least 3 IL-8 libraries.</ENAMEX> The frequency of occurrence ( 
          F ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Z</ENAMEX>-score for all the contigs
          in these cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> were calculated as:
          
          
          where 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> 
          IL8 is the number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> clones in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> tissue for a particular contig, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> 
          total is the total <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> clone count in
          that contig. Contigs were collected into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> based on
          contig size (number of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> clones in a contig), and small
          contig <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">< 1000 contigs</ENAMEX>) were merged together
          with neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (similar in contig size) to make
          sure that there were at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> contigs in each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
          The rational for grouping contigs based on size is that
          the distribution pattern of 
          F (i.e. mean and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Z</ENAMEX>-score) may vary
          for contigs of different size. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> is the total number of contigs in
          a contig <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, Σ 
          F is the sum of 
          F in a contig <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDV</ENAMEX> is the standard deviation of 
          F in a contig <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Assuming a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaussian Distribution</ENAMEX>, the fractions of the population
          that are greater than Z-score 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDV</ENAMEX> and also above the mean are
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15.87%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.28%</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.13%</NUMEX> for Z-scores of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          respectively. Similarly, a set of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor cDNA libraries</ENAMEX>
          (based on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank Annotations</ENAMEX>) in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> is
          represented was generated. This set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> is
          referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>-tumor tissue, consisting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> cDNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">libraries</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">171,521 cDNA</NUMEX> clones) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and Additional</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">file 1</ENAMEX>). Using the method described above, a database for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-tumor tissue) was
          generated and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>-tumor Z-scores were calculated.
          Databases for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GRO-α</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GRO-β related genes</ENAMEX> were
          generated in a similar way using the cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> where
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRO-α</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GRO-β</ENAMEX> were represented respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LUW</ENAMEX> carried out the in silico expression analysis
        and drafted the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SL</ENAMEX> participated in the
        cataloging of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor EST libraries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LYW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JG</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">JH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PQ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EG</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ML</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MK</ENAMEX> participated in design of the study. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
