
  
    
      
        Background
        The human disorder of sitosterolemia, also known as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phytosterolemia</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MIM 210250</NUMEX>), is an autosomal recessive
        disorder characterized by the marked elevation of plasma
        phytosterols e.g. Î²-sitosterol, campesterol and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stigmasterol</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] . Hypercholesterolemia primarily
        during childhood, accelerated atherosclerosis in some adult
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> leading to premature death, as well a hemolytic
        anaemia, arthralgias and tendon and tuberous xanthoma
        formations are other clinical features. Studies have shown
        that the sitosterolemic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> hyperabsorb all sterols
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> and phytosterols) and fail to excrete
        phytosterols into bile [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . Positional mapping
        of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus to human chromosome 2p21
        led to the identification of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> binding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cassette</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-transporters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G5 and G8</TIMEX> that were
        mutated in affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 10 11 12</NUMEX> ] . The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein products</ENAMEX> of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1</ENAMEX> and
        sterolin-2 respectively) are thought to form heterodimers
        to constitute a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">functional</ENAMEX> transporter, based primarily on
        the genetic evidence that affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are either
        completely mutated in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-2</ENAMEX>, but not
        both [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . More recently, evidence from in vitro
        expression of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> has been presented that these
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> co-immunoprecipitate, supporting this
        conclusion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . ABCG5 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ABCG8</ENAMEX> appear to be present in
        all mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">genomes</ENAMEX> examined to date and are highly
        conserved between <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, indicating that these genes may
        have a similar function in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. In order to
        identify naturally occurring animal models of
        sitosterolemia, we previously reported a screen of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
        in-bred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> strains [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . This screen showed
        considerable genetic variation at these loci in the mouse
        strains, but none of these strains exhibited
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sitosterolemia</ENAMEX>. However, a literature search revealed that
        a few strains of rats, studied primarily for investigation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, have been reported to be
        sitosterolemic as well [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] . We hypothesised that
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">rat strains</ENAMEX> may be mutated in either 
        Abcg5 or 
        Abcg8 . Tissue (and plasma) plant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sterol</ENAMEX> levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wistar Kyoto</ENAMEX> (WKY) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spontaneously hypertensive rat</ENAMEX> (SHR) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>-prone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spontaneously hypertensive rat</ENAMEX> (SHRSP) were significantly
        higher than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wistar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKA</ENAMEX> rats fed either a regular
        chow diet or diets that have higher <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> sterols and these
        were correlated with increased death, or red <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> hemolysis
        etc. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22</NUMEX> ] . Dietary sterol
        absorption rates were increased, with a decrease in sterol
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excretion</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , characteristics similar to that observed
        in sitosterolemic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        In this study, we report the gene structure
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organisation</ENAMEX>, cDNA and tissue expression patterns of rat 
        Abcg5 and 
        hybridization, the rat 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus was assigned to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chromosomal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6q12</ENAMEX>. Interestingly, a cluster of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> blood
        pressure (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX>) quantitative trait loci (QTL) in (GH Ã— BN) F2
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOD</ENAMEX> scores <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.63</NUMEX> (tail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.82</NUMEX> (intra-arterial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX>)
        has also been reported to map to rat chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> between 
        D6Mit3 and 
        D6Mit12 , an area containing the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus. We interrogated this
        region for genetic variations and found a correlation
        between sitosterolemic strains and a missense mutation in 
        Abcg5 .
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA Samples</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> strains
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA samples</ENAMEX> from the following rat strains were
          used: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sprague Dawley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles River Laboratories</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wistar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar, Outbred</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPF</ENAMEX>, Seac
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoshitomi</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKA/Sea</ENAMEX>, inbred, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPF</ENAMEX>, Seac
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoshitomi</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY/NCrj</ENAMEX>, inbred, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Charles River</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kanagawa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Charles River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR/Crl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Charles River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>), SHRSP
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP/Sea</ENAMEX>, inbred, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seac Yoshitomi, Fukuoka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BN</ENAMEX>. The genomic DNAs from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">BN rats</ENAMEX> were a
          kind gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. L Harris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>). The liver
          tissue genomic DNAs from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SHR rats</ENAMEX> were
          extracted by digestion <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">55Â°C</NUMEX> in lysis buffer
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pH8.0</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml proteinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>) followed by phenol-chloroform
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extraction</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol precipitation</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Genomic analysis and determination of exon-intron
          boundaries
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rat cDNAs</ENAMEX> for 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 were identified previously by
          amplification of these sequences from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sprague</ENAMEX> Dawley
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat enterocyte</ENAMEX> cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, using primers located in
          areas conserved between <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and human (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Genbank</ENAMEX> AF312714
          and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">AF351785</NUMEX> respectively). For 
          Abcg5 , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> PCR fragment was
          obtained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> using primers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ABCG5 F4</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATCCTCAAAGATGTCTCCTTGTAC-3</ENAMEX>', and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ABCG5 R3</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TCCTGACTCTCCTGGTCGCT-3</ENAMEX>'. For 
          Abcg8 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX> sequences, the primers,
          F11 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AGATGCTGGCCATCATAGGG-3</ENAMEX>' and R13
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GATGGAGAAGGTGAAGTTGCC-3</ENAMEX>', were used to amplify rat 
          Abcg8 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX> fragments. These
          products were sequenced and used to design primers
          specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat cDNA</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat intestinal</ENAMEX> cDNA library
          was screened by anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>.
          Direct sequencing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products led to the
          identification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat cDNA sequence</ENAMEX> and allowed for
          design of rat specific primers (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, see Additional
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">file 1</ENAMEX>). Based upon the structure of mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">putative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>-specific exonic primers were designed and
          used to amplify <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> genomic regions as previously
          described. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were directly sequenced and
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strands</ENAMEX> were sequenced as a routine. The complete
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat genomic</ENAMEX> sequences have been deposited with GenBank
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">AY145899</NUMEX>).
          Additional File 1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> shows the primer sequences used for PCR
          amplification of genomic fragement of the rat 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">STSL</ENAMEX> region.
          Click here for file
        
        
          Chromosomal localisation by fluorescence in situ
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISH</ENAMEX>)
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">FISH</ENAMEX> analysis, metaphase chromosomes were prepared
          from rat embryo fibroblasts. The cells were cultured in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> and treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> colcemid for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> min. The cells were harvested by
          mitotic shake-off and resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.075</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M KCl</ENAMEX> at room
          temperature for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fixation</ENAMEX> was carried out as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluorescence</ENAMEX> in situ hybridization (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISH</ENAMEX>) was
          performed essentially according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinkel et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ]
          with minor modifications [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> sequences used
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">FISH labelling</ENAMEX> were amplified genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> fragments (
          
          Abcg5 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6-10</ENAMEX>, primers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RG5</NUMEX>-F6
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RG5-R10</ENAMEX>, and 
          Abcg8 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4-13</ENAMEX>, primers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RG8</NUMEX>-F4
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RG8-R13</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, see Additional file <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
          gene fragments were labelled separately with
          digoxigenin-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-dUTP (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehringer Mannheim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>) by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nick-</ENAMEX>translation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). Appropriate length (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 to 500 bp</TIMEX>) of the nick
          translated fragments was monitored by checking the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nick-</ENAMEX>translation products on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 %</NUMEX> agarose gel. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
          gene fragments were precipitated separately using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> ng
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">labelled DNA</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">¼g unlabeled rat</ENAMEX> C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o t1 DNA</ENAMEX>, which was included in order
          to suppress probe hybridization to repetitive sequences.
          The probe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> mixtures were ethanol precipitated and
          dissolved in hybridization buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 %</NUMEX> formamide, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã—
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 %</NUMEX> dextran sulphate). After denaturation, the
          highly repetitive sequences in the probe mixture <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> were
          allowed to bind to the C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o t1 DNA (</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37Â°C</NUMEX>). The probe
          mixtures were then applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat fibroblast</ENAMEX> metaphase
          chromosome slides (previously denatured at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 min</TIMEX>
          in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 %</NUMEX> formamide, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Ã—</NUMEX> SSC). Hybridization was allowed to
          proceed in a moist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX> h at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>.
          Subsequently, the slides were washed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX> at 45Â°C
          in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 %</NUMEX> formamide, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã— <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>, and then in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã— SSC (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>)
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> min. The labelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> molecules were
          detected with rhodamine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-digoxigenin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oncor, Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) and the slides were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1 %</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonidet NP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>. Finally, chromosome spreads
          were counterstained with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,6</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">diamino</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-phenylindole
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) in an antifade solution (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vectashield Â®</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vector Laboratories, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burlingame</ENAMEX>, CA). The images
          were captured using the LEICA DM RXA in combination with
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Q-FISH</ENAMEX> software for microphotography.
        
        
          Tissue expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Abcg5and</ENAMEX> Abcg8
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> multiple tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Northern blot</ENAMEX> (Origene
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies, Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">immobilised</ENAMEX> poly
          A +mRNA from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Sprague Dawley rat</ENAMEX> was used. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rat</ENAMEX> sterolin
          cDNA probes were labelled and hybridization and washing
          steps were performed as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] .
          Total tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAs</ENAMEX> were extracted from multiple tissues
          from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Sprague Dawley rat</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trizol</ENAMEX> reagent as
          described previously. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX> hexamers were used as
          primers for reverse transcription of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼g</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rat RNA</ENAMEX> from
          the multiple tissues. The primers were annealed to
          template at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>, and the reaction were
          incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h in the presence of Superscript
          Reverse transcriptase, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM dNTP mix and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RN</ENAMEX>'ase Out
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibitor</ENAMEX>. The rat 
          Abcg5 -specific primers (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RG5c</NUMEX>-F1
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RG5Fc-R1</ENAMEX>), 
          Abcg8 -specific primers (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RG8c</NUMEX>-F1
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RG8c-R1</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î²-actin primers</NUMEX> (sense:
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CTACGTCGCCCTGGACTTCGAGC-3</ENAMEX>', antisense:
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GATGGAGCCGCCGATCCACACGG-3</ENAMEX>') were used for further PCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amplification</ENAMEX> (an initial denaturation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 min</TIMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplification with each cycle consisting
          of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 min at 94Â°C</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> s at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60Â°C</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 min at 72Â°C</NUMEX>,
          followed by an extension step of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">72Â°C</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX>). The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resultant PCR</ENAMEX> products were gel-purified and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequenced</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Real-Time PCR</ENAMEX>
          For quantitation, real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was employed. Primers
          used were based upon previously published mouse primer
          sets [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 28</NUMEX> ] , or designed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacVector</ENAMEX> from cDNA
          sequences between exons, avoiding the amplification of
          potentially contaminating genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> in the total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          sample (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>). Samples of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 Î¼g</ENAMEX>) from rat
          livers were reverse transcribed according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SuperScript' First-Strand Synthesis System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA) using random hexamers with a final volume
          of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼l</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real-time PCR</ENAMEX> was performed on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> Biosystems
          GeneAmp <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5700</TIMEX> sequence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detection System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Forest City</ENAMEX>, CA).
          Standard reaction volume was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼l</NUMEX> and contained 1X
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QuantiTect SYBR Green PCR</ENAMEX> master mix (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valencia</ENAMEX>,
          CA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.002</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U AmpErase UNG</ENAMEX> enzyme (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE Biosystems, Forest</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, CA), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.7 Î¼l</NUMEX> of cDNA template and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100-500</ENAMEX> nM of
          oligonucleotide primers. Initial steps of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50Â°C</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">UNG erase activation</ENAMEX>, followed by a
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minute</TIMEX> hold at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95Â°C</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cycles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>) consisted of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> melt at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95Â°C</TIMEX>, followed by a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 minute</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">annealing/extension</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60Â°C</TIMEX>. The final step was a 60Â°C
          incubation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 minute</TIMEX>. All reactions were performed in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triplicate</ENAMEX>. Threshold cycle (CT) analysis of all samples
          was set at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> relative fluorescence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>.
          The relative amounts of 
          Abcg5 , 
          Abcg8 , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cyp7a1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMG-CoA</ENAMEX> reductase,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Srebp</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> message from rat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver samples</ENAMEX> used in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">real-time RT-PCR</ENAMEX> were normalised to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX> expression
          levels to compensate for variations in input <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> amounts.
          The data were analysed using the comparative threshold
          cycle method (CT) method. Briefly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CT</ENAMEX> values were
          averaged, from triplicate determinations, defining a Î”-CT
          value calculated by taking the average CT of the gene of
          interest and subtracting it from the average CT of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX>.
          The Î”Î”-CT was calculated by subtracting the average
          Î”-CT(calibrator) values from the Î”-CT(sample). The
          relative quantification was then calculated by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">expression 2</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AverageÎ”Î”CT</ENAMEX>). The mRNA quantity for the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">calibrator</ENAMEX> (SD <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>) is expressed as 1X sample and all
          other quantities are expressed as a fold difference
          relative to the calibrator (SD <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Total membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> preparations
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500</TIMEX> mg of liver tissue cut into small
          pieces was homogenised in ice cold lysis buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-pH7.5</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> mM sucrose with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protease inhibitors PMSF</ENAMEX>,
          Leupeptin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aprotinin</ENAMEX>) by a dounce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">homogenizer</ENAMEX> times10
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>. Samples were then subjected to centrifugation
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. The supernatant was saved.
          The pellet was resuspended and subjected to dounce
          homogenisation by10 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>, centrifuged at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> g for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> and this step was repeated once more. The
          supernatants from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> steps were pooled and
          subjected to ultracentrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> g for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, and the pellet was resuspended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-pH7.5</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> TritonX-100 and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>,
          by passaging through a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>-gauge needle. Membrane protein
          concentrations were determined by a colorimetric assay
          according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s protocol (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>,
          CA) and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼g</NUMEX> of total membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> resolved by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> acrylamide gel.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunoblotting</ENAMEX> and Immunolocalization
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proteins</ENAMEX> resolved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE were transferred to
          nitrocellulose membranes and the membranes blocked for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry milk</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS-T</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phosphate Buffered</ENAMEX> saline
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> Tween <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>). Blots were then probed with a primary
          rabbit anti-peptide (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">116-VNGCELRRDQFQDCCVSYLLQS-136</ENAMEX>)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat sterolin</ENAMEX>-1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1000 dilution</ENAMEX>)
          overnight at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. The blot was washed once for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX>
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS-T</ENAMEX>, incubated with goat-anti-rabbit conjugated HRP
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:10000 dilution</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX>, washed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>-T and developed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Lightning</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemiluminescence Reagent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PerkinElmer Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sciences, Inc. Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>).
          Snap-frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rat liver</ENAMEX> and intestine tissues were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sectioned</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 Î¼m</NUMEX> thickness using a cryotome (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright</ENAMEX>),
          air-dried for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> and keep at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-80Â°C until</TIMEX> used. The
          slides were stained with hematoxylin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fixation</ENAMEX> was
          performed by incubating samples for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> min with cooled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-20Â°C</TIMEX> and washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times. The
          slides were treated with blocking solution (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> goat
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> glycine/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min., primary antibody
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> and incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. The slides were
          washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (goat-anti-rabbit
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> conjugated) was applied for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-30 min</TIMEX> at room
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">temperature</ENAMEX>, washed and the signals captured and analyzed
          using an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BX-50 microscope with Fluoview</ENAMEX> software.
          The fluorescent stained images were observed under blue
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filter</ENAMEX> excitation and capture excitation images at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">488</NUMEX> nm
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wavelength</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Nucleotide polymorphisms in Abcg5and
          Abcg8genes
          Direct sequencing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplified genomic fragments
          was performed as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'
          flanking region, all the exons and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>'UTR region, as
          well as the introns of 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 with size <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kb</ENAMEX>,
          were individually amplified using primers, as described
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. The amplified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were sequenced by
          the use of an automated capillary sequencer. The Sprague
          Dawley nucleotide sequence of 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 was regarded as wild-type.
          Comparisons to mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sterolins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> accession
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nos. AF312713, AF312714, AF312715, AF324494 AF324495,</ENAMEX>
          AF351785) as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fugu</ENAMEX> (GenBank No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CAAB01001529</NUMEX>), was
          made using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ClustalW</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genomic organisation</ENAMEX> and chromosome mapping of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rat STSLlocus</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rat cDNA</ENAMEX> sequences for 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 were isolated and
          characterized as indicated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Methods</ENAMEX>. Based upon the
          known conservation between the murine and human 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loci</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] , we designed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligonucleotides</ENAMEX> in putative exonic regions and used PCR
          amplification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> genomic region to characterise the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genome organisation</ENAMEX>. Figure 1shows a summary composite of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">genomic organisation</ENAMEX>. The intron-exon boundary
          sequences are indicated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. In keeping with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX> and mouse 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> loci, the rat 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 genes are arranged in a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">head-to-head</ENAMEX> configuration, with a distance of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">379 bp</ENAMEX>
          separating their respective initiation codons. The exact
          start transcriptional sites for either gene has not been
          definitively established. Comparison of the DNA sequence
          of isolated cDNAs, as well as the polypeptide sequence
          with human and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> sequences revealed a very high
          degree of homology (><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX>). To assign the chromosomal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">location</ENAMEX>, we performed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">FISH analyses</ENAMEX>, and we were able to
          unambiguously map the rat 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus to chromosome 6q12 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). There is specific labelling of both chromatids of
          both homologues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat chromosome</ENAMEX> (RNO) 6 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2Aand
          2B). Based on the DAPI-banding pattern the 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 genes were sub-localized to
          RNO6q12. The 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus was mapped to the same
          position as shown by the diagrammatic representation of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat Chr</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> as shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The human 
          ABCG5 and 
          ABCG8 genes are present in a group
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> 
          ABCG5, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ABCG8</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SLC8A1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRKR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCKR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KHK</ENAMEX>,
          PPP1CB, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APOB</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">POMC1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SDC1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MYCN</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DDX1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">VSNL1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RRM2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ODC1</TIMEX>,
          ID2, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPO</ENAMEX> and 
          ACP1 in the region <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HSA2p21-p25</TIMEX>, and
          this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is also present on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RNO6</TIMEX>. Thus, the 
          ABCG5 and 
          ABCG8 genes fit into a group of
          genes that are syntenic both in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HSA2</TIMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RNO6</TIMEX>. A
          conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HSA2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RNO6</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMU17</ENAMEX> on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RNO6q11-q16</ENAMEX> has been demonstrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Zoo-FISH</ENAMEX> analysis
          and gene mapping data, confirming this synteny [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31 32</NUMEX>
          ] .
        
        
          Expression patterns of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> Abcg5and
          Abcg8mRNAs
          Rat 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 mRNA expression patterns were
          determined, using a commercial multiple tissue poly A
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+Northern</ENAMEX> filter. Expression appeared mainly to be
          confined to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A), with dominant
          transcripts sizes of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~2.5 kb</NUMEX> for 
          Abcg5 and of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~4.5 kb</NUMEX> for 
          Abcg8 . However, the poly A +<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          loaded onto this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Northern blot</ENAMEX> has been adjusted to
          obtain an identical Î²-actin signal, and the intestinal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> loaded may thus have less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">enterocyte RNA</ENAMEX>. Using a
          more sensitive RT-PCR analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> obtained from
          different tissues confirmed that rat 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 genes were expressed in both
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> and small intestine, with a low level of
          expression in the colon (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3B).
          Additionally, while screening an enterocyte cDNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX> for full length cDNAs using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>, we consistently
          amplified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA products</ENAMEX> when using 
          Abcg8 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primers</ENAMEX> flanking exon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>; one
          of the expected size, and another very low copy product
          ~<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> bases larger. Direct sequencing of these products
          confirmed both of these contained 
          Abcg8 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat cDNA</ENAMEX> sequences, but the
          larger product contained a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">66 bp insertion</NUMEX>, resulting in
          a predicted in-frame addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>, between
          exons <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX>. To confirm that this insertion resulted
          from an alternatively spliced mRNA, we amplified and
          sequenced the intragenic region between exons <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX> and
          identified a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">66 bp exon</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">exon 2b</ENAMEX>), flanked by canonical
          splice-sites (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2and Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). We next screened
          total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intestinal RNA</ENAMEX>, using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">WKY rats</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). In all samples a larger DNA
          fragment of low abundance was identified (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) and
          direct sequencing showed that these fragments contained
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2b</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX> (data not shown). It is not established
          whether these transcripts are a result of aberrant
          splicing, or are translated and code for a slightly
          larger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-2</ENAMEX>. Careful interrogation of the mouse and
          human genomic sequences did not identify any homologous
          sequences, suggesting this is unique to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>.
          Additionally, both the mouse and human 
          Abcg8 genes have alternatively
          spliced mRNA, involving a CAG repeat at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">exon 2</ENAMEX> and exon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
          splice acceptor sites respectively [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 14</NUMEX> ] . However,
          despite the presence of such a repeat at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> exon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          splice acceptor site for 
          Abcg8 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>), none of the rat
          mRNAs showed any heterogeneity of splice-site selection
          at this site.
        
        
          Hypertensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> have sitosterolemia and a
          mis-sense change in Abcg5
          A number of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have reported that
          genetically hypertensive strains of rats (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>) have elevated levels of plasma sitosterol [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20 21 22</NUMEX> ] . Although the WKY strain is not
          considered hypertensive, dietary alterations involving
          plant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sterols</ENAMEX> appear to increase blood pressure in this
          strain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . We screened <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> commercially available
          hypertensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, as well as a 'genetically
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypertensive</ENAMEX>' strain, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GH</ENAMEX>, for plasma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> sterol levels
          and compared these to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> control strains, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sprague</ENAMEX>-Dawley
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wistar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>). Our analyses confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> are sitosterolemic on a chow diet, but neither
          the control strains, nor the GH <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> showed any
          significant differences.
          To identify if alterations at the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus could account for these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observations</ENAMEX>, we amplified and directly sequenced 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar, Sprague-Dawley</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SHRSP rats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5shows</ENAMEX> a
          compilation of both coding and non-coding alterations
          detected. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> polymorphic changes detected in 
          Abcg5 and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> polymorphic changes in
          
          Abcg8 . However, only one
          non-synonymous nucleotide change, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1754T</TIMEX>, resulting in a
          conservative cysteine substitution for glycine at amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid 583</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Gly583Cys</NUMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1</ENAMEX> was identified (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          5A). This 'mutation' was only detected in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> and
          WKY rats and was present in all of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> as a
          homozygous change (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>). These hypertensive strains
          also shared uniquely <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> other nucleotide changes not
          present in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>). These latter
          changes were confined to intronic areas and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>'UTR
          region. Although the intronic changes are unlikely to
          alter the biology of these genes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTR</ENAMEX> insertion in
          
          Abcg8 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> could be important, if
          message stability were affected. This possibility was not
          formally investigated.
          The identified G1754T (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Gly583Cys</NUMEX>) missense mutation of
          the 
          Abcg5 generates loss of a
          restriction site for 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hae III</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplification of
          exon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>, and this allowed a PCR-RFLP assay to further
          confirm the detected change (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5B</NUMEX>). Note that the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> chosen from a single <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wistar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> was heterozygous for
          almost all of these changes. The amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid G583</ENAMEX> is
          conserved between all known mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sterolin</ENAMEX>-1 proteins
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5C) and its alteration may have functional
          consequences, as it is also conserved in evolution, being
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conserved</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Fugu fish</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5C). Fugu sterolin-1
          shows a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX> homology to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat sterolin</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> at the amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>
          level, and its gene structure is also organized in a
          similar fashion (data not shown). Currently, a gap in the
          Fugu genomic sequence has not been completed that may
          encode for exon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The complete Fugu 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus is available on-line
          (GenBank No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CAAB01001529</NUMEX>).
          In 
          Abcg8 , a large insertional
          polymorphism was identified in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">exon 13</TIMEX>, that resulted in
          the insertion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">143</NUMEX> nucleotides in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>'UTR
          (*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2099</TIMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2100ins143nt</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">GH rats</ENAMEX> are
          homozygous, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprague Dawley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKA</ENAMEX> strains wild-type and
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar</ENAMEX> sample heterozygous for this polymorphism
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Comparison of expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Abcg5and</ENAMEX> Abcg8in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">hypertensive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> strains
          Expression levels of 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat strains</ENAMEX> were
          examined in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. For mRNA expression, quantitative
          real time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was utilised, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, western
          blotting analyses, as well as immunohistochemistry was
          employed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7shows the results of the real time PCR
          assays of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver RNAs</ENAMEX> from fasted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. Using GAPDH
          mRNA expression as a control, expression of 
          Abcg5 and 
          Abcg8 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNAs</ENAMEX> appeared to be
          increased in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> compared to Sprague Dawley
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>), the message for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cyp7 a1</TIMEX> (except for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMG CoA</ENAMEX> reductase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SR-B1</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SREBP-2</ENAMEX> (except for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>) were relatively unchanged. Interestingly, the
          message for LDL-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> was reduced in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX> and SHR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">livers</ENAMEX>.
          To compare protein expression levels of the sterolins,
          we performed western blotting. A reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to
          sterolin-1 was available only and was used to probe liver
          microsomal lysates from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprague Dawley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and Wistar
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rats</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>). Although equal amounts of microsomal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein lysates</ENAMEX> were loaded from the livers of these
          different strains, we consistently observed that the
          protein expression patterns were always different between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and the control strains (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> C, cf. tracks
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 and 8</NUMEX>). Thus, all of the data were normalised in one
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways, either by using total microsomal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, or
          by using the intensity of transferrin signal, after
          western blotting. Both of these methods gave consistent
          results and indicated that expression of 
          Abcg5 was increased approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-fold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar</ENAMEX> or SD (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>). To
          further assess if the mutant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is mis-targeted, we
          performed immunolocalization, using an anti-peptide
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rabbit antibody</ENAMEX>, on various rat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> and intestinal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sections</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>). We did not observe any differences
          between the staining patterns observed for the control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">rat strains</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar</ENAMEX> or SD) and the mutant hypertensive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strains</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX>). Interestingly, we observed a clear
          apical staining pattern for 
          Abcg5 in the intestine and this was
          not altered in the mutant strains (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> B).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Recent studies on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> transporters have significantly
        advanced our understanding of intestinal sterol absorption
        and biliary excretion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . Sterols are essential
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> of cellular membranes in human, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> is the sterol
        that is synthesised, absorbed and utilised, whereas plants
        do not synthesise <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>, but use molecules that are
        similar, such as sitosterol, campesterol and stigmasterol.
        Although similar amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> and plant sterols
        are present in the typical human diet, the intestine of
        normal subjects provides an efficient barrier against the
        absorption of the majority of plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterols</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . On
        average, < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> of dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> sterols are absorbed
        and retained compared with ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dietary cholesterol</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> ] . Thus, in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, there exists an
        exquisite mechanism that allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to distinguish
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol sterols</ENAMEX>. ABCG5 and
        ABCG8 are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> located adjacently in a head-to-head
        configuration on human chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2p21</NUMEX>, encoding for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-transporters, sterolin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and sterolin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> respectively [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 10 12</NUMEX> ] . Mutations in either of these genes causes
        sitosterolemia, characterized by hyperabsorption of
        phytosterols, reduced excretion of sterols into the bile
        and very elevated levels of plasma <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> sterol levels. In
        sitosterolemic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, the absorption of phytosterols in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intestine</ENAMEX> is dramatically increased, with absorption of
        plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterols</ENAMEX> to about the same extent (~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX>) as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>.
        Interestingly, a similar whole-body accumulation of
        plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterols</ENAMEX>, less severe than in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sitosterolemia</ENAMEX>,
        has been reported recently in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">WKY rats</ENAMEX>, but
        not in the other genetically related rat strains, such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKA</ENAMEX> rats [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . These rats exhibit defects
        at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> levels: increased absorption of sterols (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and
        animal) at the intestinal level and decreased excretion of
        sterols into bile [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . The higher sterol absorption in
        the intestine and the lower biliary excretion of plant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sterols</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat strains</ENAMEX> led us to hypothesise that 
        Abcg5 or 
        Abcg8 gene mutations may be
        responsible for the sitosterolemia observed in these
        hypertensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>.
        Characterization of the rat 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus showed that it is highly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conserved</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, and maps to rat chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6q12</NUMEX>,
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> also syntenic with the mouse and human 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> loci. Rat 
        Abcg5 and 
        Abcg8 are expressed in a
        tissue-specific manner, with expression confined to the
        liver and the intestine. We sequenced the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> loci in sitosterolemic and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> rat strains and identified a number of nucleotide
        changes. Most of these nucleotide changes were in intronic
        regions and, based upon their locations, are likely to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'silent'</ENAMEX>. However, one change, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1754T</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">exon 12</TIMEX> was
        identified that led to a coding change of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gly583Cys</ENAMEX> in
        sterolin-1 ( 
        Abcg5 ). This change was found only
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> strains that were confirmed to be sitosterolemic
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX>), but not in any of the other strains
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screened</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wistar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GH</ENAMEX> or BN).
        The significance of other genetic variances in 
        Abcg5 and 
        Abcg8 in different rat strains
        documented in this study is presently unknown. Plant sterol
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">metabolism</ENAMEX> has been extensively evaluated in different rat
        strains, but the accumulation of plant sterols occurs only
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">WKY rats</ENAMEX>. The predicted <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 trans-</ENAMEX>membrane
        domain model of sterolin-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> indicates that the Gly583Cys
        missense mutation is located within the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> extracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loop</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">residues 554-620</ENAMEX>), in a conserved region (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 5C</ENAMEX>) and
        is adjacent to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> potential 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> -glycosylation sites (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> 585
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">594</NUMEX>). Thus a mutation at <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue 583</ENAMEX> could disrupt the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> site. Finally, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-2</ENAMEX> are
        cysteine-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16 cysteines</NUMEX> in sterolin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 14</NUMEX>
        in sterolin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of these cyteines in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1</ENAMEX> are
        present in the extracellular loop containing the mutation.
        It is tempting to speculate that the gain of an additional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cysteine</ENAMEX> in sterolin-1 by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Gly583Cys</TIMEX> missense mutation
        might affect <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">intracellular</ENAMEX> trafficking or the
        heterodimerization with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-2</ENAMEX>. This possibility is
        diminished but not eliminated by the demonstration that in
        both the mutant and control <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, 
        Abcg5 is located apically in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intestine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>). Evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1</ENAMEX> and sterolin-2
        may heterodimerize has now been presented, based upon in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitro</ENAMEX> analyses [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . However, our preliminary analyses
        of immunohistochemistry, using an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to sterolin-1
        suggests that the pattern of expression in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intestine</ENAMEX> is similar for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX> or SHR rats
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>). These studies are limited in scope, as antibody
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reagents</ENAMEX> to detect rat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-2</ENAMEX> are not currently
        available.
        Another formal possibility not excluded is that the
        Gly583Cys <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missense</ENAMEX> mutation may have no significance in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of phytosterols in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX>, and
        that the alteration in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">UTR</ENAMEX> or even the intronic
        changes reported above may be the causative 'mutations'.
        Our analyses of the mRNA and protein profiles would not
        strongly support these possibilities. However, further
        investigation will be required to determine if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-base
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insertion</ENAMEX> in the predicted <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3'UTR</NUMEX> of 
        Abcg8 has any functional consequence.
        In the absence of a direct assay for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-2</NUMEX>
        function, the genetic changes presented, together with the
        correlation of the phenotypes, remains the strongest
        evidence that these genetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alterations</ENAMEX> are functional, and
        that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Gly583Cys</TIMEX> is a mutational change.
        A more relevant question raised in this study is whether
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> sterol accumulation in hypertensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> strains
        has significance in the pathophysiology of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>.
        Recent linkage mapping studies mapped hypertension <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">QTLs</ENAMEX> to
        a number of chromosomal regions in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> rats [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
        ] . Our FISH study assigned the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6q12</NUMEX>, a
        region where a cluster of blood pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lod</ENAMEX> score
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4~6</ENAMEX> has been reported to be present (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M6MIT12-M6MIT3</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> cM
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distance</ENAMEX>) in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> genetically hypertensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> (GH
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rat</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . With respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>, although the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> strains carry the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Gly583Cys</NUMEX> mutation, in
        extensive QTL mapping studies using these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX>, no loci
        mapping to the rat 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">STSL</ENAMEX> region have been reported [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ]
        . In our study, the GH <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> is neither sitosterolemic, nor
        has any nucleotide alteration at the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus that would implicate this
        region as mutated. Thus we do not believe the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus plays a role in
        determining blood pressure. However, it may play a
        significant role in modifying the pathophysiology.
        Studies reported by different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have shown
        that a dietary intake of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 %</NUMEX> canola <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> (as part of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">semi-purified diets</ENAMEX>) significantly shortened the life-span
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SHRSP rats</ENAMEX>, with accumulation of phytosterols in plasma,
        red blood cells and tissues [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 17 18 19 21 22</NUMEX> ] . Lower
        red blood cell (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBC</ENAMEX>) membrane deformability, lower density
        of platelets, as well as a higher blood pressure were also
        observed, when compared to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> fed with vegetable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oils</ENAMEX> lower in phytosterols (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 %</NUMEX> soybean oil 
        vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> canola <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>). Canola <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> has a
        higher sitosterol content than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soybean oil</ENAMEX>. In comparison,
        extensive studies on evaluation of high phytosterol diets
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SD rats</ENAMEX> (non-sitosterolemic) have consistently shown to
        be safe without any adverse consequences [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36 37 38 39 40</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41 42</NUMEX> ] . These intriguing differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> and SD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> may now be explained, at least in part, by presence of
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Gly583Cys</NUMEX> missense mutation in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1</ENAMEX>. The WKY rat
        also carries this mutation and a high dietary intake of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phytosterols</ENAMEX> will also increase the blood pressure and
        decrease the density of platelets, though to a lower extent
        than that observed in SHRSP rats [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . These data
        support a pathological role of elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> sterols in
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> and support the notion that the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> loci evolved to not only allow
        for the excretion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> into bile, but also to
        keep 'xeno-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sterols</ENAMEX>' from accumulating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. With
        respect to sitosterolemia in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, although
        atherosclerotic complications have been well-described,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hypertension</ENAMEX> has not been mentioned as feature. However, it
        is not known whether the atherosclerosis in sitosterolemic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> is accelerated, relative to
        those affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with lower blood pressures.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Gly583Cys</NUMEX> mutation in 
        Abcg5 is likely to have originated in
        the original outbred <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wistar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> bred in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> (from
        which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX> was subsequently derived), which has been widely
        employed as a normotensive control in experimental studies
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>. It gave rise to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">SHRSP strains</ENAMEX>.
        Thus, this mutation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> lines may not
        contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX> phenotype 
        per se , but may only be responsible
        for sitosterolemia. The original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wistar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> was
        established at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar Institute</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX>, and the
        Sprague <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dawley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> was derived by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawley</ENAMEX> in
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX> from a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> of unknown origin and
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar</ENAMEX> female. The SHR strain was derived by selective
        inbreeding from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kyoto</ENAMEX> outbred <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wistar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>, and both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">WKY strains</ENAMEX> have been maintained
        over many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-sister</ENAMEX> matings
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://rgd.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mcw</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">edu/tools/</ENAMEX>strains [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44</NUMEX> ] . Healthy WKA
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">GH rat strains</ENAMEX> were also generated from outbred Wistar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">rat strains</ENAMEX>, but these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> were isolated independently
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, respectively (and maintained at
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> as well). The GH <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> was selected for systolic
        hypertension that increased with successive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> and
        maintained through filial matings [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . In view of this,
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Gly583Cys</NUMEX> missense mutation of 
        Abcg5 might result from occurrence of
        a 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">de novo</ENAMEX> mutation during breeding at
        the stage of developing inbred <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">WKY strains</ENAMEX> and propagated
        into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> lines. In contrast, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">143</NUMEX>
        nucleotide fragment insertion polymorphism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'-UTR of
        
        Abcg8 may have resulted from
        acquisition of a foreign chromosomal fragment during the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wistar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat strain</ENAMEX> breeding and established as homozygous
        change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GH</ENAMEX> rat
        strains. In this context, it is important to note that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        other mutant loci have been reported in the SHR <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>;
        missense mutations in the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">KAT-1</ENAMEX> (kynurenine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">aminotransferase-1</ENAMEX>), 
        Srebf-1 (sterol regulatory element
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding factor-1</ENAMEX>) and 
        CD36 (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acid translocase</ENAMEX>) are all
        present as homozygous changes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 47 48</NUMEX> ] . The generation
        of congenic lines may assist with addressing many of these
        issues. Such lines will be useful in demonstrating that the
        variant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1 protein</ENAMEX> is responsible for causing
        sitosterolemia, but will allow comparisons between animals
        that are hypertensive and those that are hypertensive and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sitosterolemic</ENAMEX>. Currently, there are no appropriate genetic
        controls available, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX> are all
        maintained as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>-sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">matings</ENAMEX>. While
        this manuscript was in review, Scoggan 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> also reported identifying
        Gly583Cys <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alteration</ENAMEX> in 
        Abcg5 of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX> rats [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>
        ] .
      
      
        Conclusion
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> rat strain, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WKY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRSP</ENAMEX>, that are
        hypertensive are also sitosterolemic. All of these strains
        are homozygous mutant for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Gly583Cys</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterolin-1</ENAMEX>, encoded
        by 
        Abcg5 . This mutation is not present
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> that were not sitosterolemic, even though one of
        these was hypertensive (the GH <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>). The rat 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> locus, comprising of 
        Abcg5 and 
        Abcg8 , maps to rat chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6q12</NUMEX>,
        a region syntenic with both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and human 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STSL</ENAMEX> loci. Preliminary antibody
        studies show that this mutant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is expressed and
        appears to be apically targeted in the intestinal
        cells.
      
      
        Competing Interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HY</ENAMEX> conceived this study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">KL</ENAMEX> performed the
        molecular genetic studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">EK</ENAMEX> performed the real time PCR
        and the western blotting assays, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M-HL</ENAMEX> performed the
        immunostaining, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">KH</ENAMEX> performed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">FISH assay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX>
        performed the sterol analyses, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NE</ENAMEX> performed the DNA
        isolations from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBP</ENAMEX> were
        responsible for supervision, and data analyses of the
        experiments, as well as for providing the funding. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HY</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBP</ENAMEX> wrote the paper. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the
        final manuscript.
      
    
  
