
  
    
      
        Background
        Statins, potent compounds that inhibit cholesterol
        synthesis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> by blocking
        reported to induce osteoblast activity and lead to bone
        formation, both in tissue culture and in rats and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5 6</NUMEX> ] . These findings, if confirmed and extended to
        include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, have the potential to introduce immediate
        new treatment options to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with low bone mass and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoporosis</ENAMEX>. Such treatment is readily available, since an
        estimated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> alone take statins
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to treat hyperlipidemia with few side effects [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osteoporosis</ENAMEX> is increasingly recognized as an eminent
        public health problem, as the mean age of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in
        most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> increases and costs related to
        osteoporosis are expected to grow <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-fold by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2040</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examination Survey</ENAMEX>, using a definition of osteoporosis
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 20%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Caucasian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>
        have osteoporosis and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 50%</NUMEX> have low bone mass.
        Non-caucasian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> tend to have lower rates of
        osteoporosis but contribute <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 25%</NUMEX> of the fractures
        annually [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        The only bone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anabolic agent</ENAMEX> known to increase bone
        mineral density in both animal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and clinical settings
        is human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">parathyroid hormone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-34</ENAMEX> (PTH), which has recently
        been approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with advance
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoporosis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . Bone-related basic and clinical
        research has been searching intensively for alternative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anabolic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for the treatment of osteoporosis.
        Due to the potential clinical impact of statins as a
        treatment option for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with low bone mass and
        osteoporosis, it is essential to evaluate its anabolic
        activity in several 
        in vitro and experimental animal
        models. We have recently reported the anabolic action of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTH</ENAMEX> in an ovariectomized (OVX) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> mouse model,
        which like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> model, displays a substantial amount of
        trabecular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> in its femoral metaphyses and a
        quantifiable loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OVX</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . The aim of
        this study was to investigate the effect of simvastatin on
        the microarchitecture of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> in an established <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> model
        of osteoporosis, and compare its anabolic action with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTH</ENAMEX>.
        We also verified the presence of systemically administered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">simvastatin</ENAMEX> in the mouse serum, as this has previously not
        been reported and is likely to be of critical importance
        when evaluating the effect of simvastatin on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72 eleven</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-week-old</TIMEX> virgin female <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> mice
          were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taconic Farms</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Germantown, NY</ENAMEX>) and
          maintained at the animal research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deaconess Medical Center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> were fed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purina</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formulab Diet</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> Ca (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formulab</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, IN)
          and water 
          ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libitum</ENAMEX> throughout the
          experiment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> were sacrificed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 inhalation.</TIMEX>
        
        
          Experimental protocol
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro</ENAMEX>-computed tomography analysis
            For a detailed qualitative and quantitative 3-D
            evaluation, whole femoral bones were examined by a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">desktop Î¼CT system (Î¼CT 20</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scanco Medical AG</ENAMEX>,
            Bassersdorf, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>) equipped with a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼m focal
            spot microfocus X-ray tube as a source [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . For
            image acquisition, the specimen was mounted on a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">turntable</ENAMEX> shifted automatically in an axial direction
            over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">216Â°</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">180Â°</NUMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> angle on either side),
            taking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> projections. To scan the entire femoral
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">width</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.1</NUMEX> mm), including the femoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, a total
            of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-150 micro-tomographic</NUMEX> slices were acquired at a
            <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">34 Î</NUMEX>¼m slice increment. CT images were reconstructed in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">512 Ã— 512</ENAMEX> pixel matrices using a standard
            convolution-backprojection procedure with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shepp</ENAMEX> and
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX> filter. Images were stored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-D</TIMEX> arrays with an
            isotropic voxel size of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">34 Î¼m</NUMEX>. A constrained 3-D
            Gaussian filter was used to partly suppress the noise
            in the volumes and the mineralized tissue was segmented
            from soft tissues by a global thresholding procedure [
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> ] . Morphometric parameters were determined using a
            direct 3-D approach [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different
            pre-selected analysis regions: whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> (including
            the articular ends), secondary spongiosa in the distal
            metaphysis, and diaphyseal cortical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>. Parameters
            determined in the metaphyseal trabecular bone included
            bone volume density (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BV/TV</ENAMEX>), bone surface density
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS/TV</ENAMEX>), trabecular number (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">trabecular</NUMEX> thickness
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Th</ENAMEX>), trabecular spacing (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sp</ENAMEX>) and connectivity
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">density</ENAMEX>. Cortical volume (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>), percent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX> volume
            (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MV</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cortical</NUMEX> thickness (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ct</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Th</ENAMEX>) were assessed in a
            <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 mm-</NUMEX>thick slab in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-diaphysis</TIMEX>.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> Spectrometry
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond Elut</ENAMEX> C 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> SPE cartridges (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ml/100 mg</NUMEX>) were
            purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Varian/Sample Preparation Products</ENAMEX>
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Harbor City</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">ESI-MS</ENAMEX> (electrospray ionization
            mass spectrometry) were recorded on a Micromass
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Platform LCZ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">system</ENAMEX> equipped with an electrospray
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ionization</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Waters 2690 Separation Module</ENAMEX>.
            For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analytical RP-HPLC</ENAMEX> (Reverse-phase high performance
            liquid chromatography <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vydac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C18</ENAMEX> columns were used; the
            solvent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> used included <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water/TFA</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>, eluent
            A) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acetonitrile/TFA</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>, eluent B). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linear</ENAMEX>
            elution-gradient was used (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Waters Gradient 6"</ENAMEX>, t = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> B; t = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> min, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX> B; 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> min, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> B; t = <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 100%</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeOH; t</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> min, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> B). Flow rates were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ml</ENAMEX>/min
            and the detection wavelengths were set to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">220 and 240</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nm</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            Sample preparation
            All sample preparation procedures were carried out
            in an ice-water bath. Stock solution of simvastatin was
            prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> and of simvastatin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydroxy acid</ENAMEX> in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol-water</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90:10</TIMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. Calibration standards
            were prepared fresh for each analysis, by dilutions in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol-water</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">70:30</TIMEX>). The doses of the standards at
            the respective points on the calibration graphs were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>,
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 30, 60, 100</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> ng. Recovery of simvastatin and of
            simavastatin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydroxy acid</ENAMEX> from mouse plasma following
            the extraction procedure below, was assessed by
            comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> doses (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80 and 150</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ng</ENAMEX>), which were used to spike <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ml</ENAMEX> mouse plasma
            followed by extraction and injection into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LC-MS</ENAMEX>, to
            similar doses directly injected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">LC-MS. The</ENAMEX>
            quantitation was based on integration of the area under
            the respective peaks in the UV spectra obtained at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nm</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately the Î</NUMEX>» 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max</ENAMEX> for both simvastatin and
            simavastatin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydroxy acid</ENAMEX>). Each of the samples from
            the 
            in vivo tests (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.15 ml</NUMEX>), or the
            recovery test above, was diluted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> ml of water
            prior to extraction.
          
          
            Extraction procedure
            This procedure was based on the previously published
            protocol by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wu et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] , implementing minor
            modifications. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solid-phase</ENAMEX> extraction cartridge (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ml/100</NUMEX> mg) was conditioned with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Methanol-water</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50:50</TIMEX>).
            The diluted sample (see Sample preparation) was loaded
            on to each cartridge, followed by low vacuum (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 min</ENAMEX>),
            and each cartridge was subsequently washed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml H 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> formic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml H 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> and dried for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> min. Each
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cartridge</ENAMEX> was then eluted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX>-water
            (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">70:30</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> and with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of acetonitrile,
            followed by low vacuum (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 min</ENAMEX>). The combined eluates
            were evaporated to dryness in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeedVac</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45Â°C</TIMEX>. The
            dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> were reconstituted in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of ammonium
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acetate</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 mm</NUMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX>)-acetonitrile (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30:70</TIMEX>). The
            reconstituted extracts were transferred into
            autosampler vials and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼l</NUMEX> of each sample were
            injected on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC</ENAMEX> column (equivalent to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75 Î¼l</NUMEX> of
            plasma sample).
          
          
            Osteocalcin assay
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX> was sampled prior to sacrifice to determine
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX> levels of osteocalcin (OC). Serum intact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OC</ENAMEX> was
            measured by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-site immunoradiometric assay (IRMA
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immutopics Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Clemente</ENAMEX>, CA) against the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mid</ENAMEX>-region <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> and amino-terminal position of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse OC</ENAMEX> with a known sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/mL. Intra-
            and interassay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CVs</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.3% and 4.4%</NUMEX>,
            respectively.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
            A power analysis was conducted in planning the
            experiments to determine the sufficient number of mouse
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">femurs</ENAMEX> in this investigation. A total sample size of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> per treatment condition) was required to
            provide <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> power (Î± = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Î²</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>) to detect a
            significant difference of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> standard deviation (effect
            size = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX>) between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simvastatin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OVX</ENAMEX>, and SHAM
            treatments with respect to each trabecular and cortical
            bone parameter using one-way analysis of variance
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX>) with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-tailed significance level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>.
            Sample size calculations were determined using the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nQuery Advisor</ENAMEX> software program (version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX>,
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Solutions</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>).
            All continuous variables were checked for normality
            using the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kolmogorov-Smirnov goodness-of-</ENAMEX>fit test and
            were found to follow a normal distribution closely [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
            ] . Therefore, results are reported in terms of means Â±
            standard deviation (SD). Treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were compared
            with respect to trabecular and cortical bone parameters
            obtained by Î¼CT by use of analysis of variance (ANOVA)
            with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fisher</ENAMEX> least significant difference (LSD)
            method for 
            post-hoc multiple testing [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ]
            . A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-tailed value of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> was established as
            the criterion for statistical significance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX>
            analysis was performed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPSS</ENAMEX> (version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.0</NUMEX>,
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPSS Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX> (version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.12</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute, Cary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>) software packages.
          
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OVX</ENAMEX> on bone loss
          Consistent with the findings in our recent study [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
          ] , Î¼CT analyses of femoral trabecular and cortical bone
          showed little change over the duration of the study in
          any of the structural variables for SHAM OVX
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss-Webster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups T1/SHAM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">T5/SHAM, T13/SHAM</ENAMEX>).
          OVX <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> demonstrated significantly lower trabecular bone
          volume density (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BV/TV</ENAMEX>) compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHAM</ENAMEX> controls at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 Â± 5%</NUMEX>, 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 weeks</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> vs.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX>, 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>), and showed a
          reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 weeks</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX>, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.001</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). In
          addition, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">trabecular</NUMEX> thickness, spacing and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> were
          significantly different in OVX <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> compared to SHAM
          controls at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 and 13 weeks</TIMEX> (all 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>). However, cortical
          parameters including total volume, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX> volume/total
          volume, and thickness were not significantly different
          between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OVX</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHAM</ENAMEX> controls throughout the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-week</TIMEX>
          study <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> (all 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P > 0.20</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SVS</ENAMEX> treatment on bone
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">At 13 weeks</TIMEX>, trabecular bone volume density (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BV/TV</ENAMEX>) in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTH</ENAMEX> alone (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">T13/OVX/PTH</ENAMEX>) was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX>-fold
          higher than vehicle-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">T13/OVX/VEH</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTH</ENAMEX> treatment was associated with significant
          increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Th</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> as well as an expected
          decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sp</ENAMEX>. In addition, significant differences
          in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">cortical %</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MV/TV</ENAMEX> and thickness were observed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.01</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
          In comparison, trabecular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BV/TV</ENAMEX> in SVS-treated animals
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at 13 weeks</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">T13/OVX/SVS</ENAMEX>) was not significantly increased
          over that observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>-treated animals
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">T13/OVX/VEH</ENAMEX>) (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Furthermore, none of the other
          trabecular bone parameters (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Th</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Tb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>)
          revealed a significant difference after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 weeks</TIMEX> of SVS
          treatment when compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T13/OVX/VEH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, (all 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P = NS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
          Similarly, whole bone volume density at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T13</TIMEX> was higher
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTH</ENAMEX> compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OVX</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>
          Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 Â± 3%</NUMEX>, p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>), whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> treatment
          had no significant effect (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67 Â± 3%</NUMEX>, p = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NS</ENAMEX>).
          In addition, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cortical</NUMEX> thickness evaluated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T13</TIMEX> was
          higher in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PTH</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> compared to the OVX
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.31 Â± 0.03 mm</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.26 Â± 0.02 mm</NUMEX>, p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>),
          whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> treatment exhibited no effect (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.27 Â± 0.01</NUMEX> mm
          vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.26 Â± 0.02 mm</NUMEX>, p = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Osteocalcin
          Mean serum osteocalcin (OC) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHAM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">OVX</ENAMEX> treated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> did not change significantly when compared at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1,</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 and 13 weeks</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PTH</ENAMEX> treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, however revealed an
          increase (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">596 Â± 138 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T13</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/OVX/VEH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">252</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Â± 57 ng/ml,</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.001</ENAMEX>, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). SVS
          treatment at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 weeks</TIMEX>, however, caused no significant
          increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OC</ENAMEX> compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T13/OVX/VEH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">309 Â± 74</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml vs. 252 Â± 57 ng/ml</ENAMEX>, p = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NS</ENAMEX>, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Detection of the active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simvastatin</ENAMEX> hydroxy acid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metabolite</ENAMEX> in mouse serum after gavage
          administration
          In this study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> was administered by gavage, and
          requires hepatic conversion to the metabolically active
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Î²-hydroxy acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS-OH</ENAMEX>). Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> failed to have any
          effect on any static Î¼CT parameter measured at either
          site in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse femur</ENAMEX>, we conducted separate experiments
          designed to detect the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH in mouse serum
          after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> gavage by liquid chromatography/mass
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectrometry</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC/MS</ENAMEX>).
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP-HPLC</ENAMEX>) tandem electrospray ionization mass
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectrometry</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESI-MS</ENAMEX>) method published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wu et al.</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          ] was used to analyze samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse serum</ENAMEX> for the
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS-OH.</ENAMEX> The identity of the eluted
          peak in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RP-HPLC</ENAMEX> was established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of
          the mass associated with it by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESI-MS.</ENAMEX> The retention
          times for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19.5 Â± 0.5 and 15.35</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX>, respectively. Threshold of detection on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LC-MS</ENAMEX> at
          Î» 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">240 nm</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUFS</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>), the most
          sensitive wavelength, for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH was ~<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ng</ENAMEX>. Calibration curves for both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH
          extracted from the area under the curve in the HPLC
          profile was linear in the range of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-150</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>. These curves
          were used to quantitate the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and metabolite levels in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse plasma</ENAMEX>. Based on the spiking of mouse plasma 
          ex-vivo with known amounts of drug
          and subjecting the samples for the extraction procedure,
          the efficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> recovery was estimated to be
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60-75%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70-85%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS-OH.</ENAMEX> Figure 4is a
          representative example of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LC-MS</ENAMEX> analysis of a sample
          collected from a mouse <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> after treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/kg SVS</ENAMEX>. In this sample both the RP-HPLC tracing and
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ESI-MS</ENAMEX> analysis of the peaks corresponding to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">metabolite</ENAMEX> confirm the presence of both in
          the serum.
          Both residual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> and its 
          in situ -generated metabolite
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH were detected in the mouse plasma <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 10</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> after gavage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kg</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> (the
          shortest sampling interval). The levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH
          in the plasma <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> after administration were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97.3</NUMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15.3 ng</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/Î¼l</ENAMEX>, respectively. These findings establish the
          bioavailability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> following this route of
          administration.
        
      
      
        The aim of this study was to investigate the effect of
        Simvastatin on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> in an established <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> model of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoporosis</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> outbred mouse strain
        utilized in this study has proven to be a valuable model
        for investigating the efficacy of both anabolic and
        anti-resorptive therapies for the treatment of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoporosis</ENAMEX>. Here, we have used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PTH</ENAMEX> as a positive control
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] , and compared its effects to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>. While PTH
        demonstrated the expected anabolic effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>, SVS
        failed to stimulate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> formation, despite our
        verification by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC/MS</ENAMEX> of the active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH metabolite in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse serum</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH metabolite is first detectable in mouse serum
        by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> after gavage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, and serum levels
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS-OH</ENAMEX> continued to be observed by both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mass-spectrometric</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UV</ENAMEX> measurements through the last
        serum samples collected at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 minutes</TIMEX> post-gavage. Other
        experiments failed to detect SVS-OH at longer post-gavage
        timepoints of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 and 24 hours</TIMEX>. These data are in general
        agreement with studies in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> and canines that
        calculate peak serum levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40-60 minutes</TIMEX>
        after gavage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Thus, although we
        failed to document any bone anabolic activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> in a
        mouse model of OVX-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">osteoporosis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC/MS</ENAMEX> analysis of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH metabolite in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse serum</ENAMEX> document the efficacy
        of our gavage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX> to experimental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.
        Extrapolating from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, the dose of SVS
        administered in this study was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 400</NUMEX>-fold
        higher than the average dose given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. The results
        suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simvastatin</ENAMEX> does not enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> formation in
        this mouse model 
        in vivo , despite our ability to
        verify the presence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH metabolite in mouse serum
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC/MS</ENAMEX> analysis. Furthermore, the osteocalcin assay did
        not suggest any increase in osteoblast activity in SVS
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">treated mice</ENAMEX>, consistent with its failure to increase bone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">density</ENAMEX>.
        It is generally accepted that the hydroxy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> form of
        statins are potent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">coenzyme A</ENAMEX> (HMG-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CoA</ENAMEX>) reductase, an enzyme that plays a
        critical role in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol metabolism</ENAMEX>, where they block
        substrate accessibility to HMG-CoA reductase, effectively
        subverting cholesterol levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDL</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21</NUMEX> ] . In
        addition to lowering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statins</ENAMEX> seem to have a
        number of additional effects, such as the nitric
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">oxide-mediated</ENAMEX> promotion of new blood vessel growth [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ]
        , protection against oxidative modification of low-density
        lipoprotein, as well as anti-inflammatory effects and a
        reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reactive protein</ENAMEX> levels [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . All statins
        limit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> biosynthesis by inhibiting the committed
        step in the biosynthesis of isoprenoids and sterols [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ]
        .
        Considering the enormous potential impact of statins on
        the treatment of osteoporosis, several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have further
        investigated the skeletal effects of statin use. Several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have failed to confirm the initially reported
        anabolic effect of systemically administered statins 
        in vivo in rats [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26 27</NUMEX> ] . One
        obvious criticism of the negative data in these studies is
        that they did not verify the actual presence of statin in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal serum</ENAMEX>. This limitation may be of importance, as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crawford et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] could detect an increase in cortical
        bone when statin was administered locally. Our study
        demonstrated the presence of systemically administered the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH metabolite in the mouse serum by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LC/MS</ENAMEX> analysis.
        The exact mechanism by which statins perform their
        effects on bone cell function is a central issue. It has
        been hypothesized that statins mediate their effects by
        increasing the expression in bone of the growth factor bone
        morphogenic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-2</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX>) which in turn leads to
        osteoblast differentiation and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> formation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . This
        mechanism of action has been addressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baumann et al.</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, where the anabolic effect of lovastatin on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> was
        at least partially due to their inhibiting effect on
        osteoclast development [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . Similarly, in the mouse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">calvaria</ENAMEX> model <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gasser et al.</ENAMEX> failed to detect any anabolic
        activity of statins in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> and suggested that the
        disruption of the capillary integrity and local bleeding
        might explain some of the previously reported bone
        responses [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] .
        Several studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> reported a decreased risk of
        fracture after statin treatment [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3 29 30</ENAMEX> ] . However
        larger human studies failed to confirm statins beneficial
        effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaCroix et al.</ENAMEX> found the risk of hip and
        arm fracture to be similar among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who used statins and
        those who did not take lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lowering medication</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Staa</ENAMEX> et al. examining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">218,062</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with a
        fracture in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Practice Database</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>, and found no relationship between statin use and
        nonspine fracture [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . Interestingly, a report by Meier
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] had used the exact same database as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Staa</ENAMEX> et al. [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> ] , but sampled a much larger cohort (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">218,062</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with fracture) than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meier</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3940</TIMEX>), and in
        addition, selected an age and gender matched control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> for every fracture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. The clinical data
        available at the moment does not allow the conclusion that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">statin</ENAMEX> treatment has a postive relationship with fracture
        risk.
        Similarly as described in the clinical trials, the early
        animal studies reported data supportive of the initial
        findings [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 4 5 6 33 34</NUMEX> ] . These results however, were
        not substantiated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX>, where SVS
        had no or little effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone mineral density</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] .
        However, none of the studies has verified the actual
        presence of the active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH metabolite in the animal
        serum, as shown in this study. In combination with the
        osteocalcin data, this report provides strong evidence that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">simvastatin</ENAMEX> does not have an effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> in an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">established Swiss Webster</ENAMEX> mouse model of OVX-induced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoporosis</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        In summary, the currently available data on the effects
        of statins on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> has done little to confirm the finding
        that statin therapy increases bone mass and thereby lowers
        fracture risk. Few of the studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>
        have been able to show a predictable beneficial effect on
        bone mass and bone turnover. This report verifies the
        presence of the active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SVS</ENAMEX>-OH metabolite in the mouse serum
        yet failed to demonstrate any beneficial effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statins</ENAMEX> have clear effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> formation 
        in vitro , the formulation of
        existing 'liver-targeted' statins may require further
        refinement for efficacy on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> formation 
        in vivo .
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. von Stechow</ENAMEX>: participated in the study coordination,
        perfomed the microCT analysis and drafted the
        manuscript
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Fish</ENAMEX>: carried out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> experiments
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Yahalom</ENAMEX>: carried out the mass spec analsysis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. Bab</ENAMEX>: participated in the design of the study
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Chorev</ENAMEX>: participated in the mass spec analysis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. MÃ¼ller</ENAMEX>: participated in the microCT analysis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. M. Alexander</ENAMEX>: conceived of the study, and
        participated in its design and coordination, and edited the
        manuscript
      
    
  
