
  
    
      
        Background
        Opioid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> (ORs), like many other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coupled receptors</ENAMEX> (GPCRs), are capable of
        signalling via the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of mitogen activated protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> (MAPKs). It has been postulated that activation of
        these kinases allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX> agonists to modulate such diverse
        molecular events as cell proliferation, differentiation,
        and survival [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . To date, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> cloned opioid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">receptor types (μ,δ, κ</ENAMEX>) and the closely related nociceptin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> have demonstrated the ability to signal through
        their heterotrimeric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        i or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> ) to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4</NUMEX>
        ] . Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that are activated by
        opioids, are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> extracellular signal-regulated protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> (p44 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ERK 1</NUMEX>) and p42 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ERK 2</NUMEX>)) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] and the
        p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . However, the precise mechanism
        by which OR stimulation produces an increase in MAPK
        activity is still unknown and under investigation.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, and tissue-specific differences
        almost certainly exist and appear to make any single
        mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation unlikely, certain generalities
        have begun to emerge. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation by GPCRs
        is predominantly a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ras-dependent</ENAMEX> event, one that utilizes
        many of the upstream <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein intermediates</ENAMEX> (i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shc</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Gab1</TIMEX>,
        Grb2, mSOS, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> kinase (MEK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)) known to be used by
        the epidermal growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor receptor</ENAMEX> (EGFR) (for a review
        see [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] ). When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX> are activated after EGFR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulation</ENAMEX>, an essential event is the sequential tyrosine
        phosphorylation of these intermediate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and their
        binding to the tyrosine phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> before the
        GTP-loading of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, the tyrosine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX>(s) involved and the site of this multi-protein
        complex formation is less clear. For a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX>,
        including the lysophosphatidic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (LPAR) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] ,
        β-adrenergic 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (β 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -AR) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] and μ- and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">δ-OR receptors</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> ] , the activation of a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> tyrosine kinase of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> or focal adhesion kinase (FAK) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are
        involved. However, the question of what plasma
        membrane-spanning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> serves as the scaffold for Shc
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> and beyond remains to be answered.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> possibilities have emerged as potential sites of
        tyrosine phosphorylation and subsequent scaffold building
        in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX> stimulation, which results in ERK
        activation: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX>, itself, or a co-expressed RTK (i.e.
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>) that would act as a surrogate. We and others and
        we have reported that μ- and δ-opioid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> become
        tyrosine phosphorylated after agonist-stimulation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ]
        . Tyrosine phosphorylation of a membrane-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is
        an essential step in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation, because it creates
        SH2-binding domains that allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shc</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> to
        associate into a multi-protein signalling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. The
        mutation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the tyrosines (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y318F</NUMEX>) in the δ-OR or the
        presence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> inhibitor, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP1</TIMEX>, significantly reduces
        tyrosine phosphorylation of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and its ability
        to activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 13</NUMEX> ] . However, a small degree of
        δ-OR agonist-mediated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> remained in cells
        expressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Y318F mutant receptor</ENAMEX>, suggesting that a
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mechanism or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional tyrosine</NUMEX> could be
        involved. These data suggest that the tyrosine
        phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> may allow them to signal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX> in
        the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTK</ENAMEX> or FAK phosphorylation by acting as
        their own scaffolds.
        However, the majority of the published studies have
        focused on the hypothesis that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> must work in
        cooperation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTKs</ENAMEX> (i.e. the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>) to produce ERK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX>. Studies by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daub et al.</ENAMEX>, [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luttrell et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al.</ENAMEX>, [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] have demonstrated that stimulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPAR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        i/q -coupled) and β 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -ARs (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">s</ENAMEX> -coupled), respectively, results in
        the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">transactivation</ENAMEX> /transphosphorylation" of co-expressed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFRs</ENAMEX>. For example, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> and isoproterenol increase the
        tyrosine phosphorylation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>, which appears to be
        required for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation since the presence of
        kinase-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> mutants or the kinase inhibitor,
        AG1478, prevents both responses. It is hypothesized that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trans</ENAMEX>-tyrosine phosphorylation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> creates protein
        phosphotyrosine binding sites that act as a surrogate
        scaffold for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> share many
        similarities with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPAR</ENAMEX> and β 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -ARs in the way they activate the ERK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 15</ENAMEX> ] , we chose to examine whether RTK
        transactivation occurs and is a necessary aspect of
        δ-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">opioid</NUMEX>-mediated ERK activation.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ERK</ENAMEX> phosphorylation in
          δ-OR-expressing HEK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells
          We have shown that δ-opioids increase the
          phosphorylation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERKl/2</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEK-293 cells</ENAMEX> when the mouse
          wild type (WT) δ-OR is stably expressed [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 13</NUMEX> ] . The
          concentrations required to observe DSLET-mediated ERK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM; Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1a</NUMEX>) are consistent
          with those reported for other δ-OR-mediated events,
          including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> protein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">activation</ENAMEX> and adenylyl cyclase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibition</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ] . Moreover, no change in total ERK
          expression was observed, concomitantly, with ERK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> in any of our experiments (data not
          shown). Pretreating the cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTX</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 ng/ml</ENAMEX>), or
          the specific δ-OR antagonist, naltrindole (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 μM</NUMEX>),
          completely blocked the DSEET-induced increase in ERK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1b</NUMEX>). These results suggest that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> utilizes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
          i -coupled δ-OR to stimulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. We then took advantage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HEK-293</ENAMEX> cell line's
          endogenous expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> to examine this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX>'s ability to activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX>. Similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) produces a robust activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX> in
          δ-OR-expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEK-293 cells</ENAMEX> after a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minute</TIMEX> treatment
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2a</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTX</ENAMEX> did not attenuate EGF-mediated ERK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2a</NUMEX>), although this response was
          completely blocked by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> kinase inhibitor, AG1478
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μM</ENAMEX>) (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2a</NUMEX>). Conversely, DSLET-induced ERK
          activation was unaffected by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AG1478</TIMEX>, suggesting that
          different tyrosine kinases are involved in opioid- and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX>-dependent MAPK activity (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2b</NUMEX>). DSLET-mediated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation was significantly inhibited by the Src
          kinase inhibitor, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP1</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 μM</NUMEX>) (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). PP1 also had a
          significant inhibitory (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> reduction) effect on MAPK
          activation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        
        
          DSLET-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation does not produce
          hyper-phosphorylation of the EGFR
          Our next experiments were designed to examine whether
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EGFR</ENAMEX> becomes tyrosine phosphorylated during ERK
          activation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX>. As stated in the introduction,
          several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPAR</ENAMEX>, β 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -AR, and substance P (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>)) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 18</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> ] increase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> phosphorylation during the course
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation, and it is believed, that in these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, this event is an initial step in the
          progression of the MAPK cascade. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> has
          previously reported [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 13</NUMEX> ] that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-opioids induce
          tyrosine phosphorylation of the δ-OR, and it appears that
          this is catalyzed by the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> tyrosine kinase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX>. However, transphosphorylation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> has not been reported. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX>-δ-OR-expressing
          HEK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells were exposed to increasing concentrations
          of either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-1000 nM</ENAMEX>) or EGF (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml) for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> to induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ERK</ENAMEX> activation. As stated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>,
          either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DSLET</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> increased the appearance of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylated ERK</ENAMEX> in a time and concentration dependent
          manner. A portion of the lysates used to measure ERK
          activation was used to immunoprecipitate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> or δ-OR
          to determine their degree of tyrosine phosphorylation.
          After immunoprecipitation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FLAG-tagged δ-OR</ENAMEX> or the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> with the appropriate antibodies, we found that only
          DSLET induced tyrosine phosphorylation of the δ-OR,
          whereas only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> potentiated EGFR phosphorylation (Figure
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> μM DSLET-induced tyrosine phosphorylation of the
          δ-OR was inhibited by naltrindole, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP1</TIMEX>, but not by AG1478
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). These results suggest that transactivation of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> does not play a role in δ-OR phosphorylation or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">δ-opioids</NUMEX>.
        
        
          Determining whether a co-expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTK</ENAMEX> is
          structurally necessary for δ-OR-mediated ERK
          activation
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> down-regulation does not affect
            DSLET-mediated ERK activation in HEK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells
            Despite the lack of direct evidence that DSLET
            induces the transactivation of co-expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTKs</ENAMEX>, it is
            possible that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>, in some way, contributes to ERK
            activation by opioids. It is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTKs</ENAMEX> and
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> share important <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein intermediates</ENAMEX> that are
            required during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation. Therefore, we wished to
            determine what effects the down-regulation of the EGFR
            would have on ERK signalling via the δ-OR. HEK-293
            cells expressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX>-δ-OR were exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> in order to down-regulate and
            desensitize the endogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>. After chronic EGF
            treatment, the cultures were washed with serum-free
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> and then exposed acutely (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX>) to either
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) or DSLET (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μM</ENAMEX>) to stimulate ERK
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> pre-treated cultures, acute EGF
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) was unable to increase the expression of
            phospho-ERKs compared to media-exposed controls (Figure
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). This lack of response appears to be due to the
            down-regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFRs</ENAMEX> from these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> as confirmed
            by immunoblots using the anti-EGFR <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (data not
            shown). However, DSLET-mediated ERK activation was
            unaltered in identically pretreated cultures.
            In cells pretreated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 μM</NUMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>) to
            induce down-regulation of δ-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μM</ENAMEX>)
            was no longer able to activate the ERK cascade, but the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> response to acute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) was unchanged
            compared to medium-treated controls (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). These
            results indicate that a reduction in the function and
            density of endogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFRs</ENAMEX> has little effect on
            opioid-mediated MAPK cascades, and suggests that the
            enzyme cascades that control δ-OR- and EGFR-mediated
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation are separate.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> activates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> even in a cell line devoid of
            the EGFR
            C6 glioma cells have been used as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> cells for the
            transfection of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX> types, and have the
            advantage of expressing high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX>, while being
            devoid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C6</TIMEX> glioma cells that express the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse δ-OR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> produced a concentration-dependent
            increase in the appearance of phospho-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX>.
            DSLET-mediated ERK activation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C6-δ</TIMEX>-OR cells was
            completely inhibited by either pre-treatment with PTX
            or naltrindole (data not shown). In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> was
            unable to elicit ERK activation, at any concentration
            tested, up to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 μM</NUMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). Furthermore, the EGFR
            antagonist, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AG1478</TIMEX>, had no effect on DSLET-mediated ERK
            activation, which eliminated the possibility that these
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antagonists</ENAMEX> produced non-specific, inhibitory effects
            (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>).
          
          
            Potential of endogenously expressed insulin
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX> (IR) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX> to act as surrogate protein
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scaffolds</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation by δ-opioids
            However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C6</ENAMEX> glioma cells express additional RTKs
            including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> (IR) and platelet-derived growth
            factor (PDGFR) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. It is possible that these
            sites can be used as surrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">scaffold proteins</ENAMEX> during
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation, and we explored the possibility that
            δ-opioids induce the transphosphorylation of these two
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTKs</ENAMEX>. At concentrations of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 μM</NUMEX>, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DADLE</ENAMEX>,
            nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPDPE</ENAMEX> were found to increase the tyrosine
            phosphorylation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IR</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) or PDGF (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) induced significant
            tyrosine phosphorylation of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>).
            Moreover, we pre-treated C6-δ-OR cells with the IR
            antagonist, hydroxy-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-napthalenylmethylphosphonic
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid-tris acetoxymethylester</ENAMEX> (HNMPA-(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX>) 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 μM</ENAMEX>), or the PDGFR
            antagonist, (tyrosphostin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 μM</ENAMEX>) before the
            addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μM</ENAMEX>). Despite the presence of these
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">catalytic RTK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">δ-opioid-mediated</ENAMEX> ERK
            activation was not significantly altered in comparison
            to untreated cultures (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>). Furthermore,
            immunoprecipitation of the δ-OR, followed by
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunoblotting</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-phosphotyrosine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>,
            revealed that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> did not attenuate
            tyrosine phosphorylation of δ-ORs after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> treatment
            (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>). The results presented, herein, strongly
            suggest that transactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTKs</ENAMEX> does not make a
            significant contribution to DSLET-induced ERK
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> different cell lines.
          
        
      
      
        Discussion
        With the first evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> could signal via the
        MAPK cascade, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have looked for a common
        mechanism of activation that could be applied across
        receptor types. Unlike the better understood mechanism
        whereby single-transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTKs</ENAMEX> (e.g. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IR</ENAMEX>, or PDGFR)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stimulate ERKs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] , no single sequence of events
        appears to hold among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX>, even when they are expressed
        in the same cell line. For instance, studies from two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laboratories</ENAMEX> reported marked differences in the way the β 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -adrenergic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (β 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -AR) activates <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ERK 1 and 2</NUMEX> in HEK-293
        cells. In one study, the β 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -AR activates <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ERK</ENAMEX> through it's
        coupling to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTX-sensitive G</ENAMEX> 
        i <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ras</ENAMEX> activation
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] , while, in another, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> phosphorylation occurred in
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTX</ENAMEX>-independent and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">s</ENAMEX> - and cAMP-dependent fashion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
        Furthermore, these studies indicate that the same receptor
        may activate ERKs via one mechanism when it is endogenously
        expressed and via another when it is transfected into a
        cell line [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
        Despite numerous reported differences, it does appear
        that diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> share common mechanistic themes during
        ERK stimulation, including the tyrosine-phosphorylation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shc</ENAMEX> and its complexing with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Grb2</TIMEX>, mSOS recruitment, the
        GTP-loading of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Raf-1</ENAMEX> activation leading to MEK-1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . However, the progression of each of
        these downstream events after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX> stimulation depends
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> on the tyrosine phosphorylation of a membrane-bound
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that will be used as a scaffold, which will bind
        the other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (e.g. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shc</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Grb2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Gab1</TIMEX>, mSOS.... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc...</ENAMEX>)
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Moreover, the exact identity of the tyrosine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX>(s) involved in this initial step appears to vary
        among receptor types, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTKs</ENAMEX>, non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor protein</ENAMEX>
        tyrosine kinases (PTKs), or FAKs being involved in
        particular instances [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] .
        In this report, we questioned whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> acts as a
        surrogate scaffold during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation through the δ-OR,
        as it appears to do for several other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . To act
        as a surrogate-binding site for complex formation, the
        literature states that this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> must first become
        tyrosine-phosphorylated [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Tyrosine phosphorylation of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> is apparent after agonist stimulation of the α 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -AR (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS-7</ENAMEX>), β 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -AR (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS-7</ENAMEX>), insulin-like growth
        factor (IGF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS-7</ENAMEX>), substance P, and the
        lysophosphatidic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid receptor</ENAMEX> (LPAR) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . In addition,
        each of the aforementioned ligands also increases ERK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> when the proper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> is expressed in
        these cell lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> phosphorylation
        via each of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> was inhibited by prior exposure
        to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> kinase inhibitor, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AG1478</TIMEX>.
        However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> inhibitor, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PP1</TIMEX> or the expression of a
        dominant-negative Src mutant, will reduce GPCR-mediated
        transphosphorylation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> and GPCR-mediated ERK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> to varying degrees (partial to total),
        suggesting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> different tyrosine kinases can
        be involved [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Src was found to co-immunoprecipitate
        with the phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells exposed to
        either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LPA</ENAMEX> or EGF [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> reported that the
        autophosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Y350</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> does not occur
        after LPA exposure, suggesting that c-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Src</ENAMEX> is the principal
        tyrosine kinase in this instance and not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>'s
        intrinsic tyrosine kinase. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> has also been found to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-immunoprecipitate with the agonist-stimulated β 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -AR during the period of ERK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . Our previous work [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 13</NUMEX> ] suggested
        that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Src</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein tyrosine kinase</ENAMEX> was primarily
        responsible for tyrosine phosphorylation of the δ-OR and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTLET</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> was
        expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CHO</ENAMEX> or HEK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells, because both responses
        were blocked by the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 μM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PP1</ENAMEX>. The seemingly
        dominant role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Src</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">opioid-mediated</ENAMEX> ERK stimulation is
        strengthened in the present report because of considerable
        evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> antagonist, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AG1478</TIMEX>, was unable to
        reduce DSLET-mediated ERK activation. This suggests that
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> has minimal, if any, involvement in the
        opioid-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ERK</ENAMEX> cascade. It is possible, that the dual
        coupling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPAR</ENAMEX> to both inhibitory (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        i ) and stimulatory (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">12/13</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">q</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> is a reason for these
        differences.
        In this report, we have presented considerable evidence
        that δ-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFRs</ENAMEX> activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX>, independently, without
        the need for transphosphorylation of a co-expressed RTK. We
        used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C6</ENAMEX> glioma cells, transfected to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stably</ENAMEX> express the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse δ-OR</ENAMEX>, to examine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">δ-opioids</NUMEX> in a
        line that does not express the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> to confirm our results
        obtained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> down-regulation experiments. We
        observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p42 mapkand p44</ENAMEX> mapkvery
        robustly in this cell line. C6 glioma cells do express
        growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor receptors</ENAMEX> that bind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>.
        However, neither of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> has been reported to act
        as a surrogate scaffold during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation by non-opioid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . In the present report, DSLET-mediated ERK
        phosphorylation was unaltered by the presence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IR</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PDGFR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX>, HNMPA-(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX>) 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> and tyrosphostin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, respectively. It
        is probable that the δ-OR in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C6</TIMEX> glioma cells also acts as
        its own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> for the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shc</ENAMEX>, etc., since the
        δ-OR also undergoes agonist-mediated tyrosine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> in this particular cell line (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kramer et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al.</ENAMEX>, unpublished observations), similar to what we
        previously reported for the δ-OR expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        hamster ovary or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEK-293 cells</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 13</NUMEX> ] . Thus, in at
        least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different cell lines, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEK-293</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">glioma</ENAMEX>, we
        have significant evidence that transactivation of an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenously</ENAMEX> expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTK</ENAMEX> is not required for ERK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> through opioid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>.
        While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> does not appear to be phosphorylated
        during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">DSLET-mediated</ENAMEX> ERK activation, it is possible that
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> is somehow involved in this response when it is
        present. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buist et al.</ENAMEX>, [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] reported that
        endogenously-expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPA</ENAMEX> and endothelin-1 (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK-N-MC</ENAMEX> cells do not activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX> unless the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> is co-expressed, although each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCR</ENAMEX> is functional as
        evidenced by their ability to increase intracellular [Ca
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+]. In the presence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>, ligand activation of LPA
        and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> did not increase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> phosphorylation
        even though both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPA</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors stimulated</ENAMEX> ERK
        activity by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-fold</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">basal</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . Specifically, key
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein intermediates</ENAMEX> may be physically associated with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous RTKs</ENAMEX> in HEK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells, and therefore,
        down-regulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> may negatively affect ERK
        phosphorylation by opioids. To examine this, we induced
        significant down-regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> density and function by
        exposing δ-OR-HEK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 ng/ml EGF</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>.
        Functionally, these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> are no longer capable of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activating ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX> in response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> (Figure),
        whereas this concentration produces a strong effect in
        non-pretreated cells. Conversely, DSLET-mediated ERK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> is actually greater in chronically-treated
        EGF cultures to that observed in cells not previously
        exposed to high EGF concentrations. This may represent a
        compensatory effect to counteract the loss of function of
        an important growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor receptor</ENAMEX>. In a similar
        experiment, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 μM</NUMEX>) induced
        significant δ-OR down-regulation and an almost complete
        loss of DSLET-mediated ERK phosphorylation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> kinase
        activation by a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minute</TIMEX> exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> was unaffected by
        δ-OR down-regulation. These results, taken together,
        suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPCRs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTKs</ENAMEX> can act as independent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase cascades</ENAMEX>, although interactions
        between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> receptor types may exist in certain
        cases.
        In conclusion, we report that the δ-OR agonist, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX>,
        induces significant ERK activation in the absence of any
        increase in phosphorylation of the co-expressed EGFR in
        HEK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEK-293 cells endogenously</ENAMEX> express the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> produces robust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation concomitant with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> tyrosine phosphorylation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunoprecipitation</ENAMEX> studies
        showed that the δ-OR becomes tyrosine phosphorylated after
        exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX>, but not to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX>. These studies were
        repeated in δ-OR-transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C6</ENAMEX> glioma cells, which do not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express the EGFR</ENAMEX>. In these cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSLET</ENAMEX> was still able to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induce ERK</ENAMEX> activation. Additional studies showed that the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTKs</ENAMEX>, which are present in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C6</TIMEX> glioma cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRs</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFRs</ENAMEX>, had no apparent role on ERK activation by a
        δ-opioid agonist. Furthermore, inducing down-regulation of
        either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> or δ-OR by chronic agonist treatment has
        little effect on ERK activation by the other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEK-293 cells</ENAMEX>, suggesting that these pathways are distinct.
        These results demonstrate that opioid-mediated ERK
        activation occurs independently of EGFR
        transphosphorylation, and that the tyrosine-phosphorylated
        δ-OR may serve as the primary scaffold.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> and compounds
          All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> used for these studies were of reagent
          grade and obtained from the following <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. The Src
          inhibitor, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-amino-5-</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-methylphenyl</ENAMEX>)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t-butyl</ENAMEX>)pyrazolo
          [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,4</NUMEX>-d]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pyrimidine</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PP1</NUMEX>), was purchased from Calbiochem
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> antagonist, AG1478
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-chloroanilino</ENAMEX>)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,7</NUMEX>-dimethoxyquinazoline), the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin receptor antagonist</ENAMEX>,
          hydroxy-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-napthalenylmethylphosphonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-tris
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acetoxymethylester</ENAMEX> (HNMPA-(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX>) 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX> antagonist,
          tyrosphostin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biomol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth</ENAMEX>
          Meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>). The opioid agonist,
          [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-Ser-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leu-enkephalin-Thr</ENAMEX> (DSLET), was received from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute of Drug Abuse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIDA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>)
          and the antagonist, naltrindole, was purchased from
          Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biochemicals, Inc.</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Natick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pertussis</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> (PTX) was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemical Co.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Insulin</ENAMEX> was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Hospital</ENAMEX>
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGF</ENAMEX> was purchased from Biomol
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plymouth Meeting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>). All other compounds were obtained
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> listed under the individual methods.
        
        
          Cell transfection and culture
          C6 glioma cells were stably transfected with the cDNA
          encoding the epitope-tagged (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLAG</ENAMEX>) mouse δ-opioid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C6-δ</TIMEX>OR) and were created in our laboratory
          using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flp</ENAMEX>-In transfection method. HEK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells were
          transfected, in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, with the cDNA encoding the
          FLAG-tagged wild-type (HEK-δOR) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse δ-OR</ENAMEX>. Complete
          methods for the stable transfection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEK-293 cells</ENAMEX> to
          express the wild type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> can be found in a previous
          report [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . Both cell lines were seeded in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well
          dishes at an initial cell density of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 × 10 6cells/well</ENAMEX>
          and were maintained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM; GibcoBRL</ENAMEX>) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM L-glutamine, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>
          fetal bovine serum (FBS) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gemini Bio-Products</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calabasas</ENAMEX>,
          CA), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100 μg/</ENAMEX>ml gentamycin sulfate (Gemini
          Bio-Products, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calabasas</ENAMEX>, CA). Selection pressure was
          maintained by the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mg/ml G418</ENAMEX> sulfate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies, Inc.</ENAMEX>) in the culture media, which was kept
          at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37°C</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 /humidified</ENAMEX> air and was changed
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 3-4 days</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Cell treatment and the immunoprecipitation (IP) of
          the δ-OR or the EGFR
          C6-δOR or HEK-δOR cells were not treated until they
          reached <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80-90%</NUMEX> confluency. Relative levels of receptor
          expression were continuously measured among cell types by
          radioligand binding assays [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] to insure that all
          cells used expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-2 pmol/</ENAMEX>mg <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of
          3H-diprenorphine ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3H-DIPR; 3H-DIPR</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> Ci/mmol,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> nM) binding. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Sixteen hours</TIMEX> before the
          addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, the culture medium was removed and
          replaced by fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serum</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>. All
          inhibitors/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> were added at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>
          before opioid agonists or EGF. After a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> opioid
          or EGF incubation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell monolayers</ENAMEX> were rinsed twice
          with ice cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphate-buffered saline</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>), and the
          cells were solubilized by the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 μl</NUMEX> of
          solubilization buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-HCl/Base</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pH7.4</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 %</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> glycerol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> mM CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> mMNaCI, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM NaVO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> , and the protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leupeptin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 μg/ml</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 μM</ENAMEX>), and aprotinin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">μg/ml</ENAMEX>)) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">+4°C</TIMEX>. Soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were
          isolated by centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+4°C.</ENAMEX> Primary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysates</ENAMEX> were analyzed for protein
          concentration using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX> method. A mouse
          monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> raised against the FLAG-epitope
          (Flag-M 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-5 μg/μl</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>) was used to immunoprecipitate
          the tagged δ-OR from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysates</ENAMEX>, and a murine
          anti-EGFR <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> ((<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 μg/μl</ENAMEX>) clone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LA22</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upstate</ENAMEX>
          Biotechnology, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Placid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>) was used to
          immunoprecipitate out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX>. Antibodies to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-19</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">epitope-β subunit</ENAMEX>; rabbit polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 μg/μl</ENAMEX>))
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF</ENAMEX> receptor (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-20</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">epitope</ENAMEX>; rabbit polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">μg/μl</ENAMEX>)) were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA). Immunoprecipitation of all receptor
          types was performed using magnetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dynabeads</ENAMEX> (Dynal
          Bioscience, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>) coated with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-rabbit IgG</ENAMEX> and used according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          instructions. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Proteins</ENAMEX> were prepared for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE by
          boiling them in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> × <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lammeli</ENAMEX>'s sample buffer and stored at
          -70°C until used.
        
        
          Immunoblotting for the presence of phosphorylated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>) and phosphorylated tyrosines
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS PAGE</ENAMEX> and immunoblotting (IB) were performed
          following the methods contained in a previous report [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
          ] , and all procedures were performed at room temperature
          unless otherwise noted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-20 μg/lane</ENAMEX>) were
          separated by using <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10-20%</NUMEX> acrylamide gels, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electroblotted</ENAMEX> onto nitrocellulose membranes.
          Non-specific binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> were blocked by incubating the
          nitrocellulose for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 minutes</TIMEX> in blocking buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM
          Tris-HCl/<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Base</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> Tween-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat</ENAMEX>
          dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>). For the identification of the activated form
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> (pERK) from primary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysates</ENAMEX>, we used an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibody</ENAMEX> raised against pERK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/2</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:5,000 dilution in
          blocking solution, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>,
          CA). Total MAPK levels were quantified using the ERK-1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-16</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">epitope</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:5,000 dilution in blocking
          solution), which was also obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>
          Biotechnology (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA). <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse</ENAMEX> monoclonal
          antibodies raised against phosphorylated tyrosines (clone
          PY20 (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:2,000 dilution), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA) were used to identify tyrosine phosphorylated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFR</ENAMEX> or δ-ORs. Incubation with all primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> was
          carried on overnight at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">+4°C</TIMEX>. Membranes were then
          incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 minutes</TIMEX> in the presence of a
          goat-anti-mouse secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> linked to
          horseradish-peroxidase (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>) at room temperature.
          Immunoreactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were visualized using a
          horseradish peroxidase-sensitive ECL chemiluminescent
          Western blotting (WB) kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Analysis</ENAMEX> and statistical methods
          Radioligand binding curves (to determine k 
          D and B 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max</ENAMEX> ) were generated, and all
          regression analyses were performed using the LIGAND
          curve-fitting program [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . Graphs were produced using
          Sigmaplot for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> (version <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.0</NUMEX>). Images of
          immunoreactive bands were captured on x-ray film and
          analyzed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCID</ENAMEX> morphometric system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imaging</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>). All immunochemical
          assays were performed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> times, although
          results from a single experiment are sometimes shown for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clarity</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">One-way</ENAMEX> and two-way analyses of variance (ANOVA)
          and the post-hoc <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tukey</ENAMEX> test were used for multiple
          comparisons at a minimum significance level of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p </ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>.
          Student's t-test was substituted for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX> for simple
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-sample tests at the same significance level.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX> data are expressed as mean ± standard error
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>) of the indicated number of observations.
        
      
    
  
