
  
    
      
        Background
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus anthracis</ENAMEX> contains a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96.2</NUMEX> kb
        plasmid, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pXO2</TIMEX>, that is required to cause the disease
        anthrax [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sequencing</ENAMEX> and annotation
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneMark</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hmm</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pXO2</ENAMEX> predicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85</TIMEX> open reading frames
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX>) [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Genbank accession NC</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">002146</ENAMEX>]. Little is known about
        the identity and function of pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> beyond the virulence
        genes associated with the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis capsule</ENAMEX> ( 
        goal of this study was to determine if many of the novel
        pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> were unique to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> , or were conserved in
        other closely related 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus cereus</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus thuringiensis isolates</ENAMEX>.
        Conservation of plasmid sequences can provide clues about
        the origin of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">pXO2</NUMEX> plasmid and about potentially
        conserved gene functions. Identification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> that are
        specific to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> are potentially useful
        as markers for detection of the pathogen in clinical and
        forensic applications.
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. cereus/B.</ENAMEX>
        thuringiensis phylogenetic group [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
        this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> are nearly indistinguishable by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16S</TIMEX> rDNA
        analysis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plasmids</ENAMEX> in the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. cereus/B.</ENAMEX> thuringiensis isolates
        vary greatly in number and size, and many of the phenotypic
        differences among 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cereus</ENAMEX> , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> isolates are conferred
        by plasmid encoded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10 11 12</ENAMEX> ] . Horizontal
        plasmid transfer among <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, including isolates of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cereus</ENAMEX>/thuringiensis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> has
        been documented [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13 14 15 16</NUMEX> ] .
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 350</NUMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cereus</ENAMEX>, B. thuringiensis , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> isolates, identified
        several distinct isolate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18</NUMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. cereus/B.</ENAMEX> thuringiensis isolates
        were found to be very closely related to all 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> isolates and formed a
        distinct cluster. In the present study, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cereus</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> isolates that vary
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AFLP</ENAMEX>-based genomic relatedness to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> were examined for the
        presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequence similar to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pXO2</TIMEX>, to determine
        whether portions of this plasmid are conserved in closely
        related 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus isolates</ENAMEX>, and to determine
        whether the conservation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pXO2</ENAMEX> sequences correlated with
        genomic relatedness established by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFLP</ENAMEX> comparisons [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18</NUMEX>
        ] .
      
      
        Results and Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">template DNA</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus isolates</ENAMEX> that vary in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relatedness</ENAMEX> to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> anthracis with primer sets
        designed to amplify DNA fragments from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> different pXO2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX>. This method was chosen to detect sequences with
        potential similarity to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pXO2</TIMEX> because it is rapid and the
        reaction products can be readily sequenced. Table 1lists
        the isolates tested, their genomic relatedness to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> as determined by Jaccard
        distances calculated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFLP</ENAMEX> profile comparisons [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18</NUMEX>
        ] , and the number of positive PCR reactions obtained for
        each isolate. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequencing of the amplified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products
        revealed a high degree of sequence similarity to pXO2 ORFs
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genbank</ENAMEX> accession numbers <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF547271-AF547318</ENAMEX>]. BLAST
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">blastn</NUMEX>) e-values were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 × 10 -13or</NUMEX> less for each ORF
        fragment detected, which corresponded to sequence
        similarity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> or greater. In a previous study, a
        similar approach was used to demonstrate that many of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pXO1</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX>-encoding plasmid of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> , were highly conserved
        in other isolates from the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. cereus/B.</ENAMEX> thuringiensis group [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
        ] .
        The number of plasmid ORFs detected in a 
        Bacillus isolate did not correlate
        directly with phylogenetic relationship to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> as determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFLP</ENAMEX>.
        The isolates most closely related to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> as determined by AFLP
        produced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no more than two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products each. However, two
        of the more distantly related isolates, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33679</NUMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AWO6</TIMEX>, produced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> positive PCR reactions, respectively. Neither of
        these isolates is known to be a human or animal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathogen</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2lists</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> that were tested in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> assay, their putative functions or similarities to
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (blastp), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> results obtained in this
        experiment. Nineteen different pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> fragments were
        detected among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus isolates</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conserved ORFs</ENAMEX> were similar to sequences contained in
        public databases; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> were unidentified. The only pXO2 ORFs
        found in common with the isolates most closely related to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> (Jaccard distance of
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.55 or less</NUMEX>) were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ORFs 47 and 48</NUMEX>. These ORFs have sequence
        similarity to a conserved hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> found in
        several bacterial genera and the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tetR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of transcriptional
        repressors, respectively.
        A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25.3</NUMEX> kb region that contains the capsule-associated
        genes has sequence characteristics that are different from
        the rest of the plasmid. This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> of pXO2 spans
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">nucleotides 48242-73500</ENAMEX> and includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53 through 65</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX>). In comparison to the rest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pXO2</TIMEX>, this region has a
        larger average gene size (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">818</NUMEX> bases 
        vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">725</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>), a lower gene density
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> gene 
        vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> per kb of sequence), and
        larger average intergenic spaces (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1125</TIMEX> bases 
        vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> also has a
        slightly lower percent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>+<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX> (~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX>) than the rest of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX> (~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX>). Although the region is not bracketed by 
        IS elements or tRNAs that are
        characteristic of pathogenicity islands (PAIs), it bears
        features that are similar to the putative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAI</ENAMEX> identified in
        the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> plasmid <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pXO1</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] .
        Bacterial sequences with similarity to the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> anthracis cap genes are present in
        sequence databases. However, the capsule-associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (
        
        capABC, dep, acpA ) were not detected
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> in the tested 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus isolates</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">pXO2</NUMEX> ORF
        sequences detected in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33679</NUMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AWO6</TIMEX> were
        distributed across the entire plasmid sequence, except in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25.3</NUMEX> kb 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX> gene-containing region, which
        appeared to be unique to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis .</ENAMEX>
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> strain <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">AWO6</NUMEX> produced
        the most products in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> assay. A hybridization assay
        was performed using total genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from this isolate as
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pXO2 DNA</ENAMEX> targets amplified using the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>
        primer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sets</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> assay (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>). The hybridization
        assay complimented the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> analysis by identifying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
        additional conserved ORF sequences that might not have had
        exact matches to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> primer sequences. Total genomic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> strain AWO6
        hybridized with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> fragments, including all ORFs
        tested in the region <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between ORF 5 and ORF 38</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25.3 kb</NUMEX> pXO2 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cap</ENAMEX> gene-containing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> did not
        hybridize with 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> strain AWO6 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>.
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis AWO6</ENAMEX> is a strain
        containing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> kb plasmid designated pAW63 [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 21</NUMEX> ] .
        This strain was derived from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HD73</TIMEX> by curing of
        its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal toxin</ENAMEX> bearing plasmid, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pHT73</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 21</NUMEX> ] . The
        pAW63 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plasmid</ENAMEX> contains a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">replication complex</ENAMEX> that is
        classified as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the pAMB-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of theta
        replicating plasmids that are present in a broad range of
        Gram positive species [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plasmid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pXO2</ENAMEX> also appears to
        be a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">pAMB1</NUMEX>-like theta replicating plasmid [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">replication complex</ENAMEX> are present in
        both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pXO2 and pAW63</TIMEX> (see pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35, 37, 38, 39</TIMEX> in Tables
        2and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35, 37</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> were sufficiently conserved
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between pXO2 and pAW63</TIMEX> to allow detection by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tables 2and 3</ENAMEX>).
        Pulsed field gel electrophoresis was used to separate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX> and chromosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AWO6</TIMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
        hybridization blot using a mixed pool of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pXO2</NUMEX>-derived
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">probes</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ORFs 6</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 50, 63, 72, 81</TIMEX>) was performed to
        determine if any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> were present on the pAW63
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX> (Figure). A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> fragment estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> kb in
        size hybridized to the mixed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pXO2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, which is slightly
        larger, but within <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> of the reported size of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pAW63</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kb</ENAMEX>). This same PFGE protocol produced a similarly accurate
        measurement of the size of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> plasmid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pXO1</TIMEX> as
        determined by complete <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequencing</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] . The
        detection of sequences similar to pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> on pAW63
        suggests that other pXO2 genes, in addition to those
        involved with replication, are also located on the pAW63
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        The presence of pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> sequences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> 
        Bacillus isolates did not correlate
        with their genomic relatedness to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> as determined by AFLP
        comparisons. A similar observation was made in previous
        work that examined the conservation of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis</ENAMEX> plasmid <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">pXO1</NUMEX> among
        closely related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] .
        This study explored the extent of sequence conservation
        between pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> and total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from other 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus isolates</ENAMEX>, and detected
        similar sequences that may be located on the chromosome or
        any of several plasmids in each isolate. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> isolates
        with the most sequence conservation with pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> isolates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33679</NUMEX> and
        AWO6, are known to contain large plasmids [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 19</NUMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> with high sequence similarity to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AWO6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plasmid</ENAMEX> pAW63
        were detected [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] , and a mixed pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> probe
        hybridized with a PFGE fragment similar in size to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pAW63</TIMEX>.
        The presence of considerable sequence conservation in more
        distantly related isolates rather than among close
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, combined with the observations stated above, is
        a pattern consistent with the potential plasmid location of
        these sequences. Comparative sequence analysis of these
        large plasmids with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pXO2</ENAMEX> could determine if the observed
        sequence conservation was located on these plasmids.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Bacterial isolates and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> isolation
          The genomes of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> 
          Bacillus isolates selected for
          study were found by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFLP</ENAMEX> analysis to vary in relatedness
          to 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis .</ENAMEX> Isolates with
          Jaccard distances of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 0.55</NUMEX> formed a distinct
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cluster</ENAMEX> with all of the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. anthracis isolates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.J.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, unpublished data) while the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> isolates
          were present in less closely related clusters (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacteria</ENAMEX> were grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nutrient Broth</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NB</ENAMEX>; DIFCO
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Lakes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) or on NB agar plates at
          28°C. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (including chromosomal and plasmid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>)
          was extracted as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robertson</ENAMEX> 
          et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] with slight
          modifications. Cultures grown for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> h in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutrient Broth</ENAMEX>
          were centrifuged into a pellet, washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM Tris
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pH 7.5/1</NUMEX> mM EDTA pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>), and suspended in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> sucrose.
          Cells were incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37°C</NUMEX> in lysozyme solution (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/ml</ENAMEX> lysozyme, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM EDTA pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>),
          followed by addition of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SDS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX>
          beta-mercaptoethanol. A potassium acetate precipitation
          was performed to further clarify lysed cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . DNA
          was purified by organic extraction and ethanol
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precipitation</ENAMEX>. Purified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was quantified by UV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectrophotometry</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from a 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthracis</ENAMEX> isolate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">213C</NUMEX>-1
          provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.J. Jackson</ENAMEX> was included as a positive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> primer sets
          Oligonucleotide primer sets were identified for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX>
          pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> primer sets were typically positioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> termini unless A/T richness of the
          DNA sequence prohibited the design of primers in that
          region. Primer sequences are located at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://bdiv.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lanl</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/databases/databases.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>. The
          remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> were not included in the present
          survey due to sub-optimal A/T richness, amplicon size,
          and thermodynamic characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> primer
          sets.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> assays and amplicon sequencing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> assays to detect each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> individual pXO2
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> were conducted using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from each bacterial isolate
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>) as template. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifty μl PCR</ENAMEX> reactions contained
          1X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer PCR</ENAMEX> buffer with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.8</NUMEX> mM each dNTP, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> AmpliTaq
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">45 μM</NUMEX> of each primer.
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PTC-200 Peltier Thermocycler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MJ Research</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Watertown</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) was used for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>-cycle reactions (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">94°C, 2 min</ENAMEX> for
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> cycle only; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94°C</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> s.; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48°C</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> s.; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72°C</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> s).
          Reactions were resolved on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> agarose gels that were
          stained with ethidium bromide and viewed using a UV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trans</ENAMEX>-illuminator. A reaction was considered positive if
          the amplified fragment was abundant and was the expected
          size DNA fragment.
          The majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were sequenced using
          dye-terminator chemistry (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABI Prism FS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE Applied</ENAMEX>
          Biosystems, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>). Sequencing primers were the same
          as those used in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplification reactions. Sequencing
          reactions were resolved on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> cm polyacrylamide gels (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:1 acrylamide:bisacrylamide</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad Laboratories</ENAMEX>)
          using an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABI</ENAMEX> model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">373</ENAMEX> fluorescence sequencer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosystems, Inc.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequence</ENAMEX> was analyzed using
          Lasergene software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNASTAR, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>).
          Sequences were deposited in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GenBank</ENAMEX> as accession numbers
          AF547271 to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AF547318</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Hybridization assay
          A dot-blot hybridization assay was performed using DNA
          from 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis</ENAMEX> strain AWO6 as
          probe against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>-amplified pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> applied to a
          nylon membrane. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> ng of each pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> fragment was
          denatured by adding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 M NaOH</ENAMEX> and incubation
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. An equal volume of 20X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 M NaCl</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0.3 M</ENAMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">citrate</ENAMEX>, adjusted to pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M HCl</ENAMEX>)
          was added and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were quickly placed on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          min. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was then applied to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hybond-N</ENAMEX>+ membrane
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) pre-soaked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10X</TIMEX> SSC
          using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HYBRI-DOT Manifold</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies, Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          Rockville, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). The membrane was exposed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> mjoules
          of ultraviolet light in a UV-STRATALINKER <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1800</TIMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STRATAGENE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LaJolla</ENAMEX>, CA) to crosslink <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">membrane</ENAMEX>. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> extracted from 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis AWO6</ENAMEX> was used to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">synthesize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> by incorporating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[α- 32P</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dCTP</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">μCi/mMol</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) into randomly primed DNA
          synthesis reactions using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megaprime DNA Labeling</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amersham-Pharamacia Biotech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>)
          according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> instructions. The membrane
          was incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50°C</NUMEX> in hybridization buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
          NaHPO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM EDTA pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]) for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 min</TIMEX>, followed by hybridization with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> h at
          50°C. After hybridization, the membrane was washed twice
          for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 min at 30°C</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">2X SSC</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> and
          twice for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 min at 45°C</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">0.2X SSC</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>.
          Results were viewed using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fugi Phosphorimager</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> ml culture of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. thuringiensis AWO6</ENAMEX> was grown in
          NB <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37°C</NUMEX> with shaking. Chloramphenicol was
          added at a concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">180 μg/ml</ENAMEX> and the culture was
          incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">min. Cells</ENAMEX> were incubated on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX>, then centrifuged at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2500</TIMEX> × 
          g for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">min. Cell pellets</ENAMEX> were
          suspended in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 ml TE</TIMEX> buffer that contained <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 mg/ml</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysozyme</ENAMEX> and incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>.
          Lysozyme-treated cells were washed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffer NT</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 M NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>) and were suspended in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffer NT</ENAMEX> to a final volume of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 μl</NUMEX>.
          Agarose plugs containing bacterial cells were prepared
          in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml syringe by combining cells with an equal volume
          of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SeaKem Gold</ENAMEX> agarose (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FMC BioProducts, Rockland, ME</ENAMEX>)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">melted</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Plugs were allowed to solidify at 4°C
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">h. Thin agarose slices</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-3 mm</ENAMEX>) containing embedded
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> h in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">500 μl Buffer</ENAMEX> NTE
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM EDTA pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>)
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> lysozyme at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">lysozyme/Buffer NTE</ENAMEX>
          solution was replaced with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffer NTE</ENAMEX> that contained 2
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mg/ml Proteinase K</ENAMEX> and incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> h at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50°C</TIMEX>. Slices
          were then incubated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffer NTES</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM
          Tris pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM EDTA pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> h at
          50°C. Before electrophoresis, slices were incubated twice
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> mM phenylmethylsulfonyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX> (PMSF)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) diluted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> and twice in 0.5X
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBE</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tris-borate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM EDTA).
          Treatment of agarose slices linearized the plasmid DNA
          and allowed for plasmid size determination using a
          concatomerized bacteriophage lambda standard (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>
          BioLabs, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from agarose slices was
          resolved on a gel of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SeaKem Gold</ENAMEX> agarose melted in
          0.5X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBE</ENAMEX>. Electrophoresis conditions were 175 V in 0.5X
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBE</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> h in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">CHEF-DR II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulsed Field</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electrophoresis System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIORAD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA) with a
          field switch ramp of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 to 40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s. Gels</ENAMEX> were stained with
          ethidium bromide and viewed using a UV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trans</ENAMEX>-illuminator.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> hybridization
          The pulsed field gel was sequentially soaked in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCl</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 min</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 M NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M NaOH</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 min</TIMEX>; and 0.5X
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBE</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> min. Electro-transfer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> to a nylon
          membrane was performed using a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Mini Trans-Blot</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Electrophoretic Transfer Cell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA)
          according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> instructions. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crosslinked</ENAMEX> to the membrane by exposure to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> mjoules
          of ultraviolet light in a UV-STRATALINKER <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1800</TIMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STRATAGENE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LaJolla</ENAMEX>, CA). The membrane containing 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> thuringiensis <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AWO6 DNA</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridized</ENAMEX> using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[α- 32P</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dCTP-</ENAMEX>labeled probe prepared
          from a mixture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> PCR-amplified pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> fragments
          (pXO2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORFs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 50, 63, 72, 81</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care</ENAMEX> was taken to
          avoid the IS elements present on the plasmid. Probe
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synthesis</ENAMEX>, hybridization conditions, and wash regimen
          were performed as described above for hybridization
          reactions. Results were viewed using a Fugi
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phosphorimager</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' Contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JP</ENAMEX> was responsible for experimental design, protocols,
        and data management. RTO designed the pXO2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligonucleotides</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EW</ENAMEX> performed PCR reactions and DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequencing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RS</ENAMEX> conducted the hybridization reactions and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequencing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOT</ENAMEX> provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFLP</ENAMEX> data and statistical
        analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRK</ENAMEX> was the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> who began the
        study and coordinated the work. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> contributed to
        preparation of this manuscript.
      
    
  
