
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Prostate cancer</ENAMEX> is the most frequently diagnosed
        visceral <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> leading
        cause of cancer death in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Unfortunately, there
        are no proven primary prevention strategies for prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and no curative treatments for distant-stage cancers
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] . Consequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> control efforts have focused
        on detecting early-stage prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> with screening
        tests and then aggressively treating the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> with
        surgery or radiation. The most effective screening test is
        the prostate-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>) assay, which in
        combination with digital rectal examination (DRE)
        substantially enhances the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> detection rate [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Urologic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> recommend annual cancer screening with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
        testing and digital rectal examination for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with life
        expectancies greater than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . However, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Preventive Services Task Force</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College of Physicians</ENAMEX> have not endorsed routine
        screening because there is no conclusive evidence that
        screening and treatment reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and mortality from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] . Another concern about prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer screening</ENAMEX> is uncertainty about the diagnostic
        performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>. The available data on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing
        generally come from urologic case series comprised of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> responding to advertisements for screening [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX> ] . However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening recommendations encompass
        the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> at risk for prostate cancer
        and results from the urologic literature may not be fully
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">generalizable</ENAMEX>. We have not found any large community-based
        studies evaluating the accuracy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing.
        In this report we link <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing and prostate biopsy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> metropolitan area
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> registry data collected by the
        End Results (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEER</ENAMEX>) Program. The objective of our study was
        to evaluate the diagnostic accuracy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">detecting prostate cancer</ENAMEX> in community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> collection
          We collected computerized data from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> major
          clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
          testing occurring from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 1995 through December</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1997</TIMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> provided testing services
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Maintenance</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizations</ENAMEX>, and private plan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> within the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-county <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX> metropolitan area. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> included
          test date, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> level, and patient demographics, including
          birth date, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at testing, and personal identifiers.
          Additionally, we used the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GUESS</ENAMEX> program, a validated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">algorithm</ENAMEX> developed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Mexico</ENAMEX>, to
          identify ethnic background based on surname [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . We
          evaluated only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 40 years and older</TIMEX> at the time of
          initial testing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing data were matched with
          the NMTR database to exclude <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> tests ordered for cancer
          surveillance and to identify incident cases of prostate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between January 1, 1995 and December 31</TIMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. The NMTR database provided information on cancer
          stage, using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEER</ENAMEX> categories of local, regional, and
          distant. Trained medical record abstractors from the NMTR
          also collected data from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area laboratories</ENAMEX> on all benign
          prostate biopsies during the same time period. The human
          subjects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of the participating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laboratories</ENAMEX> approved the study protocol.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> analysis
          We evaluated the diagnostic accuracy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>-tested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohort</ENAMEX> who had a
          confirmed diagnosis of incident prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> who underwent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> prostate biopsy and
          were not diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> during the study
          period. For a subject to be included in this analysis, we
          required that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> result be obtained within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX>
          before a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosis or a negative biopsy result. If
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> had multiple negative biopsies, we analyzed the
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> biopsy that could be linked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> test within
          the preceding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> had multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
          tests within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> preceding a negative biopsy or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosis, we analyzed the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> test.
          Clinical characteristics of cases and controls were
          compared with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">chi-square</NUMEX> tests for categorical variables
          and either t-tests or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney U</ENAMEX> test for
          continuous variables. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linear</ENAMEX> regression analyses were
          used to test for linear trends. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX> tests were
          performed with the software program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Statistica</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ]
          .
          We constructed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">receiver</ENAMEX> operating characteristic (ROC)
          curves by plotting sensitivity against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> - specificity.
          We estimated the discriminating power of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing by
          determining the area under the ROC curve using the method
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROC</ENAMEX> curves were constructed
          for the entire cohort, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> age ranges, and for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">non-Hispanic whites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>. We also constructed an
          ROC curve using only cases with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">localized cancers</ENAMEX>, the
          target of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> accuracy was evaluated according to standard
          epidemiologic definitions for specificity, sensitivity,
          likelihood ratios, and predictive values [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
          Briefly, we defined sensitivity as the proportion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases with an elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>; specificity is the
          proportion of non-cancer controls with a normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>. The
          positive predictive value of a test is the proportion of
          subjects with an abnormal test result who have the target
          disorder. The negative predictive value is the proportion
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> with a normal test result who do not have the
          target disorder. A likelihood ratio compares the
          proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with and without the target disorder
          within a stratum of diagnostic test results. Likelihood
          ratios provide a magnitude of probability revision using
          a version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayes</ENAMEX>' theorem:
          Post-test odds for the target disorder = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pre-test</ENAMEX> odds
          for the target disorder × Likelihood ratio for diagnostic
          test results
          The diagnostic accuracy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing was further
          evaluated by examining different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> cutpoints, by
          stratifying analyses into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> age ranges (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 to 49, 50</TIMEX>
          to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 to 69, 70 to 79</TIMEX>, and ≥ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years</TIMEX>), and by using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">age-specific PSA</ENAMEX> reference ranges [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . We also looked
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">stratum</NUMEX>-specific likelihood ratios and predictive
          values for the following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> strata: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">< 2 ng/ml, ≥ 2 -</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/ml, > 4 - 10 ng/ml, > 10 - 20 ng/ml</ENAMEX>, and >
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">20 ng/ml.</ENAMEX> An <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Excel</ENAMEX> spreadsheet developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peirce</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX> was used to compute likelihood ratios and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>
          confidence intervals for different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> cutpoints and
          test-result strata [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Subject characteristics
          We obtained data on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41,261</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> without a previous
          diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> who underwent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between January 1</TIMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and December 31, 1997</TIMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1998</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,620</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.3%</NUMEX>) of the testing cohort had undergone a prostate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biopsy</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> following an initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> test and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">930</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.3%</NUMEX>) of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were diagnosed with prostate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. The median age at testing was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61 years</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
          thpercentile <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52, 75</TIMEX> thpercentile <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">69</NUMEX>); <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63.4%</NUMEX> of the men
          were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28.3%</NUMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>. The
          median <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> value for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
          thpercentile <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.9</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> thpercentile <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.2</NUMEX>) was significantly
          higher than the median value for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> without cancer
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> thpercentile <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> thpercentile
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.1</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.0001</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were also
          significantly older, with a median <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 68 years</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
          thpercentile <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63, 75</TIMEX> thpercentile <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>) vs. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66 years</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
          thpercentile <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60, 75</TIMEX> thpercentile <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0001</NUMEX>.
        
        
          Diagnostic accuracy
          The discriminating power of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing for detecting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>, as estimated by the area under the ROC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curve</ENAMEX> (Figure. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.67</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE 0.02</ENAMEX>). When we analyzed
          the ROC curve just using the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">796</NUMEX> cases with localized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, we found a similar area of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.64</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE 0.01</ENAMEX>). The
          discriminating power remained relatively constant across
          age ranges, with areas of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.70</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.68</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.63</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.65</NUMEX>, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.69</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40s</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50s</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60s</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70s</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80s</ENAMEX>,
          respectively. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> under the ROC curve was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.66</NUMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">non-Hispanic whites</ENAMEX> compared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.69</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>.
          Estimates for sensitivity, specificity, and predictive
          values for different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> cutpoints, stratified by age
          range, are reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tables 1and 2</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> are presented
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50s and 60s</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in
          their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">70s</NUMEX> and all age <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> combined (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in
          their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40s</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years</TIMEX> and older) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. For the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard PSA</ENAMEX> cutpoint of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/ml</ENAMEX>, test sensitivity was
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86%</NUMEX> and specificity was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX>. With this cutpoint, the
          likelihood ratio for a positive test was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.28</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.23</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.34</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.42</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.36</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.50</NUMEX>) for a
          negative test.
          Raising the cutpoint to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ml</ENAMEX> decreased the
          sensitivity to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38%</NUMEX> while specificity increased to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84%</NUMEX>.
          The associated likelihood ratio for a positive test was
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.38</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.08</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.72</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.74</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.70</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.78</NUMEX>)
          for a negative test. Lowering the cutpoint to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 ng/ml</ENAMEX>
          increased the sensitivity to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> but dropped specificity
          to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>. At this cutpoint the likelihood ratio for a
          positive test was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.19</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.15</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.22</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.19</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.34</NUMEX>) for a negative test. The predictive
          value for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> was significantly correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cutpoint</ENAMEX> level, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> for linear trend, ranging from
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">≥ 2 ng/ml</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels ≥ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml.</ENAMEX>
          Stratum-specific likelihood ratios and predictive
          values are presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. We found that the
          likelihood ratio for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 and 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
          was statistically equivalent to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, indicating that no
          significant probability revision occurred with testing.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> values <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml or greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
          produced the largest probability revisions for detecting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4shows</ENAMEX> the diagnostic accuracy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels ≥
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/ml</ENAMEX> stratified by age. The sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
          significantly increased with age, going from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> for men
          in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40s</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> in men <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX> and older, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.03</NUMEX>
          for linear trend. However, specificity significantly
          decreased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX> in the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX> in older
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.03</NUMEX> for linear trend. With age-specific
          references ranges (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>) we found that, compared to
          the traditional cutpoint of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/ml</ENAMEX>, sensitivity was
          higher in the younger age ranges and specificity was
          higher in the older age ranges. Overall, however, the
          magnitudes of the likelihood ratios with age-specific
          reference ranges were similar to those found with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml</ENAMEX> cutpoint, except for higher likelihood ratios
          following negative tests in men <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years and older</TIMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensitivity</ENAMEX> and specificity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>, using either a
          cutpoint of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/ml</ENAMEX> or age-specific reference ranges, did
          not differ significantly between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        We evaluated the diagnostic performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing
        using a community-based analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who underwent
        prostate biopsy within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were
        analyzed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">930</NUMEX> prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1690</TIMEX> controls
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 40 years and older</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> under the ROC curve was
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.67</NUMEX>, indicating fair discriminating power for detecting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing performed equally well in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">detecting localized cancers</ENAMEX> and in detecting <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> across
        all age ranges and in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
        The standard cutpoint of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/ml</ENAMEX> had a sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86%</NUMEX>
        and a specificity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX> and was most sensitive - but least
        specific - for older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml cutpoint was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with a likelihood ratio for a positive test of
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.28 and 0.42</NUMEX> for a negative test, representing only
        moderate probability revisions [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> values < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml</ENAMEX> or greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml were associated with large
        probability revisions. Likelihood ratios did not change
        substantially when we used age-specific reference ranges,
        though test sensitivity decreased with increasing age while
        specificity increased. Lowering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> cutpoint to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 ng/ml</ENAMEX>
        raised the sensitivity to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97%</NUMEX> but led to an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> false
        positive rate.
        Most previous reports from the urologic literature
        provided similar estimates for the discriminating power of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> test. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Areas</ENAMEX> under the ROC curve have been reported
        to range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.65 to 0.77</NUMEX> in case series comprised of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> enrolled in screening trials [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 19 20 21</ENAMEX> ] or
        followed in urologic practice [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . Among urologic
        studies, we found only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labrie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> reporting a
        substantially higher area under the ROC curve: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.88</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.03</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . However, biopsies were performed only when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> rectal or transrectal ultrasound examinations were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abnormal</ENAMEX>, which would inflate the apparent sensitivity of
        an elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> level. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gann</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> reported an area
        under the ROC curve of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.83</NUMEX> in a nested case-control study
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians Health Study</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> of
        follow-up [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . Stored serum from cases clinically
        diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> and age-matched controls
        were assayed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>. However, the specificity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> was
        probably overestimated because asymptomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were
        unlikely to be biopsied.
        We identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>-based studies
        evaluating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing performance [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 25 26</NUMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urologic</ENAMEX> studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 25</NUMEX> ] randomly selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from
        either electoral rolls or census records and invited them
        to have prostate examinations. However, neither study used
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels as a criterion for biopsy thus confounding the
        reported predictive values with results from digital rectal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">examinations</ENAMEX> and transrectal ultrasonography. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> conducted a retrospective, case-control study
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">analyzing 177</ENAMEX> prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases diagnosed in Olmsted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> was
        highly discriminating with an area under the ROC curve of
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.94</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>) for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Age-stratified analyses
        showed that the discriminating power remained high across
        all age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, even for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70s</TIMEX>. Test sensitivity
        was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 85%</NUMEX> for all age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, though
        specificity decreased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50s</NUMEX> to
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70s</TIMEX>.
        Methodologic differences in study design may explain the
        disparities in the results between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minnesota cohorts</ENAMEX>. Controls in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Olmsted County</ENAMEX> were drawn
        from a longitudinal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayo Clinic</ENAMEX> study on the natural
        history of lower urinary tract symptoms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> with initial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> elevations <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">> 4 ng/ml</ENAMEX> or an abnormal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRE</ENAMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biopsied</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases were excluded. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with
        normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRE</ENAMEX> results did not undergo biopsy, thus
        potentially inflating estimates for specificity.
        Sensitivity may have been higher if urologists at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayo</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinic</ENAMEX> had a lower false negative biopsy rate than did New
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> urologists.
        Our estimates for the sensitivity (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86%</NUMEX>), specificity
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX>), and positive predictive value (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels ≥
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml were similar to previously reported values. In the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">urologic</ENAMEX> literature, sensitivities ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67% to 90%</NUMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">specificities</ENAMEX> ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28% to 59%</NUMEX>, and positive
        predictive values ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30% to 43%</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 10 11 19 20 27</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> ] . However, almost all of the published studies,
        including our own, are flawed by potential work-up bias
        because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels were significantly
        more likely to be biopsied. In our cohort, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">level ≥ 4 ng/ml</ENAMEX> had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-fold increased rate of biopsy
        compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with normal values.
        Accurately estimating the true and false negative rates
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> requires that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> values undergo
        biopsy, but we found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> small urologic series where
        all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>-tested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> were subsequently biopsied.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vallencian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> biopsied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> consecutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with
        normal or non-suspicious digital rectal examinations and
        detected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 14</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, none with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gann</ENAMEX> study provided the least biased
        estimate of sensitivity and specificity, but even these
        results were limited because <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asymptomatic cancers</ENAMEX> would not
        have been detected [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . Additionally, serum was stored
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 10 years</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> is not completely stable [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31</NUMEX>
        ] .
        Modifications of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> level have been proposed to
        improve the discriminating power of the test. Oesterling
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> developed age-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> reference ranges
        that lowered the cutpoint in younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, to increase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensitivity</ENAMEX>, and raised the cutpoint in older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in order
        to increase specificity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . We found that using
        age-specific reference ranges did not substantially change
        likelihood ratios for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>, though we confirmed
        that sensitivity would increase in younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specificity</ENAMEX> would increase in older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
        The age-specific reference ranges have been further
        modified for racial differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
        ] . Because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> have an increased incidence
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> and higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels at diagnosis, the
        age-specific reference ranges have been adjusted to
        maintain a high sensitivity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33 34</NUMEX> ] . Our study cohort
        had too few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> for a subgroup analysis, but
        we were able to compare <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. We found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing discriminated equally well
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cutpoints</ENAMEX> do not need to be adjusted for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>. We are
        unaware of any other studies comparing the performance of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>,
        though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abdalla</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have reported similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
        levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with and
        without prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36</NUMEX> ] .
        Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are now recommending that lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cutpoints</ENAMEX> should be used as an indication for prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biopsy</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37 38 39</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catalona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> detected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> biopsied with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6</NUMEX>
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/ml</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lodding</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> detected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> values between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/ml</ENAMEX>
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . We found that lowering the cutpoint to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 ng/ml,</ENAMEX>
        while greatly increasing sensitivity, led to an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> false
        positive rate.
        Aside from work-up bias, there were some other important
        limitations in our study. We do not know the indications
        for testing or results from digital rectal examinations.
        The positive predictive value of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX> that we found for a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> cutpoint of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml was at the high end of values
        reported in screening studies and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> was detected in
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in our cohort with normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> levels. These
        findings suggest that our estimates for sensitivity and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specificity</ENAMEX> may be less applicable to a true screening
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. However, we believe that our results more
        accurately reflect community testing practices than the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> reported by urologic series of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer subjects</ENAMEX>.
        Finally, our study cohort was largely comprised of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> suggest that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> assay may perform differently in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> ] .
      
      
        Conclusions
        Our community-based study showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing had
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> discriminating power for detecting prostate cancer
        with an area under the ROC curve of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.67</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing had
        similar discriminating power for detecting localized
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, and it performed equally <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> across age ranges
        and in different ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> cutpoint of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/ml</ENAMEX>
        was sensitive but relatively non-specific and likelihood
        ratios for this cutpoint demonstrated only moderate
        probability revisions. Although age-specific reference
        ranges improved sensitivity in younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and specificity
        in older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, they did not substantially change likelihood
        ratios for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Lowering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> cutpoint below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
        increased test sensitivity but markedly decreased
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specificity</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RMH</ENAMEX> conceived of the study, obtained research funding,
        analyzed data, and drafted the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDG</ENAMEX> helped
        design the study and draft the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MA-C</ENAMEX> collected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, created analytic files, and helped analyze data. WCH
        helped create analytic files and analyze the data. CRK
        helped obtain research funding and supported data
        collection and analysis.
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
