
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Differentiation</ENAMEX> is commonly associated with intermingled
        some differentiating cell types, changes in both gene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> and proliferation are regulated by the same
        transcription factor [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCAAT</ENAMEX>/Enhancer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Binding Protein alpha</ENAMEX> (C/EBPα) is a transcription factor
        that is required for the differentiation of a number of
        tissues [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> homozygous
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> null alleles have severe defects in tissues
        involved in metabolic homeostasis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21</NUMEX> ] . Cellular
        proliferation is elevated in the liver of these knockout
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> blocks proliferation 
        in vivo. In cultured cells, C/EBPα
        expression leads to decreased <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> formation upon
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX> selection [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24 25</NUMEX> ] , decreased DNA synthesis
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 24 25 26 27</NUMEX> ] and an enhanced proportion of cells in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> phase of the cell cycle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . Thus, C/EBPα
        regulates cellular proliferation, as well as gene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX>.
        C/EBPα contains a bZIP domain conserved at the carboxy
        terminus of a number of transcription factors [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 28</NUMEX> ] .
        The bZIP domain consists of a basic region that binds
        directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, followed immediately by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">leucine zipper</ENAMEX>.
        C/EBPα dimerizes via the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">leucine zipper</ENAMEX>. This dimerization
        is required for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] . At least three
        transcription activation functions have been described in
        the more amino terminal regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31 32</NUMEX> ] .
        C/EBPα domains and activities associated with proliferation
        arrest also have been identified, but vary considerably
        between studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 25 33 34 35 36</NUMEX> ] .
        C/EBPα binds to and activates transcription of the gene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p21</TIMEX> inhibitor of cyclin-dependent kinase
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDK</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] . This led to speculation that p21 gene
        activation may contribute to cell cycle arrest by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> ] . Similarly, suppression of mitotic growth during
        adipocyte differentiation was associated with C/EBPα
        activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gadd45</TIMEX> (growth arrest and
        DNA damage-inducible gene <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gas2 and gas3</TIMEX> (growth
        arrest-associated genes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6 38 39</NUMEX> ] . However,
        C/EBPα mutants defective in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding still blocked
        proliferation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 33</NUMEX> ] . This suggested that direct
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter activation</ENAMEX> was unnecessary, or redundant, for
        C/EBPα proliferation arrest [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        Possible mechanisms of transcription-independent
        proliferation arrest by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> have been suggested by a
        number of studies. Decreased proliferation was associated
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> stabilization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p21 protein</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 24</NUMEX> ] .
        p21 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interacted</ENAMEX> directly with a large internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> of
        C/EBPα that included transcription activation domain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
        ] (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). CDK2 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CDK4</ENAMEX> also interacted with
        segments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> close to, and within, transcription
        activation domain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . CDK2 also interacted with the
        basic region of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . p21 also has a second
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX> site, within the leucine zipper of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
        ] . 
        in vitro, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> enhanced p21
        inhibition of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CDK2</TIMEX> activity. C/EBPα inhibition of CDK2
        activity correlated with p21 binding to C/EBPα
        transcription activation domain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . However,
        proliferation arrest by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> still occurred in cell lines
        not containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p21 genes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . This indicated that
        proliferation arrest by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> did not rely solely upon
        C/EBPα enhancement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDK</ENAMEX> inhibition by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p21</TIMEX>.
        Another mechanism reported for proliferation blockage by
        C/EBPα involves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-DP1</ENAMEX> transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>. E2F
        complexes activate genes required for entry into S phase.
        C/EBPα binds to and inhibits transcriptional activation by
        E2F [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 33</NUMEX> ] . The complex of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">E2F</TIMEX> with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma</ENAMEX>-related p107 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is prevalent in cycling
        cells. Transcription activation domain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> was
        observed to interact specifically with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p107</NUMEX> to disrupt
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p107/E2F</ENAMEX> complex formation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX> ] . Disruption of E2F
        activity also was associated the basic domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34</NUMEX> ] .
        Thus, a variety of interactions and mechanisms are
        potentially involved in proliferation arrest by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>.
        This variability may indicate divergent mechanisms for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> of proliferation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> in different study
        conditions and/or cell types. In pituitary cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> is
        part of a multi-subunit complex [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41 42</NUMEX> ] that activates
        the growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] and prolactin [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44</NUMEX> ]
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Full-length C/EBPα</ENAMEX> is absent from the pituitary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progenitor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cell line [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 45</NUMEX> ] in which ectopically
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">expressed C/EBPα</ENAMEX> activates co-transfected growth hormone
        and prolactin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 44 45</NUMEX> ] . We show here that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ectopically</ENAMEX> expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα prolongs GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cells in the
        G1 and S phases of the cell cycle in a
        transcription-independent fashion. Different <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> domains
        were required for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">G1</NUMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-phase</ENAMEX> arrest. C/EBPα domains
        previously described for the interaction with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p21</TIMEX> were not
        required for arrest in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells. Rather, domains
        previously implicated in the regulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the E2F</TIMEX> and CDK2
        pathways by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> were required for arrest of these
        progenitor cells.
      
      
        Results
        
          Transcriptionally active and inactive GFP fusions
          with C/EBPα
          The domains of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> and their known interactions
          with cell-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are summarized in figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1A</TIMEX>. We
          conducted studies to determine which, if any, of those
          activities affect the proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> pituitary
          progenitor cells. In prior studies, we noticed that fewer
          cells were present in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cell cultures transfected
          with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> expression vector than in cultures
          transfected with control vectors (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X. Wang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. S.</ENAMEX>,
          unpublished data). The decreased cell number might be due
          to impaired proliferation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells expressing
          C/EBPα. To examine if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> affected the progression of
          GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells through the cell cycle, we needed to
          distinguish transfected cells that expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> from
          those that did not. We fused the cDNA for the green
          fluorescence <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (GFP) to either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX>)
          or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX>) end of the coding sequence of the
          C/EBPα cDNA. The cDNAs for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-</ENAMEX>GFP
          fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were inserted into an expression vector
          and transfected into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells. Flow cytometry was
          used to specifically identify green fluorescent,
          C/EBPα-expressing cells.
          We initially characterized the abilities of the
          C/EBPα-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> to bind <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and
          activate transcription in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The
          C/EBPα-GFP or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> expression vectors were
          transfected into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells with a promoter consisting
          of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> binding site upstream of the growth
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hormone TATA box</ENAMEX>. This minimal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> was specifically
          responsive to C/EBPα expression in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45 46</NUMEX>
          ] . Cells transfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> expression
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> showed a statistically significant (p<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.05</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> =
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.66</NUMEX> +/- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.08</NUMEX>-fold higher promoter activity than did
          cells sham-transfected with the same expression vector
          deleted of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> cDNA (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A). In contrast,
          activation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> was a statistically
          insignificant <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.88</NUMEX> +/- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.48</NUMEX>-fold (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A). Promoter
          activation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> was reproducibly less than
          promoter activation by unfused <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blots</ENAMEX> of
          nuclear extracts from the transfected cells showed that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unfused</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> was expressed at marginally higher levels
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B).
          C/EBPα-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> both were expressed as
          intact, full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> of the appropriate molecular
          weight [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B, arrow). In addition, both
          C/EBPα-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> bound similarly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DNA (Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2C). Extracts of cells expressing either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> shifted the electrophoretic mobility of a
          radiolabeled oligonucleotide containing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> binding
          site (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C). No shift was observed with
          sham-transfected cells (not shown). The shifted bands
          were specifically competed by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-fold molar excess of
          the cold oligonucleotide and were supershifted with an
          antibody directed against <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> truncated of
          its leucine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zipper</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B) was ineffective at shifting
          the binding site (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ΔLZ</NUMEX>). Flow cytometry
          (discussed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>) showed that comparable levels of green
          fluorescence were emitted from cells expressing
          C/EBPα-GFP, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> and ΔLZ. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> were expressed and could bind to C/EBPα
          binding sites in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, but differed in their ability to
          activate gene transcription.
        
        
          Cell cycle distribution of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells
          Transcriptionally active <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> and
          transcriptionally inactive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> were compared for
          their effects on proliferation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells. We first
          determined the distribution of untransfected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-5
          cells in each phase of the cell cycle. GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells were
          grown to subconfluence, collected and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> within the
          cells was stained with propidium iodide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> content
          within each cell was quantified by flow cytometry as the
          amount of orange <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluorescence</ENAMEX> from the propidium
          iodide-stained <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Materials and Methods for</ENAMEX>
          details). The fluorescence intensity measured from each
          cell falls into one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>: cells centered
          around the lowest level of orange <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fluorescence</ENAMEX>, cells
          centered around the highest level of orange fluorescence
          which is twice that of the lowest, and cells with
          intermediate levels of orange <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">fluorescence</ENAMEX>. This
          corresponds, respectively, to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> containing a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">2n</NUMEX> DNA
          complement prior to duplication of the genome (in G1
          phase), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> containing a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">4n DNA complement</ENAMEX> following
          genome duplication (in growth phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or in mitosis,
          G2<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/M</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> containing a partially replicated genome
          intermediate between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2n and 4n</TIMEX> (in S phase). As averaged
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> independent experiments, the proportion of
          growing GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G2/M</ENAMEX> corresponded to
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38% and 20%</NUMEX>, respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 3</ENAMEX>, white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX>).
          We next synchronized GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells in particular
          stages of the cell cycle. GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells were treated for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 hours</TIMEX> with nocodazole, which prevents microtubule
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">polymerization/depolymerization</ENAMEX> and exit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> phase [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47</NUMEX> ] . The delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>, was added to parallel
          cell cultures. Cells also were treated with mimosine (in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>), which <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks cells</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late G1</TIMEX> immediately before
          entry into S phase [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mimosine</ENAMEX> also prolongs some
          cell types in the S phase itself [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] . GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells
          grow with an average doubling time of approximately <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> to
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 hours</TIMEX> of treatment allowed most cells to
          pass through one cell cycle and to accumulate as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4n</NUMEX> cells
          upon nocodazole treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, light gray bars) or as
          2n cells at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G1/S</ENAMEX> boundary upon mimosine treatment
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, stippled gray bars). Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cells can be
          synchronized at particular stages of the cell cycle.
          Synchronization facilitated characterization of the cell
          cycle stages blocked or prolonged by C/EBPα
          expression.
        
        
          Transcriptionally active and inactive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> both
          retain GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G1</TIMEX> and S phases of the cell
          cycle
          We determined if either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX>
          altered the distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G1</TIMEX>, S or
          G2<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/M</ENAMEX> phases of the cell cycle. GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells were
          transfected with the expression vectors for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX>, or with the sham expression vector not
          containing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> cDNA. The cells were incubated for
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> to allow time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> expression. Cells were
          then synchronized in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M-</ENAMEX>phase or in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G1/S</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-hour</TIMEX>
          incubations with nocodazole (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A) or mimosine (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          4B). Cells were collected and stained with propidium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iodide</ENAMEX>. Flow cytometry was used to measure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> content in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) cells transfected with the sham expression vector
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sham</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) green fluorescent cells expressing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GFP-tagged C/EBPα</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX>) or
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) the subpopulation of cells from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> transfections that did not express measurable
          amounts of green fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, No C/EBP).
          The "No <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP</ENAMEX>" cells represent an internal control for
          cells not expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> collected simultaneously with
          cells expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>. The No C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBP</ENAMEX> controls also
          indicated the extent to which green fluorescent,
          C/EBPα-expressing cells were distinguished from
          non-expressing cells by flow cytometry. For all our
          experiments, the distribution of cells in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and
          G2<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/M</ENAMEX> phases was similar for the "No <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> " and
          sham-transfected cells.
          The expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> resulted in
          a statistically significant decrease in the amount of
          cells blocked in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G2/M</ENAMEX> upon nocodazole treatment compared
          to sham-transfected cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A) (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><< 0.01</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> =
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). This indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> expression prevented a
          significant proportion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells from reaching
          G2<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/M</ENAMEX> to be blocked by nocodazole. When cells were blocked
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> by mimosine treatment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> expression caused no
          decrease in the proportion of cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G2/M</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B).
          This demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> expression did not actively
          decrease the proportion of cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G2/M.</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>-induced reduction in cells blocked in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G2/M</ENAMEX>
          was associated with a highly statistically significant
          increase in the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> pituitary
          progenitor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>) and a statistically
          significant increase in the proportion of cells in S
          phase (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.03</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A). This retention of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-5
          cells in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G1</TIMEX> and S phases of the cell cycle occurred
          for both the transcriptionally active <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inactive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> fusions. The independence of
          C/EBPα-induced proliferation arrest from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-</ENAMEX>regulated
          transcriptional activation also has been observed in
          other studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] . Thus, simple transcription
          activation mechanisms do not account for the effect of
          C/EBPα on the cell cycle.
        
        
          Targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> to the presumed centromeric
          G1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">checkpoint</ENAMEX> is insufficient for prolongation of
          G1
          Our prior fluorescence microscopy studies showed that
          C/EBPα-GFP, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>-stained <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> ] , concentrated at specific intranuclear domains in
          GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX>). These domains
          coincide with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> that stain with the blue
          fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-binding dye <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX> 33342 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst 33342</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX> 33342 stains AT-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> that
          concentrates around the centromeres [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45 49</NUMEX> ] . Given the
          role of the centromere as a checkpoint for regulation of
          the mitotic phase of the cell cycle [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 51</NUMEX> ] , it was
          hypothesized that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> localization around the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centromere</ENAMEX> could play a role in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> regulation of the
          cell cycle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] .
          To investigate if targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> to the
          peri-centromeric chromatin is necessary or sufficient to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cause</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G1</ENAMEX> and S phase prolongation in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells, we
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> determined the domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> required to target
          C/EBPα to the peri-centromeric chromatin. It was
          previously suggested that the peri-centromeric targeting
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> was a function of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA binding</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> binding
          sites are concentrated within the repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequences
          that comprise the bulk of peri-centromeric chromatin [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>
          ] . Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> truncated to contain little more than
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding, bZIP domain still concentrated at
          peri-centromeric chromatin [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . By contrast, C/EBPα
          deleted of amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">310 to 358</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ΔLZ</NUMEX>) no
          longer targeted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peri-centromeric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DNA (Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B).
          This deletion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">disrupts DNA</ENAMEX> binding (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C) by
          eliminating the leucine zipper required for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding
          by all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the bZIP <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of transcription
          factors [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] . Thus, as predicted [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] , the bZIP
          domain is necessary and sufficient for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> targeting
          to peri-centromeric chromatin.
          When expressed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells, ΔLZ was as effective
          as full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> in prolonging both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">G1</ENAMEX> and S
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6A). Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leucine zipper dimerization</ENAMEX>,
          site-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA binding</ENAMEX> and targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> to
          peri-centromeric were not required for C/EBPα
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prolongation</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> and S. In contrast, the isolated
          C/EBPα bZIP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding domain (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX>), which
          still targeted to peri-centromeric chromatin, did not
          prolong G1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6B). S phase remained prolonged upon DBD
          expression. The different effects of the isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> on
          G1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">blockage</ENAMEX> indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> regulation of G1
          and S phase arrest was mechanistically distinct. Thus,
          C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBPα</ENAMEX> regulates proliferation by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct pathways.
          Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> do not depend upon site-specific DNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX>, which is commonly considered a prerequisite for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>-specific transcription.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prolongation</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> requires the amino terminal
          domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPα
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα DBD</ENAMEX> therefore was insufficient for
          prolongation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6B). We next determined which
          additional domains of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> were required for G1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prolongation</ENAMEX>. C/EBPα amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-154</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">154-257</ENAMEX> were
          appended to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B). The addition of amino
          significant increase, relative to sham-transfected cells,
          in the proportion of cells in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><< 0.01</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> =
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). The proportion of cells in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> was not statistically
          different in cells expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-154 from that in
          cells expressing full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX>. Adding amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">acids 1-125</ENAMEX>, instead of amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-154</ENAMEX>, caused a
          similar prolongation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX>). Thus,
          an element in the amino terminal domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> was
          required for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> prolongation.
          In contrast, addition of amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">154-257</ENAMEX> to C/EBPα
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> did not rescue G1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prolongation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> +
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">154-257</ENAMEX>). Again, appending amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-125</ENAMEX> to this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mutant restored G1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">prolongation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">A126-153</ENAMEX>), as did amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">acids 1-97</ENAMEX> (A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-153</NUMEX>). All of the mutants contained the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> and prolonged the cell cycle in S phase (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>).
          Thus, the DNA binding, bZIP domain was sufficient to
          direct S phase regulation by C/EBPα whereas amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-97</TIMEX> contained a domain required for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> regulation.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
          C<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/EBPα prolongs GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cells in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> and S
          The differentiative and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-mitotic</ENAMEX> actions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPα
          have been observed in a variety of cell culture models [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24 26 40 53</NUMEX> ] . To date, studies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> block
          of proliferation have relied on comparing the growth [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25 40</NUMEX> ] or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> synthetic [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 24 25 26 27</NUMEX> ] rates of
          C/EBPα-expressing and non-expressing cells. These studies
          suggest that multiple, possibly independent, mechanisms
          may contribute to C/EBPα arrest in a variety of cells [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 23 24 25 26 33 34 35 36 37 40 54 55 56</NUMEX> ] . Studies
          that distinguish the anti-proliferative actions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPα
          at different phases of the cell cycle, and in specific
          cell types, may clarify these discrepancies.
          Our studies showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> expression prolonged
          the proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> pituitary progenitor cells
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different phases of the cell cycle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> has been reported previously in
          C/EBPα-expressing mouse L cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . However, those
          studies did not define the activities within C/EBPα
          required for that blockage. Here, we observed that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prolongation</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> required the amino terminal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">97</TIMEX> amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acids</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>.). In contrast, amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids 1</ENAMEX> to
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX> were not required for S phase arrest (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Figs. 6, 7</ENAMEX>).
          This showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> prolongation of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> and S phases occurred through molecularly distinct
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX>. Such distinct effects on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> may
          contribute to the wide variations in mechanisms reported,
          to date, to participate in proliferation arrest by
          C/EBPα.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Cycle Proteins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα Inhibition</ENAMEX> of
          Proliferation
          Candidate mechanisms for the block of proliferation by
          C/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">EBPα</ENAMEX> include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) activation of the gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor</ENAMEX> p21 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gadd45</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gas2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gas3</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38 39</NUMEX> ] , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) post-transcriptional
          stabilization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p21</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] , or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) interactions of
          C/EBPα with cell cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> including p21 [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 24 25</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CDK2</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 36</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CDK4</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX>
          ] , the retinoblastoma-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> p107 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] and
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G1/S</ENAMEX>-regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E2F</ENAMEX> transcription complex [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 33</NUMEX> ]
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). We found that transcriptional activation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">domain 3</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">leucine zipper</ENAMEX> were not required for
          prolongation of either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G1</ENAMEX> or S (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fig 7</ENAMEX>). These domains
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">interact with p21</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CDK2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CDK4</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 24 25 36 55</NUMEX> ] .
          Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> interactions with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least p21 and CDK4</TIMEX> were
          not required for the anti-proliferative actions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPα
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells. CDK2, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, also interact
          with another domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] required for
          proliferation arrest (discussed below).
          Arrest in S phase was associated with amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> 259
          to 310 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>), which include the basic amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-rich,
          DNA binding region of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>. C/EBPα deleted of the
          leucine zipper dimerization domain, also required for DNA
          binding [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C), was as effective as full-length
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> in prolonging both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6A). Thus,
          DNA binding 
          per se was not required for
          proliferation arrest. The basic region of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> blocks
          the transcriptional activity of E2F by unknown mechanisms
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] and contains another known CDK2-interaction site [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ] . Either of these activities may contribute to basic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">region-dependent</ENAMEX>, S phase arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cell
          proliferation.
          G1 block in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells required <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-97</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>), comprising activation domains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>
          ] . Amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids 1</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX> have been implicated in C/EBPα
          growth arrest via the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">E2F/pl07</ENAMEX> complexes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX> ] .
          C/EBPα interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p107</ENAMEX> is believed to prevent the
          formation of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-phase</ENAMEX> promoting complex containing p107
          and E2F [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 34 35</NUMEX> ] . Thus, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells
          may be related to the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> to interact with
          p107. However, the amino terminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> also
          functionally interacts with a number of other factors [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31 45 46</NUMEX> ] , any of which might contribute to
          proliferation arrest.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subnuclear Architecture</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα Inhibition</ENAMEX> of
          Proliferation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> becomes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with peri-centromeric chromatin upon
          expression during adipocyte differentiation. We observed
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>, expressed in mouse pituitary progenitor
          GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells, also localized to peri-centromeric
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chromatin</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . Here we show that targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPα
          to peri-centromeric chromatin in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GHFT1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells required
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). However,
          C/EBPα deleted of the DNA binding domain was as effective
          as full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> in prolonging <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cells in the
          G1 and S phases of the cell cycle (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6A). Thus, the
          specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> with peri-centromeric
          chromatin, speculated to contribute to C/EBPα growth
          arrest [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] , was not necessary for disruption of the
          cell cycle by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>. The independence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPα
          regulation of proliferation from its intranuclear
          localization may even be necessary since we have recently
          determined that pituitary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell differentiation</ENAMEX> is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the dispersal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> from
          peri-centromeric heterochromatin by the
          pituitary-specific transcription factor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pit-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. F. E.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. A. Kawecki</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. S., R. N. D.</ENAMEX>, submitted).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Transcription-Independent Inhibition</ENAMEX> of
          Proliferation
          Transcription factors, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>, may regulate cell
          proliferation by directly controlling the expression of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> required for cell cycle progression. Indeed,
          C/EBPα activates transcription of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p21</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] , gadd45
          [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gas2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gas3</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38 39</NUMEX> ] genes. However, similar
          levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p21</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> in the livers of wild-type and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homozygous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knock-out mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] argue against a
          physiologically significant contribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> to p21
          gene transcription in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>. We also observed that
          transcriptionally inactive and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-binding-defective
          forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> still blocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cell proliferation
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">both the G1</TIMEX> and S phases of the cell cycle (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Figs. 2,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, 6</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-binding-defective mutants of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> have also
          been observed to block proliferation in other cell lines
          [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 33</NUMEX> ] . Together, this suggests that C/EBPα
          regulation of transcription, in general, might not
          contribute to the regulation of cell proliferation. It
          remains possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> activation of the
          transcription of some cell cycle regulatory genes does
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> proliferation in some cell types or under certain
          conditions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 37 38 39 56</NUMEX> ] .
          The absence of a dependence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cell
          proliferation on transcription factor activities that are
          more classically associated with transcription regulation
          strongly suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>, and perhaps other
          transcription factors, control proliferation and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> through completely separable pathways. The
          effects of human papilloma virus E7 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> on
          C/EBPα-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">differentiation</ENAMEX> and growth arrest also
          suggest that the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> on proliferation are
          mechanistically divergent [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . Having distinct
          mechanisms for regulation of gene transcription and
          proliferation allows a transcription factor to regulate
          these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> critical processes completely independently of
          one another. This may be particularly important in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">differentiated</ENAMEX>, non-proliferating cells in which events
          that regulate a transcription factor's contribution to
          gene expression must be disconnected from that
          transcription factor's continuing blockage of
          proliferation.
        
      
      
        Conclusions
        C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBPα</ENAMEX> is a transcription factor that controls both
        proliferation and gene expression. C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBPα</ENAMEX> uses molecularly
        distinct mechanisms to prolong the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> and S phases of
        pituitary progenitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cells. The anti-proliferative
        effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> do not require activities in C/EBPα
        commonly required for gene-specific transcription.
        Proliferation arrest instead corresponds with C/EBPα
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">domains</ENAMEX> previously implicated in post-transcriptional
        effects on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">E2F</TIMEX> and/or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CDK2</TIMEX> activity.
      
      
        
          Plasmid construction
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> vector was constructed by inserting the
          cDNA encoding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the S65T</TIMEX> derivative of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX> ] at the
          start codon of the cDNA encoding rat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>. The fused
          cDNA was cloned into a previously described expression
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> portions of the fusion
          were separated by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> long linker including
          the epitope for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FLAG antibody</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> vector
          was constructed by inserting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the S65T</TIMEX> GFP into the NcoI
          site present near the carboxy terminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> C/EBPα
          (also tagged at the amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">terminus</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">FLAG epitope</ENAMEX>)
          in our previously described <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> expression vector [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
          ] . This resulted in a deletion of the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acids</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">154</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">257</NUMEX> derivatives of
          C/EBPα were constructed by replacing, respectively, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amino</ENAMEX> terminal 257 amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> (to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SgrAI</ENAMEX> site of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>) and the amino terminal 153 amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acids</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX> (to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NotI</ENAMEX> site of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX>) with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oligonucleotides</ENAMEX> containing a strong Kozak sequence. DBD
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+ 1-154</ENAMEX> was constructed by replacing amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids 155</ENAMEX> to
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">257</NUMEX> (from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NotI</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SgrAI</ENAMEX> sites) with an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligonucleotide</ENAMEX>. The remaining constructs (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) were
          generated by appending <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> fragments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NotI</ENAMEX> site
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">154</NUMEX>, or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SgrAI</ENAMEX> site of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX>. ΔLZ was
          constructed by deleting amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> from amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> 310
          (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Tth111II</NUMEX> site) at the junction of the basic region and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leucine zipper</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> to the carboxy terminus of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX> fusion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP-TATA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> used to
          determine the transcriptional activity of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> GFP
          fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> was previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Transfection
          GHFT1-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells were propagated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DME-H21</ENAMEX>) medium supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal calf serum.
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately 1 ×</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 7cells</TIMEX> were transfected by
          electroporation, as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] , with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          μg of either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα-GFP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP-C/EBPα</ENAMEX>, or control
          expression vectors. Following transfection, cells were
          propagated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33°C</TIMEX>. Incubation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33°C</TIMEX> results in
          significantly higher levels of green fluorescence
          (unpublished data), presumably because of better folding
          of the jellyfish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX>. Transfected cells were maintained
          in the dark throughout the experiment to minimize
          fluorescence activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> prior to flow
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytometry</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DNA Binding</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promoter Activation</ENAMEX>
          Electrophoretic mobility shifts assays were done by
          mixing a radiolabeled oligonucleotide containing a
          consensus, high affinity <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP</ENAMEX> binding site
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATCGAGCCCCATTGCGCAATCATAGATC</ENAMEX>) together with extracts
          prepared from transfected cells as previously described [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58 59</NUMEX> ] . Competition with the same, unlabeled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligonucleotide</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 or 100</NUMEX> molar excess of the
          radiolabeled probed indicated specific binding. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein DNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was supershifted with an antibody
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>,
          sc-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX>). For studies of the transcriptional activation
          properties of the fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 μg</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP-TATA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] was co-transfected and transcriptional
          activity was assessed by measuring the amount of
          chloramphenicol acetyltransferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> expressed with
          and without <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Fluorescence Microscopy
          Following transfection, most cells were plated into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
          cm dishes and allowed to grow for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>. This ensured
          that the cells were not confluent by the time of
          collection for cell cycle analysis. A small portion of
          the transfected cells were cultivated on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 × 22</NUMEX> mm No.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> borosilicate glass cover slip in a separate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well dish
          and treated with nocodazole, mimosine or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> alone as
          described below. The coverslips were removed for
          fluorescence microscopic observation immediately before
          collecting cells for flow cytometric analysis of DNA
          content and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> expression. Cells were stained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-20</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 </NUMEX>g/ml of the cell-permeable DNA binding
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dye Hoechst</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33342</NUMEX>. The green fluorescence emitted from
          C/EBPα tagged with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> and the blue fluorescence emitted
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33342</NUMEX>-stained <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> were readily distinguished
          by selectively exciting each fluorophore and capturing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluorescence</ENAMEX> emissions specific for each fluorophore
          using appropriate excitation and emission filter sets
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chroma Technology Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brattelboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VT</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] .
          The images shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5were acquired using an Olympus
          40X <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PlanApochromat</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.95</NUMEX> numerical aperture) objective on
          an Olympus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IX</NUMEX>-70 microscope. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metamorph</ENAMEX> acquisition
          software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Imaging Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Downingtown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>)
          on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orca</ENAMEX> cooled interline camera (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamamatsu</ENAMEX>,
          Bridgewater, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) were used to collect the images.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-transfection Cell Synchronization</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPα</ENAMEX> fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were expressed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
          following transfection, after which we added to the cell
          culture media <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml nocodazole (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dimethylsulphoxide</ENAMEX> (DMSO), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM mimosine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>, or DMSO <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. In some experiments, cells were
          also grown for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48 and 72 hours</TIMEX> post-transfection before
          applying nocodazole (data not shown). The distributions
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G2/M</ENAMEX>, in the presence or absence of
          C/EBPα expression, were similar for cells grown for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          (reported here), <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 or 72 hours</TIMEX> (data not shown) prior to
          nocodazole addition. Following nocodazole, mimosine or
          DMSO addition, the transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHFT1-5</ENAMEX> cells continued to
          be cultivated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33°C</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Flow Cytometry
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> or vehicle treatment, transfected
          cells were trypsinized, collected in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DME-H21</ENAMEX> media
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal calf serum, and washed twice with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. The harvested cells (typically <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 × 10 6to 1 × 10</ENAMEX>
          7cells) were resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 μl</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8 μg/ml propidium</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iodide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 </NUMEX>g/ml RNAse A, then incubated at room temperature
          in the dark for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> suspension was then
          analyzed on a FACScan flow cytometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>)
          at a flow rate of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12 </NUMEX>l/min. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fluorescence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> and
          propidium iodide-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was excited with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">488</NUMEX> nm
          argon-ion laser. Green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> fluorescence was collected
          using a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">530/30</NUMEX>-nm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> pass filter, and orange emission
          from propidium iodide-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was detected using a
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">585/42</NUMEX>-nm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> pass filter. Photomultiplier tube voltage
          and spectral compensation were initially set using
          single-stained cells (cells expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> fusions with
          C/EBPα but not stained with propidium iodide and cells
          transfected with the control vector containing no GFP
          cDNA but stained with propidium iodide). Electronic
          compensation was adjusted among the fluorescence channels
          to remove residual spectral overlap. The area and width
          of each event were measured to discriminate intact single
          cells from debris and from doublet or multiple cells
          stuck together. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> fluorescence and propidium
          iodide-stained <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA fluorescence</ENAMEX> was thus collected from
          single cells. A minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> cellular events was
          collected for each sample. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> was analyzed using
          CELLQuest software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickenson</ENAMEX>), and cell cycle
          subset analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA histograms</ENAMEX> were performed using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ModFitLT™</ENAMEX> software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verity Software House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Topsham</ENAMEX>,
          ME).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          One-way analysis of variance was used to compare data
          from multiple independent experiments. Statistically
          significant differences (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">**</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>; *, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>
          compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sham</ENAMEX>-transfected cells) and experiment
          number are indicated in the figures and legends. All
          significant differences were confirmed by paired,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-tailed t-tests.
        
      

      
        List of abbreviations
        C<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/EBPα CCAAT/Enhancer Binding Protein</ENAMEX> alpha
        G1 Growth phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of the cell cycle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S DNA Synthesis</ENAMEX> phase of the cell cycle
        G2 Growth phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> of the cell cycle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M Mitsosis</ENAMEX> phase of the cell cycle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDK Cyclin</ENAMEX>-Dependent Kinase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP Green Fluorescent Protein</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GFP-C/EBPα Fusion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> attached to the amino
        terminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPα
        C<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/EBPα-GFP Fusion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFP</ENAMEX> attached to the
        carboxy terminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPα
        Δ Symbol signifying "deletion" when naming
        constructs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LZ Leucine Zipper</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DBD DNA Binding Domain</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX> Dimethyl Sulfoxide
      
    
  
