
  
    
      
        Background
        
        Yersinia pestis , the causative agent
        of bubonic plague, harbors a large virulence <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plasmid</ENAMEX> that
        is essential for pathogenicity. This plasmid, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pCD1</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ] in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis , encodes for a type III
        secretion apparatus necessary for the translocation of
        effector <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX>) into eukaryotic target cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ]
        . The net result of this polarized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin translocation</ENAMEX> is
        the disruption of eukaryotic cell signalling and structure
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Induction of the virulence-related genes on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pCD1</TIMEX> is
        linked to an in vitro phenomenon termed the Low Calcium
        Response (LCR). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LCR</ENAMEX> is believed to mimic the response
        of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis in contact with eukaryotic
        cells when calcium ions are removed from the growth medium
        at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. The result of this in vitro induction of virulence
        genes is the massive secretion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> into the growth
        medium, accompanied by a characteristic growth restriction
        that is a hallmark phenotype of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LCR</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] .
        Secretion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> by the type III secretion system is
        not constitutive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> of secretion is complex and
        involves several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that positively and negatively
        regulate the activity of the secretion apparatus in
        response to environmental conditions [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> has been
        implicated in blocking the secretion apparatus either
        directly or indirectly [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , as strains lacking 
        lcrG constitutively secrete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
        ] , regardless of inducing conditions. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">YopN</ENAMEX>,
        TyeA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SycN, YscB, LcrH, YopD</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrQ</ENAMEX> are all also
        required for the negative regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretion</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>) is
        thought to positively regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yops</ENAMEX> secretion as 
        lcrV strains do not secrete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yops</ENAMEX>,
        even under conditions that normally favor secretion [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19</NUMEX>
        ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> have been demonstrated to physically
        interact in the bacterial cytoplasm [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . Disruption of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LcrG-LcrV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interaction</ENAMEX> or overexpression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> in a
        low-LcrV background both result in a constitutive blockage
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretion</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 20</NUMEX> ] . This evidence led to a model
        of how these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> may control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> secretion. The
        LcrG-titration model theorizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LcrG</ENAMEX> blocks the
        secretion apparatus (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ysc</ENAMEX>) from the bacterial cytoplasm and
        that interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> is required to relieve the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockage</ENAMEX>. Upon induction by eukaryotic cell contact or
        removal of calcium from the growth medium, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intracellular</ENAMEX> level of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrV</ENAMEX> becomes elevated relative to
        that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX>. The increased amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> removes LcrG
        from its secretion-blocking role, resulting in full
        induction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LCR</ENAMEX> and secretion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX>. Evidence
        accumulated to date clearly demonstrates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrG</ENAMEX>-LcrV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX> is critical for the regulation of this complex
        virulence system [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 20</NUMEX> ] . Therefore, dissection of the
        LcrG-LcrV interaction is warranted.
        Utilizing yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid analyses, we further
        investigated the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LcrG-LcrV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interaction</ENAMEX>. We determined that
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus of LcrG</ENAMEX> is essential for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> interaction.
        The smallest linear region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> required for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX> is predicted to form a coiled-coil motif, a
        structure often associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interactions</ENAMEX>. We used both alanine-scanning and a 'radical'
        site-directed mutagenesis strategy to identify amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
        critical for the interaction within this region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX>.
        While alanine mutants failed to disrupt the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrG</ENAMEX>-LcrV
        interaction, radical mutations of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> revealed a
        region important for the interaction. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> are
        likely to reside on the same face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> if a
        coiled-coil structure is assumed. Based on this evidence,
        we predict that the interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> occurs
        within an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal coiled-coil domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrG</ENAMEX> via
        hydrophobic interactions.
        Additionally, we investigated whether the 
        Pseudomonas homolog of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG, PcrG</ENAMEX>,
        could transcomplement an 
        lcrG strain of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis . The opportunistic
        pathogen 
        Pseudomonas aeruginosa utilizes a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">type III</ENAMEX> secretion system for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">intracellular</TIMEX> delivery of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toxins</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22 23</NUMEX> ] that is the most similar to the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yersinia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . Several
        components of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pseudomonas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> have been
        demonstrated to functionally complement genetic defects in
        the 
        Yersinia homologs including the LcrV
        homolog, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PcrV</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25</NUMEX> ] . Homologs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrV</ENAMEX> (i.e.,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrV</ENAMEX>) have only been identified in 
        P. aeruginosa, suggesting that this
        pair of regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> may fulfill similar roles in
        these extracellular pathogens. In the present study, we
        found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> could not substitute for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX>, although
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> interacted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. This result led to a
        genetic selection for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> variants that could
        transcomplement an 
        lcrG defect. Isolation of a PcrG
        variant that could substitute for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> led to the
        identification of a region within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> that may be involved
        in blocking the activity of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis type III secretion
        system.
      
      
        Results and Discussion
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Delineation of the LcrV-interaction</ENAMEX> domain of
          LcrG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> physically interact in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , and that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interaction</ENAMEX> plays a significant role in the regulation of
          Yops secretion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> interact in a yeast
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">assay</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , therefore this technique was
          used to further investigate the region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> required
          for its interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Truncations of LcrG</ENAMEX> were
          constructed and fused to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GAL4</NUMEX> activation domain of
          pACT2. These plasmids were co-transformed into yeast
          strain Y187 with full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrV</ENAMEX> fused to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GAL4</NUMEX> DNA
          binding domain of plasmid <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pAS2-1</ENAMEX> to determine if the LcrG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">truncations</ENAMEX> could continue to participate in an
          interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. Using a filter-lift assay as a
          qualitative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of an interaction and a liquid
          β-galactosidase assay to quantify the results, we found
          that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrV</ENAMEX>-interaction domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> lies in the
          N-terminus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. The smallest linear region of
          LcrG that was still capable of interacting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> was
          determined to be amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-40</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; shown
          highlighted in yellow in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Deletion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
          additional amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7-40</NUMEX>
          construct or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-40</ENAMEX> construct eliminated our ability to detect an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX> using this system (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Interestingly,
          this approximate region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-35</ENAMEX>) is
          predicted to form a coiled-coil domain when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrG</ENAMEX> is
          analyzed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">COILS algorithm</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] (data not
          shown). These results suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrG</ENAMEX>-LcrV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX> requires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus of LcrG</ENAMEX> and may
          involve a coiled-coil domain.
        
        
          Alanine-scanning mutagenesis of the LcrG
          N-terminus
          To determine individual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> required for
          interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>, a systematic site-directed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutagenesis</ENAMEX> strategy was used to change conserved or
          charged <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> within the delineated interaction
          region. Initially, alanine-scanning mutagenesis was used
          for this study as alanine substitutions are generally
          thought to minimally effect protein folding [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
          Sequence conservation from the alignment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> with the
          
          Pseudomonas aeruginosa homolog,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), allowed the targeting of specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>
          likely to be important for the interaction. After
          construction of specific missense mutants, each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">full-length LcrG</ENAMEX> alanine variant was screened for
          interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> using the yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">assay</ENAMEX>.
          Surprisingly, the alanine-scanning mutagenesis results
          failed to demonstrate amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> of LcrG involved in the
          LcrG-LcrV interaction. All of the alanine mutants
          screened were capable of interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> as
          demonstrated in a filter-lift assay. Liquid
          β-galactosidase assays showed that the strength of the
          interactions were not significantly reduced from that of
          wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). These results showed that
          single alanine substitutions are insufficient to disrupt
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LcrG-LcrV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interaction</ENAMEX>. A likely explanation for the
          failure of alanine-scanning to reveal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> in LcrG
          important for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> interaction is that alanine is a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> capable of interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydrophobic residues</ENAMEX>.
          Our subsequent studies suggest that the interaction of
          LcrG with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> occurs at a hydrophobic patch within
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Radical</ENAMEX>' site-directed mutagenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> allows
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG-LcrV</ENAMEX> interaction to be disrupted
          Based on our experience with the alanine-scanning
          combined with the similar results of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francis et</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
          ] , it seemed likely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LcrG-LcrV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interaction</ENAMEX> was
          occurring between hydrophobic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>. Accordingly, we
          continued to examine the interaction domain using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutagenesis</ENAMEX> strategy described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX> termed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'radical</ENAMEX>' site-directed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mutagenesis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . This method
          involves replacing hydrophobic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> with charged
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residues</ENAMEX>, or changing charged <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> to oppositely
          charged <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>. This method was used to mutagenize
          several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">conserved residues</ENAMEX> in the interacting region in
          the effort to disrupt the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LcrG-LcrV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interaction</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). These 'radical' site-directed mutants were then
          screened using the yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid system for their
          interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. Radical mutagenesis revealed
          several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> with decreased β-galactosidase activity
          in the yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hybrid system</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LcrG mutants A16R</ENAMEX>,
          A16D, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S23R</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">L30R</NUMEX> all had significantly decreased
          activity when assayed for β-galactosidase expression
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). LcrG mutants <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">I20R</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A27E</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">I37R</TIMEX> demonstrated
          somewhat decreased activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). These results
          suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues A16</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S23</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">L30</TIMEX> (red asterisks
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) all participate in the interaction of LcrG
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues I20</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A27</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">I37</ENAMEX> may also
          contribute to the interaction. Of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> identified
          in these experiments, only changes to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A16</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S23</TIMEX>, and L30
          were detected with a more sensitive filter-lift assay for
          β-galactosidase activity and were therefore chosen for
          further characterization.
          The alanine at position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> was previously identified
          as a critical residue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LcrG-LcrV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interaction</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ]
          . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> mutations were characterized at this position (A16R
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A16D</ENAMEX>) and they failed to interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>, showing
          that single substitutions of this kind can disrupt the
          LcrG-LcrV interaction [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . Additional data from this
          study showed that a substitution of the leucine at
          position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> with an arginine also prevented the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrG</ENAMEX>-LcrV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Interestingly, when L30
          is replaced with alanine (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>) or threonine (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), the interaction is not effected. Mutagenesis of the
          serine at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> to arginine resulted in an LcrG
          variant that weakly interacted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> as determined by
          a filter-lift assay for β-galactosidase activity. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> change of the yeast <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> due to the hydrolysis
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-bromo-4-chloro-3-indolyl-β-D-galactopyranoside</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-gal) by β-galactosidase was significantly delayed and
          less intense than the reaction we observed for strongly
          interacting mutants. The liquid β-galactosidase assay
          confirmed that the strength of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX>-LcrV
          interaction was reduced (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>), indicating that this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residue</ENAMEX> is likely involved in the interaction of LcrG
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. As coiled-coil motifs show a characteristic
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> repeat pattern, with each repeat
          representing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> turns of the α-helix, it is interesting
          that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> identified as important to the
          LcrG-LcrV interaction (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 23</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>) are each separated
          by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>. When this region was analyzed using
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helical</ENAMEX> wheel projection, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> fall on
          the same face of the helix, which appears to be largely
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hydrophobic</ENAMEX> in nature (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). These results and
          observations further indicate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrG</ENAMEX>-LcrV
          interaction may require the participation of a
          coiled-coil motif and occurs at a largely hydrophobic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interface</ENAMEX>.
          To evaluate the biological significance of the changes
          in interaction seen in the yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid system
          between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L30R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX> and
          L30R were expressed in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lcrG Y.</ENAMEX> pestis where their ability
          to control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> secretion was examined. Neither the S23R
          or the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">L30R</NUMEX> mutant displayed the calcium-independent
          growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phenotype</ENAMEX> previously observed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A16R</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ]
          . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX> displayed a wildtype growth and secretion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenotype</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L30R</ENAMEX> was Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-blind (data not
          shown). To further understand the phenotypes obtained,
          the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L30R</ENAMEX> to interact with LcrV
          was examined in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis . Wild type <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrG</ENAMEX>, LcrG
          S23R, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L30R</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A16R</ENAMEX> were independently
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-expressed with His 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> -tagged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> in a strain of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis deleted for 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lcrGV</ENAMEX> . The cells were French
          pressed and the cleared lysates were applied to Talon
          columns to purify His 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> -tagged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. As previously reported
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> copurified with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A16R</ENAMEX> did not
          copurify with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrV</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 and 12</TIMEX>). When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrG</ENAMEX>
          S23R was coexpressed with His 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> -tagged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrV</ENAMEX>, a small amount was
          recovered in the elution fraction from the column (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, lane 6</ENAMEX>). This result is indicative of a weaker
          interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> than the
          interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wildtype</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. The weaker
          interaction seen in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX> and
          LcrV corresponds with our yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid data for the
          S23R mutant, which showed an interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>, and
          suggests an interaction with decreased affinity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The interaction results for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX> provide an
          explanation for the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX> to confer a Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-independent phenotype like the previously described
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A16R mutant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S23R</ENAMEX> still interacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> and
          therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> can neutralize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrG</ENAMEX>-mediated secretion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX>. In fact, this result is consistent with the fact
          that very low levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> are required to provide LcrG
          function [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L30R</ENAMEX> either interacts weakly with
          or does not interact with His 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> -tagged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, lane 9</ENAMEX>). This
          result also corresponds with the lack of interaction
          observed in the yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">assay</ENAMEX> for this mutant.
          found to be involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG-LcrV</ENAMEX> interaction using
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid analysis are relevant in the bacterial cell.
          However, the inability of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">L30R</NUMEX> to function like our
          previously described A16R mutant was somewhat surprising.
          One explanation is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the L30R</TIMEX> change
          is simply misfolded. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> explanation is that the
          secretion-blocking and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrV</ENAMEX>-interaction domains of
          LcrG overlap. Currently we do not possess the data
          required to differentiate between the two possibilities
          and we are pursuing the reasons for the failure of L30R
          to function like wildtype <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> does not complement an lcrGstrain, but
          interacts with LcrV
          Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> required for interaction
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> are strongly conserved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG of</ENAMEX> 
          P. aeruginosa (red asterisks in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), we determined if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PcrG</ENAMEX> could interact directly
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PcrG-GAL4-AD and LcrV-GAL4-BD</ENAMEX> chimeras
          were coexpressed in a yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">assay</ENAMEX>. Activation
          of β-galactosidase by the chimeric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> was
          demonstrated by a filter-lift assay showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> and
          PcrG interact (data not shown). To determine if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> also interacted in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis , we attempted to
          copurify the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> from bacterial extracts. PcrG
          and His 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">LcrV</ENAMEX> were coexpressed in a 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis strain with 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lcrG</ENAMEX> and 
          lcrV deleted and the cleared
          lysates were applied to a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talon</ENAMEX> column. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> reacts
          weakly with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrG</ENAMEX>, allowing us to detect the
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> on immunoblots. PcrG was present in the
          elution fraction (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A, lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>), indicating that PcrG
          was retained on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Talon</ENAMEX> column. This result
          demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> interact in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis . The interaction of PcrG
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrV</ENAMEX> supports the mutagenesis and sequence data
          indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues conserved</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> and PcrG
          are likely to be important for interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>.
          Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> interacted in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis , the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> to
          complement an 
          lcrG strain of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis was examined. Cultures of
          
          lcrG <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains transcomplemented</ENAMEX> with
          either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LcrG</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> were grown in the presence and
          absence of calcium and harvested after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> of
          growth at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. Culture supernatants were examined for
          the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">secreted proteins</ENAMEX> by immunoblotting for
          LcrV, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">YopE</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YopM</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5Bshows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> expression
          blocked secretion in this strain in the presence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">calcium</ENAMEX> and allowed secretion in its absence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">lanes 3</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). However, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PcrG</ENAMEX> was expressed,
          secretion was not blocked in either the presence or
          absence of calcium (calcium-blind phenotype) similar to
          the parent strain (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 and 6</TIMEX>). Therefore,
          while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> is capable of interacting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>, it
          differs from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> in its ability to block secretion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis .
        
        
          Selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> mutants that block
          secretion
          PcrG of 
          P. aeruginosa can interact with
          LcrV, but cannot block secretion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B). This result
          suggested that mutagenesis of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pcrG</ENAMEX> could be used to isolate PcrG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mutants</ENAMEX> capable of blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> secretion in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis . This genetic screen
          allowed the isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> mutants that functioned in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis in a manner
          indistinguishable from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B, compare <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7</TIMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 and 4</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequencing of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> independent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">isolates</ENAMEX> revealed the presence of a phenylalanine to
          leucine change at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> in all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">isolates</ENAMEX>. This result suggests that a region of PcrG
          including amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> is capable of interaction with 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis secretion components and
          suggests that the homologous <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> region is likely to be
          involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrG</ENAMEX>'s secretion-blocking activity.
        
        
          Analysis of the putative secretion-blocking region
          of LcrG
          Change of residue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PcrG</ENAMEX> from phenylalanine to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leucine</ENAMEX> made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> sequence look more like that of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX>. That is, position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> became identical to
          the corresponding LcrG <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">L39</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, boxed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">residues</ENAMEX>). This information suggested that residue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> of
          LcrG was an ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for site-directed mutagenesis
          to disrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX>'s secretion blocking activity.
          Accordingly, the leucine at position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrG</ENAMEX> was
          mutated to both phenylalanine and arginine. Surprisingly,
          neither mutant LcrG <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein L39F</ENAMEX> (data not shown) or L39R
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6B, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 and 6</TIMEX>) effected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> function.
          Subsequent mutagenesis of the phenylalanine at position
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> to arginine resulted in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> mutant (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">F48R,</ENAMEX>
          blue asterisk in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) that was defective for secretion
          blocking activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6B, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 and 8</TIMEX>). Mutation of
          F48 to either alanine or leucine had no effect on the
          function of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">LcrG</ENAMEX> variants, suggesting that the
          hydrophobic nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F48</ENAMEX> is important for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> function.
          The expression level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F48R</ENAMEX> from our
          plasmid constructs were also analyzed in whole cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extracts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F48R</ENAMEX> was expressed as well as wild type
          LcrG, demonstrating that its inability to block secretion
          is not due to a change in the expression or stability of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6A, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-4</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-8</ENAMEX>). An interesting
          point to note is that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skrzypek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straley</ENAMEX> deleted
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residues</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39-53</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> (highlighted in blue in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>),
          they obtained a mutant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that did not block Yops
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F48R mutant</ENAMEX>, like the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Δ39-53</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mutant</ENAMEX>, interacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrV</ENAMEX> (data not shown and [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] ),
          demonstrating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> likely folds in a native
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conformation</ENAMEX>. Additionally, the mutant confirms previous
          work that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> known LcrG functions (secretion
          blocking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> interaction) are genetically separable
          [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . Further experiments will more precisely delineate
          the region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> required to block the type III
          secretion apparatus.
        
      
      
        Conclusions
        The interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> is a critical factor
        in controlling the activity of the type III secretion
        system in 
        deeper understanding of this critical interaction, we
        determined the region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> required for interaction with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. Results presented in this study demonstrate that the
        smallest linear region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> required for interaction
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX> is residues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 to 40</TIMEX> (highlighted in yellow in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Interestingly, this region is predicted to form a
        coiled-coil domain. We have identified several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>
        (indicated with red asterisks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) within the
        interacting region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> that contribute to the
        interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrV</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues 7</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> of the protein
        are analyzed with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helical</ENAMEX> wheel projection, these three
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residues</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A16</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S23</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L30</ENAMEX>) appear to lie on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> face of
        an amphipathic helix (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> amino-acid
        periodicity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> is consistent with a
        coiled-coil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein motif</ENAMEX>. These data strongly suggest the
        LcrV-interaction domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> is contained within an
        amphipathic coiled-coil domain. Additionally, we exploited
        the inability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> to block secretion in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis as a point to start mapping
        the region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> required for blocking the type III
        secretion apparatus. We found that mutation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> 42
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PcrG</ENAMEX> (boxed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> to function
        in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis . This information, coupled
        with a previous observation that deletion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">53 within LcrG</ENAMEX> (highlighted in blue in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) abolished
        the secretion-blocking activity [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] , allowed us to
        identify amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> as a residue (blue asterisk in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) required to block the activity of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis type III secretion
        apparatus.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bacterial strains</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX>, and growth
          conditions
          
          Yersinia pestis , 
          Pseudomonas aeruginosa , 
          Escherichia <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coli</ENAMEX> , and 
          Saccharomyces cerevisiae strains
          used are listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis strains were grown in
          heart <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">infusion broth</ENAMEX> or on tryptose blood agar base
          medium (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Difco Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26°C</TIMEX> for
          genetic manipulations. For physiological studies, growth
          of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis was conducted in a
          defined medium, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TMH</ENAMEX>, as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> were grown in
          Luria-Bertani medium or agar [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. When
          appropriate, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> were grown in the presence of
          antibiotics, which were used at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> μg/ml for both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carbenicillin</ENAMEX> and kanamycin.
        
        
          DNA methods and plasmid construction
          Plasmid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was isolated using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QiaPrep Spin</ENAMEX> kit
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Studio City</ENAMEX>, CA). Cloning methods were
          essentially as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . PCR
          fragments were purified using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QiaQuick</ENAMEX> PCR
          purification kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>). Transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> into 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> was accomplished by using
          commercially obtained competent cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>). Electroporation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> into 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y.</ENAMEX> pestis was done as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gene amplification</ENAMEX> was performed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeepVent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Biolabs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) or Taq
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eppendorf Scientific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>) DNA polymerase in a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin-Elmer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GeneAmp Model 2400</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">thermocycler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosystems, Foster City</ENAMEX>, CA).
          Site-directed mutagenesis was performed with 
          PfuTurbo <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> polymerase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA) using the QuikChange
          Site-directed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mutagenesis Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>) according to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions. Complementary
          oligonucleotides were designed to contain the desired
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mutation</ENAMEX>, flanked by unmodified sequence to anneal to the
          same sequence on opposite strands of the template
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX>. Oligonucleotide primers were synthesized by MWG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biotech</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">High Point</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>). pACTG was used as the template
          for all plasmids listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and Table 2</ENAMEX>. pAraG18K
          was used as the template for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pJM99</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pJM131</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pJM143</TIMEX>, and
          pJM144. All mutations were confirmed by sequence analysis
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MWG Biotech</ENAMEX>). The sequences of all mutagenic
          oligonucleotides are available upon request.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plasmids</ENAMEX> used in this study are described in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>.
          All plasmids expressing truncations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pJM1, pJM2,</ENAMEX>
          pJM3, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pJM4</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pJM5</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pJM23</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pJM52</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pJM53</ENAMEX>) were
          constructed by cloning 
          Bam HI- and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nco I-</ENAMEX>cleaved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products into
          pACT2. pJM110 was constructed by cloning a 
          Bam HI- and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I-cleaved PCR</ENAMEX> product of 
          pcrG into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pACT2</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plasmid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pJM127</ENAMEX> was
          constructed by cloning an 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eco</ENAMEX> RI-cleaved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p6roduct</ENAMEX> of 
          pcrG into 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eco</ENAMEX> RI- and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sma I-cleaved pBAD18</ENAMEX>. pJM127 was
          digested with 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eco RI</ENAMEX> and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xba</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> to release a 
          pcrG fragment that was subsequently
          subcloned into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EcoRI</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">XbaI</ENAMEX>-cleaved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pBAD18</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kan</ENAMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">create pJM132.</ENAMEX> The sequences of all oligonucleotide
          primers are available upon request.
          To facilitate the selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> variants that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">functioned to block Yops</ENAMEX> secretion (see below), the
          virulence <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plasmid</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pCD1</TIMEX>, of the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lcrG Y.</ENAMEX> pestis strain KIM8-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3002.7</NUMEX>
          was tagged with a kanamycin resistance cassette to select
          for its presence. pCD1 in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">KIM8</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3002.7</NUMEX> was tagged with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mini-Tn5</ENAMEX> derived transposon EZ::Tn™ <R6Kγori/KAN-2>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epicentre Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX> WI) according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions to obtain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KIM8-3002.7.MN1</ENAMEX>.
          Location of the insertion was not determined but the LCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenotype</ENAMEX> and ability to translocate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HeLa</ENAMEX> cells
          was verified (data not shown).
        
        
          Yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid assays
          Yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">assays</ENAMEX> were performed as recommended
          by the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, CA).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vectors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pAS2-1</ENAMEX> (encoding the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAL4 DNA</ENAMEX> binding domain) and
          pACT2 (encoding the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GAL4</NUMEX> activation domain) were obtained
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech Laboratories</ENAMEX> as part of the Matchmaker
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hybrid System 2 Kit</ENAMEX>. Plasmids were transformed into 
          Saccharomyces cerevisiae strain
          Y187 by using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frozen-EZ Yeast Transformation II</ENAMEX> kit
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zymo</ENAMEX> research, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange</ENAMEX>, CA) and plated on appropriate
          minimal yeast synthetic-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropout medium plates</ENAMEX>. Colony
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filter</ENAMEX>-lift assays to detect β-galactosidase activity
          were performed as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clontech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>.
          Liquid β-galactosidase assays were performed using the
          Yeast β-galactosidase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assay Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>)
          β-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">galactosidase</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX> were calculated as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PcrG</ENAMEX> selection
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Error-prone PCR</ENAMEX> was used to mutagenize 
          pcrG for selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX> variants
          that could block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX> secretion in an 
          lcrG background (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KIM8-3002.7.MN1</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutazyme</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA) was used to amplify
          PcrG for cloning into pBAD18 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . The ligation
          reaction was electroporated into 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lcrG Y.</ENAMEX> pestis (which is
          temperature sensitive due to its Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-blind phenotype)
          and the cells were plated on TMH medium [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] containing
          arabinose, Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+, kanamycin and carbenicillin.
          Transformants that grew at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX> were streak purified and
          checked for phenotype by determining Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-dependence,
          which suggests restoration of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrG</ENAMEX> function" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcrG</ENAMEX>. Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">-dependent strains</ENAMEX> were subsequently used for plasmid
          isolation. Isolated plasmids were re-electroporated into
          an unmutagenized background and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-evaluated for growth at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX> and secretion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yops</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Cell fractionation and affinity purification
          Bacterial cells were fractionated as previously
          described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, bacterial cells were chilled
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> after growth, harvested by centrifugation, and
          washed in cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphate-buffered saline</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>; [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] ).
          Bacterial whole cell fractions were prepared by
          resuspending the washed cells in cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and
          precipitating total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">vol/vol</ENAMEX>)
          trichloroacetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (TCA) on ice <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. Secreted
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were recovered from the bacterial growth medium
          by centrifuging the spent medium a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time,
          transferring the supernatant to a clean tube, and
          precipitating with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">vol/vol</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCA</ENAMEX> on ice <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>.
          The TCA-precipitated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were pelleted by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centrifugation</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,800</NUMEX> × g at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4°C</NUMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min and</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuspended</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2X</TIMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dodecyl sulfate</ENAMEX> (SDS) sample
          buffer [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein extracts</ENAMEX> for
          affinity-purification were prepared by disintegration
          with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> press. Ice-cold yersiniae were resuspended
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and passed through a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> pressure cell
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> psi. Following disintegration, the extracts
          were clarified by centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,800</NUMEX> × g for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> min
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. Affinity purification with His 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LcrV</ENAMEX> was performed using Talon
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>) as described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein electrophoresis</ENAMEX> and immunodetection
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Proteins</ENAMEX> were separated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-polyacrylamide gel
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrophoresis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE), using <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.5 %</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">wt/vol</ENAMEX>)
          polyacrylamide gels according to the method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laemmli</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> ] . Samples were boiled <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3-5 min</TIMEX> before loading on the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gels</ENAMEX>. Samples were loaded such that lanes containing
          different culture fractions represented equivalent
          amounts of the original cultures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proteins</ENAMEX> resolved by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE were transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immobilon</ENAMEX>-P membranes
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millipore Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) using carbonate transfer
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.9</NUMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . Specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were visualized
          using rabbit polyclonal antibodies specific for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glutathione S-transferase</ENAMEX> (GST)-tagged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LcrG (α-LcrG</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          ] , His-tagged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LcrV (α-LcrV</ENAMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YopM (α-YopM</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ]
          , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-tagged LcrQ (α-LcrQ</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">YopN</ENAMEX> (aka <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LcrE</ENAMEX>)
          (α-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LcrE</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] ), His-tagged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">YopD (α-YopD</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , and
          YopE (α-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">YopE</ENAMEX>; gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. C. Straley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KY. Alkaline</ENAMEX> phosphatase-conjugated
          secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (goat anti-rabbit immunoglobulin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>;
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>) was used to visualize <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> by development
          with nitroblue tetrazolium and
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-bromo-4-chloro-3-indolylphosphate</TIMEX> (NBT-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCIP; Fisher</ENAMEX>
          Scientific, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fair Lawn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.S.M.</ENAMEX> performed all of the studies described and wrote
        the draft of the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. L N.</ENAMEX> conceived of the
        study, supervised the work, and edited the manuscript.
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
