
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Prostate cancer</ENAMEX> is one of the major diseases that pose
        serious health problems for aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . It is
        generally believed that androgen has a significant role in
        the development and progress of this disease [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] .
        Changes in the growth response of cancer cells to androgen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ablation</ENAMEX> and anti-androgen during the progress of the
        disease [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5 6</NUMEX> ] suggest that multiple androgen-related
        signaling events are involved in neoplasia and disease
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progression</ENAMEX>. It has also been documented that prostate
        epithelial cells exhibited squamous metaplastic phenotype
        during <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">vitamin A deficiency</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , and prostate cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carcinogenesis</ENAMEX> could be prevented by retinoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) and
        its analogs in vitro [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 10</NUMEX> ] . These findings suggest
        that retinoid-dependent cellular events were involved in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tumorigenic</ENAMEX> transformation of prostate epithelial
        cells.
        Retinoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid receptors</ENAMEX> (RARs) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">retinoid X receptors</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXRs</ENAMEX>) are nuclear transcription factors that mediate the
        action of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">retinoids</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] . We have demonstrated that
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>, castration resulted in an increase in mRNAs for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± and Î³ in the prostate; such effects were prevented by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . We also demonstrated that the levels
        of mRNAs for RAR Î± and Î³ in non-tumorigenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> epithelial
        cells (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NRP152</NUMEX>) were down-regulated, whereas those in
        tumorigenic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NRP154</NUMEX>) were unaffected or up-regulated
        following T treatment [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± was
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expressed in tumorigenic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">NRP154</NUMEX> cells. These findings
        suggest that tumorigenic transformation and perhaps
        neoplasia of prostate epithelial cells are associated with
        abnormal expression and androgen regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARs</ENAMEX>.
        Androgen exerts its biologic effects by binding to and
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">androgen receptor</ENAMEX> (AR) that trans-activates
        target genes through androgen responsive element (ARE) in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of target genes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . In human breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cells the effectiveness of retinoids in cell growth
        suppression was dictated by the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
        Estrogen regulation of the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± was mediated
        by interactions between estrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>) and estrogen
        responsive element (ERE) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± gene [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
        ] . Because the DNA binding domains of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid receptors</ENAMEX>
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> are highly homologous, we postulated
        that similar mechanisms might also mediate the effect of
        androgen on RAR genes in prostate cells.
        The current experiments investigate the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> and
        its interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> on cell growth and the expression
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARs</ENAMEX> in human prostate cancer cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LNCaP</ENAMEX>. Furthermore,
        we present evidence to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> may affect the
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± gene through direct interaction between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">putative</ENAMEX> ARE in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± gene. Because
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>) are involved in prostate cell
        growth, and their expression can be modulated by androgen
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20</NUMEX> ] , we also examined the interaction of T
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> on the expression of EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R.</ENAMEX>
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Cell culture
          Human prostate carcinoma cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LNCaP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX>,
          Rockville, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>), were maintained and propagated in T25
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flasks</ENAMEX> in RPMI <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> media (GIBCO-BRL, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>)
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gemini Bio-Products</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calabasas</ENAMEX>, CA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM glutamine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fungizone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penicillin</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> unit/ml)/ streptomycin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>)
          (referred as complete medium) in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> humidified <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          3H-thymidine incorporation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sub-confluent</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80-90%</NUMEX>) LNCaP cells propagated in T25
          flasks were washed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ml of plain RPMI <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> medium
          and trypsinized with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ml <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">trypsin</ENAMEX>/EDTA solution
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIBCO-BRL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). The cells were then seeded
          onto the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-well plates (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-5 Ã— 10 4cells/well</ENAMEX>) in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ml
          complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, the cells were well
          attached and covered <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40-50%</NUMEX> of the surface area. At this
          time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX> in the medium was replaced by
          charcoal-stripped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cFCS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gemini Bio-Products</ENAMEX>), and
          various concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> and/or all trans retinoic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) were added in triplicates. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three days later</TIMEX>,
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was removed and the cells were incubated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ml</ENAMEX> plain medium containing 3H-thymidine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼Ci/ml</ENAMEX>) for
          an additional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h.</ENAMEX> After washing twice with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ml of plain
          medium, the cells were lysed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> ml of lysis buffer
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">containing 0.1 M NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.0</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sucrose</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was extracted with
          precipitated with an equal volume of isopropanol. After
          washing with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was subsequently
          precipitated by centrifugation. The specific activity of
          3H-thymidine was then determined and expressed as <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cpm/Î¼g</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Northern blot analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> mRNA
          To determine the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> on RAR mRNA expression,
          LNCaP cells were propagated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ml complete medium in
          T175 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flasks</ENAMEX>, with medium change <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 4th day</TIMEX>, until the
          monolayers reached ><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> confluence (usually <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8-10</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>
          after seeding). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX> in the medium was then replaced
          by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">cFCS.48 h later</TIMEX>, various concentrations of testerone
          were added in the absence or presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. The
          cells were harvested <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 h later</TIMEX>. This time was selected
          based on results of preliminary experiments (data not
          shown).
          Detailed procedures for isolation of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>,
          enrichment of poly (A)+ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> by oligo-dT cellulose
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chromatography</ENAMEX> and electrophoresis and Northern blotting
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> have been described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . The cDNA
          probes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse RAR Î±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RAR Î³</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22</NUMEX> ] were isolated
          by agarose electrophoresis after appropriate
          endonucleases digestion and were radio-labeled with
          32P-dCTP, using random priming kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehringer-Mannheim</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN). The blots were pre-hybridized in a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-strength SSC (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> mM
          Na-citrate, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> formamide, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/ml</ENAMEX> denatured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm DNA</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2-4 h</TIMEX>, and were
          hybridized overnight in the same buffer containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 6cpm</TIMEX>/ml of radiolabeled cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>. The
          membranes were washed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Ã—</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SSC solution</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20-30 min</TIMEX>, followed by several changes in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>-strength <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2-4 h.</TIMEX> The
          radioautographs were developed after they were exposes to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastman Kodak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">XAR-5</ENAMEX> film for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2-10</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> using an intensifying screen. The membranes were
          subsequently stripped and rehybridized with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32P</TIMEX> labeled
          cDNA for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">18S ribosomal RNA</ENAMEX>. The relative abundance of
          different transcripts (RAR Î±, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kb; RAR</ENAMEX> Î³, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kb</ENAMEX>) were scanned, and area under the curve was estimated
          by densitometry. The result of each sample was normalized
          against that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">18S ribosomal RNA</ENAMEX> in each sample. The
          average ratio between the mRNA and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> S <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal RNA</ENAMEX>
          of untreated control cells were considered <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 %</NUMEX>, and the
          results for individual experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> in each blot
          were expressed as a percentage of this average.
        
        
          The oligo corresponding to nucleotides <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-100</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-59</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> (antisense strand: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCGACTGCCCGCCCACCGACCAATCACCAGTCAGGGGCGGATCTAC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'; sense
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">strand: 5</ENAMEX>' CCGGGTAGATCCGCCCCTGACTGGTGATTGGTCGGTGGGCGGGCAG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>') [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] was synthesized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Medical</ENAMEX>
          School <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Resource Facility</ENAMEX>. The oligo probes were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">radiolabeled</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klenow</ENAMEX> fragment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> polymerase
          and 32P-dATP. The binding between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> was
          determined by gel electrophoretic mobility shift assay.
          Purified human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AR protein</ENAMEX> over-expressed in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">baculovirus</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] or nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> extracts of LNCaP
          cells were incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î</NUMEX>¼g
          polydeoxynosinic-deoxycytidylic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Ã—</NUMEX> binding
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 mM HEPES</TIMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM mercaptoethanol, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glycerol</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM KCl) on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30-60</NUMEX> min. After
          addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32P</NUMEX>-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 ng/reaction</ENAMEX>), the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mixture</ENAMEX> was incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an additional 30 min</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>.
          Non-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CGCCC GGGGT CCTCA GCG 3</ENAMEX>') or
          excess unlabeled specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> were added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-15</NUMEX> min
          before adding the radioactive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>. To super-shift the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AR-DNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was incubated with polyclonal
          AR-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CW2</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] prior to the addition
          of the radioactive oligo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>. The reaction mixtures
          were electrophoresed on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 %</NUMEX> non-denaturing
          polyacrylamide gel (acrylamide: bisacrylamide, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30: 0.8</TIMEX>)
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 %</NUMEX> glycerol at 180 V in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAE</ENAMEX> buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEAE</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX> mM sodium acetate and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>). The
          gels were dried at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60Â°C</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA/protein</ENAMEX> binding was
          visualized by radioautography. The same experiments were
          repeated at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times.
        
        
          Measurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">EGF</ENAMEX> receptor
          
            Ligand-binding assay
            Duplicates of membrane preparations equivalent to
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mg <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125I</NUMEX>-EGF (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 or 100</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ng; Amersham Life Sciences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) in
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> Î¼l reaction buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX> mM
            sucrose, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>) at 25Â°C
            for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> min. Non-specific binding was obtained by adding
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100Ã—</NUMEX> non-radioactive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Biochemicals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). The reaction was stopped by addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
            ml ice cold washing buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>,
            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pH 7.0</NUMEX>), and membrane bound ( <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">125I</NUMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> was precipitated
            immediately by centrifugation (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">14,000 rpm Ã— 4 min</NUMEX>) at
            4Â°C. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> were washed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml washing buffer
            and re-pelleted. Specific binding was obtained by
            subtracting non-specific binding (in the presence of a
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-fold excess unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX>) from total binding. The
            results were expressed as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fmol</ENAMEX>/mg <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            Western blots analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF-R</ENAMEX>
            The cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> were re-suspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>,
            lysed by boiling and stored as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> ml aliquots at
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-70Â°C.</ENAMEX> For Western blot analysis, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 Î¼l</NUMEX> of samples
            containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼g <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were mixed with equal volume
            of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã— loading buffer (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1X</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIS-HCl</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.8</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> glycerol, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.003%</NUMEX> bromphenol blue and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-mercaptoethanol</TIMEX>), and boiled for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fifteen</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX>)
            Î¼l of the samples were electrophoresed on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5%</NUMEX>
            SDS-polyacrylamide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini-gel</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V. The</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were transferred to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PVDF</ENAMEX> membrane (Amersham
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Sciences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mini</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trans</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blot Cell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio Rad Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA) at
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 mA</TIMEX>. The membranes were blocked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4Â°C</NUMEX> in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> Tween; pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>)
            containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> fat free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry milk</ENAMEX>. Thereafter, the
            membrane was incubated with a monoclonal anti-human
            EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oncogene Research Products</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>,
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) diluted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:10</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX> at room temperature for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h.</TIMEX>
            After washing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX>, the membrane was
            incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">anti mouse</ENAMEX> IgG/peroxidase conjugate
            (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,000</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at room temperature. The
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> was enhanced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECL</ENAMEX> Western blot detection kit
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Life Sciences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) and
            exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak X-OMAT</ENAMEX> film. The identical experiments
            were repeated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times.
          
        
        
          Statistics
          Analysis of variance (ANOVA) was used to detect the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dose-effect of T</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, using the JMP statistical
          software package (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>). Subsequently,
          Dunnetts multiple-range test was used to compare the
          means among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unpaired Student</ENAMEX>'s t test was used to
          determine the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> mRNA responses to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.</ENAMEX>
        
      
      
        Results
        
          3H-thymidine incorporation
          Treatment of LNCaP cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2000</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> alone for
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX> resulted in dose-dependent, biphasic stimulation
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-thymidine incorporation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>; Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1A</NUMEX>).
          While effects of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> was abolished by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 100</NUMEX> nM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>), the effect of higher doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> were
          suppressed by all doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> used (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). The
          extent of suppression depended on the doses of both T and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Specifically, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-thymidine uptake in cells treated
          with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-2000</TIMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> was suppressed by the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> nM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> to an extent that was significantly lower than
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">untreated</ENAMEX> controls (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). Similarly, treatment of
          LNCaP cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> alone resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX>
          stimulation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-thymidine uptake (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>, Figure
          1B); these effects were suppressed by concomitant
          presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). Such effects
          became less pronounced when higher doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> were used.
          Combination of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100 and 1000</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX> nM T resulted
          in lower 3H-thymidine uptake than those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> alone (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± and Î³ mRNA
          Treatment of LNCaP cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> alone for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> h resulted
          in dose-dependent, biphasic increases in levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î±
          and Î³ mRNA transcripts, with the maximal effect of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2-20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.05</ENAMEX>; Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). When the cells were treated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± and Î³
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNAs</ENAMEX> in LNCaP cells were suppressed in a dose dependent
          manner (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.05</ENAMEX>, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX> kb RAR Î± mRNA was
          not affected by these treatments.
        
        
          Incubation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AR protein</ENAMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">32P</NUMEX>-labeled oligo
          probe of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± promoter resulted in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-DNA</ENAMEX> complex
          after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSA</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4A</NUMEX>); radioactivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was
          displaced by unlabeled oligo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, but not by oligo
          probe of unrelated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was not
          present when the probe was incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>. Incubation
          of nuclear extracts of LNCaP cells with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">32P</NUMEX>-oligo
          probe also resulted in a complex that migrated to the
          same distance as that achieved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32P</NUMEX>-oligo probe
          complex (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4B</NUMEX>). The specificity of such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was
          demonstrated by displacement of radioactivity with
          unlabeled specific oligo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>. Incubation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> protein
          with anti-AR polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CW2</NUMEX>) prior to the
          addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32P</NUMEX>-labeled oligo probe resulted in
          super-shifting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-DNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (Figure
          4C).
        
        
          Interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA and T</ENAMEX> on EGF-R
          Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5shows</TIMEX> that treatment of LNCaP cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100 nM</NUMEX>) alone for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h resulted in > <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> decrease in
          the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">125I-EGF</ENAMEX> and membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.05</NUMEX>). On the other hand, binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125I</NUMEX>-EGF was
          stimulated by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> in cells treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.05</NUMEX>), but this effect was attenuated by the presence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Western blot analysis revealed a similar pattern of
          change in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> kd EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Androgen</ENAMEX> is essential for normal prostate function, but
        has also been implicated in the pathogenesis and neoplasia
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 26</NUMEX> ] . On the other hand, retinoid
        is essential for normal prostate function [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7 27 28</ENAMEX> ] and
        exhibits anti-proliferative and chemopreventive efficacy in
        experimental prostate carcinoma [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 10</NUMEX> ] . The
        dose-dependent stimulation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-thymidine incorporation in
        LNCaP cells by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> when administered alone, and
        reciprocal suppression of such effects by each other, are
        consistent with previous findings [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30 31 32</NUMEX> ] . These
        results illustrate interactions between androgen and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retinoid</ENAMEX> in the control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LNCaP</ENAMEX> cell growth. A correlation
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX> dose effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-thymidine incorporation and
        that on RAR Î± and Î³ mRNA levels further suggests that RAR
        signaling events might be involved in such interaction.
        Stimulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LNCaP</ENAMEX> cell growth by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> analog [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± in tumorigenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> prostate
        epithelial cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] support the above notion.
        Modulation of the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> and its receptor
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF-R</ENAMEX>) in prostate cells by androgen [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 26</NUMEX> ] , and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expression of EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> during the advanced stages of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] , imply that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF/EGF</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> signaling
        events might be involved in neoplasia and perhaps
        progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>. An increase in EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> in
        LNCaP cells after treatment with growth-stimulating dose of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> is consistent with this postulate. Suppression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF-R</ENAMEX>
        in LNCaP cells after treatment with a dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> that also
        attenuated the stimulating effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> on EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, further
        suggest that EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> signaling might have a role in the
        interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> on LNCaP cell growth. In this
        regard, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> was reported to blunt the growth response of
        LNCaP cells to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> also
        reported increases and decreases in LNCaP cells in S-phase
        after exposure to growth stimulating and anti-proliferative
        doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, respectively. Treatment of LNCaP cells with an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> agonist also caused an increase in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">G1</NUMEX> cells and a
        decrease in S phase cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] , suggesting that cell
        cycle kinetics are involved in the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA/RAR</ENAMEX>
        signaling.
        Binding between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> and nucleotide sequences of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± gene and that such <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-DNA
        complex was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-</ENAMEX>shifted in the presence of anti-AR serum
        suggest the presence of ARE in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± gene. This notion is
        supported by the presence, within the oligo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">nucleotides sequences 5'AGATCC 3</ENAMEX>' 
        (n-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-93</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5'ACTGGT 3</ENAMEX>' 
        (n-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-80</NUMEX>) which are identical or
        complementary to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">palindromic</ENAMEX> ARE motif of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prostatien</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C3</ENAMEX> subunit gene (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5'AGTACG 3</ENAMEX>') [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] and that of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGTGCT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>') [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , respectively. Binding
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LNCaP</ENAMEX> cell nuclear extract and oligo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î±
        promoter thus suggests that AR-ARE interaction might
        mediate the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> on the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± in
        LNCaP cells. A similar mechanism may also pertain for the
        effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> on RAR Î³ since the DNA binding domains are
        highly homologous among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARs</ENAMEX>. In addition, sequences in
        other segments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGGACA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'
        
        (n <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-46</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-41</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCTGCT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' 
        (n <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-25</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-20</NUMEX>) were similar or
        complementary to that of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> site of the up-stream ARE
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGAACAtatTGTATC</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> ARE (AGAACAgcaAGTGCT) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
        gene [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , respectively. Oligo probes containing these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> also interacted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
        These results further suggest possible presence of multiple
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AREs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± gene. Functional importance of multiple
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AREs</ENAMEX> in androgen effects has been demonstrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> gene
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] .
        Stimulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± and Î³ mRNA in LNCaP cells by T
        differed from that in normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat prostate</ENAMEX> and
        non-tumorigenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat prostate</ENAMEX> epithelial cells (NRP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">152</NUMEX>),
        but was comparable to that in tumorigenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> prostate
        epithelial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (NRP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">154</NUMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] . In cervical
        carcinoma cells, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î² gene was abnormally
        down-regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> positive human breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± mRNA was also up-regulated by estrogen
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . Thus, T stimulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> mRNAs in LNCaP cells
        could be related to the pathologic state of the cells.
        LNCaP cells contain high levels of functional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> with
        mutated ligand binding domain and exhibit aberrant cellular
        responses to androgen [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5 37 38</ENAMEX> ] . The mutated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> when
        interact with the ARE of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX>-Î± gene, may trans-activate
        the gene in an abnormal fashion resulting in increases in
        its mRNA.
        In summary, current results demonstrate interactions
        between T and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> in the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± and Î³ and
        EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, as well as cell growth in LNCaP cells. These results
        suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> and EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> signaling events might be
        involved in the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA and T</ENAMEX> on LNCaP cell growth.
        Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSA</ENAMEX> demonstrated the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">putative</ENAMEX> ARE on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> Î± <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>, suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>)-DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX> might be involved in the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> on RAR
        genes. While the importance of these in vitro findings for
        prostate cell patho-physiology in vivo must be interpreted
        with caution, current results nevertheless provide a
        molecular basis for the interaction between androgen and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retinoid</ENAMEX> in LNCaP cells. Further understanding the
        down-stream signaling events in such interaction will
        and pathologic growth of prostate cells, and will
        facilitate the use of retinoid analogs in the prevention or
        treatment of such <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        Author <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1</NUMEX> has been responsible for most of the
        experiments including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-thymidine incorporation, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
        some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> culture experiments. Author <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX> was responsible
        for all EGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> experiments. Author <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#3</NUMEX> has contributed
        purified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">androgen receptor</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSA</ENAMEX>, as
        well as consultation in the design of the experiments.
        Author <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#4</NUMEX> has provided suggestions for the experiments and
        potential clinical relevance of the findings. Author <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#5</NUMEX> has
        been responsible for the progress of the experiments,
        participated in cell culture experiments and preparation of
        the manuscript
      
    
  
