
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Conventional cancer incidence rates contain new cases of
        the disease for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given year</TIMEX> in the numerator and the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in the denominator [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . However,
        this rate is potentially problematic for those <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> in
        which the denominator includes cases not at-risk of
        developing the disease [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . For example, a large portion
        of the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> will undergo a hysterectomy in
        their lifetime [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4</NUMEX> ] , removing them from being at risk
        of developing corpus <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX>. In addition, a woman
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> of the corpus uterine is very unlikely to be
        diagnosed with the disease a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Hence,
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should be removed from the at-risk population
        in the rate calculation.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX> presented a method
        for obtaining hysterectomy prevalence and applied it to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancers</ENAMEX> in order to produce corrected incidence and
        mortality rates [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . The approach used the prevalence of
        hysterectomy, as determined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Health</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examination Survey</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-1962</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] , and a cohort model
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> applied to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> female
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was corrected over time by
        hysterectomy rates obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discharge Survey</ENAMEX>, a survey providing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> probability
        samples of hospital discharges from nonfederal, short-stay
        hospitals [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . A more recent study provided corrected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX> rates for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by applying the
        method proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX> and using hysterectomy
        rates from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX> through
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] .
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other methods may be used to obtain hysterectomy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevalence</ENAMEX> estimates that have an advantage in that they do
        not require <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> of follow-up data to obtain
        hysterectomy prevalence estimates. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> involves
        calculating hysterectomy prevalence estimates by applying
        cross-sectional hysterectomy incidence and all-cause
        mortality data to single- and double-decrement life tables
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . However, this approach may be limited by trends in
        the data. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> approach obtains prevalence estimates
        directly from responses to cross-sectional survey data. An
        advantage of this method is that it does not require
        complicated modeling, but it may be limited by potential
        biases that affect self-reported survey data.
        methods for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">correcting corpus uterine cancer</ENAMEX> incidence
        rates and probabilities. The methods yield estimates of the
        proportion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> at risk for developing the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and correct the incidence rates and probabilities
        accordingly. Although the focus is on corpus uterine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, the same methods may be applied to other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> of
        the female genital system, such as of the cervix uteri or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ovaries</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Method 1</ENAMEX>. Life-table method of estimating
          hysterectomy prevalence
          A single-decrement life table was used to calculate
          the proportion ( 
          p1 
          
            x 
           ) of a hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohort</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 million</NUMEX> newborns
          alive at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of age</TIMEX> interval 
          x when exposed to the
          cross-sectional hazard of death from all causes. From a
          multiple-decrement life table, the proportion ( 
          p2 
          
            x 
           ) of a hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohort</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newborns</ENAMEX> alive and at
          risk of the disease <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the beginning of age</TIMEX> interval 
          x is calculated based on their
          chance of having undergone a hysterectomy, having been
          diagnosed with the disease, or dying of any cause. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>
          having undergone a hysterectomy or previously diagnosed
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus cancer</ENAMEX> without having had a hysterectomy are
          assumed to reflect those not at risk of developing the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. The prevalence of having undergone a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hysterectomy</ENAMEX> or having been previously diagnosed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine cancer</ENAMEX> (minus those having had a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hysterectomy</ENAMEX> is calculated as 
          P 
          
            x 
           <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">= 1-</ENAMEX>( 
          p2 
          
            x 
           <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/</ENAMEX> 
          p1 
          
            x 
           ).
          Estimates derived from the life tables represent the
          prevalence that would be observed if a cohort of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were exposed to the current hysterectomy,
          corpus uterine (minus those having had a hysterectomy),
          and all-cause mortality rates over their entire
          lifetime.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Method 2</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross-sectional</ENAMEX> survey method for
          estimating hysterectomy prevalence
          The status of an individual with respect to the
          presence or absence of a disease or health-related event
          may be obtained through assessment at a given point in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. There are national and international surveys that
          track the disease and health status of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Behavior Risk Factor</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surveillance System</ENAMEX> (BRFSS) collects information about
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s health issues, such as pregnancy and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hysterectomy</ENAMEX>. A question that asks whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> has
          ever had a hysterectomy, along with solicitation of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s current age, indicates the prevalent proportion
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have had a hysterectomy by a certain
          age.
        
        
          Corrected denominators in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rate
          calculation
          In order to correct the denominator in the rate
          calculation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine cancer</ENAMEX>, we need to alter
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> so that it reflects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at risk of
          developing the disease. We assume that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is at risk
          of developing corpus <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX> if she has not
          already been diagnosed with the disease or has had her
          uterus removed because of a hysterectomy. The majority of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine cancer</ENAMEX> are
          treated with a hysterectomy. The percentage of corpus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX> cases that underwent a hysterectomy
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1995-97</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">93%</NUMEX> overall, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX> for ages <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0-39</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX>
          for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 40-59</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91%</NUMEX> for ages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 and older</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
          Thus, the prevalence ( 
          P 
          
            x 
           ) derived using the life-table method involves the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">age-specific</ENAMEX> number of hysterectomies plus women
          diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine cancer</ENAMEX> who did not undergo
          a hysterectomy (i.e., not at risk). In the survey method,
          the age-specific rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> not at risk of corpus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX> divided by the age-specific rate of women
          having undergone a hysterectomy provided an index which
          was multiplied by the age-specific hysterectomy
          prevalence obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRFSS</ENAMEX> to get an estimate of
          prevalent proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> not at risk of corpus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancers</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Corrected incidence rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> of the corpus
          uterine
          Conventional cancer incidence rates are derived as 
          R 
          
            x 
           = 
          C 
          
            x 
           <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> 
          
            x 
           , where 
          C 
          
            x 
           is the age-specific number of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> 
          
            x 
           is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> from cross-sectional
          census dat. Corrected rates are derived as:
          
          for x = <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0-4, 5-9, .</ENAMEX> . ., <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80-84</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX>+.
        
        
          Lifetime and age-conditional probability
          estimates
          Lifetime and age-conditional probability (risk)
          estimates of being diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> are derived
          using life-table methods. Conventional lifetime and
          age-conditional probability estimates of being diagnosed
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> are corrected for the prevalence of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. This involves multiplying the cancer incidence
          rate used in the computation of the probability estimates
          by 
          p1 
          
            x 
           <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/</ENAMEX> 
          p2 
          
            x 
           <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">= 1/</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-</ENAMEX> 
          P 
          
            x 
           ). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> methods for obtaining 
          P 
          
            x 
           are described above. A complete description of the
          method for deriving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> and age-conditional
          probability estimates of being diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> is
          given elsewhere [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . Probability estimates of
          developing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> are reported across the age span and
          interpreted as the probability that the average child
          born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> will be diagnosed with the disease by age 
          x . This statistic assumes that the
          current rates upon which the probability estimates are
          based will remain constant over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s lifetime.
          Given that current rates are unlikely to remain constant
          over an extended period of time, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> are
          more likely interested in their chance of developing the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> from their current ages onward, short-term,
          age-conditional probability estimates are perhaps more
          relevant [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . Both types of probability estimates are
          reported in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostic</ENAMEX> and procedure codes
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Cancer Registry</ENAMEX> identifies <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Classification of Disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Edition</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ICD-02</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . Invasive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> of the corpus uteri
          and other uterus not otherwise specified (hereafter
          called corpus uteri) are identified as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C540-C549</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classification of Disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth Revision, Clinical</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modification</ENAMEX> (ICD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-CM) procedure codes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68.3</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68.8</NUMEX>,
          where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68.3</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68.4</NUMEX> reflect abdominal hysterectomy, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68.5</NUMEX>
          reflects vaginal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hysterectomy</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68.6</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68.8</NUMEX> reflect
          radical hysterectomy [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> sources
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> were used in the
          analysis: hysterectomy cases obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discharge Data</ENAMEX> Base (HDDB) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, hysterectomy
          prevalence obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRFSS</ENAMEX>, invasive corpus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX> cases from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Cancer Registry</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> estimates from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Bureau of the</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>, and mortality data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah State Health</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Population</ENAMEX> estimates of the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> were combined with case data to compute
          hysterectomy incidence rates, prevalence proportions, and
          invasive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates and probabilities. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of data were considered in order to provide more
          stable estimates. The influence of race was not
          considered because of the high percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> (i.e., <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> White, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Indian</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black</ENAMEX>) [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> ] .
          Fifty-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> submit data to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Data Committee</ENAMEX> on an ongoing basis. These
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> psychiatric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
          specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Administration</ENAMEX>
          Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shriners Hospital</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity hospital</ENAMEX>, is
          exempt from reporting requirements. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
          report discharge data (i.e., the consolidation of
          complete billing, medical, and personal information
          describing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> received, and the
          charges billed) for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> served on an inpatient
          basis.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer</ENAMEX> data were obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Cancer</ENAMEX>
          Registry, which is one of the oldest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
          originating in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Cancer Registry</ENAMEX>
          has participated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surveillance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidemiology</ENAMEX>, and
          End Results (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEER</ENAMEX>) Program of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Cancer</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . The registries in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEER Program</ENAMEX> meet
          high-quality standards and are the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s source of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX> and survival data. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer registries</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEER Program</ENAMEX> have also collected
          first course of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>-directed therapy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Cancer</ENAMEX>
          Registry ensures complete incidence and treatment
          information by abstracting information from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>, clinical and nursing home records, private
          pathology <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> and radiotherapy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, and death
          certificates.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRFSS</ENAMEX> is a state-based surveillance system active
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disease Control</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention</ENAMEX> has collaborated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to develop questions that would reveal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>'
          knowledge, attitudes, and practices related to health
          issues. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> has been involved in collecting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRFSS</ENAMEX>.
          Age-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine</ENAMEX> rates are fit using
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>- or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-order polynomial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        Numbers and crude rates of hysterectomy per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> are shown for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-94 and 1995-97</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). The rates
        increase early in life, peak, and then decrease over the
        older ages. The rates were significantly higher in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-94</TIMEX>,
        compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-97</TIMEX>, in the age groups <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25-34 and 35-44</NUMEX>.
        Estimates of hysterectomy prevalence based on the
        life-table method and the survey method are presented in
        Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Higher prevalence estimates based on the
        life-table method with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-94</TIMEX> data versus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-97</TIMEX> data
        reflect lower hysterectomy rates in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later time</TIMEX> period
        for most ages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prevalence</ENAMEX> estimates based on the BRFSS
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-97</TIMEX> are highest, particularly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> through
        69.
        During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-97</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">549</NUMEX> cases of invasive cancer
        of the corpus uteri in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-</TIMEX>adjusted rate was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
        per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">conventionally</ENAMEX> derived rate is based on
        the denominator of the rate calculation including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
        are not at risk of being diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">invasive cancer</ENAMEX> of
        the corpus uterine. Figure 2presents corrected and
        uncorrected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> denominators with the corrections
        based on the two methods. Applying the corrected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX>, the age-adjusted rates using the life - table
        method became <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-97</TIMEX> data, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-94</TIMEX> data,
        and using the survey method was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>.
        Figure 3presents corrected and uncorrected invasive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates of the corpus uteri in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>. The
        correction for hysterectomy prevalence was greatest among
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> ages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75-79</NUMEX>. In this age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the uncorrected rate
        was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> and the corrected rate using the
        life-table method was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">223</NUMEX> based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-97</TIMEX> data, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">243</NUMEX> based
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-94</TIMEX> data, and the corrected rate using the survey
        method was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">228</NUMEX>.
        The lifetime probability of developing corpus uterine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.6%</NUMEX> (uncorrected); and corrected, based on the
        life-table method, was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.2%</NUMEX> using <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-97</TIMEX> data, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.5%</NUMEX> using
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-94</TIMEX> data; and according to the survey method was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.6%</NUMEX>.
        Corresponding percentages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> free of the disease at age
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> are slightly lower, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.1%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.4%</NUMEX>, and for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.5%</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2shows</ENAMEX> the corrected and uncorrected number per
        100,000 invasive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> of the corpus uteri expected in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 10 years</TIMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged 
        x . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten-year</TIMEX> probability estimates
        are largely influenced by the age in which they are
        conditioned. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year</TIMEX> probability of being diagnosed
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> of the corpus uterine is greatest for women
        aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX>. The corrections increase these probabilities
        considerably, most noticeably for those corrected using the
        survey method.
      
      
        Discussion
        This paper presents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> methods for obtaining corrected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates and probabilities. In
        the life-table method, hysterectomy or corpus uterine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> prevalence estimates were derived from
        cross-sectional hysterectomy, corpus uterine, and all-cause
        mortality data applied to life tables. In the survey
        method, hysterectomy prevalence estimates were obtained
        directly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRFSS</ENAMEX> data. The purpose of the correction was
        to adjust the population values used in the calculations in
        order to reflect the at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> for developing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine cancer</ENAMEX>.
        Both methods have the advantage that several years of
        follow-up data are not required to determine the at-risk
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Hence, for areas of the world that do not have
        sufficient years of hysterectomy or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> data to directly
        compute prevalence, corrected rates and probabilities can
        still be obtained. However, the life-table method is
        limited by trends in the data. Because the hysterectomy
        rates were lower in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-97</TIMEX> than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">previous years</TIMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevalence</ENAMEX> estimates based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these years</TIMEX> underestimated
        the prevalence of this procedure. Use of the higher
        incidence rates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-94</TIMEX> produced higher hysterectomy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevalence</ENAMEX> estimates across the age <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">span</ENAMEX>. However,
        prevalence based on these rates may also have been
        underestimated, at least through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 69</TIMEX>, as suggested by
        the hysterectomy prevalence estimates from the survey
        method.
        According to a self-reported national survey,
        hysterectomies have remained stable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1965-95</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ]
        . However, based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX>,
        there is evidence that hysterectomy rates decreased
        slightly from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1970s through the 1980s</TIMEX> and then may
        have leveled off through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 15 16</ENAMEX> ] . Our results
        show that hysterectomy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> significantly decreased
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1992-94 and 1995-97</TIMEX> in the age groups <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25-34</NUMEX> and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35-44</NUMEX>, where hysterectomy is most common. This suggests
        that hysterectomy prevalence based on the cross-sectional
        method, at least for ages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than 55</TIMEX> based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-97</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, underestimates hysterectomy prevalence. Use of the
        survey method to obtain prevalence has the advantage that
        it does not require complicated modeling and is not
        influenced by trends, but it may or may not represent the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, given potential biases that may influence
        self-reported responses. Yet a high level of correspondence
        has been previously shown to exist between self-reports and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> records of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hysterectomy</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        In an earlier report by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feuer</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] , based
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-92</TIMEX> national data, the hysterectomy prevalence
        correction based on an historical, rather than a
        cross-sectional, approach increased the age-adjusted rates
        of corpus uterine rates from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22.2</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33.0</NUMEX>. Although we
        cannot compare our results directly because of difference
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">time</TIMEX> periods studied, the unique racial makeup in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>,
        and because we also incorporated the prevalence of corpus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uterine cancer</ENAMEX> cases not treated with a hysterectomy, the
        magnitude of the correction is similar to those reported in
        this prior study.
        As anticipated, the hysterectomy prevalence corrections
        had large influences on the rates and probabilities. The
        percentage increase was smallest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> in life and
        increased consistently with age. This is because the number
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> alive that have undergone a hysterectomy increases
        over the age span, as evident in the corrected versus the
        uncorrected rates and probabilities. Yet, although the
        percentage change increases with age, the greatest absolute
        change tends to be where the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates are largest.
        It should be emphasized that correcting the rates and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">probabilities</ENAMEX> had a large impact because of the high
        prevalence of hysterectomy. The additional influence of
        prevalent cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine cancer</ENAMEX> cases who had not
        undergone a hysterectomy was relatively very small. Several
        studies have explored the benefits, risks, and costs of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hysterectomy</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28</NUMEX> ] . Despite
        the potential risks and costs associated with this medical
        procedure, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 35%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> received
        a hysterectomy by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 50</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Hysterectomies are
        primarily performed for nonmalignant conditions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] ,
        with the expectation that the benefits of the surgery
        outweigh the risks.
        Given the high percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, the study
        results primarily reflect this race. Hence, comparison of
        the results to other geographic locations should be
        restricted to primarily white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. Yet the results
        provide an important baseline for future comparisons.
        In addition to the limitations stated above, because it
        is impractical to expect cross-sectional rates upon which
        lifetime and age-conditional cancer probabilities are based
        to remain constant in the long run, lifetime probabilities
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> are less reliable than shorter term,
        age-conditional probability estimates. They are also less
        relevant to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> already aged to mid-life. However,
        lifetime probability estimates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> may provide a
        guide to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and health policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> as to the
        burden of these select <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>.
        As already well established, an accurate representation
        of the expected risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine cancer</ENAMEX> requires that
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in the incidence-rate calculation be
        corrected to reflect the at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Similarly, an
        accurate measure of the burden of this <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, in terms of
        lifetime and age-conditional probabilities of developing
        the disease, also requires a population correction to
        reflect those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at risk. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> methods developed in
        this study reflect unique strengths and weaknesses. Yet
        despite their potential weaknesses and in the absence of
        long-term hysterectomy and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> data, they will provide
        more reasonable estimates of the rates and probabilities of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">corpus uterine cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing Interests
        None declared
      
    
  
