
  
    
      
        Background
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>'s response to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> is a dynamic process
        that requires the efficient transmission of signals from
        the extracellular environment to specific intracellular
        sites. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>, the primary signal is generated at
        the plasma membrane and proceeds through intermediary
        G-proteins that stimulate adenylyl cyclase [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phospholipases</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] to generate the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messengers</ENAMEX> cAMP
        and diacylglycerol, respectively. The diffusion of these
        soluble second <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messengers</ENAMEX> leads to the activation of PKA
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> at specific subcellular locations [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of the regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subunits</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RII</ENAMEX>,
        have distinct cAMP binding properties and phosphorylation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5</NUMEX> ] . Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different isoforms, a
        and (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, resulting in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> distinct types, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIβ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIα</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIβ</ENAMEX>. The different <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> isoforms have distinct tissue and
        subcellular distributions suggesting that they may be
        selectively targeted by scaffold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, e.g., AKAPs
        anchored through different anchoring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] . PKC
        has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isoforms</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . The physiological role of
        the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCs</ENAMEX> has not been elucidated because most
        cells express multiple isoforms having nearly identical
        ligand binding properties and substrate specificity.
        Compartmentation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> isoforms has been suggested as a
        mechanism for targeting selectivity near their
        physiological substrates [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10</ENAMEX> ] . Consistent with this
        theme of selectivity, work with isoform-specific antibodies
        demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isoforms</ENAMEX> have distinct subcellular
        locations [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] .
        It has been known for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> that
        compartmentalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> can occur through association
        with A-kinase anchoring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (AKAPs). This association
        ensures specificity in signal transduction by placing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> close to their appropriate substrates where they
        can swiftly respond to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messengers</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . Another
        advantage of compartmentation to specific subcellular
        locations is to restrict accessibility to certain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">substrates</ENAMEX>. Selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX> have been identified that can
        interact with both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . For example, it
        was shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAP</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> maintains <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>, and protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphatase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2B</ENAMEX> at the postsynaptic density of mammalian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synapses</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 12</NUMEX> ] . Likewise, gravin, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> PKA/PKC
        anchoring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, targets these kinases to the membrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytoskeleton</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . AKAP79, gravin, and its mouse homolog
        clone 72 thus belong to the recently identified class of
        scaffolding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that coordinate multiple kinase
        activity by bringing them to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> site.
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> binding, it was thought for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> that
        only RII subunits bind to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX>. However, a new class of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX> was discovered when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dual-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-AKAP1
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP2</NUMEX>) were cloned using a fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of the RIα
        as the bait in a yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid screen [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] ).
        Therefore, the contrasted distribution pattern between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RII</ENAMEX> may in part be due to selective association with
        different compartmentalized pools of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX>.
        Only recently has the subcellular distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> at
        neuromuscular junctions (NMJs) and the adjacent muscle been
        systematically studied [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18</NUMEX> ] . Imaizumi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scherrer</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> is localized at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> ] , but whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-AKAP in this
        region of muscle is not known. However, a recent study
        showing the colocalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX> at the NMJ
        supports the prediction that localization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> subunit
        there requires interaction with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RII</ENAMEX> has
        been shown to be associated with mAKAP in heart and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skeletal</ENAMEX> muscle [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] ; however, little is known
        regarding the expression patterns of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RII</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX> in the
        perijunctional regions. More information has accumulated
        concerning PKC expression associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skeletal</ENAMEX> muscle. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCβ</ENAMEX> was shown to localize to the
        presynaptic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] , whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCθ</ENAMEX>
        plays a postsynaptic role at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . In skeletal
        muscle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCα</ENAMEX> was found in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">muscle fibers</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] and
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>tubules in rabbit skeletal muscle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . However,
        it is unknown whether tethering to a PKC-anchoring protein
        mediates the localization to these compartments.
        The work reported here was undertaken to further
        understand the compartmentalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> was observed in close
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> postsynaptic membrane [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] , we
        probed for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-AKAP expression and possible colocalization
        with this and other regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subunits</ENAMEX>. We also
        investigated the distribution of gravin at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> because
        this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAP</ENAMEX> is an autoantigen for myasthenia gravis, a
        degenerative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blot assays</ENAMEX> confirmed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> used
        are monospecific (fig. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The blots show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCα</ENAMEX>, the
        major PKC isoform present in muscle, is not detected by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PKCβII antibody</ENAMEX>, and that there is little overlap between
        the specificities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> regulatory subunit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>.
        As with a previous report studying different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skeletal</ENAMEX> muscle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] , the soluble fraction contained
        most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIβ</ENAMEX> was detected in contrast
        to a report of no RIIβ detection in soleus or extensor
        digitorum longus muscles [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] , which might be explained
        by the presence of nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> or adipocytes wherein RIIβ
        is prevalent [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . The blot for the affinity-purified
        D-AKAP1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> is shown because the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-A purified
        antibody displayed additional, unexplained bands; however,
        no difference in fluorescence labeling was observed when
        using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> purified either way.
        A previous report using immunofluorescence demonstrated
        colocalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> with the nicotinic acetylcholine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX> (nAChR) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> postsynaptic membrane [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] .
        We used immunohistochemistry coupled with confocal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microscopy</ENAMEX> to acquire detailed information as to the
        intracellular localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> in the several
        regions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> and adjacent intercostal muscle to
        compare with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX>. Rhodamine-conjugated
        α-bungarotoxin was used to delineate the postsynaptic
        membrane of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> because it binds tightly to the nAChR
        found at this membrane. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> was shown to
        associate with mitochondria [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] , double-labeling with
        markers for this organelle, either anti-lipoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> or
        anti-cytochrome c, was used to examine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> or
        D-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> are associated with mitochondria in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX>.
        We found partial overlap of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RIα</ENAMEX> label with
        synaptophysin, which labels presynaptic vesicles (fig. 2a).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> was observed to be concentrated in other
        vicinities of the presynapse as well. In the postsynaptic
        region, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> immunoreactivity showed partial overlap with
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mitochondrial marker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lipoic acid</ENAMEX>); overlap with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mitochondria</ENAMEX> in muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> was also observed (fig. 2b).
        In muscle, labeling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>-band by anti <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> was dominant.
        The I-band contains actin and is where mitochondria are
        located, but has no myosin.
        The distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> at the postsynaptic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> and
        the adjacent muscle is similar to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX>, although
        there is no codistribution at the presynaptic region
        between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> labels (fig. 3a). D-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> is expressed in
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> and intercostal muscle. D-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> codistribution
        with cytochrome c (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mitochondrial marker</ENAMEX>) is significant
        (fig. 3a), but not as pronounced as the RIIα association
        with mitochondria (compare with fig. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). We observed an
        enrichment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> at the postsynaptic membrane, as
        shown by codistribution with nAChR (fig. 3b). As with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX>,
        labeling of the actin region by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> was dominant
        (fig. 3a, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3c</TIMEX>). Because the labeling patterns for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> and
        D-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> appear similar in the muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> and at the
        postsynaptic membrane, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> may anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> in these
        regions, which further supports the cloning and biochemical
        evidence of interaction between these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 28</NUMEX> ] .
        Phalloidin was used as a positive control for the actin
        region of muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> (fig. 3c). The no-primary control
        was clean (fig. 3d). Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> were produced in rabbit and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>, respectively,
        double-labeling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">confocal</ENAMEX> experiments could be performed
        with these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> on the same tissue slice in order to
        test for colocalization. The same applies for anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIα</ENAMEX> and
        anti-RIIβ. We found that the labeling patterns for these
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> in muscle tissue counterstained with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bungarotoxin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-D</ENAMEX>-AKAP1 (data not shown) was not
        modified from that found when counterstained with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bungarotoxin</ENAMEX> and a mitochondrial marker (see below),
        indicating partial colocalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIα</ENAMEX> but,
        little if any overlap with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIβ</ENAMEX>. In contrast, the RIα
        labeling was invariably almost completely abolished when
        counterstained with bungarotoxin and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> in
        multiple experiments (data not shown). This suggests to us
        that anti-D-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> may be occluding RIα bound to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> to
        the extent that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> has little access to its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>.
        As shown in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIβ</ENAMEX> is found in the postsynaptic
        region of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> and did not precisely overlap with the
        α-bungarotoxin label but instead encompassed a broader area
        of this region. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIβ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immunoreactivity</ENAMEX> appeared to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">punctate</ENAMEX> in the cytosol, yet contrasted with the punctate
        distribution of mitochondria. The presence of labeling at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> is consistent with the prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RII</ENAMEX> in
        neuronal tissue [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . The lack of staining in the muscle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> is in agreement with the report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIβ</ENAMEX> did not
        show significant hybridization with skeletal muscle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ]
        .
        Triple-labeling immunofluorescent staining patterns
        (fig. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIα</ENAMEX> is concentrated in the
        postsynaptic vicinity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> but is not colocalized
        with the nAChR. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIα</ENAMEX> immunoreactivity exhibited significant
        overlap with mitochondria in the postsynaptic region of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> and with mitochondria in skeletal muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX>.
        Labeling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was dominant. Interestingly, intense
        immunoreactivity was found to be consistently localized
        with the z-line. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> kinase and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAP</ENAMEX> labeling patterns
        shown in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIα</ENAMEX> is the only one that strongly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> with the z-line (contrast with the phalloidin
        labeling shown in fig. 2c).
        The labeling pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-AKAP2 (fig. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) differs from
        that of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX>. Even though the striated labeling in the
        muscle fibers appears similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">striations</ENAMEX> noted for
        D-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> and is where actin is prevalent, the
        overlap with the mitochondrial marker (cytochrome c) is
        poor, in contrast with observations of close overlap in
        cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-AKAP2 pattern is rather
        diffuse, being present in both postsynaptic and presynaptic
        vicinities, and appears dissimilar to the mitochondrial
        pattern.
        Intense PKCβ immunoreactivity was found in both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">postsynaptic</ENAMEX> and presynaptic regions (fig. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>), consistent
        with enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCα</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCθ</ENAMEX> labeling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
        Over a background of more diffuse staining, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stronger
        bands can be observed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> codistributes with nAChR.
        The other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> is in the presynaptic region and parallels
        the nAChR <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. In addition to these bands, there is strong
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunoreactivity</ENAMEX> in other areas of the presynapse. The
        labeling pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCβ</ENAMEX> is sufficiently different from
        that of the mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX> to indicate that there is
        no association with this organelle in either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">muscle fibers</ENAMEX>. PKCβ labeling in the muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> is faint,
        which corroborates the report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCα</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCθ</ENAMEX> are the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">predominant PKC</ENAMEX> isoforms in skeletal muscle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] , with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCθ</ENAMEX> being more abundant in the membrane fraction of muscle
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCα</ENAMEX> being more abundant in the cytosolic fraction.
        As with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCβ</ENAMEX>, gravin codistributes with nAChR (fig. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunoreactivity</ENAMEX> is predominantly in the postsynaptic
        region and doesn't overlap particularly well with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mitochondrial marker</ENAMEX>. The strongest labeling is at the
        plasma membrane. This labeling is consistent with the
        report that gravin possesses several targeting motifs that
        direct it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">membrane-cytoskeleton</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . In the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">muscle fibers</ENAMEX>, striations of staining are noticeable. Even
        though there is partial overlap of these striations with
        those typical of mitochondria (labeled with cytochrome c),
        the staining occurs where actin is prevalent. Because
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gravin</ENAMEX> has a putative actin-binding domain, it is likely
        that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> is with actin. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Tables 1and</ENAMEX> 2summarize
        the compartmental localization and mitochondrial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> and intercostal muscle of the
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX> studied based on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunofluorescence</ENAMEX> work reported here.
      
      
        Discussion
        The work presented here adds to the emerging evidence
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> signaling at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> and adjacent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">intercostal</ENAMEX> muscle is compartmentalized. Differential
        compartmentation of these signaling molecules in cells and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tissues</ENAMEX> is being recognized as a mechanism to regulate
        their specificity [reviewed recently by [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] ]. A Kinase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anchoring Proteins</ENAMEX> (AKAPs) can direct their subcellular
        localization by binding directly to regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subunits</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> or to the catalytic core of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">AKAPs</ENAMEX> have been
        identified, although information about their subcellular
        distribution in different tissues is largely lacking.
        Because we produced antibodies to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> novel dual-specific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP2</NUMEX>), and gravin, we were uniquely
        positioned to use immunofluorescence to investigate their
        possible roles in kinase signaling in and around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX>.
        Our interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> and PKC activity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> derives
        from: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a report that RIα not only is enriched there, but
        also appears to be tethered to the postsynaptic membrane [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> ] , (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the rich literature describing selective PKC
        isoform activity and functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compartmentalization</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> and skeletal muscle, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) our discoveries that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-AKAP1
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP2</NUMEX> bind to and appear to colocalize with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX>, and
        often mitochondria [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 28</NUMEX> ] ; and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) our finding that
        gravin binds to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] .
        We found that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> appears to colocalize with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> at
        the postsynaptic membrane of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> the
        nAChR, but not in the presynaptic region. This observation
        is supported by previous work that demonstrated RIα
        codistribution with nAChR [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-AKAP1 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ]
        suggesting that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAP</ENAMEX> is the anchoring protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recruiting RIα</ENAMEX> to this membrane. This putative association
        is strengthened by finding for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that
        targeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> requires the AKAP binding surface [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yotiao</ENAMEX> is another AKAP enriched at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX>, but appears to
        bind only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RII</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> phosphorylates the nAChR when
        stimulated at the synapse by the neuropeptide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CGRP</ENAMEX> and by
        adenosine from muscle responding to acetylcholine [reviewed
        by [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] ]. This phosphorylation may regulate the
        degradation of the nAChR [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . Consistent with the
        action at the presynapse, it was shown that PKA
        facilitation of acetylcholine release is dependent on nerve
        endplate calcium concentration [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . Based on our
        observation of colocalization with synaptophysin at
        presynaptic vesicles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> may be the isotype that
        influences this release of neurotransmitter.
        We found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> occupies the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mitochondria</ENAMEX> in intercostal muscle. The presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">soleus</ENAMEX> muscle was shown with Western blots by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoover</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coworkers</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] , but was not seen with immunofluorescence
        of tibialis anterior muscle [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 19</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reinitz</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coworkers</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] provided evidence suggesting that RIα
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> with membrane fractions in cardiac muscle when
        it is not associated with the catalytic subunit. The same
        may be true for intercostal muscle, in which case,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> with the sarcolemma, mitochondria or other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organelles</ENAMEX> is possible. Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> was shown to bind
        to cytochrome c oxidase subunit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vb</ENAMEX> (a mitochondrial inner
        membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>), which faces the matrix, in a
        cAMP-dependent manner [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . How RIα passes across the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mitochondrial</ENAMEX> inner membrane is not known. Previously, we
        observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> mRNA and protein expressions are high
        in muscle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . In situ hybridization showed consistency
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> staining in tongue muscle, indicating
        that in vitro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> can indeed predict in situ
        interaction for these molecules. Consistent with the
        observed mitochondrial staining by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX>, it was
        shown previously that one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> alternative
        NH2-terminal motifs of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAP</ENAMEX> is necessary and
        sufficient for targeting to mitochondria [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] .
        Interestingly, another AKAP governs voltage-dependent
        potentiation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-type calcium <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> through anchoring
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> in transverse tubules [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . Because this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">potentiation</ENAMEX> is not dependent on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIα</ENAMEX>, it is thought that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIα</ENAMEX> is capable of this AKAP-directed modulation of calcium
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] .
        The labeling pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP2</NUMEX> is diffuse in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX>,
        yet localized to the actin region in muscle. In our
        previous immunofluorescence work examining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-AKAP2
        subcellular localization, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> displayed a diffuse
        background in addition to mitochondrial staining [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] .
        It was thought that the combination of specific and diffuse
        labeling indicated the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> pool of
        D-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP2</NUMEX> inside the cells examined. Whereas, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP1</NUMEX> appears
        to colocalize with mitochondria in muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-AKAP2
        shows no such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>. This observation is not
        surprising because it is not expected that their targets
        need to be in the same organelle or even subcellular
        region. Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">binds</ENAMEX> specifically to actin remains
        to be determined.
        RIIα localized quite well to mitochondria in both NMJ
        and muscle regions. PKA association with mitochondria has
        been well documented [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38 39 40 41 42</NUMEX> ] . In mammalian
        sperm, it was found that nearly all RII-specific labeling
        was with mitochondria [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] . Furthermore, in bovine
        heart, PKA activity was detected in the matrix or the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">matrix</ENAMEX> side of the mitochondrial inner membrane [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44 45</NUMEX> ] .
        However, the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Halestrap</ENAMEX> and coworkers provided
        little evidence for intramitochondrial protein
        phosphorylation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX>, but gave some evidence for outer
        membrane phosphorylation, both integral and loosely bound
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 47 48</NUMEX> ] . The localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIα</ENAMEX> to the
        postsynaptic <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> beyond the postsynaptic membrane is
        consistent with part of the immunostaining of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJs</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">soleus</ENAMEX> muscle [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] , yet differs in part because there is
        no overlap with the bungarotoxin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">label</ENAMEX>; however, this is in
        agreement with another study [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCβ</ENAMEX> colocalizes with gravin at the postsynaptic
        membrane where the gravin staining is strongest. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> has
        been suggested to play a role in synapse stability and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> transduction at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJ</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . When calcium influx
        through the nAChR occurs, acetylcholine appears to activate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> phosphorylation of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> [reviewed by [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] ].
        Phorbol ester activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> causes loss of synapses and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nAChR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] . Because the presynaptic PKCβ fluorescence
        band parallels the nAChR <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> (see fig. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>), it may be
        labeling the presynaptic membrane, consistent with reports
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCβ</ENAMEX> localization to the presynaptic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NMJs</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCβ</ENAMEX> initially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> with the cytoskeleton [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ] . Phosphorylation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> places on the kinase core is
        required <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to release it
        from its cytoskeletal anchorage. Our immunofluorescence
        results may be the visualization of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pools of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCβ</ENAMEX>. The
        observed bands may represent kinase anchored directly to
        the cytoskeleton, perhaps on the presynaptic side, where
        little gravin staining was found, or anchored to gravin,
        perhaps on the postsynaptic side. The more diffuse staining
        found in both pre- and postsynaptic regions may represent
        released, hence activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinase</ENAMEX>.
        As with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKCβ</ENAMEX>, gravin was seen to be directed to the
        postsynaptic membrane. Strong labeling was also seen at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">plasma membrane-cytoskeleton</ENAMEX> (see fig. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>), consistent with
        the report of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nauert</ENAMEX> and coworkers [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . Interestingly,
        a homology search of a database revealed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MARCKS</ENAMEX> homology
        actin-binding domain in gravin. In addition to acting as a
        scaffolding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> for kinases and phosphatases, gravin
        forms a dynamic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> with beta-adrenergic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>
        ] . The same report also showed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of
        beta-adrenergic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> could be blocked by the
        Ht31 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX>, which blocks AKAP-kinase binding. In addition
        to a PKC binding site, gravin contains a PKA binding site.
        Hence, the beta-adrenergic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> may be tethered to PKA
        via gravin. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> may bind to this anchoring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> through
        displacement of the pseudosubstrate, thus inhibiting the
        kinase activity, by analogy with a functionally similar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scaffolding AKAP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AKAP79</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] .
      
      
        Conclusions
        The distinctive labeling patterns of each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> and anchoring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> investigated argues for the
        existence of microdomains of signaling pathways. It appears
        that several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKAPs</ENAMEX> may be in close proximity; yet, it still
        needs to be determined if waves of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX> would turn on
        signals in a local or global way. Moreover, the signals
        that cells in tissues receive from the surrounding matrix
        may provide a different micro-environment of kinase
        anchoring from that of cultured cells. An example is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AKAP2</NUMEX> with mitochondria in cultured
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">myocytes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] that is not present in muscle tissue (fig.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Materials
          Mouse anti-PKA RIα, mouse anti-PKA RIIβ, and mouse
          anti-PKA RIIα were purchased from Transduction
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratories</ENAMEX>. Mouse anti-cytochrome c was purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PharMingen</ENAMEX>. Rabbit anti-PKC bII was purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panvera</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rabbit anti-D-AKAP1</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] , rabbit anti-D-AKAP2
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] , and rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-gravin</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] were previously
          detailed. Rabbit anti-PKA RIα was prepared by
          synthesizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> of human RIα
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and conjugating this peptide (MESGSTAASEEARSLREC)
          to keyhole limpet haemocyanin (KLH) via the bifunctional
          reagent, m-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">maleimidobenzoyl</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-hydroxysuccinimide ester
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MES</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KLH-RIα 18</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mer</ENAMEX> was sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cocalico Biological</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polyclonal antibody</ENAMEX> production in rabbits using
          established procedures. Rabbit anti-lipoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> cofactor
          was produced as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humphries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Szweda</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX> ]
          . Phalloidin-rhodamine binds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">actin</ENAMEX> and was obtained
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>. Fluorescein-labeled donkey
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anti-rabbit IgG</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Cy5</NUMEX>-labeled donkey anti-mouse IgG
          were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson ImmunoResearch</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRITC</ENAMEX>(rhodamine)-α-bungarotoxin was purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Probes, Inc.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> Blots
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-gravin</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blots</ENAMEX> were performed as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . For all other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat intercostal</ENAMEX> muscle was excised and homogenized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM HEPES</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nad</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA/EGTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ImM DTT</ENAMEX> and protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. The
          homogenate was centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> × <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at
          4°C; the soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX> and insoluble pellet were
          each mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4×</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE sample buffer. These samples
          were separated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE, electrophoretically
          transferred to polyvinylidene difluoride membrane, and
          blocked with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS-T.</ENAMEX> Membranes were then probed
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-fold higher dilution than used for
          immunofluorescence for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX>, followed by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX>
          incubation with peroxidase conjugated secondary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> and detection with chemiluminescence. Western
          blots were repeated at least once to confirm results.
        
        
          Immunofluorescence
          Sprague-Dawley male rats weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 g</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 4 weeks</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>) were anesthetized with the general anesthetic,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nembutol</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were then whole-body,
          perfusion-fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glutaraldehyde</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> solution, after perfusion with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ringers</ENAMEX> solution to clear the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Intercostal</ENAMEX> muscle
          was quickly extracted and immersion-fixed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>.
          Small strips of muscle were cut that were suitable for
          confocal microscopy. All of the following steps were
          performed on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> or at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. Strips of intercostal muscle
          were rinsed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml glycine (to quench the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aldehydes</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX>, and permeabilized with blocking
          buffer for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> triton <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-100</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> normal donkey
          serum, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> cold-water fish gelatin and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>-glycine). Primary and secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were
          diluted in working buffer (blocking buffer diluted 10×
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>). The tissue was stained with a mixture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          primary antibodies - a kinase or AKAP, and a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mitochondrial marker</ENAMEX> (either anti-cytochrome c or
          anti-lipoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid cofactor</ENAMEX>) - <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. The tissue
          was washed extensively with working buffer after the
          overnight incubation. Secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> and
          bungarotoxin were added for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4°C</NUMEX> in the dark.
          Afterwards, the tissue was again washed extensively with
          working buffer before mounting on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> slides and
          cover-slipped with gelvatol (anti-fade medium). The
          slides were stored in a refrigerator until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">imaged</TIMEX>. A
          no-primary control was used to select conditions that
          blocked the nonspecific labeling of secondary antibodies.
          Laser-scanning confocal microscopy was performed as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . Experiments were repeated
          at least once to confirm the fluorescence patterns. Each
          fluorophore was recorded separately using narrow-band
          filters centered at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">522</NUMEX> (fluorescein), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">605</NUMEX> (rhodamine),
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">680</NUMEX> nm (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cy5</NUMEX>). Z-series were recorded with each
          fluorophore with x,y pixel size of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> microns and
          z-step of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.18</NUMEX> microns. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX> comprised between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> optical sections. Z-series were deblurred using a
          blind deconvolution algorithm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Autoquant</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        List of abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AKAP - A</ENAMEX> kinase anchoring protein
        D-AKAP - dual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX> and RII-specific AKAP
        KLH - keyhole limpet haemocyanin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MES - m-</ENAMEX>maleimidobenzoyl-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-hydroxysuccinimide ester
        nAChR - nicotinic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acetylcholine</ENAMEX> receptor
        NMJ - neuromuscular junction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PKA - protein</ENAMEX> kinase A
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PKC - protein</ENAMEX> kinase C
        RIα - PKA regulatory type I subunit alpha
        RIIα - PKA regulatory type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> subunit alpha
        RIIβ - PKA regulatory type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> subunit beta
      
    
  
