
  
    
      
        Background
        
        Pneumocystis carinii causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX>
        in immunocompromised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with a high <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and
        mortality rate. However, the interaction between this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> and the host <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is not well understood. The
        target cell for 
        P. carinii is believed to be the type
        I pneumocyte. After contact with the type I pneumocyte, 
        P. carinii trophozoites anchor
        themselves to the host <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. It was found that the major
        surface glycoprotein of 
        P. carinii up-regulates the
        expression of integrins on the surface of cultured lung
        cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] to facilitate this attachment. 
        P. carinii attachment to type I
        pneumocytes may also be mediated by laminin, vitronectin [
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2, 3</ENAMEX>], or mannose [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>].
        Alveolar macrophages interact with 
        line of defense against infection. The major surface
        glycoprotein of 
        P. carinii has been shown to be a
        chemotactic factor for macrophages and monocytes 
        in vitro [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. The interaction of
        alveolar macrophages with 
        P. carinii is mediated by fibronectin
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. 
        P. carinii <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> are phagocytized
        when they bind to mannose <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> on the surface of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. Alveolar macrophages have been shown to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">release TNF-Î±</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prostaglandin</ENAMEX> E 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , and leukotriene B 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> upon interaction with 
        P. carinii [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. These compounds are
        potent modulators of pulmonary inflammation and lung injury
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. These are early and important events in the acute
        response to infection and clearance of 
        P. carinii <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> from the lung [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>].
        Although it is not certain whether 
        P. carinii organisms attach to type
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pneumocytes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II</ENAMEX> pneumocytes do respond to 
        P. carinii infections. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Type II</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pneumocytes</ENAMEX> maintain the structural integrity of alveoli
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. They produce alveolar surfactant and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">replicate</ENAMEX> and differentiate into type I pneumocytes after
        lung injury [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Type II pneumocytes</ENAMEX> have been shown to
        increase the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">surfactant protein-A</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-A</ENAMEX>) in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with 
        P. carinii <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcP</ENAMEX>), and the
        increase of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-A</ENAMEX> correlates with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> load in the
        lung [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>]. The secretion of phosphatidylcholine from type
        II cells has been found to be inhibited upon 
        P. carinii infection [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>], leading
        to a deficiency of phosphatidylglycerol and the loss of
        surfactant function in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>].
        The purpose of this study was to detect alterations in
        P. carinii infection. We have
        compared gene expression patterns in 
        P. carinii -infected and
        mock-infected cells using mRNA differential display and
        found that the mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene is
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expressed in response to 
        P. carinii infection in rats. We also
        found that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II pneumocytes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> cells are
        responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> in 
        P. carinii -infected rat lung.
      
      
        Results
        In order to determine whether 
        P. carinii infection causes increases
        in gene expression in host cells, experiments using mRNA
        differential display were performed. Human embryonic lung
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEL</ENAMEX>) cells were used as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> cells and were inoculated
        with lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">homogenate</ENAMEX> of dexamethasone-immunosuppressed and 
        P. carinii -infected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. A separate
        set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEL</ENAMEX> cell cultures was inoculated with lung
        homogenate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">dexamethasone-immunosuppressed</ENAMEX>, non-infected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> to serve as non-infected (mock-infected) control.
        Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product bands were seen in the 
        P. carinii -infected but not in the
        mock-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> of the mRNA differential display gel.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of these bands (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), designated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A4II</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A6I</TIMEX>, and
        A8I, were selected for further study. To identify the genes
        represented by the differentially displayed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was recovered from the gel, re-amplified, cloned,
        and sequenced. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Local Alignment Search Tool</ENAMEX>
        (BLAST) was used to identify the sequences thus obtained.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A4II</NUMEX> product was determined to be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">234</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bp DNA</ENAMEX> fragment
        with sequence <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 60%</NUMEX> homologous to nucleotides
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">234</NUMEX> of the yeast mitochondrial ori <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> sequence
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">gb|K02488|YSCMTORIA</NUMEX>). This product was not further
        investigated since it is not a human or rat gene. The A6I
        product was found to be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">332</NUMEX>-bp fragment with sequence
        identical to nucleotides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">177</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">508</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat ribosomal</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein S19 gene</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">emb|X51707|RRRPS19</NUMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">287</NUMEX>-bp A8I
        product was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 %</NUMEX> identical to nucleotides <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3421 - 3707</TIMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat mitochondrial</ENAMEX> ATPase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">gb|J01435|RATMTCYOS</NUMEX>).
        Since we sought to detect genes that were up-regulated in
        the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> cell line, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">299</ENAMEX>, in response to 
        P. carinii infection, it was
        surprising that none of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product
        bands were of human origin.
        To verify the expression pattern seen in the mRNA
        differential display, the cloned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A6I and A8I</TIMEX> fragments were
        used to probe Northern blots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNAs</ENAMEX> derived from
        non-infected and 
        P. carinii -infected rat lungs. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A6I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> reacted with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.8</NUMEX>-kb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, but the
        intensities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> bands of samples from mock- and 
        P. carinii -infected rat lungs were
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> the same. Therefore, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A6I</NUMEX> product <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was
        not further studied. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A8I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> reacted with an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> band
        of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 0.7 kb</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), which is the size of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rat ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. Both 
        P. carinii -infected and
        mock-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA samples</ENAMEX> showed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.7</NUMEX>-kb <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. The
        intensity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA sample</ENAMEX> from 
        P. carinii -infected rat lung is
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX> times stronger than that of the sample from
        non-infected rat lungs based on densitometric analysis of
        the autoradiogram. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> intensities of the same blot
        probed with a fragment of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">18S</NUMEX> rRNA gene were used as an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> control for variations in the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> loaded
        on the blot (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). These results indicate that
        non-infected rat lungs have a basal level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene
        expression and that this expression is increased in 
        P. carinii -infected lungs.
        To verify over-expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> in rat
        lung tissue, 
        in situ hybridization with
        digoxigenin-labeled riboprobes was performed. Slides, each
        of which contained lung tissue sections of both
        dexamethasone-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">immunosuppressed</NUMEX> non-infected (NRL) and 
        P. carinii -infected (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcIRL</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>,
        were probed with sense and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>sense riboprobes of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene. The sections reacted with the sense probe
        served as a control for non-specific background signal. The
        sections reacted with the anti-sense <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> were expected to
        show a dark blue precipitate in cells as an indication of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene expression. A dark blue precipitate was not
        seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PcIRL</ENAMEX> sections reacted with the sense
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">riboprobe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, panels <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PcIRL</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>) but was seen in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> cells per alveolus in the NRL
        sections reacted with the anti-sense riboprobe (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3,</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AS</ENAMEX>). Large alveolar macrophages with
        blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">precipitates</ENAMEX> were also seen in some of the alveolar
        spaces. In addition, some of the epithelial cells of the
        very distal parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">respiratory tree</ENAMEX> also showed blue
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precipitate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> not shown). In sections of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcIRL</ENAMEX> reacted
        with the anti-sense riboprobe, hybridization signal was
        seen in many more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> per alveolus when compared to those
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRL</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alveoli</ENAMEX> were packed with foamy exudate
        indicative of a heavy 
        P. carinii infection. Most of the
        cells in the septal areas around these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alveoli</ENAMEX> reacted with
        the probe (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcIRL, AS</ENAMEX>), but there
        was no reaction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> in consolidated alveolar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spaces</ENAMEX>, indicating that the probe did not react with 
        P. carinii <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>.
        Cells in the apical areas of the alveoli are usually
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II pneumocytes</ENAMEX>, and the non-ciliated cuboidal
        epithelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the very distal parts of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">respiratory tree</ENAMEX> are usually <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. The
        observation that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> reacted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene probe
        are located in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas suggests that type II
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pneumocytes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> cells are the cell types that
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene. To confirm this
        possibility, 
        in situ hybridization with a probe
        specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II pneumocytes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> cells was
        performed. This probe was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-bp fragment of a portion of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> surfactant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-B (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">emb|X14778|RNSPB</NUMEX>)
        that is expressed only in type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pneumocytes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX>
        cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>].
        As seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>(SPB <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>), tissue sections (NRL or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcIRL</ENAMEX>) reacted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> sense probe showed no
        hybridization signal. Similarly to those probed with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the apical area of alveoli (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-3</ENAMEX> per
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alveolus</ENAMEX>) and epithelial cells lining the distal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airways of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NRL</ENAMEX> sections showed blue precipitate when reacted with the
        anti-sense <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SPB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AS</ENAMEX>). In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PcIRL</ENAMEX> sections reacted with the anti-sense probe, more
        cells than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NRL</ENAMEX> sections in apical areas of alveoli
        had blue precipitate, indicating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3,</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SPB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcIRL, AS</ENAMEX>).
        To confirm that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-expressing cells are type II
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pneumocytes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> cells, double-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> fluorescent 
        in situ hybridization was performed.
        Sections of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcIRL</ENAMEX> tissues were hybridized
        simultaneously with fluorescein-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> and
        digoxigenin-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">riboprobes</ENAMEX>. Hybridized
        fluorescein-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> or digoxigenin-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> 6
        riboprobes were visualized as green or red fluorescence,
        respectively, using the appropriate filter on a fluorescent
        microscope. Cell nuclei were stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPI</ENAMEX> and emitted
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">blue fluorescence</ENAMEX> under the appropriate filter. Sections
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PcIRL</ENAMEX> hybridized with the sense probes for both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> showed little red or green fluorescence
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>). These sections exhibited predominately
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> cell nuclei that appeared as large blue elliptical
        rings or spherical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>, whereas 
        P. carinii nuclei appeared as small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blue</ENAMEX>, punctate clusters in the alveolar spaces (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4H).
        Composite images of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PcIRL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B)
        sections hybridized with the anti-sense riboprobe for both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> exhibited large blue nuclei surrounded by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yellow fluorescence</ENAMEX> in the cytoplasm. This yellow
        fluorescence was due to complementation between red and
        green signals derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>sense <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ATPase 6</NUMEX> (red signal)
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> (green signal) probes that hybridized with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAs</ENAMEX> in
        the same cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Panels 4</ENAMEX>, C and D; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E and F</ENAMEX> are images
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4A and 4B</TIMEX>, respectively, split into individual green
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX>) and red (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ATPase 6</NUMEX>) channels. With very rare
        exceptions, cells that expressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> also
        expressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX>. In addition, no hybridization
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> (red or green) was seen in areas that had clusters
        of 
        P. carinii <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>. These results
        strongly indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II pneumocytes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> cells
        are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ATPase 6</NUMEX> over-expression during 
        P. carinii infection.
      
      
        Discussion
        The technique of mRNA differential display has been used
        to detect differences in gene expression between different
        types of cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 19</TIMEX>], during cell transformation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>], and in various stages of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> development [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. In
        this study, we used it to detect genes that are
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expressed in 
        P. carinii -infected cells.
        Homogenates of lungs from non-infected and 
        P. carinii -infected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were used
        to inoculate a human cell line, the HEL cell line, to
        determine whether 
        P. carinii would up-regulate or
        induce gene expression in infected HEL cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Unexpectedly,</ENAMEX>
        we detected and identified the mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene,
        which appears to be over-expressed in response to 
        P. carinii infection as demonstrated
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> blot analysis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) and 
        in situ hybridization (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3and 4</ENAMEX>)
        in rat lungs. The possibility that the observed increase in
        hybridization signal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> ATPase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> was due to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crossover</ENAMEX> contamination by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX>- or 
        P.carinii -derived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> is
        remote because the mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene of yeast
        shares <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 16 %</NUMEX> sequence identity with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>.
        Furthermore, there was no indication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> 6 signal
        originating from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> or 
        P. carinii <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> in the 
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">situ</ENAMEX> experiments that were
        performed (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3and 4</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> is a component of the F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> synthase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, which converts
        the energy stored in the form of the proton motive force to
        chemical energy in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is
        composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> major domains, F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> . F 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1</ENAMEX> is the catalytic portion of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enzyme</ENAMEX>. It lies on the matrix side of the inner
        mitochondrial membrane and is composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> subunits of Î± 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> Î² 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> Î³Î´Îµ [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 24</TIMEX>] and an ATPase inhibitor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. F 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0</ENAMEX> is the integral membrane domain of the
        complex and functions as a proton <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> synthesis.
        F 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> domains: the stalk-like domain
        and the integral membrane domain. The stalk-like domain of
        F 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0</ENAMEX> is composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, OSCP
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oligomycin sensitivity-conferring protein</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>] and F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSCP</ENAMEX> is found as a dimer in
        each F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX>. It interacts with the F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> and is required for H
        +translocation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. The integral membrane domain is
        composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">subunits 6, A6L</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Subunit 6</ENAMEX> is the product of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene. Little is
        known about the structure and function of the subunit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
        protein except that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it is an integral</ENAMEX> membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that
        interacts with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSCP</ENAMEX> subunit and may be involved in
        energy coupling to the F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A6L</NUMEX> subunit is also an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">integral</ENAMEX> membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> associated with the F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. There are approximately
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> copies of subunit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> involved in forming the proton
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>].
        Except for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A6L</ENAMEX>, which are encoded by the
        mitochondrial genome, all of the subunits of the F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> synthase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> are encoded by
        nuclear genes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. It is not clear how expression of each
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein subunits</ENAMEX> is regulated or how the complexes
        are assembled on the mitochondrial inner membrane. It has
        been shown that triiodothyronine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">T3</NUMEX>) increases the
        transcription of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> gene of the F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> but has no effect on the
        transcription of the Î² subunit of the F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>]. This result suggests
        that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sectors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> are not necessarily
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coordinately</ENAMEX> expressed.
        As mentioned above, the cells that expressed the ATPase
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene were found to be located at the apical areas of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alveoli</ENAMEX> and in the epithelium of the very distal parts of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">respiratory tree</ENAMEX>. The apical areas are where type II
        pneumocytes are located, and the very distal parts of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">respiratory tree</ENAMEX> are where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> cells are located. Cells
        in these locations were also found to react with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX>
        probe. Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> is known to be expressed only in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II pneumocytes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clara</ENAMEX> cells, the results suggest
        that these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> types of cells are over-expressing the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> in response to 
        P. carinii infection.
        The fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat mitochondrial</ENAMEX> ATPase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene was
        isolated from HEL cells inoculated with homogenate of 
        P. carinii -infected rat lungs
        suggests that rat cells were present in the inoculum and
        survived in culture. This possibility is consistent with
        the nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II pneumocytes</ENAMEX>, as they are known to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">long-lived</ENAMEX> in culture [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>]. In this study, the HEL cells
        were incubated with the inoculum for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 days</TIMEX> before the
        cultures were processed for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolation. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This 5-day</TIMEX>
        incubation was to allow sufficient time for 
        P. carinii <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> to interact with
        the feeder layer (HEL cells) and for apoptosis of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">short-lived rat</ENAMEX>-derived cells that were present in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inoculum</ENAMEX>. It is likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II</ENAMEX> pneumocytes survived
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire 5-day</TIMEX> period of incubation. It is also
        likely that some of the HEL cells died in the incubation
        period and that differentially expressed HEL RNAs were
        missed. Since no human genes were found to be
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expressed by the mRNA differential display performed
        in this study, the effects of 
        P. carinii infection in gene
        expression in HEL cells or in human lungs remain to be
        investigated.
        The significance of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expression of the mitochondrial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> in 
        P. carinii -infected lung is unknown.
        Since type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> pneumocytes transform into type I pneumocytes
        in response to lung injury [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>], it is possible that this
        process requires a higher amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>. To satisfy this
        need, these cells may increase the expression of the genes
        of the F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> synthase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. This hypothesis
        implies that the expression of all or most of the genes
        encoding various components of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> synthase complex
        would be up-regulated in response to 
        P. carinii infection. It is also
        possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> plays a role in other functions that
        also respond to 
        P. carinii infection. If this were
        the case, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> of other components of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> synthase
        would not necessarily be up-regulated together with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene. All of these possibilities remain to be
        studied. It also remains to be determined whether
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene is specific for 
        P. carinii infection. It is
        conceivable that over-expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> can
        be a diagnostic marker if it is unique to 
        P. carinii infection. Studies are
        underway to explore these possibilities.
      
      
        Conclusions
        The technique of mRNA differential display was used to
        detect genes that have an altered expression in 
        Pneumocystis carinii -infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>.
        The nucleotide sequence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> differentially displayed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragment</ENAMEX> was found to be identical to that of the gene
        encoding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX>, which is a subunit
        of the F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> F 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> synthase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. Northern blot
        analysis of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> extracted from 
        P. carinii -infected rat lung versus
        that from mock-infected rat lung revealed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> 6
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX> is over expressed during 
        P. carinii infection. Cells that
        expressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene were found lining the distal
        parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">respiratory tree</ENAMEX> and in apical areas of
        alveoli by 
        in situ hybridization. With a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-color fluorescent 
        in situ hybridization, most cells
        that expressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene were also found to express
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX>, indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II pneumocytes</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Clara cells</ENAMEX> are the cell types responsible for the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> in 
        P. carinii infection.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Development of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. cariniiinfections</ENAMEX> in rats and
          preparation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. cariniiinoculum</ENAMEX>
          To develop 
          P. carinii infection,
          Sprague-Dawley female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were immunosuppressed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dexamethasone</ENAMEX> and then trans-tracheally inoculated with
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.2 ml</NUMEX> of homogenate of an infected rat lung containing 1
          Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 6</NUMEX> 
          P. carinii trophozoites or with a
          homogenate of uninfected rat lung as controls as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>]. After development of 
          P. carinii infection (approximately
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> after inoculation), <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were sacrificed, and
          lungs were removed and homogenized in minimal essential
          medium (MEM) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal calf serum and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          non-essential amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>. Following removal of gross
          cellular debris by centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g, the number of 
          P. carinii <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> per ml of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatant</ENAMEX> in the infected lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">homogenate</ENAMEX> was
          determined as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>].
        
        
          Cell cultures
          The human embryonic cell line <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">HEL 299</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Culture Collection</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) was used for 
          P. carinii culture. When the cell
          monolayer was confluent, the cells were split into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75-cm</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2flasks</ENAMEX> and grown to confluence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> on all
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 confluent HEL</TIMEX> cell culture flasks was then removed. Two
          flasks, designated non-infected (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NI</ENAMEX>) controls, were each
          replenished with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> ml of fresh complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. Two
          flasks, designated mock-infected (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>), were inoculated
          with an aliquot of normal rat lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">homogenate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ml of
          complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. The remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> flasks, designated
          infected (I), were each inoculated with an aliquot of 
          P. carinii -infected lung
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 5</NUMEX> 
          P. carinii <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> per ml in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>
          ml of media. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> flasks were then incubated in an
          isolation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> containing a gas mixture of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , and balance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> extraction
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was isolated using the hot-acidic phenol
          extraction method described by Chuang 
          et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>]. HEL cells were
          dislodged from the flask with a trypsin-EDTA solution,
          washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DEPC-</ENAMEX>treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and then resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
          ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold resuspension buffer [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.5</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KC1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> ml of hot (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70Â°C</NUMEX>) lysis buffer
          [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M NaCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          Î²-mercaptoethanol, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>] and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of citrate-buffered
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenol</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX>) were added to each cell suspension. The
          resulting mixtures were boiled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 minute</TIMEX> and then
          extracted with phenol:chloroform (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1</ENAMEX>). The aqueous
          portion of the extraction was layered onto a cushion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5.7 M CsCl</ENAMEX> in ultracentrifuge tubes. The tubes were
          centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">147,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18.5 hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18Â°C</TIMEX>. After
          ultracentrifugation, the supernatant was removed and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA pellets</ENAMEX> were dissolved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> buffer [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM Tris-HCl
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pH 8</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>] and then treated with RNase-free DNase
          I (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 U/ml</ENAMEX>) to remove any residual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. To extract <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          from tissue, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mg of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat lung</ENAMEX> was ground in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ml of
          ice-cold resuspension buffer. The resulting homogenate
          was centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> Ã— g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> to remove the
          gross cellular debris. The supernatant was then treated
          as above starting with the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ml of hot lysis
          buffer. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> Î¼g of each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was electrophoresed in
          triplicate on a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde agarose</ENAMEX> gel to check for
          integrity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> and to perform Northern
          hybridizations, which were done as described previously [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>].
        
        
          Densitometry of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Blots</ENAMEX>
          The intensities of hybridization signal on
          autoradiograms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> blots were determined by laser
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">densitometry</ENAMEX>. An LKB <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2202</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UltroScan Laser</ENAMEX> Densitometer
          set in absorbance mode was used to scan <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 mm-long</NUMEX> areas
          of each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> on the autoradiogram. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Height</ENAMEX>, width, and
          area of each peak were determined by a least-squares-fit
          method, and the amount of absorbance over the scan length
          was evaluated and corrected for baseline absorbance by
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LKB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2190 GelScan</ENAMEX> software package.
        
        
          mRNA differential display
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RNAimageâ„¢ Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenHunter Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>) was used to detect differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA samples</ENAMEX> of
          mock- (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>) and 
          P. carinii -infected (I) HEL cells.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three 20</NUMEX>-Î¼l reverse transcription (RT) reactions were set
          up per sample. Each reaction contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> ng of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>,
          reaction buffer [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.3</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">37.6 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KC1</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MgCh</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX>], <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼M</NUMEX> of each deoxribonucleoside
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triphosphate</ENAMEX> (dNTP), and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.2 Î¼M</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">anchored primers: H-T</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 -A</TIMEX>, H-T 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, or H-T 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 -C</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H= AAGCTT</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> reactions
          were performed as described in the procedure manual of
          the kit.
          The resulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> reaction products were used to
          prepare <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight 20-Î</NUMEX>¼l <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PCRs</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> reaction. Each PCR
          included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Î¼l of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> reaction containing the primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strand</ENAMEX> cDNA, reaction buffer [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.4</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KC1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.001%</NUMEX> gelatin], <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼M</NUMEX> of each
          dNTP, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.2 Î¼M</NUMEX> of the same anchored primer used in the RT
          reaction, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.2 Î¼M</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight 13</NUMEX>-mer arbitrary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">API-8</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12.5 Î¼Ci</NUMEX> of Î±-[ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35S</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dATP</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1270</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ci/mmole</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U of AmpliTaq</ENAMEX> DNA polymerase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin-Elmer, Foster City</ENAMEX>, CA). Thermal cycling
          parameters included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of denaturation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94Â°C</TIMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 seconds</TIMEX>, annealing at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 minutes</TIMEX>, and
          extension at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>. The final cycle
          included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> additional <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72Â°C</NUMEX> to ensure
          complete extension of all products and a subsequent hold
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one fifth</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products from each
          reaction were electrophoresed on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> denaturing
          polyacrylamide gel to display the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product bands. The
          samples of reactions performed with the same primer pairs
          but different templates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> or I) were loaded into
          adjacent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of the gel. An autoradiogram of the gel
          was obtained and analyzed to detect bands which were
          present in one of the paired <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> but not in the other.
          Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was labeled with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-part designation
          representing the anchored primer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-T 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 -A</TIMEX>, H-T 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>, or H-T 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 -C</TIMEX>), arbitrary primer (API - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>),
          and the number of the differential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in the lane from
          the well. Therefore, band A4II was found in the
          A-anchored primer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-T 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 -A</TIMEX>) reaction with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">AP4</NUMEX> arbitrary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primer</ENAMEX> and was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> differentially displayed band
          in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Differentially</ENAMEX> displayed bands were
          isolated and reamplified with the same primer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> as
          that used to produce the isolated differential display
          band. The amplified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was cloned into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA</ENAMEX> cloning
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> pCRII (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA) and then
          sequenced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanger</ENAMEX> method using the Sequenase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Life Science</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>) protocol as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>].
        
        
          Cloning of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> surfactant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> B gene
          fragment
          A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX>-bp portion corresponding to nucleotides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">441</NUMEX> to
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">643</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> surfactant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> B gene
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">emb|X14778|RNSPB</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>] was amplified from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> lung <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> and then cloned as follows. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two hundred</TIMEX> ng of
          rat lung total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was added to a reaction which
          contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.3</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KC1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl
          
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.001%</NUMEX> gelatin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM of each dNTP,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM dithiothreitol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U RNasin</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> pmoles of primer
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-BR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAATCACAGCTTGGACCCGC-3</ENAMEX>'), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U MMLV</ENAMEX> reverse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcriptase</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> reaction was incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42Â°C</TIMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 minutes</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> reaction products were mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          pmoles of primer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-BF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GACTAAGCCAGAGCAGAAGC-3</ENAMEX>') and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U of AmpliTaq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> and then subjected to PCR
          which included <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94Â°C</TIMEX> followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of
          94Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 minute</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">72Â°C</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. The resulting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> product was cloned into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pCR2.1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> clones,
          pCR21<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/4SP-B and pCR22/lSP-B</ENAMEX>, which had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX> gene
          fragment in opposite orientations, were selected.
        
        
          Generation and preparation of riboprobes
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ATPase 6</ENAMEX> clones were used as templates in PCRs
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">primer</NUMEX> pairs RATPase6F (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACCCCCATCTCACTAATTCC-3</ENAMEX>')
          and RATPase6R (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AGTACTAGGGTAGCTCCTCC-3</ENAMEX>') to generate a
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">145</NUMEX> bp fragment to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ATPase 6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">riboprobes</ENAMEX>. Similarly, a
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">202</NUMEX> bp fragment was amplified from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pCR21/4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-b</ENAMEX> with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">primers SP-BF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-BR</ENAMEX> (see above) to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">riboprobes</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product was ligated to adapters that
          contained an SP6 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> sequence (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SP6 adapter</ENAMEX>) in one
          reaction or to adapters with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">T7</NUMEX> promoter sequence (T7
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adapter</ENAMEX>) in another reaction according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lig'nScribeâ„¢</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>) protocol. The ligation
          products were amplified with an adapter-specific primer
          and either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>-specific forward primer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RATPase6F</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-BF</ENAMEX> (for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the T7</TIMEX> adapter ligation) or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>-specific
          reverse primer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RATPase6R</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-BR</ENAMEX> (for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the SP6</TIMEX> adapter
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligation</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were thus generated:
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RATPase6F-T7</ENAMEX> adapter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP6 adapter-RATPase6R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-BF-</ENAMEX>T7
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adapter</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP6 adapter-SP-BR</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RATPase6F-T7</ENAMEX> adapter and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-BF-T7</ENAMEX> adapter PCR
          products were used as templates for 
          in vitro transcription to produce
          antisense riboprobes, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP6 adapter-RATPase6R</ENAMEX> or
          SP6 <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">adapter-SP-BR PCR PCR</ENAMEX> products were used to make
          sense probes. The 
          in vitro transcription was
          performed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in reactions containing 100
          ng of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">template DNA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T7 RNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (for
          antisense probes) or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SP6 RNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (for
          sense probes), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM dithioerythritol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM
          spermidine, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM each of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTP</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTP</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.65</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTP</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.35</NUMEX> mM digoxigenin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIG</ENAMEX>)-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTP</ENAMEX> (or
          fluorescein-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-UTP), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U RNasin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>). After 
          in vitro transcription, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U of</ENAMEX>
          RNase-free DNase I was added to digest the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA templates</ENAMEX>,
          and the labeled riboprobes were precipitated with ethanol
          and then resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DEPC-</ENAMEX>treated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. One
          Î¼l of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNasin</ENAMEX> was added to the suspension, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          concentration was determined by spectrophotometry.
        
        
          in situhybridization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> lung tissue using
          riboprobes
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX>-micrometer thick sections of lung tissue from
          dexamethasone-suppressed uninfected and 
          P. carinii -infected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were
          mounted on a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ProbeOnPlus</ENAMEX> slide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisher Scientific</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>). Processing of tissue sections for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization</ENAMEX> and reactions with riboprobes were
          performed as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>]. For colorimetric
          detection, hybridization with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> was revealed by
          reacting the tissue sections with anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIG</ENAMEX>-alkaline
          phosphatase conjugate, followed by reaction with
          nitroblue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tetrazolium chloride</ENAMEX> (NBT),
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-bromo-4-chloro-3-indolyl phosphate</TIMEX> (BCIP), and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">levamisole</ENAMEX> as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>]. The sections
          were counter-stained with nuclear fast red dye (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>
          nuclear fast red, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> aluminum sulfate) and mounted in
          glycerin jelly (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> gelatin, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> glycerin, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenol</ENAMEX>).
          Florescent 
          in situ hybridizations were
          performed as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40, 41, 42</TIMEX>].
          Detection of hybridized fluorescein-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP-B</ENAMEX>
          riboprobe was accomplished by reacting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> with
          rabbit anti-fluorescein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> followed by
          FITC-conjugated goat anti-rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. For detection
          of hybridized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIG</ENAMEX>-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATPase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">riboprobes</ENAMEX>, hybridized
          sections of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat lung</ENAMEX> were incubated with mouse anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIG</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas Red-conjugated</ENAMEX> horse
          anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas Red</ENAMEX>-conjugated rabbit
          anti-horse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>.
          For evaluation by fluorescence microscopy, slides were
          covered with antifade containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">4</ENAMEX>', <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>'-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">diamidine</NUMEX>-2'
          phenylindole dihydrochloride (DAPI), which stained the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">nuclei</ENAMEX> blue. Microscopic analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">FISH images</ENAMEX> was done
          using an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aristoplan</ENAMEX> fluorescence microscope (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leitz</ENAMEX>,
          Rockleigh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">63 Ã—</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Ã— <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>-immersion
          objectives and appropriate filters. Separate gray images
          of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> probes (red, green, and blue) were taken
          using filters specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Red</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPI</ENAMEX>. The
          images were colored and superimposed using a software
          package by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vysis, Inc</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Downers Grove</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) to yield the
          final image.
        
      
    
  
