
  
    
      
        Background
        Phorbol esters are often used as activators of protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> (PKC) to investigate the role of the kinase in
        cellular functions [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Pancreatic Î²-cells possess Î±,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Î²1, Î´ and Îµ PKC</ENAMEX> isotypes [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] , and activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> is
        known to synergize with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose stimulation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>, via <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> phosphorylation
        seems to facilitate exocytosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin granules</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7 8</NUMEX>
        ] . In <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose-stimulated insulin secretion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>-sensitive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SUR1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir6.2</ENAMEX>)) play a crucial role
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> produced by the metabolism of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibits K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity, resulting in development
        of depolarization responsible for opening of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-type Ca
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, allowing Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+influx. Elevation of
        intracellular Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+([Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i ) accelerates exocytosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">granules</ENAMEX>. The possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity is regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> has
        long been studied. In this respect, however, contradictory
        results have been obtained. For example, in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-secreting cell lines, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> was reported to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">potentiate K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] , although
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PKC-dependent inhibition</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] or inhibition followed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] has been also reported. In primary
        Î²-cells from the mouse, activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> did not
        cause any change in membrane potential [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] , although
        in the same cell type, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> reduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>-stimulated
        elevation of [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i depending on activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ]
        . On the other hand, recent studies in myocytes suggest
        that activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> increases the open-time probability
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SUR2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir6.1</ENAMEX>) by reducing the
        sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18 19 20</NUMEX> ] . Therefore,
        whether regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> is mediated
        through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> or not is still obscure. Recently, we reported
        that phorbol <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ester</ENAMEX> inhibited Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+influx through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-dependent and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PKC-independent pathways</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . In the
        present study, we further evaluated the non-PKC mechanism
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> action on Î²-cell electrical excitation by using
        patch-clamp techniques. The results indicate that in rat
        pancreatic Î²-cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> modulates <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion through
        a mixed mechanism: increases <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion by
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>, and meanwhile decrease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion
        by impairing Î²-cell excitability in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-independent
        manner. The enhancement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity by reducing sensitivity of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> seems to underlie the
        PMA-induced impairment of Î²-cells electrical excitation in
        response to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> stimulation.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> inhibits electrical excitation of single rat
          Î²-cells
          With <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX> mM in the extracellular solution,
          the membrane potential, measured using the
          nystatin-perforation technique, was stable (-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52.9</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>
          mV, mean Â± <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bath</ENAMEX>-applied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
          induced the action potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spikes</ENAMEX> superimposed on a
          slow membrane depolarization (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1panel A). When PMA
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 nM</NUMEX>) was applied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulation</ENAMEX>, both slow depolarization and action
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">potentials</ENAMEX> was abolished. The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> was
          reversible after removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1panel A). This
          inhibitory effect by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> appeared to be independent of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> since addition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blocker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) did not
          prevent PMA-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhibition</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1panel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
          experiments, higher concentration (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> failed
          to prevent PMA-induced inhibition too (data not shown).
          In the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX> of tested Î²-cells
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/8</NUMEX>) showed spontaneous action potentials superimposed
          on a slow depolarizing potential, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 nM</NUMEX>)
          inhibited these action potentials as well (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1panel
          C).
        
        
          PMA induces hyperpolarization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> Î²-cells
          In the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, application of PMA
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 nM</NUMEX>) alone induced a slow, reversible membrane
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperpolarization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2panel A). The magnitude of the
          hyperpolarization depended on the concentration of PMA
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>). Pretreatment of cells with the PKC
          inhibitor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 60 min</TIMEX> did not prevent
          PMA-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hyperpolarization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2panel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). Figure
          2Csummarized that PMA-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hyperpolarization</ENAMEX> was not
          significantly different between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX>-treated and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BIM-untreated Î²-cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>). These results
          indicate that PMA-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hyperpolarization</ENAMEX> of pancreatic
          Î²-cells is not mediated through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activation.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K ATPactivity</ENAMEX> in cell-attached single
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> recording
          Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> plays a crucial role in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose-stimulated insulin secretion</ENAMEX>, PMA-induced
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperpolarization</ENAMEX> could be mediated by changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity. To test this hypothesis,
          we examined the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> on single channel
          activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> . In the cell-attached
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">configuration</ENAMEX>, spontaneous single channel currents were
          recorded at a pipette potential of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0 mV</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The
          specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blocker</ENAMEX>, tolbutamide (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.5 mM</NUMEX>)
          completely inhibited channel activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>),
          indicating that the recorded single channel currents are
          passed through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> channels. Application of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> nM PMA
          to the bath solution significantly increased channel
          activities (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Values of open-time probability for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.08 Â± 0.01</NUMEX> before
          application of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.11 Â± 0.01</NUMEX> during application of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mean Â± SEM</ENAMEX>, P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>). This result
          indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> indeed increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increases whole-cell membrane current through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
          In the whole-cell configuration, membrane currents in
          response to repeatedly applied voltage ramp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pulses</ENAMEX> from
          -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-50</NUMEX> mV were recorded. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolbutamide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.5 mM</NUMEX>)
          markedly reduced the size of the current, and after
          blockade of membrane current, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> failed to increase the
          current (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4panel A), suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increased
          membrane currents through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> . Application of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 nM</NUMEX>)
          increased the magnitude of membrane current (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4panel
          B) and the magnitude of increased currents depended on
          the concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4panel <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>). In cells
          treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> still increased membrane
          current (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>). No significant differences were
          observed between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX>-untreated and treated cells for
          PMA-induced membrane current increase (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4panel <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>),
          suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> -mediated currents in a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-independent manner.
        
        
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Î±</NUMEX>-PDD mimics the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> on electrical
          properties of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> Î²-cells
          There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways to test the hypothesis that the
          effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> on electrical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">properties</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> Î²-cells is
          independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activation. One is to use specific PKC
          blockers, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX>, to examine whether the effect of PMA
          can be prevented (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2, 4</ENAMEX>). Another way is to employ
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> analogs, which do not stimulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>, to see if they
          can mimic the PMA effect. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Î±</NUMEX>-PDD, as a PKC
          non-stimulating phorbol ester [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] , provides a good
          opportunity to test our hypothesis. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          5panel A, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Î±</NUMEX>-PDD (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) completely abolished action
          potentials elicited by elevation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> concentration
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5 to 15</NUMEX> mM, just like the PMA effect in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1panel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> In voltage-clamp current recordings (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          5panel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Î±</NUMEX>-PDD (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) increased membrane current
          evoked by ramp from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-90</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-50</NUMEX> mV, similar to the PMA
          effect in figure 4panel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> The similar results have also
          been obtained by low concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Î±</NUMEX>-PDD (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 nM</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> =
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> for current-clamp data and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for voltage-clamp
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, data not shown). These results indicate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Î±</NUMEX>-PDD
          virtually mimics PMA effects, and these data further
          support the idea that the increase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> does not depend on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activation.
        
        
          Possible mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
          ATPactivity
          How does PMA increase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> possible
          explanations might be addressed. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> reduces the
          sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> as reports using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">myocytes</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18 19 20</NUMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> may reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> production. To
          assess the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity, we performed two
          experiments. First, using inside-out recording
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">configuration</ENAMEX>, spontaneous single channel activities were
          more prominent when there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> in bath solution
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">intracellular</NUMEX> face), and recorded currents were very
          sensitive to bath-applied tolbutamide (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.5 mM</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          6panel A). In the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> in the bath, application
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> showed little effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6panel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). Values
          of the open-time probability for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.19 Â± 0.02</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>) without
          and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.20 Â± 0.02</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P > 0.05</ENAMEX>). The
          average single channel conductances were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pS</ENAMEX> without
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX> pS with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, measured <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between -90</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> mV
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6panel <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>). Application of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> to the bath
          decreased the open probability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> , and under this condition, PMA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restored K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>) even in
          the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX> BIM (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6panel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>). Values for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
          concentration producing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-maximal inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> , taken from the
          concentration-response relationships of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> inhibition of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity, were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10.8 Â± 1.9 Î¼M</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> =
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) without and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24.9 Â± 4.9 Î¼M</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (P
          <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>). Values of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> coefficient
          were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.04 Â± 0.02</NUMEX> without and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.08 Â± 0.02</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> >
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.05</NUMEX>). These results indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity in the presence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intracellular ATP</ENAMEX>, which implies that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> may reduce the
          sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> content of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat islets</ENAMEX> was measured during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> treatment. As shown in
          Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,10</NUMEX> min loading of islets with extracellular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> did not alter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> content
          of islets. On the other hand, loading cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM
          NaCN markedly reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> content.
        
        
          Effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose-induced insulin</ENAMEX>
          secretion
          The results presented such far indicate that PMA
          decreases electrical excitation of Î²-cells and this
          effect is independent on PKC activation. According to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX> theory, decrease of electrical
          excitation of Î²-cells should reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX>. To
          address this question, we measured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX> from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat islets</ENAMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 nM</NUMEX>) increase both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">basal</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> in the extracellular solution) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evoked</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.6</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> in the extracellular solution)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion rates. However, as we expected, in
          BIM-treated islets <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">80 nM</NUMEX>) decreased the rates of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). These data indicate that PMA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">regulates insulin</ENAMEX> secretion mediated by a mixed
          mechanism, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-dependent increase of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion
          and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-independent decrease of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Phorbol esters are often used as activators of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> to
        investigate the role of the kinase in cellular functions [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ] . Accumulating lines of evidence indicates that PMA
        plays a complex role in regulation of cellular function,
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PKC-dependent</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20</NUMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-independent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24 21</NUMEX> ] . In the present results, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PMA</ENAMEX> inhibited
        slow membrane depolarization and action potentials in
        response to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose stimulation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), and caused a
        membrane hyperpolarization in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> Î²-cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). These
        findings are consistent with the observation that
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tetradecanoylphorbol 13</NUMEX>-acetate lowers [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i at a stimulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> concentration
        in pancreatic islets from obese-hyperglycaemic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ]
        . Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), it is obvious
        that the hyperpolarization caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> results from
        activation of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> type, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> inhibition of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glucose</ENAMEX>-induced electrical excitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> Î²-cells is
        ascribable at least in part to hyperpolarization resulting
        from an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity. The activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> can be regulated by changes in
        intracellular concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP/ADP</ENAMEX> ratio [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
        ] . In order to examine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> decrease Î²-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentration</ENAMEX>, we measured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> content of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat islets</ENAMEX>, and
        results indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> did not change <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> levels in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">islets</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). It is not clear at present whether ADP
        concentrations are changed by the phorbol ester. Under a
        condition where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> concentration in the Î²-cell was clamped
        at a constant level, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increased tolbutamide-sensitive
        currents in response to voltage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ramps</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-90</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-50</NUMEX> mV
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Furthermore, in inside-out single channel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recordings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> restored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity, which had been reduced by
        the preceding application of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6panels C</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>).
        Together, these findings support the idea that PMA
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> does not result from a change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
        concentration.
        In cardiac myocytes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> is known to activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> through activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20</NUMEX>
        ] . In <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-secreting cell lines as well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activation
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> was shown to potentiate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] . In the present
        study, however, the activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> is independent on
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. First, the PKC
        activation inhibitor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX>, did not prevent either the
        PMA-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hyperpolarization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2panels B & C</ENAMEX>) or
        augmentation of whole-cell membrane currents (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4panels
        C & <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the non-PKC-stimulating phorbol ester,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Î±</NUMEX>-PDD, mimicked the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>).
        Pharmacological effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> independent of activation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> have been demonstrated in various tissues [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24</NUMEX> ]
        . Since the magnitude of hyperpolarization induced by PMA
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>) and the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6panel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>) were not
        significantly different between cells treated or untreated
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX>, activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> seems to show little effect on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> , at least in this cell type. In
        this regard, the present findings support the idea derived
        from previous findings on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] or
        obese-hyperglycaemic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> Î²-cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . However,
        PMA-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-independent hyperpolarization of Î²-cells
        was not previously reported [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] . The reason for the
        discrepancy is not clear at the moment. The difference in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species (rat</ENAMEX> in the present study and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> in previous
        studies) could be one explanation. In addition,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperpolarization</ENAMEX> in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> might be unnoticed
        under some conditions with intracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> at particular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentrations</ENAMEX>, because, as shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6panel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>, the
        effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity, which produces
        hyperpolarization, varied as a function of intracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> concentration.
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possible explanations for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-independent activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> by phorbol esters: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) phorbol esters
        may increase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity in an intracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>-independent manner and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) phorbol esters may reduce
        sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>. The first possibility can be
        discounted because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> does not affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
        6panel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> restoration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity which had been reduced by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6panels <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>) supports the conclusion that
        phorbol esters decrease <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> sensitivity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>.
        In the present study, application of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> potentiated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat islets</ENAMEX> in response to elevation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">extracellular glucose concentration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>), supporting
        the hypothesis that activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> synergizes secretory
        process activated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose stimulation</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> is known to selectively inhibit Î± and Î² PKC isotypes [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ] , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat pancreatic</ENAMEX> Î²-cells possess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> PKC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isotype</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . In fact, in this study, the treatment of
        islets with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> reversed the PMA effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> can be used as a PKC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibitor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat pancreatic</ENAMEX> Î²-cells, as already shown in
        other tissues including murine macrophages [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] , rat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adrenal cortex</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] , human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">melanocytes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] and rabbit
        vetricular myocytes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] .
        Recent reports with a truncated isoform of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir6.2</ENAMEX> have
        revealed that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>-inhibitory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> lies on the Kir6.2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subunit</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30</NUMEX> ] . In addition, mutations of the
        C-terminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kir6.2</ENAMEX> showed that the amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> sequence of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX> was responsible for regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
        sensitivity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . It is not clear at present
        whether phorbol ester effects reflection at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX>.
        In addition, other recent studies have shown that the
        membrane phospholipid
        phosohatidylinositol-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">bis</NUMEX>-phosphate (PIP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) reduces sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, and therefore, activates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> report of regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity by phorbol ester in rat
        Î²-cells. The present findings provide new insight into
        mechanisms of PMA regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        The major and important finding in this study is that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> impairs electrical excitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat pancreatic</ENAMEX> Î²-cells
        through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-independent mechanism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity, induces a membrane
        hyperpolarization, then reduces the electrical excitability
        of pancreatic Î²-cells, leading to a decrease of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX>. Reduction of sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> seems to underlie the
        PMA-induced impairment of Î²-cells electrical excitation in
        response to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> stimulation. These results provide a
        novel insight of modulation mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, increases <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion by activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>,
        and meanwhile decrease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion by impairing
        Î²-cell excitability in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-independent manner in rat
        pancreatic Î²-cells.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Islet preparation and Î²-cell isolation
          Isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat islets</ENAMEX> was performed as previously
          described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36</NUMEX> ] . In short, male adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar</ENAMEX>)
          were anesthetized with diethyl ether, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ml <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX>'s
          buffered saline (HBSS) containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">collagenase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 U/ml,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wako Chem.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>) was injected into the common bile
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">duct</ENAMEX>. The pancreas swollen with digestion solution was
          quickly excised and incubated in a plastic culture bottle
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. The suspension obtained by shaking
          the bottle was filtered through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mm metal mesh and
          washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> including <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> bovine serum albumin (BSA).
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 100</NUMEX> islets were obtained from one rat with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">histopaque</ENAMEX> (specific gravity <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.077</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) gradient
          method. After washing with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HBSS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, islets
          were cultured for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C02</TIMEX> in the tissue
          culture medium. Separation of islets was carried out
          using dispase (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Godo Shusei</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>) as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . Separated cells were again
          cultured for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-4 days</TIMEX>. Only single cells were chosen for
          experiments. Î²-cells were identified by detecting the
          responses of the cells to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tolbutamide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Patch-clamp recordings
          Cells were kept in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-mm Petri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX>, and the dish
          was placed on the stage of an inverted microscope (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IMT-2</ENAMEX>,
          Olympus, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>). Membrane potentials and membrane
          currents were measured using a patch-clamp amplifier
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EPC-7</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">List Electronic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Darmstadt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>). The
          nystatin-perforation method [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] was used to measure
          the membrane potential, and the standard method was used
          to measure whole-cell currents [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> of
          the electrode, filled with the pipette solution, ranged
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 2 to 4</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MÎ©.</ENAMEX> To measure the whole-cell membrane
          current, voltage ramp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pulses</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-90</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-50</NUMEX> mV were
          repeatedly applied using a ramp pulse generator
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SET-2100</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nihon Kohden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>). The membrane
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">capacitance</ENAMEX> ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 to 14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pF</ENAMEX>. Series resistances
          below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MÎ</ENAMEX>© were accepted. Single channel current
          recordings were carried out by the cell-attached and
          inside-out configurations. All electrophysiological
          experiments were carried out at room temperature. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data of</ENAMEX>
          single channel currents were low-pass filtered at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KHz</ENAMEX>,
          digitized at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KHz</ENAMEX> and analyzed using a single channel
          current analysis program (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">QP-120J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nihon Kohden</ENAMEX>). The
          open time probability (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po</ENAMEX>) of the single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> was
          calculated according to the equation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 - Pc1</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> where
          pc is the total closed time probability and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> is the
          total number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> was shown as function of the
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>. Theoretical curves for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
          inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> activity were fitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">equation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P/Po</ENAMEX>)=l/{<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>+ ([<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>]/ki)h} where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> is the open
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> probability with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> at each concentration, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po</ENAMEX> is
          the open time probability without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>] is the
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, ki is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> concentration at
          which the inhibition is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> maximal, and h is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coefficient</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Measurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> content
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> concentration of islets was measured by the
          luciferin-luciferase method [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . Assay kits (FL-ASC)
          were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> assay, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> isolated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat pancreatic</ENAMEX> islets were suspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> ml standard
          extracellular solution. After application of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> at the
          final concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> nM, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">islet</TIMEX> suspensions
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">containing 17</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">islets</ENAMEX> were transferred to reaction tubes,
          and the amount of emission was immediately measured using
          a luminescence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BLR-301</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aloka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bioluminescence</ENAMEX> produced by the luciferin-luciferase
          reaction was amplified and output as the count rate (cpm)
          after converting pulse signals. Using a calibration
          curve, values of counting rate were calculated in terms
          of moles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Measurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> secretion
          Isolated islets were hand-picked under microscopy, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> islets were distributed to each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-mm Petri</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HBSS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>. After pre-incubation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 min</TIMEX>, islets were
          exposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Î¼M BIM for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 min</TIMEX>, and then measured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          secretion rate. The PMA effects with or without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin secretion</ENAMEX> were measured by using immuno-reactive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> (IRI) and stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-20Â°C until the assay</TIMEX>. IRI
          was measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIA</ENAMEX> using anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin antibody</ENAMEX>
          with rat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> standard (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Radio-immunoassay Kit, Insulin</ENAMEX>
          "Eiken", <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo Japan</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solutions and Drugs</ENAMEX>
          The standard extracellular solution contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX> mM
          NaCl, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.6</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.2 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MgCl2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CaCl2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.3</NUMEX>. For membrane potential
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recordings</ENAMEX>, the pipette solution contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K-gluconate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml nystatin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>),
          pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX>. For whole-cell recordings, the pipette solution
          contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K-gluconate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX>. For cell-attached and inside-out single
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> recordings, the pipette solution contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM HEPES</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.3</NUMEX>. The ionic composition of the solution
          inside the membrane (bath solution) in inside-out
          recordings was the same as that of the pipette solution,
          but the pH of this solution was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX>. In inside-out
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recordings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> was added to the bath solution at various
          concentrations. Phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-myristate 13</NUMEX>-acetate (PMA),
          4a-phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,13</NUMEX>-didecanoate (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4a</NUMEX>-PDD),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bisindolylmaleimide</ENAMEX> (BIM) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCN</ENAMEX> were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4a-PDD</ENAMEX> were dissolved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, and the
          final concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> in the experimental
          solution was less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> was dissolved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>,
          and the final concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX> in the experimental
          solution was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>. Cells in the experimental bath were
          continuously exposed to a stream of the extracellular
          solution throughout the experiment. In the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">islets</ENAMEX> or cells were preincubated in the solution
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">containing BIM</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼M</NUMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-60 min</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIM</ENAMEX> was present
          in the bath <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> throughout the experiment
        
        
          Statistics
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were expressed as mean Â± <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> of several
          experiments, and statistical significance was evaluated
          by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-tail paired and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unpaired</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX>'s t-tests. A
          value of P <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 0.05</NUMEX> was accepted as
          significant.
          This study was carried out in accordance with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guidelines for Animal Experimentation</ENAMEX>, Hirosaki
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        List of abbreviations
        phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-myristate 13</NUMEX>-acetate (PMA), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase C
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP-sensitive K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> ), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4a</NUMEX>-phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,13</NUMEX>-didecanoate
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4a</NUMEX>-PDD), bisindolylmaleimide (BIM).
      
    
  
