
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytomegalovirus</ENAMEX> (CMV) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epstein-Barr</ENAMEX> virus (EBV), in
        immunocompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, are etiologically associated
        with infectious mononucleosis as well as other disease
        presentations and malignancies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] . Once a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has
        recovered from an active herpesvirus infection, it will
        establish a latent infection. Maintenance of viral latency
        is primarily determined by the immune status of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>;
        but there are other factors that can contribute to
        herpesviral reactivation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] .
        There are numerous studies observing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> and EBV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivation</ENAMEX> in immunosuppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> is the most
        important pathogen among these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and the virus can
        cause both direct and indirect effects [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 10 11 12 13</NUMEX> ]
        . Among solid organ transplant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, the effects of
        CMV <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> are similar among all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, with the
        exception being the effect on the transplanted organ [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15 16 17</NUMEX> ] . The most common <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> presentation of CMV
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> is retinitis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 11</ENAMEX> ] . The significance
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CMV disease</ENAMEX> in transplant and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
        goes much further than the direct pathological effects
        because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> has been shown to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immune modulator</ENAMEX> and
        may contribute significantly to the net immunosuppressive
        status of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . This immunomodulation would
        therefore increase the susceptibility to superinfections
        from other pathogens.
        Oral hairy leukoplakia, caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX>, can be present in
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 18</ENAMEX> ] . Other clinical
        presentations have been observed as well [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 19 20</ENAMEX> ] . Birx
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">et al.</ENAMEX> observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> or AIDS-related
        disorders have a defect in the regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> infected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-cells</ENAMEX> and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have high circulating numbers of
        lymphoproliferative disorder (PTLD) results from the
        uncontrolled lymphoproliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-cells</ENAMEX> in
        transplant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] . There are many known
        factors for the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTLD</ENAMEX>, among which is the
        presence of an active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> infection [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 19 22 23 24</NUMEX> ]
        .
        Many studies have focused upon the presence of a single
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">herpesvirus</ENAMEX> in the transplant or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 10</NUMEX> ] .
        There are fewer studies examining virus-virus interactions
        and the effect they may have on each other. Although
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have focused upon the relationship of
        human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">herpesvirus-6</ENAMEX> (HHV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) (same herpesvirus subfamily as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26 27 28 29</NUMEX> ] , studies dealing with
        potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herpesvirus-herpesvirus</ENAMEX> interactions are very
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX>. Such studies would be interesting since CMV
        infection has been suggested as a risk factor for the
        development of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTLD</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 24</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> have showed
        that a large percentage of transplant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had
        developed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTLD</ENAMEX> also had CMV disease [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 30</NUMEX> ] . In addition
        to CMV being implicated as a factor for the development of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTLD</ENAMEX>, serological studies have shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with an
        active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> infection experienced a serological profile of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reactivation</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 31 32</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> reactivities between
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viruses</ENAMEX> were ruled out as a cause for the observed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunoreactivations</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> study performed 
        in vitro superinfections of EBV
        positive cell lines (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akata, Raji</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX>) with HHV-6.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation was observed to occur in those cell lines
        that were superinfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HHV-6</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        hypothesized that there was a direct effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HHV-6</ENAMEX> on EBV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . A more recent study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vieira et</ENAMEX> al.
        was able to show human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">herpesvirus-8</ENAMEX> (HHV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) activation of
        lytic replication by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HHV-8</ENAMEX> is in the same
        herpesvirus subfamily as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX>. The clinical studies do
        suggest that there may be a relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>
        infection and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation, and the 
        in vitro studies strengthen the
        notion of potential herpesvirus-herpesvirus interactions
        occurring. However, the effect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> may have on each
        other has not specifically been investigated. Therefore
        this study examined an 
        in vitro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfection of EBV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">latently</ENAMEX> infected cell lines (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells) and
        the effect on EBV reactivation. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B-cell</ENAMEX> lines were
        observed to be susceptible to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfection and EBV
        reactivation occurs only in the cell lines superinfected
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>. The observations in this study support the
        previous 
        in vivo and 
        in vitro findings by showing that
        potential interactions exist between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX>. Overall,
        these data suggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> may be a cofactor in EBV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathogenesis</ENAMEX> in the immunosuppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        
          CMV transcript in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells
          The CMV MIE transcript was present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and
          P3HR-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells superinfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> at all time points as
          shown by the real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> data (Figures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1Aand 2A</TIMEX>,
          respectively). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> copy standards were run for
          calculation of the standard curve. The CMV standards (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ×
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 3</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 1</NUMEX>) for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells are
          shown (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1C</NUMEX>) and the standards for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells
          were not shown. Agarose gel analysis was run only with
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1D</NUMEX>) and the greatest amount of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcript</ENAMEX> was observed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> post CMV
          superinfection with a decline in the latter time points.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells that were exposed to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UV-irradiated CMV</ENAMEX> had no presence of the CMV MIE
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcript</ENAMEX>, indicating that the virus was inactivated
          (Figures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1Band 2B</TIMEX>, respectively). The uninfected cell
          lines were negative for the CMV MIE transcript and show
          that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> primers do not cross-react with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> (data
          not shown). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P3HR-1</ENAMEX>) show the
          quantitative analyses calculated from the standard curve.
          The calculated starting quantity (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SQ</ENAMEX>) values given in
          both tables suggest that these cell lines, although they
          are susceptible to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>, do not show a high amount of
          infection. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mock RT-PCRs</ENAMEX> were performed in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> grade
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was substituted for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> enzyme. These mock
          reactions served as a check for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> contamination and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mock RT-PCRs</ENAMEX> of the respective experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were
          negative (data not shown).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CMV antigen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells
          Immunofluorescent staining for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p52 antigen</ENAMEX> was
          performed to further show the susceptibilities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cell lines. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p52</NUMEX> gene expresses
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA binding protein</ENAMEX> that is present in the nuclei of
          infected cells beginning in the early phase of infection
          through to the late phase. All time points for both cell
          lines (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX>) were positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p52 antigen</ENAMEX>
          and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> slide is shown at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> post CMV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superinfection</ENAMEX> (Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3Aand 4A</ENAMEX>, respectively). All
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells exposed to UV-irradiated CMV
          were consistently negative for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p52 antigen</ENAMEX> indicating
          sufficient CMV inactivation (Figures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3Band 4B</TIMEX>,
          respectively). The uninfected cells from both cell lines
          were also negative showing no cross-reactivities with CMV
          (data not shown). Flow cytometric analysis was performed
          only with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> from the flow
          experiments were able to give a quantitative analysis by
          analyzing the fluorescence of the individual cells.
          Positive cells were determined by subtracting the
          background fluorescence of the uninfected samples from
          either the superinfected cells or cells exposed to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">inactivated</ENAMEX> virus. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CMV p52 antigen</ENAMEX> expression (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">575</NUMEX> cells)
          was observed beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX> compared to a
          background staining of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX> cells that were exposed to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inactivated CMV</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three hundred seventy nine</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> p52
          positive cells were present at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">96 and 168 hours</TIMEX>,
          respectively. The UV-irradiated CMV exposed cells had
          counts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 and 76</NUMEX> cells (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">96 and 168 hours</TIMEX>,
          respectively). Positive counts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells
          exposed to inactivated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> represents non-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staining</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> cells were collected and analyzed per
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">experimental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The flow cytometry data is summarized
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. The amount of CMV positive BJAB-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">B1</NUMEX> cells, as
          also observed in the real-time data, show a decrease with
          respect to time. Both the transcript data as well as the
          p52 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> expression data show that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells
          are susceptible to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfection and there was not
          a high amount of infection. Qualitative analyses of the
          immunofluorescent staining in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells
          also show that a low amount of infection was
          occurring.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> undergoes an abortive infection in BJAB-B1
          cells
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> abortive infection was not determined for the
          P3HR-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells. In order to determine if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> was undergoing
          an abortive or replicative infection, separate CMV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superinfection</ENAMEX> experiments were performed. Cells were
          washed after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 hours</TIMEX> incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> and fresh media
          was added. The CMV infections were carried out to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. Supernatants were taken immediately after washing
          to show absence of unattached <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>. Aliquots were taken at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 and 48 hours</TIMEX> for immunofluorescence analysis to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">confirm CMV</ENAMEX> infection (data not shown). After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX> the
          cells were vortexed and supernatant was collected and
          placed into cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MRC-5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fibroblasts</ENAMEX>. MRC-5
          infections were carried out to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPE</ENAMEX> was
          observed in any of the fibroblast infections, suggesting
          that an abortive infection was occurring in the BJAB-B1
          cells.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfections of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells
          This project has shown that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-1
          cells were susceptible to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfection by
          detecting viral transcript and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. The effect on EBV
          latency was next examined. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">BZLF1</NUMEX> gene product, Zebra
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zta</ENAMEX>) is an indicator for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ionomycin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μg/ml</ENAMEX>) non-specifically reactivates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> and
          was used as a positive control for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BZLF1</TIMEX> transcript
          expression in the cell lines. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-1
          cells were incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PMA</ENAMEX>/ionomycin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μg/ml</ENAMEX>)
          (Figures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5Aand 6A</TIMEX>, respectively). Presence of the BZLF1
          transcript in the superinfected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells was observed
          beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> post superinfection, decreased at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> and then was observed to increase after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX>
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6B</NUMEX>). Detection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BZLF1</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells was
          performed by real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> only. BZLF1 transcript in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells was first observed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> post CMV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superinfection</ENAMEX> and was expressed through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">to 96 hours</TIMEX>, as
          shown in the real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> data (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5B</NUMEX>). The amount
          of BZLF1 transcript expression in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells
          started to decrease after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX>. Agarose gel analysis
          confirms the real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> data and shows that the PCR
          was specific (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6D</NUMEX>). Due to the relatively low
          amount of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BZLF1 PCR</ENAMEX> product in the real-time data and
          gel analysis, it was expected that the immunofluorescence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staining</ENAMEX> would be minimal. Immunofluorescence analysis
          was performed only with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">experimental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that was superinfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> was
          observed to have expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BZLF1 protein</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">168</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7A</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells stimulated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>/ionomycin were used as a positive IF control (Figure
          7B). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uninfected</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">UV-irradiated CMV</ENAMEX> treated cells
          showed no expression of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">BZLF1</NUMEX> transcript or protein
          indicating no EBV reactivation (data not shown). Mock
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCRs</ENAMEX> were not performed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the BZLF1 PCR</TIMEX> reactions
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">G3PDH</NUMEX>)
          Amplification of the housekeeping gene G3PDH served as
          a control for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> integrity. The product was analyzed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agarose</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>) gel electrophoresis and stained with
          ethidium bromide. This transcript was present at all time
          points among all experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for both cell lines
          (data not shown).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        This study has shown that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cell
        lines were susceptible to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfection, and a low
        amount of infection was observed. Numerous studies have
        been able to show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMCs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-cells</ENAMEX> in particular can
        have expression of viral transcript and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37 38 39 40 41</NUMEX> ] however, other studies have been
        contradictory [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 42</NUMEX> ] and therefore no consensus among
        the observations noted. Early studies have shown that in
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B-cell</ENAMEX> lines, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> has been observed [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44 45</NUMEX> ]
        . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MOI</ENAMEX> used in this study (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX>) indicates that there were
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> virus particles per <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cell. This high
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOI</ENAMEX> would have seemed to ensure that enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CMV</ENAMEX> was present
        to superinfect the respective cell lines. However, despite
        the high MOI, the real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> and immunofluorescent
        staining data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells show low
        amounts of infection present.
        The concept of this study was to show evidence that CMV
        can superinfect these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">B-cell</ENAMEX> lines and may induce EBV
        reactivation by using a standardized CMV preparation.
        Infectivity differences have been observed between clinical
        isolates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> and laboratory adapted strains. The strain
        used in this study, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AD169</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Towne strains</ENAMEX> were both
        used to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] . Differences in
        infectivity have been observed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 2</NUMEX> of the same
        strains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> and this may be attributed to the deletion
        or mutation of certain tropism <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> upon extensive serial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">propagation</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 51</NUMEX> ] . Clinical isolates (wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>)
        can carry <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 220</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, and some of these genes can
        be lost by deletion and/or rearrangement during laboratory
        passage [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">AD169</NUMEX> strain used in this study has
        been passaged many times and because of these variations
        observed among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">CMV strains</ENAMEX>, this may partly account for
        the low infectivity observed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-1
        cells. Perhaps an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> infection in the cell
        lines could have been obtained with the use of a clinical
        isolate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> is currently collecting
        clinical isolates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> for future superinfection
        experiments.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> infection is attachment to its
        cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>; however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> have not
        yet been delineated. Heparin sulfate and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD13</ENAMEX> have been
        suggested to be involved in CMV attachment [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52 53 54</NUMEX> ] .
        Heparin sulfate is a receptor present on many cell types,
        but <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD13</ENAMEX> is not expressed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-cells</ENAMEX>. Even with these
        receptors being implicated as requirements for CMV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adherence</ENAMEX> and penetration, the wide range of cellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tropism</ENAMEX> observed would suggest that additional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
        might be used.
        The detection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CMV protein</ENAMEX> was performed to further
        show <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CMV</ENAMEX> infection in the cell lines used. The CMV p52
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antigen</ENAMEX> is expressed in the early phase of infection and in
        the nuclei of infected cells. During a replicative
        infection, expression of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> continues through to
        the late phase of infection [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> function of the
        p52 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is to aid in replication by binding to the
        viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX>. The immunofluorescence data confirms
        the real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> data showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-1
        cells were susceptible to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfection and a low
        amount of infection was observed. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p52</NUMEX> expression as
        shown in the flow cytometry data of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells also
        indicate that a low amount of infection was observed. The
        numbers of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p52</NUMEX> positive cells was also observed to decrease
        with respect to time, perhaps indicating an abortive
        infection may be occurring. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPE</ENAMEX> was observed in any of
        the fibroblast superinfection studies indicating a lack of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extracellular</ENAMEX> CMV infectious particles. We did not test for
        cell associated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> in these experiments, so it is possible
        that virus emerging from the infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-cell</ENAMEX> line may be
        bound to other cells in the culture. However, the fact that
        only a small percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-cells</ENAMEX> showed evidence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> infection along with the lack of virus in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supernatant</ENAMEX> supports the probability that the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CMV</ENAMEX> infection
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells represents an abortive infection. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> represented here support the work of others showing
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> may undergo an abortive infection in B-cells
        rather than a productive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36 46 47 48</NUMEX> ] .
        Regardless of whether viable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> or UV-irradiated CMV is
        used, the virus still can attach to the host <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> and cause
        the upregulation of cellular genes, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proto-oncogenes</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55 57 58 59</NUMEX> ] . It was observed in this
        study that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UV-irradiated CMV</ENAMEX> had no effect on BZLF1
        transcript expression, suggesting that the effect observed
        in the superinfected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells was not
        attachment mediated and infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> is at least
        required. At this point it has not been determined if CMV
        acts directly or indirectly to cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">EBV reactivation</ENAMEX>. A
        direct effect would imply that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> transactivator is
        produced that could somehow cause the expression of or at
        least aid in the activation of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">BZLF1</NUMEX> gene. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flamand et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al.</ENAMEX> observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HHV-6</ENAMEX> (same subfamily as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>) could cause
        the reactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> suggested that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HHV-6</ENAMEX> was having a direct effect on EBV reactivation
        because they were able to observe the presence of both
        viral antigens in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. However, this observation
        does not necessarily suggest direct activation because the
        effect cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> may have on EBV latency is not
        known. There may be some as yet unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> cell gene or
        genes that are activated or upregulated in association with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HHV-6</ENAMEX> penetration and infection. Obviously the same
        uncertainties can be applied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfections of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">BZLF1</NUMEX> gene of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> is an immediate early gene
        involved in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation, and its
        activity is controlled at the transcriptional level [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60 61</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62 63 64 65 66</NUMEX> ] , by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-protein interactions</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64 65</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66 67 68</NUMEX> ] , and phosphorylation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64 69 70</NUMEX> ] . Perhaps CMV
        may cause the activation of certain cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kinases</ENAMEX>, which
        in turn may activate BZLF1 transcript expression. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> has
        been shown to cause calcium flow and protein kinase <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX> (PKC)
        activation that could then be involved in the early
        activation of transcription factors [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX> ] . Cellular
        levels of secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messengers</ENAMEX> inositol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,4,5</NUMEX>-triphosphate
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,2</NUMEX>-diacylglycerol [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71 72 73</NUMEX> ] , as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ERK1 and ERK2</TIMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74 75</NUMEX> ] are also known to be
        upregulated, which may have an effect on EBV reactivation.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> study performed a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> microarray analysis on CMV
        infected cells and observed an upregulation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">258</NUMEX> cellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNAs</ENAMEX> whose level changes were by a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> or more
        after the onset of viral replication [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">76</TIMEX> ] . The functions
        of some of these genes still remains highly speculative,
        yet it gives an insight as to what potential roles these
        genes may play, particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation.
        The CMV transcript expression in BJAB-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">B1</NUMEX> cells was
        observed beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> and was expressed through to
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">168 hours</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">BZLF1</NUMEX> transcript was observed beginning at
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> and expressed though <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">96 hours</TIMEX>. There was a greater
        amount of CMV MIE transcript present compared to the BZLF1
        transcript in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells. BZLF1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expression
        was observed only at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">168 hours</TIMEX> post CMV superinfection. CMV
        p52 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expression was observed through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">168 hours</TIMEX> post
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superinfection</ENAMEX> (immunofluorescence and flow cytometry data)
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p52</NUMEX> positive cells peaked at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX> (flow cytometry).
        Among the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells, the CMV transcript was also
        expressed from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">96 hours to 168 hours</TIMEX>; however, the viral
        load increases with respect to time as opposed to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells. During the earlier time points (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 48</TIMEX>, and
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX>), the sample curves have not yet crossed the
        threshold and therefore were not included in the program's
        final quantitative analysis. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">BZLF1</NUMEX> transcript in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superinfected</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells shows presence at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>,
        decreases at subsequent time points and finally peaks at
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">168 hours</TIMEX>. Differences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BZLF1</ENAMEX> transcript
        expression between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells may be
        attributed to the fact that these are different cell lines,
        despite the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX>. The kinetic expression of both
        viral transcripts and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> in the respective cell lines
        would seem to suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> may be having an indirect
        effect on EBV reactivation through the participation of
        cellular factors.
        Despite the low infectivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-1
        cells by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation was observed in the
        experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> superinfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>. The cell lines
        that were exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UV-irradiated CMV</ENAMEX> had no indication of
        BZLF1 transcript or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> suggesting that the effect on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation was not attachment mediated and that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infectious CMV</ENAMEX> was required. 
        In vivo , it would be difficult to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pinpoint</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> specific factor to cause the switch from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">latency</ENAMEX> to lytic infection. However, 
        in vitro , it was most interesting to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">observe EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation only in the cell lines that were
        superinfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>.
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CMV</ENAMEX> infection, 
        in vivo , can contribute to the net
        immunosuppressive status of the immunocompromised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> ] . A <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CMV</ENAMEX> infection can result in the production of
        certain <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immune effector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (cytokines and chemokines)
        that may affect latency in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-cells</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77</TIMEX> ]
        . The production of these cytokines and chemokines from a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> may affect
        neighboring cells and therefore cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">EBV reactivation</ENAMEX>,
        implying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> could be having an indirect effect on EBV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">latency</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Because <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CMV</ENAMEX> infection and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> is such an important
        concern among the immunosuppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient populations</ENAMEX>
        (transplant and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>), its involvement
        in the reactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> must be considered. This report
        has shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> cells, both latently
        infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX>, were susceptible to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfection
        and only in the experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that were superinfected
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> were there any indication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation.
        These data support the clinical studies showing an 
        in vivo relationship between a CMV
        active infection and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation. Although it would be
        very difficult to prove that a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CMV</ENAMEX> infection is the cause
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> reactivation in clinical situations due to the gamut
        of factors that are involved, the fact that EBV
        reactivation was observed after 
        in vitro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfections supports
        this role. Inducers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> replication are of importance
        because of the serious complications that are associated
        with recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">EBV infections</ENAMEX>, particularly in
        immunosuppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. Since a majority of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> is seropositive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>, reactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> in
        immunosuppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> may further accentuate the
        reactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> therefore contributing to the
        proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-cells</ENAMEX>. The results in this
        project suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> may contribute as a co-factor in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> pathogenesis. More detailed molecular studies are
        needed to examine the direct and/or indirect effects CMV
        may have on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Cells and virus
          P3HR-1 (ATCC) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells (generously donated by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Miller</ENAMEX>) are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX> latently infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B-cells</ENAMEX> kept
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> medium (supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> and an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic-mycotic solution</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco, Invitrogen Corp.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AD169</NUMEX> laboratory strain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> was
          from the clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">virology laboratory</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX> General
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>), and used for the superinfections.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> was grown and harvested from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MRC-5</ENAMEX> fibroblast
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cultures</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biowhittaker, Walkersville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) and
          concentrated by ultra-centrifugation (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">28000 g</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4°C</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> titer was determined using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shell</ENAMEX> vial assay. Briefly, this is an immunofluorescence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> in which <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:10 dilutions</TIMEX> of the virus were prepared
          in shell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vials</ENAMEX> and incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">37°C overnight</TIMEX>. The MRC-5
          cells in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shell vials</ENAMEX> were fixed and permeabilized for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX>:acetone (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1</ENAMEX>) and then washed in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartels Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intracel Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconstituted</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> liter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Millipore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.6</NUMEX>).
          The cells were stained with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> labelled antibody
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> against the major immediate early <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> (MIE)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemicon, Temecula</ENAMEX>, CA) and visualized using a
          fluorescent microscope. Each green (positive) cell was
          counted as one viral particle.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-1
          cells
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> cells were counted using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cell-DYN</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4000</TIMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbott Systems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abbott Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) and placed in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well
          culture plate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> medium. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P3HR-1</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells were infected at a multiplicity of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infection</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOI</ENAMEX>) of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> and were either uninfected,
          infected, or exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">UV-irradiated</ENAMEX> virus. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> was
          exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">UVC</ENAMEX> light for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> in our biological safety
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cabinet</ENAMEX>. The experiments were carried out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX> and
          samples were taken at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 48, 72, 96</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">168 hours</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
          points for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were the same except for an
          additional time point at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">120 hours</TIMEX>. At each time point,
          cells were analyzed by immunofluorescence and real-time
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were not subjected to flow cytometric
          analysis. Superinfections were repeated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> shown are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> experiments.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MRC-5</ENAMEX> fibroblast infection of supernatants from CMV
          superinfections
          Separate superinfection experiments of the BJAB-B1
          cells were set up and were incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 hours</TIMEX>
          to allow for viral attachment. The cells were then washed
          to remove any unattached virus and fresh medium was
          added. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> superinfections were carried out to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. The cultures were vortexed, supernatant was
          collected, and added to cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MRC-5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fibroblasts</ENAMEX>.
          Supernatant fluid was collected immediately after
          infection and washing to establish that any unattached
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> was not present. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MRC-5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> were examined for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPE</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Immunofluorescent staining for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p52</TIMEX> (CMV) and BZLF1
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBV</ENAMEX>)
          Aliquots of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 μl</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 50,000</NUMEX> cells) from
          each experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were subjected to a cytospin and
          fixed and permeabilized similarly to the shell vial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX>. The anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p52</NUMEX> and anti-BZLF1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (Dako
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation, Carpinteria</ENAMEX>, CA) were prepared according to
          package inserts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> was added to the final p52
          solution. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p52 antibody</ENAMEX> was directly labelled with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> (fluorescein isothiocyanate) and did not require a
          secondary antibody step. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BZLF1 antibody</ENAMEX> is unlabelled
          and required a secondary goat anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>
          labelled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX>. The secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was diluted
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:200</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> was added. The primary and
          secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were incubated in a humidified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>. The slides were washed in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> after each incubation step, prepared with mounting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, and visualized under a fluorescent microscope.
        
        
          Flow cytometry of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p52 antigen</ENAMEX>
          Aliquots of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 μl</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 150,000</NUMEX> cells) were
          placed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcon</ENAMEX> tubes and washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. The cells
          were fixed and permeabilized with pre-made <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caltag Laboratories</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burlingame</ENAMEX>, CA) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fix & Perm</ENAMEX>)
          according to kit instructions. During the
          permeabilization step, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FITC-labelled antibody</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">p52</NUMEX>) was
          added at a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:5</ENAMEX> dilution. Cells were washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and
          then <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">750 μl</NUMEX> of paraformaldehyde was added and read on the
          FACScalibur flow cytometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>, CA). Fluorescence parameters were set with
          regards to infected and uninfected samples. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> infected
          and uninfected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MRC-5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> were used as positive
          controls for viable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody staining</ENAMEX>. 10,000
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells were first separated according to size and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">granularity</ENAMEX> (forward vs. side scatter) on a dot plot.
          Viable cells were then selected and gated for further
          analysis on a histogram for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FL1</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p52 antigen</ENAMEX>)
          versus cell counts. The final histogram analyses involved
          subtracting background of the corresponding mock-infected
          cells from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells superinfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UV-irradiated CMV</ENAMEX>. Analysis was performed using the
          CellQuest software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, CA).
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">P3HR</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were not analysed by flow cytometry.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> extraction and isolation
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleic acid isolation</ENAMEX> was performed on an
          automated extractor from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organon Tekinika Corporation</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boxtel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>) and the extractions were performed
          according to kit instructions modified from the method by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boom et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78</TIMEX> ] . All reagents used for extractions
          were from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Aliquots of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400 μl</NUMEX> (approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> cells) were used per experimental time point. The
          final result was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 50 μl</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleic acid</ENAMEX> in
          elution buffer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleic acid samples</ENAMEX> were then
          subjected to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DNase</ENAMEX> treatment and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> clean up with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambion's</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-free kit following their
          provided protocol.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> quantitation
          Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ribogreen</ENAMEX> dye and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> quantitation standards
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR), the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> in
          the experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were calculated. Briefly, an
          aliquot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA samples</ENAMEX> were diluted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100</ENAMEX> in TE
          buffer. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> standards were prepared (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4000, 2000, 1000</TIMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500, 250</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX> ng). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ribogreen</ENAMEX> dye was diluted
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:200 in TE</TIMEX> buffer and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 μl</NUMEX> of the diluted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (standard
          or sample) was mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 μl</NUMEX> of the diluted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ribogreen</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dye</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Samples</ENAMEX> and standards were placed in a microtiter
          plate and read on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">CytoFluor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosystems</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster City</ENAMEX>, CA) (excitation <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485 nm/20</NUMEX> nm and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">emission 530 nm/25 nm</ENAMEX>). The standard curve and sample
          quantitations were determined using an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excel</ENAMEX>
          spreadsheet.
        
        
          Reverse transcription
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> for cDNA production was performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>'s
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>) random hexamers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAsin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> buffer, and RT
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enzyme</ENAMEX>. For each sample, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 μg</ENAMEX>) was initially
          incubated with the random hexamers (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 μg</NUMEX>) and enough
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to bring the volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 20</NUMEX> μl.
          Incubation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> and random hexamers was performed
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX> and then held at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. The RT mix
          included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.6</NUMEX> μl of 5X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> buffer, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX> mM of dNTPs (with
          dTTP, not dUTP, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer, Foster City</ENAMEX>, CA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.22</NUMEX>
          units of AMV RT enzyme, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> units of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNAsin</ENAMEX> per
          reaction. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9.68 μl</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix</ENAMEX> was added to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA samples</ENAMEX> (with the random hexamers) and then
          subjected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> cycle conditions (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">42°C</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 minutes</TIMEX>,
          95°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4°C</NUMEX> hold). All incubations were
          done on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX>'s iCycler (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, CA). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mock RTs</ENAMEX> were
          set up in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was substituted for the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> enzyme as a check for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> contamination.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Real-time PCR</ENAMEX>
          The PCR <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix</ENAMEX> per reaction included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> μl <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SYBR Green</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 μM</NUMEX> dNTP mix (with dUTP), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 </NUMEX>l
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> primer mix, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX> Ampli 
          Taq <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> units of
          uracil-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-glycosylase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNG, Epicentre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>) that
          had been diluted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:10</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNG</ENAMEX> buffer, and molecular grade
          water to bring the volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 45</NUMEX> μl with the addition
          of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 μl</NUMEX> of cDNA or standard. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reagents were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> primers, from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synthetic Genetics, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA), amplify the MIE
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">BZLF1</NUMEX> primers recognize only mRNA and the
          sequences are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTCCACAGCCTGCACCAGTG-3</ENAMEX>' and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGCAGCAGCCACCTCACGGT-3</ENAMEX>' [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">79</TIMEX> ] . Primers were
          generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Genosys</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Woodlands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>). The CMV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was quantitative and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">BZLF1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was qualitative.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> pre-incubation steps, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37°C/15</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes and 95°C/10 minutes</TIMEX> (for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">UNG activation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNG</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">denaturation/</ENAMEX> 
          Taq activation). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> for PCR
          were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95°C/30</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55°C/30</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72°C/30</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CMV DNA</ENAMEX> copy standards (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synthetic</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetics, Inc.</ENAMEX>) were used to set up a standard curve.
          Standards were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500000, 5000</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CMV DNA</ENAMEX> copies.
          Dilutions were set up using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The software
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, CA) calculated the standard curve as
          well as determined the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CMV DNA</ENAMEX> in the
          superinfected samples. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agarose</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>) gel electrophoresis
          was performed in order to determine the specificity of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reactions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BJAB-B1</ENAMEX> cells only. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primers</ENAMEX> and
          positive control for the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">glyceraldehyde-3-phosphate</ENAMEX>
          dehydrogenase housekeeping gene were from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clontech</ENAMEX> (BD
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosciences Clontech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, CA). PCR recipe and
          conditions were run according to the included protocol.
          G3PDH transcripts from both cell lines were analyzed on a
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> agarose gel only.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Real-time PCR</ENAMEX> analysis
          The instrument camera took numerous fluorescence
          readings during the annealing stages and displayed the
          average reading for that particular cycle. At the end of
          the PCR cycling, the base line fluorescence was
          calculated and all the samples were normalized to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>.
          The threshold level (C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> ) was set at a point when the
          standards or positive control were in its respective
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exponential</ENAMEX> phase of amplification. The C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> value is the cycle number in which a
          sample's fluorescence crosses the set threshold level,
          and therefore is called positive. During quantitative
          analysis, the standard curve was calculated and the
          sample concentrations were derived from the curve. All
          calculations were performed with the included
          software.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RCA</ENAMEX> performed all assays, drafted the manuscript, and
        participated in the conception of this project. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RHW</ENAMEX> also
        participated in the conception as well as real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> and
        flow cytometry analyses.
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> have read and approved the final
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
