
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glycosaminoglycans</ENAMEX> (GAGs) are negatively charged
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polysaccharides</ENAMEX> derived from an amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hexose</ENAMEX>. They are
        structural and functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">modulators</ENAMEX> of extracellular
        matrices that play important roles in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNS</ENAMEX> development and
        repair. They exhibit both stimulatory and inhibitory
        influences on neurite outgrowth and survival. Evidence
        demonstrates the ability of heparin sulfates (HSs) to bind
        to growth/trophic factors and selectively regulate such
        factors' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] . They can act as co-receptors
        of growth/trophic and survival factors to regulate cell
        behavior and/or restrict diffusion and create a relatively
        high local concentration of ligand.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Pigment epithelium-</ENAMEX>derived factor (PEDF) is an
        extracellular neuronal differentiation and survival factor
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> derived from the retina and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNS</ENAMEX>. It induces
        neuronal differentiation in retinoblastoma cells, protects
        retina neurons (including photoreceptors) from death by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> and other insults, and has a morphogenetic effect
        on photoreceptor cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5 6</NUMEX> ] . It also has
        neurotrophic effects on neurons from the cerebellum,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hippocampus</ENAMEX> and spinal cord [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9 10 11 12</NUMEX> ] . In the
        intact retina, this factor is identified as a secreted
        protein associated by ionic interactions with the
        interphotoreceptor matrix [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] , where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> are the
        major polyanionic components.
        Biochemically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50-kDa</NUMEX> glycoprotein with
        structural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homology</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the serine-protease
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibitor</ENAMEX> (serpin) superfamily [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3 15</ENAMEX> ] . However, it has
        no inhibitory effects on proteases. Its neurotrophic
        activities are independent of its protease inhibition
        potential but dependent on its interaction with
        cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 12 16 17 18</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> has high
        binding affinity for cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retinoblastoma Y</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        
          d 
         = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.7</NUMEX> nM), which is mediated by interactions between a
        region spanning amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> positions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78-121</NUMEX> of the PEDF
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polypeptide</ENAMEX> and the extracellular domains of the receptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Blockage of these interactions inhibits
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> neurotrophic effects. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> also has binding
        affinity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX>, such as, heparin, heparin- and
        chondroitin-sulfates, but this affinity is ~<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1000</NUMEX>-fold lower
        than for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
        
          d 
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Î¼M for the heparin-PEDF interactions) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 19</NUMEX> ] .
        The binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> is mediated by ionic interactions
        between an area clustered with positively charged lysines
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> and the negatively charged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX>. In the PEDF
        spatial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>, the putative GAG binding domain is
        distinct from and non-overlapping with the neurotrophic
        active region [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 20</NUMEX> ] .
        Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> coexists with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> in extracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">matrices</ENAMEX> and has binding affinity for them, it is of
        interest to investigate the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> on PEDF activity.
        Given that binding to cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> is the first
        step in the biological activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>, we used human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retinoblastoma Y</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells and their conditioned media (CM)
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of functional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF receptors</ENAMEX> and extracellular
        matrix components, respectively, to examine the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAG</ENAMEX> content
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> and their effects on PEDF ligand-receptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interactions</ENAMEX>. The data suggest that heparan sulfate
        participates in the formation of a PEDF binding complex
        with its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, and constitutes a positive
        modulator for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF-</ENAMEX>receptor interactions.
      
      
        Results
        
          Complex formation between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> and component(s) in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> conditioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma</ENAMEX> cells
          To determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> interacts with component(s)
          in media conditioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma</ENAMEX> cells (CM), we
          used an ultrafiltration assay. In this assay, soluble
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-kDa is filtered through a membrane with an
          exclusion limit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MW 100,000</NUMEX>, however it is retained
          upon formation of a complex larger than this limit [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ]
          . The binding reactions were with a given 125I-PEDF
          concentration and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>. Incubations were at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Â°C</NUMEX> to minimize
          enzymatic degradation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and glycosaminglycans
          during the reaction. We found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125I</NUMEX>-PEDF was
          retained by the membrane in the presence of concentrated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 4%</NUMEX> retention in the presence of
          defined medium (non-conditioned medium) concentrated in
          an identical fashion. Specific retention, termed PEDF
          bound, was calculated by subtracting the retention in
          defined media from that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>. Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1shows</TIMEX> that PEDF
          was specifically retained when mixed with soluble
          conditioned media and the value for PEDF bound increased
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proportionally</ENAMEX> to the concentration factor of the media
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). Interestingly, protease treatment of the CM
          did not abolish the binding (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B). These observations
          revealed that the retained forms in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> were PEDF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">complexes â‰¥ 100-kDa</ENAMEX>, and that the majority of these
          complexes were formed with soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CM</ENAMEX> components other
          than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heparin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX> in the conditioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> with
          affinity for PEDF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> and polyanions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> were fractionated by
          anion-exchange column chromatography followed by
          PEDF-affinity column chromatography (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The GAG
          content was followed by staining with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toluidine Blue-O</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C,2D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,2</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX>). The final <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fraction</TIMEX> (CM PEDF) contained
          components with binding affinity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> that stained
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toluidine Blue</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> and migrated as high molecular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weight GAGs</ENAMEX>.
          To determine the type of sulfated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, we
          designed a spectrophotometric assay using heparinase and
          heparitinase, specific degrading enzymes for heparin and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX>, respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The activities of both GAG
          lyases reached a plateau by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> of incubation (Figs.
          3A,3C) and the degradation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> substrates between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0-30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Î¼g</ENAMEX> was linear. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM PEDFcontained</ENAMEX> substrates
          for heparinase and heparitinase (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Figs.</ENAMEX> 3B,3<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>). The amount
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> was determined by comparison of the amount of Î”
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-hexuronate</NUMEX> produced with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CM samples</ENAMEX> to the standard
          curves with commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAGs</ENAMEX>. The estimated content of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> in CM varied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 12.4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22.7</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml for heparin and
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9-10 Î¼g/</ENAMEX>ml for HS-like molecules, among media
          conditioned by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different batches of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells. The
          estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAG</ENAMEX> content in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PEDFranged 0.2-1.8 Î¼g/Î¼l</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/Î¼l</ENAMEX> for heparin and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX>, respectively. Similar
          assays were followed with chondroitinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, but its
          substrates, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Î”Di4S</TIMEX>, dermatan and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Î”Di6S</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> were below
          detection limits. These results demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> and
          CM PEDFcontained heparin- and HS-like molecules,
          demonstrating that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells produced GAGs with binding
          affinity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> conditioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma</ENAMEX> cells enhances
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">125I</NUMEX>-PEDF binding to cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
          We have demonstrated previously that biologically
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">active 125I-PEDF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binds</ENAMEX> specifically, competitively and
          with high affinity to cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX>
          cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Because the reaction conditions were
          identical to those used for biological assays, the
          binding reactions were performed in the presence of media
          conditioned by the cells for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX> (CM). We
          investigated the effect of components of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>, a source
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">extracellular matrix</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF-</ENAMEX>receptor
          interactions using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> and non-conditioned defined media
          in radioligand binding assays. Comparison of reactions in
          the absence and presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> showed that the specific
          PEDF-binding to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.8</NUMEX>-fold
          higher with conditioned medium than with defined medium
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Note that with the binding method used, the
          amount of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125I</NUMEX>-PEDF retained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> without cells is the
          same to the amount of non-specific 125I-PEDF binding
          (reactions with cells and in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-fold
          molar excess of unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] , indicating
          retention by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEI</ENAMEX>-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass-fiber</ENAMEX> filters of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF-receptor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAG-PEDF-</ENAMEX>receptor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> rather than
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF-GAG</ENAMEX>. Similar results were obtained when the
          cell-bound 125I-PEDF was separated by centrifugation,
          rather than filtration through <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass-fiber</ENAMEX> filters, and
          comparing reactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> versus those with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> (data not shown). These observations showed that a
          component(s) secreted by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma</ENAMEX> cells enhanced
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF-</ENAMEX>receptor interactions.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> lyases and chlorate on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125I</NUMEX>-PEDF
          binding to cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
          To deplete the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-79 cell cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX> and
          heparin-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX>, we used heparitinase and heparinase,
          respectively. The cultures were pretreated with each GAG
          lyase before using them in radioligand binding assays.
          The morphology and viability of the cells were not
          affected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> lyase treatments. Figure 5Ashows
          that specific 125I-PEDF binding decreased significantly
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heparitinase</ENAMEX> treated cultures compared to untreated
          controls, and less drastically in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heparinase</ENAMEX> treated
          ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hyaluronidase</ENAMEX> treatment to deplete the cultures of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyaluronan</ENAMEX> did not have an effect on the binding. These
          results demonstrated that removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heparin</ENAMEX>/HS from the
          cell cultures decreased the PEDF binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chlorate</ENAMEX> is a competitive inhibitor of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>-sulfurylase, and inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> sulfation in cell
          cultures can be achieved by pretreatment of the cultures
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorate</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . The effect of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undersulfated GAGs</ENAMEX> on the PEDF binding to its receptor
          was examined. Cells pretreated with sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorate</ENAMEX> did
          not show changes in viability or morphology; however, the
          treatment resulted in a decrease in the specific
          125I-PEDF binding to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 35%</NUMEX> relative to untreated
          controls (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B). Sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfate</ENAMEX> was used to recover
          the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> sulfation by chlorate increasing the
          binding to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX> maximal with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM sulfate additions. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> revealed that inhibition of sulfation of GAGs
          reduced the PEDF binding to cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20%</NUMEX> of specific inhibition. Thus,
          these observations implied that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS/heparin</ENAMEX> might play a
          functional role in the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> to its
          cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        It has been proposed that the GAG-binding property of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> provides the molecular basis for its association with
        extracellular matrices and may serve to localize PEDF
        activity in the retina and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNS</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 19</NUMEX> ] . However, the
        present results point to direct effects these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polysaccharides</ENAMEX> might have on the biochemical interactions
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF receptors</ENAMEX> on the surfaces of cells
        that respond to this neurotrophic factor. We have shown
        that the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in retinoblastoma
        cells is enhanced by the presence of extracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heparin/HS</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX>, which can be found in the culture
        medium of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma</ENAMEX> cells. The fact that the binding
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> to cell surfaces decreases with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heparin</ENAMEX>/HS
        depletion, implies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heparin</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HS</ENAMEX> molecules might act as
        cofactors for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF-</ENAMEX>receptor interactions. Interactions
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> and extracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> can also explain the
        complex formed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> even after protease
        treatment of the latter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF-heparin/HS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> may
        somehow facilitate encounters between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> and its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">receptor,</ENAMEX> 
        e.g. , by inducing a conformational
        change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>, which might accelerate the ligand-receptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interactions</ENAMEX>. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> may also form a
        complex with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heparin</ENAMEX>/HS to facilitate interactions with the
        production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma</ENAMEX> cells. We found that
        these cells produce <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HS</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heparin</ENAMEX> secreted into the culturing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>. The retina and malignant solid tumors also produce
        the sulfated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 22 23 24 25 26</NUMEX> ] . Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSs</ENAMEX> are
        mostly found as proteoglycans associated with the basal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lamina</ENAMEX> or the plasma membrane, the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSs</ENAMEX> in the
        culturing medium might be a result of shedding or release
        of their extracellular domains from the cell membranes as
        soluble components. Cell-associated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX> proteoglycans can
        undergo regulated shedding from the membrane into the
        soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">extracellular matrix</ENAMEX> or culturing medium converting
        the membrane anchored molecules into soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">effectors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ] . In the conditioned media of all the tested batches of
        retinoblastoma cells, we detected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heparin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX> with
        binding affinity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>. The estimated concentrations of
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> may vary with cell density and
        conditioning time. However, under the conditions used, they
        were within the linear range of HS-PEDF complex formation (
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] .
        The fact that depletion of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heparin</ENAMEX>/HS-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> from the
        culturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> results in inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> binding to
        cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> points to functional roles for these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAGs</ENAMEX> such as those of positive modulators of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF-</ENAMEX>receptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interactions</ENAMEX>. In this regard, we observed that depletion
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-79 cell cultures of heparin with heparinase was
        lower than those depleted of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX> with heparitinase,
        suggesting that the retinoblastoma-derived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX> was more
        effective than the retinoblastoma-derived heparin. This
        observation can be explained by structural, compositional
        and functional differences between heparin and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS GAGs</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAG-binding proteins</ENAMEX> can be differentially sensitive to
        variations in GAG structure [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> produced among
        different cell types have structural and compositional
        differences and structural changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> are known to
        occur in cells undergoing morphological differentiation
        and/or malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">transformations</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29 30 31</NUMEX> ] . Thus, in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native retina</ENAMEX>, or other tissue, modulation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF-</ENAMEX>receptor interactions may depend on the expression of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX>, which occur during development and pathological
        conditions.
        Our data offer interesting possibilities of regulation
        of the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>. The ratio and amount of production
        of heparin and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> bearing PEDF <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> may be an
        important mechanism to control the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> as is
        the modulation of the rate of expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF receptors</ENAMEX>.
        The data obtained so far on the action of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> on different
        cells may have not considered the presence of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cofactors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. The binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> that
        modulate the binding of these factors to its receptor opens
        also the possibility that different GAGs may modulate
        differently the affinity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> for its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, by
        increasing or even decreasing it in some cases. Finally,
        the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> binding regions are on
        opposite regions of the PEDF molecule, suggest the
        possibility of the existence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> mutants or engineered
        variants that, having lost or decreased GAG-binding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">capabilities</ENAMEX>, still show high affinity for the PEDF
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> in a way not dependent upon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAGs</ENAMEX> content or
        composition. These possibilities are discussed under the
        consideration that some of them may have important
        implications if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>, or molecules derived from it, are to
        be used in the future as therapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.
        The primary consequence of reducing the heparin<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/HS</ENAMEX> and
        its sulfation was to minimize a binding site required for
        PEDF activity. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> in the
        extracellular matrix [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] , a more direct mechanism
        appears necessary, namely, its participation in the binding
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> to its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. In a spatial structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heparin</ENAMEX>/HS binding domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> maps to the opposite
        side of the neurotrophic active <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , allowing
        distinct and non-overlapping interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heparin</ENAMEX>/HS
        on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, and with the neurotrophic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> on its opposite side. Our data suggest that the
        intrinsic affinity of the cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> for PEDF
        appears low, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heparin</ENAMEX>/HS-PEDF <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> is
        recognized with high affinity. In addition, a direct
        interaction between the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> may also be
        necessary. Although details of the mechanism remain to be
        revealed, it is clear that heparin<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/HS</ENAMEX> is required for the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step of the neurotrophic activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>, namely the
        encounters with its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> at the cell surface. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> and survival of cells in vivo may be
        regulated not only by the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> and its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> but also by the temporal and spatial expression of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Materials
          Heparin purified from bovine intestinal mucosa,
          chondroitin sulfates A, B and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>, chondroitinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>,
          sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorate</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toluidine Blue</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>. Subtilisin was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehringer Mannheim</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heparitinase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.C.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.2.2.8</NUMEX>) and heparinase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.C.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.2.2.7</NUMEX>)
          purified from 
          Flavobacterium heparinum were from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICN Biomedicals, Inc.</ENAMEX> and alternatively from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seikagaku</ENAMEX>.
          Heparan sulfate (HS) purified from bovine kidney was from
          Seikagaku, hyaluronidase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.C.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.2.2.1</NUMEX>) purified from 
          Streptomyces hyalurolyticus from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICN Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coomassie Brilliant Blue</ENAMEX> from
          BioRad, and Q-Sepharose from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Recombinant PEDF</ENAMEX>
          was purified from BHK cells containing an expression
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> with human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF</ENAMEX> cDNA, as previously described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
          ] .
        
        
          Preparation of conditioned media
          Human retinoblastoma <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.45</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6cells/ml</ENAMEX>) were cultured in defined media (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MEM</ENAMEX> containing
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 mM HEPES</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Na-pyruvate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mM non-essential amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acids</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM L-glutamine, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> penicillin/streptomycin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LifeTechnologies</ENAMEX>)) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16-24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h. Media</ENAMEX> exposed to
          these conditions is referred as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> was separated from
          cells by centrifugation (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> Ã— 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4Â°C</NUMEX>) and
          concentrated by ultrafiltration using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">membrane</ENAMEX> filters
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MWCO</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amicon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">YM10</ENAMEX> filters). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">GAGs/polyanions</ENAMEX>
          purification was performed as follows: concentrated CM
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 ml</NUMEX>) was dialyzed against buffer Q (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX>, pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M NaCl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6 M Urea</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHAPS</ENAMEX>), filtered through
          a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> micron membrane and its soluble components
          subjected to anion-exchange column chromatography using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q-Sepharose Fast Flow</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ml</NUMEX> bed volume). The column was
          washed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-column volumes of buffer Q, the bound
          material eluted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M NaCl</ENAMEX> and termed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> a.
          Alternatively, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEAE-Sephacel</ENAMEX> column was used.
        
        
          PEDF-affinity column chromatography
          To identify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> with PEDF-binding affinity,
          purified recombinant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was used to prepare
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF-affinity resin</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 M Emphazeâ„¢ Biosupport Medium</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pierce Chemical</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> awas dialyzed against
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">buffer P</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphate pH 7</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHAPS</ENAMEX>) and filtrated through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> Î¼m filters. The soluble
          dialysate was mixed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PEDF-resin</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> mg <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PEDF</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">resin</ENAMEX>)
          at a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2:1</ENAMEX> volume-to-volume ratio and incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4Â°C</NUMEX> with
          gentle rocking for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 h.</TIMEX> The mixture was packed into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ml Polyprep</ENAMEX> chromatography column (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>) and washed
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-column volumes of buffer P. The bound material
          was eluted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-column volumes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 M NaCl</ENAMEX>, desalted
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> glycerol, treated for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> depletion, dialyzed against deionized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lyophilized</ENAMEX> and resuspended in deionized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The final
          sample was termed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM PEDF</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 100</NUMEX> Î¼l of CM PEDFwere
          obtained from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 ml</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>. Alternatively, concentrated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> was used as starting material and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> depletion
          was omitted.
        
        
          Radioligand binding assays
          PEDF binding to cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> was assayed
          using biologically active radioligand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">125I-PEDF</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX>
          cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] by a widely-used method with a mechanism of
          retention of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> on polyethylenimine-treated
          glass-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fiber</ENAMEX> filters based mainly on ionic interactions [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> ] . Polyethylenimine binds strongly to glass, which is
          negatively charged and integral membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> tend to
          be acidic. The resultant polycationic
          polyethylenimine-coated glass can retain cell membranes
          due to their negative charges. Because binding of
          cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polyethylenimine</ENAMEX> filters is
          rather insensitive to ionic strength, the ionic
          phenomenon is thought to be supplemented by hydrophobic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and hydrogen binding [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . The method used with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells and radiolabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> has been described
          before in detail [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, cells cultured
          overnight in serum-deprived medium at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> were
          transferred to ice/water bath for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> before the
          addition of ligand. The reaction mixtures containing cell
          suspensions with given radioligand concentrations in
          untreated or treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min, unless</ENAMEX> indicated. The free and bound 125I-PEDF were
          separated by filtration through <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass-fiber</ENAMEX> filters and
          the bound radioactivity was determined in the filters
          using a Î²-scintillation counter (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckman</ENAMEX>, model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LS 3801</ENAMEX>).
          Nonspecific binding was calculated from reactions with a
          molar-excess of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">unlabeled ligand (â‰</ENAMEX>¥ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-fold</NUMEX>) over
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">radioligand</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Complex-formation assays
          Complex formation between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> was
          assayed by a method using ultrafiltration through
          membranes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MW</ENAMEX> exclusion limit [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . Binding
          reactions were performed with a given concentration of
          125I-PEDF in defined or conditioned media, and
          incubations with gentle rotation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h. Free</ENAMEX> and
          bound ligand were separated by ultrafiltration through
          Microcon-100 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amicon</ENAMEX>). The reaction mixtures were diluted
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40-fold</NUMEX> with cold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphate</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM
          NaCl, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> glycerol and immediately ultrafiltrated,
          repeating twice to ensure removal of free ligand from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complexes</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microcon</ENAMEX> retenate cup was transferred to
          scintillation vials, mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ml</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BioSafe II</ENAMEX> liquid
          scintillation <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Products International</ENAMEX>)
          by extensive vortexing, and its radioactivity determined
          using a Î²-scintillation counter. Nonspecific binding,
          calculated from reactions with an excess of unlabeled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligand</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-fold) over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">radioligand</TIMEX>, reached <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40%</NUMEX> of
          the total binding.
        
        
          Enzymatic digestion treatments
          The presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> was assayed using specific GAG
          lyases, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX> , the presence of heparin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HS</ENAMEX>,
          and chondroitin sulfates with heparinase, heparitinase,
          and chondroitin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> respectively. The amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> was
          determined by the amount of Î” <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-hexuronate</NUMEX> produced after
          the eliminative cleavage of each substrate by the
          corresponding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> lyase. Samples were depleted of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> by protease treatment to avoid interference in
          absorbance readings of the product. For heparinase and
          heparitinase reactions, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          milliunits of each enzyme in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> sodium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acetate</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> and incubations at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for
          various time periods. The reactions were stopped by the
          addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.06</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M HCl</ENAMEX>. The soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> was
          separated by centrifugation (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX> Ã— 
          g , <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 min</NUMEX>) and assayed for
          absorbance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">235</NUMEX> nm to measure the concentration of
          product <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î” 4-hexuronate</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molar</ENAMEX> extinction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coefficient</ENAMEX> =
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5500</TIMEX>; [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] ). For the chondroitinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> reactions,
          each chondroitin sulfates A, B and C substrate (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mg
          each) and concentrated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CM</ENAMEX>, were incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.12</NUMEX> units
          of chondroitinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> mM sodium acetate, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.02%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. At various
          time periods, aliquots of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> ml were removed and mixed
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.9</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> mM KCl pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX> to stop the reaction.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insoluble</ENAMEX> material was removed by centrifugation (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> Ã— 
          g , <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 min</NUMEX>) and the supernatant
          assayed for absorbance of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î” 4-hexuronate</NUMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">232</NUMEX> nm. For
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> depletion, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> was mixed with subtilisin at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> glycerol and
          incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h. Subtilisin</ENAMEX> was
          heat-inactivated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> min. The protein
          concentration after the reaction was less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> of
          the starting material.
          To deplete cell cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells in
          defined serum-free medium (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as above</NUMEX>) at a density of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.25</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ã— 10 5cells/ml</ENAMEX> were cultured in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well culture plates
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">150 Î¼l/well</ENAMEX>) and incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> environment for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h. Hyaluronidase</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">>1TRU/Î¼l</ENAMEX>), heparinase (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mu/Î¼l</ENAMEX>) or heparitinase (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mu/Î¼l</ENAMEX>) were each added to various <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> and incubated at
          37Â°C in a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> environment for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h.</TIMEX>
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Chlorate</ENAMEX> treatment of cell cultures
          To prevent sulfation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> in cell cultures, we used
          a method previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> cells (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.25</NUMEX> Ã—
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 5cells/ml</ENAMEX>) were cultured in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>-well plates (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">300</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Î¼l</ENAMEX>/well) in defined serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> with or without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chlorate</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfate</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in a
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> environment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> detection assays
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> resolved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-polyacrylamide gel
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrophoresis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tricine/SDS</ENAMEX> buffer, as instructed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novex</ENAMEX>), were detected with specific stains.
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> detection, the gels were incubated sequentially
          in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toluidine Blue</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol-water</ENAMEX>-acetic acid
          (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50:49:</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol-water</ENAMEX>-acetic acid
          (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50:49:</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX>, and in H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> h. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . For protein
          detection, the gels were sequentially incubated in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coomassie Brilliant Blue</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50% methanol/10%</NUMEX> acetic acid
          and in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10% methanol/10%</NUMEX> isopropanol. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> detection was
          also performed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toluidine Blue</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> precipitation and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dot</ENAMEX>-blot method as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î¼l</NUMEX> of sample were applied to each well of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>-well
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manifold</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies</ENAMEX>) onto a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PVDF</ENAMEX> membrane without
          vacuum. Then, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> Toluidine blue-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> were added to
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> and vacuum was applied. The membrane was
          removed, washed twice with destaining solution
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol-water-acetic acid</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50:49:</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min and</TIMEX>
          air-dried.
        
        
          Other methods
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> concentration was determined using BioRad
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Protein Assay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEDF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pigment epithelium-</ENAMEX>derived factor; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glycosaminoglycan; HS</ENAMEX>, heparan sulfate; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>, media
        conditioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma</ENAMEX> cells.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMA</ENAMEX> participated in the design, assay development and
        carried out the complex-formation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAG</ENAMEX> detection and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor binding assays</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JEW</ENAMEX> carried out the purification
        and characterization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAGs</ENAMEX>, the enzymatic and chemical
        treatments of cell cultures for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> binding studies,
        and drafted the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SPB</ENAMEX> conceived the study, and
        participated in its design and coordination. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
