
  
    
      
        Background
        The lysosome is a pivotal organelle responsible for a
        diverse spectrum of cellular functions including protein
        and lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">catabolism</ENAMEX>, vesicular transport and sorting [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ]
        . Abnormal lysosomal physiology may result in cellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dysfunction</ENAMEX>, and eventually lead to a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>.
        For example, deficiencies of various enzymes responsible
        for lipid metabolism result in lipid accumulation in
        lysosomal storage diseases such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Niemann-Pick</ENAMEX> and Gaucher
        diseases [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Alternatively, modulation of lysosomal
        lumen pH may alter membrane trafficking and associated
        metabolic processes. It has been reported that elevated
        lysosomal pH is associated with the genetic lysosomal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disorder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Mucolipidosis type IV disease</ENAMEX> where various
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sphingolipids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mucolipids</ENAMEX> accumulate in the lysosome [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        ] . Finally, lysosomes may play multiple roles in cellular
        oxidative metabolism [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . The oxidative activity in
        lysosomes may regulate the modification of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and
        lipids, resulting in disruption of lysosomal membrane
        integrity [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] .
        The tumor promoter phorbol myristate acetate (PMA) has
        been shown to activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> (nicotinamide adenine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dinucleotide phosphate</ENAMEX>) oxidase and initiate the oxidative
        burst response in various phagocytes, including neutrophils
        and the macrophage-like cell line J774A.1 [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] . During
        the oxidative burst, generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reactive oxygen</ENAMEX> species
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROS</ENAMEX>), such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydrogen peroxide</ENAMEX> (H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) and superoxide anion (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 â€¢-</ENAMEX>), is involved in degranulation,
        secretion of lysosomal enzymes and subsequent cytotoxic
        killing of invading pathogens. Although activation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> oxidase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> in phagolysosomal or lysosomal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">membranes</ENAMEX> has been reported, 
        in situ generation of either H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 â€¢</ENAMEX>-in these organelles in live cells
        has not been demonstrated [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . This is partly due to the
        lack of appropriate indicators that can monitor the
        formation of these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ROS</ENAMEX> and the concurrent change of
        oxidative activity in these vacuoles. Furthermore, since
        the charged free radical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 â€¢-</ENAMEX>should have difficulty leaking
        across hydrophobic membranes, formation of this anion
        radical inside the lysosome may have an immediate impact on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pH</ENAMEX> in this organelle. The question addressed in the present
        study is: what is the distribution of oxidative activity
        and pH changes in the lysosome when cells are stimulated
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>. A fluorogenic substrate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURSTâ„¢ Green H</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 HFF Bovine Serum Albumin</ENAMEX> (OxyBURST
        Green H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA), was used to detect lysosomal
        oxidative activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX> consists of bovine serum
        albumin coupled to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dihydro-2</ENAMEX>'<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">,4,5,6,7,7</NUMEX>'-hexafluorofluorescein (H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF), a reduced dye with improved
        chemical stability. The non-fluorescent BSA conjugate is
        internalized into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> through the endocytic pathway, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulates</ENAMEX> in lysosomes where the extent of its oxidation
        depends on the oxidative activity in this organelle. The
        spatial distribution of lysosomal pH in cells after PMA
        treatment was investigated using both
        fluorescein-conjugated dextran and a selective lysosomal
        probe, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LysoTrackerâ„¢ Red</ENAMEX>. Finally, possible mechanisms of
        regulation between pH and oxidative activity in lysosomes
        are discussed.
      
      
        Results and discussion
        
          Effect of phorbol ester on the oxidative activities
          of lysosomes
          Although the location of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NADPH</ENAMEX> oxidase
          complex in phagolysosomes has been reported, the release
          of either H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 â€¢-</ENAMEX> 
          in situ upon stimulation with PMA
          has not been directly shown in live cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX> ] . In
          order to directly measure the oxidative activity in
          lysosomes, I use a reduced fluorescein derivative that is
          conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX>, as shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
          Spectrofluorimetric analysis indicates that this reduced
          compound is non-fluorescent, and becomes fluorescent upon
          HRP-catalyzed oxidation. Furthermore, upon incubation
          with macrophages, the reduced compound was internalized
          into cells through fluid phase endocytosis, and
          eventually accumulated in lysosomes. Therefore, the
          oxidation activity inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lysosome</ENAMEX> determines the
          oxidation of the reduced dye. Upon oxidation, this
          compound emits strong fluorescence with emission maximum
          centered at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î</NUMEX>» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">545</NUMEX> , which can be viewed and
          quantified using fluorescence microscopy.
          I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> labeled the total lysosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in
          cells with a well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lysosomal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marker</ENAMEX>, dextran
          conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascade Blue</ENAMEX> fluorophore, according to a
          previously reported procedure [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] (see Methods
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section</ENAMEX>). Cells were then labeled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX>, followed by chase labeling
          without the reduced dye but in the presence or absence of
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">200 nM PMA</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co-localization</ENAMEX> experiments indicate that all
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX> is distributed in lysosomes
          but not endosomes after this labeling procedure (see
          below). The fluorescence intensity of the oxidized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA in total lysosomal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX> was then quantified by a process using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascade Blue</ENAMEX>-conjugated dextran as a mask for lysosomes [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> ] . As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, when cells were treated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, fluorescence intensity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST</ENAMEX> fluorophore
          in lysosomes significantly increased (i.e. oxidative
          activity, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>). This increase in fluorescence
          is not due to the internalization of oxidized dye since
          no oxidation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA was observed in the labeling
          medium during the loading procedure (data not shown).
          Furthermore, cells were incubated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 HFF</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> min so that the
          reduced dye is transported primarily into endosomes
          rather than lysosomes. Stimulation of endosome loaded
          cells with control medium or medium containing PMA
          resulted in no detectable changes in the fluorescent
          properties of the endosome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
          These results demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> initiates an elevation
          of oxidative activity selectively within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lysosomes</TIMEX>.
          In order to understand the 
          in situ enhancement of lysosomal
          oxidative activity by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, the subcellular distribution
          of the oxidized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA in cells was investigated.
          As shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, oxidized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA distributed within the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of lysosomes where they co-localized with the
          fluorescent dextran. It was also noticed that strong
          fluorescence of oxidized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA only existed in a subset of
          lysosomes, as indicated by arrows in the inset.
        
        
          Effect of phorbol ester on lysosomal pH
          I next sought to investigate the effect of PMA
          treatment on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lysosomal pH. Averaged lysosomal</ENAMEX> pH was
          measured in control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>,
          using fluorescein-conjugated dextran in dual-excitation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ratiometric</ENAMEX> mode [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . The validation of lysosomal pH
          measurements was performed by the calibration curve using
          ionophore-clamped cells as shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The ratio
          of emission fluorescence under excitation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX> nm
          versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> nm (i.e. F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX> )/F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> )) correlated linearly with
          calibrated lysosomal pHs from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.0 to 6.5</NUMEX>, with a high r
          2value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.9689</NUMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, the average pH in
          total lysosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> significantly increased
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pH units</ENAMEX>) upon PMA stimulation. Most
          interestingly, a heterogeneous distribution of lysosomes
          with elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pH</ENAMEX> was observed by ratiometric images as
          shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Here, lysosomal pH in untreated cells
          is very homogeneous, and estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX>. Upon
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> treatment, pH was significantly elevated to as high
          as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX> in a subset of lysosomes (indicated by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arrow</ENAMEX>).
          The effect of PMA-induced oxidation on lysosomal pH as
          measured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fluorescein-dextran</ENAMEX> is worthwhile further
          discussion (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and</ENAMEX> Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). It is critical to
          test the possibility that the increase of oxidative
          activity may change the pH-dependence of
          fluorescein-dextran. In other words, lysosomes with
          higher oxidative activities may induce abnormal change of
          the pH-dependence of fluorescein-dextran that is within.
          If this is true, then the resulting F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX> )/F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> ) ratio of the fluorescence is no
          longer pH-dependent, and can not be used as an indication
          of pH increase in lysosomes. To test this possibility,
          effect of HRP-catalyzed oxidation on pH-dependence of
          fluorescein-dextran was investigated 
          in vitro . As shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>,
          increase in oxidation showed no effect on the
          pH-dependence of fluorescein-dextran. Conversely, changes
          in lysosomal pH do not affect the fluorescence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oxidized OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA as will be shown later.
        
        
          Regulation of lysosomal pH and oxidative
          activities
          The observation that there are elevations of both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oxidative</ENAMEX> and pH activities in only a subset of lysosomes
          (Figures <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2and 4</NUMEX>) suggests that pH and oxidative activity
          may be coupled in this organelle. In order to demonstrate
          this relationship in live cells, the oxidative activities
          and pH in lysosomes were simultaneously monitored by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LysoTracker Red DND-99</ENAMEX>
          which is able to qualitatively indicate acidic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysosomes</ENAMEX>.
          Briefly, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell monolayers</ENAMEX> were incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 Î¼g/mL</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>, washed,
          and then incubated in fresh medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> nM PMA
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">0.5 hour</TIMEX>. Cell monolayers were washed and
          then incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LysoTracker Red DND-99</ENAMEX>, at 37Â°C
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>, to label acidic lysosomes. Consistent with
          previous results, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PMA</ENAMEX> treatment elicits high oxidative
          activity and thus increased <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">OxyBURST</ENAMEX> fluorescent
          intensity in a subset of lysosomes (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
          Interestingly, lysosomes with strong OxyBURST
          fluorescence contain only very weak fluorescence of
          LysoTracker <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red</ENAMEX> (see arrows). On the other hand, acidic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysosomes</ENAMEX> strongly stained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LysoTracker Red</ENAMEX> exhibited
          very weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OxyBURST</ENAMEX> fluorescence (see arrowhead). The
          mutual regulation of oxidative activity and alkalinity in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysosomes</ENAMEX> can be better demonstrated by a ratio image as
          shown in the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LysoTracker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red DND-99</ENAMEX> is a chloroquine analogue that
          had been reported to selectively accumulate in acidic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysosomes</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . In the present study, when lysosomal pH
          was elevated to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>6.5</NUMEX> and then cell was stained with
          the dye, the fluorescence in lysosomes greatly decreased
          or diminished. This decrease in fluorescence is due to a
          decrease in accumulation of the dye in lysosomes since
          the change in pH itself has no effect on the fluorescence
          of the dye (data not shown). Nevertheless, the
          fluorescence decrease of this dye in a subset of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysosomes</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> stimulation could also result from
          reactions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LysoTracker Red</ENAMEX> with higher oxidative
          activity, while the pH in this subset of lysosomes
          remains unchanged. This possibility was tested 
          in vitro by incubating LysoTracker
          Red with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 -donor</NUMEX>) in buffer solutions with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acidic</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.5</NUMEX>) or alkaline (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.5</NUMEX>) pHs. As shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>,
          the fluorescence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LysoTracker Red</ENAMEX> is not affected
          by either of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">oxygen species</ENAMEX>. This data strongly
          supports the contention that decreased fluorescence of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LysoTracker Red</ENAMEX> in a subset of lysosomes does
          indicate elevation of pH.
          I then characterized the heterogeneous fluorescence
          distribution of oxidized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA. Fluorescence of fluorescein
          and its analogs such as carboxyfluorescein has been shown
          to be pH-dependent [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX> ] . Elevation of pH increases
          the ratio of fluorescent emission at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î</NUMEX>» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> as excited by Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">485 over Î</NUMEX>» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> . The heterogeneous fluorescence
          of the oxidized dye in subsets of lysosomes where it
          exhibits a significant difference in pH (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.5 to 7.5</NUMEX>) may
          simply reflect the pH-dependency of the oxidized dye, and
          not represent different levels of oxidative activity
          among lysosomes. The pH-dependency of fluorescence of
          both oxidized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-(and
          -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)-carboxyfluorescein were thus examined by the dual
          excitation ratiometric measurement 
          in vitro , as shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>.
          While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-(and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX>)-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carboxyfluorescein</ENAMEX> exhibits strong
          pH-dependency, the experiment clearly demonstrates that
          fluorescence of the oxidized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX> is not affected by variation
          of the pH within a range <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between 4.5</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>.
          It is also possible that the heterogeneous
          distribution of fluorescence intensity of oxidized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX> is due to preferential
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of the reduced dye in a subset of lysosomes
          rather than being determined by a variation of oxidative
          activity in these lysosomes. In other words, lysosomes
          that accumulate more reduced dye will produce stronger
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorescence</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> stimulation. To address this
          possibility, I performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following</TIMEX> experiment. Cell
          monolayers were grown on circular glass coverslips and
          labeled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA as previously described. The
          cells were then mounted onto a temperature-controlled
          stage with a perfusion <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> for microscopy. The
          temperature was controlled at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> throughout the
          experiment. Cells were then treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LysoTracker Red DND-99</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> to label lysosomes. Cells were next washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
          and the fluorescence images of both oxidized OxyBURST
          Green H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">LysoTracker Red</ENAMEX> were
          recorded. As shown in Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9a</TIMEX>, the fluorescence
          intensity is higher in a subset of lysosomes (see arrow)
          that accumulate very little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LysoTracker Red</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9b</NUMEX>).
          Conceivably, if there was more reduced dye in this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">lysosome</ENAMEX> area, complete oxidation of the reduced dye
          inside lysosomes should release more OxyBURST
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorescence</ENAMEX>. This was tested by adding H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> (final concentration of
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>). The cells were then incubated for an
          additional <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX> to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oxidation</ENAMEX> of all the lysosomal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA. The fluorescent image of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oxidized OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA in the same cell was then
          recorded as shown in Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9c</TIMEX>. The addition of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> resulted in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX>-fold average
          intensity increase (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">349.5</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">73.5</NUMEX>) among the total
          lysosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluorescence</ENAMEX> changes in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
          selected lysosomal areas before (insets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9a) and
          after (insets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9c) H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> addition are further quantified as
          shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>. The figure shows that the maximal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorescence</ENAMEX> released by H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment among these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> lysosomal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> is very similar (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">421.21</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">455.81</NUMEX> gray level/pixel
          area). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, lysosomal area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, which exhibited
          stronger fluorescence before H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">175.12</NUMEX> gray level/pixel
          area), does not release more fluorescence after complete
          oxidation by the peroxide. This clearly eliminates the
          possibility that there is more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA accumulating in lysosome
          area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>. The experiment strongly supports the notion that
          the oxidative activity within the lysosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is
          heterogeneous.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> regarding to the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA in the present study is that
          the accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 HFF BSA</ENAMEX> itself may drive the
          increase in pH. If this is the case, then lysosomes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">containing OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA should have more alkaline
          pH. However, this possibility is not consistent with one
          observation that was presented in Figure 9where I showed
          that distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA was very homogenous among
          lysosomes, nevertheless not every lysosomes exhibited
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">elevated lumen pH.</ENAMEX>
          Although direct measurements of lysosomal oxidative
          activity in live cells were not available before the
          present study, several lines of evidence did point to a
          regulatory mechanism in phagolysosomes or lysosomes in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phagocytes</ENAMEX> during phagocytosis and oxidative burst.
          First, it has been shown that activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> oxidase
          during a phagocytosis event results in alkalization of
          phagolysosomal pH in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neutrophil</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . The
          phagolysosomal pH is influenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> oxidase activity
          and to a lesser extent by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Na +/H</ENAMEX> +antiporter. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>,
          disruption of normal lysosomal pH by lysosomotropic weak
          bases inhibits the respiratory burst in neutrophils [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
          ] . A normal transmembrane pH gradient in lysosomes is
          suggested to play an important role in assembling the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> oxidase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> during cell activation. These
          observations and my present results can be integrated and
          summarized in a model proposed in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>. PMA
          treatment induces the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and activation of NADPH
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oxidase</ENAMEX> in the lysosomal membrane. Activation of the
          oxidase generates intralysosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 â€¢-</ENAMEX>that is membrane impermeable, with
          a short life span and is converted to H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> instantly by the consumption of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protons</ENAMEX> (see (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> then oxidizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA that accumulates in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysosome</ENAMEX> in the presence of peroxidases. This
          enzyme-catalyzed oxidation generates hydroxyl ion (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">OH -</ENAMEX>)
          and radical (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>) (see (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)). Intralysosomal pH elevation
          can be explained by a net effect of H +consumption and OH
          -generation. Alternatively, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive OH â€¢radical</ENAMEX> may
          interact with lysosomal membrane lipids or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and
          disturb a normal transmembrane-dependent pH gradient [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ] . Eventually, the elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pH</ENAMEX> may then act as a
          negative feedback control to down regulate the activation
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> oxidase and inhibit oxidative activity.
          Finally, generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ROS</ENAMEX> during phagocytosis has been
          implicated in inactivation of lysosomal enzymes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ]
          . It is conceivable that an elevation of lysosomal pH to
          as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">high as 6.5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX> will inactivate various proteases in
          this organelle.
          Another novel finding in the present study is the
          heterogeneous distribution of oxidative activity and pH
          in lysosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PMA</ENAMEX> treatment.
          Heterogeneous distribution of low molecular weight
          redox-active iron has been reported in lysosomal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> within cells, which may contribute to
          differing stability of lysosomal membranes to oxidative
          stress as shown by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brunk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . Although
          the regulation of this heterogeneity is too complicated
          and beyond the scope of the present study, it does open
          up another window for investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lysosomal</ENAMEX> trafficking
          in various <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. For example, the accumulation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lipids</ENAMEX> in lysosomal storage <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> appears to be
          heterogeneous [unpublished data]. Oxidative activity and
          pH distribution may be used as 
          in situ indexes to improve our
          understanding of lipid accumulation in subsets of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysosomes</ENAMEX>. Understanding the regulation mechanism will be
          helpful in developing new treatment strategy for these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Conclusions
        Using a novel indicator for oxidative activity, OxyBURST
        Green H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX>, I am able to study the
        distribution of lysosomal oxidative burst activity and its
        concurrent pH changes in live macrophage-like J744A<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>.
        The present result indicates that oxidative activity and pH
        in lysosomes are inter-regulated. Higher oxidative activity
        results in higher alkalinity while lower lysosomal pH is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with lower oxidative activity. This approach
        provides a better opportunity to study the dynamic changes
        of oxidation and pH in phagolysosomes during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">phagocytosis</TIMEX>,
        which can not be resolved by conventional biochemical
        analyses.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagents</ENAMEX> and cell cultures
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX>, dextrans (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>, lysine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fixable</ENAMEX>) conjugated with either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascade Blue</ENAMEX> or
          fluorescein fluorophores, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LysoTracker Red DND-99</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-(and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX>)-carboxyfluorescein were from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR). Nigericin, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monensin</ENAMEX>, Phorbol
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-myristate 13</NUMEX>-acetate (PMA), horseradish peroxidase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX>, type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydrogen peroxide</ENAMEX> (H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). Potassium superoxide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>).
          All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">buffered solutions</ENAMEX> and other reagents for organic
          synthesis were analytical grade and freshly prepared.
          Murine macrophage-like cell line (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">J774A.1</NUMEX>) was from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collection</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manassas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>). They
          were routinely grown in a monolayer (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%-50%</NUMEX> confluence)
          on a glass cover slide at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modified Eagle Medium</ENAMEX>), supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L -glutamine</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> HEPES
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> gentamicin, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> penicillin/streptomycin and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> Fetal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bovine Serum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gibco, NY</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Measurement of oxidative activity in lysosomes
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2HFF</ENAMEX> BSA
          The lysosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was first labeled with a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascade Blue</ENAMEX>-conjugated dextran as previously described [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell monolayer</ENAMEX> was then incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼g/mL OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA in complete culture medium
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>. Afterwards, excess <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dye</ENAMEX> was removed
          by washing with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">phosphate-buffered</NUMEX> saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) and the
          cells were incubated in complete culture medium in the
          presence or absence of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">200 nM PMA</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for an
          additional <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">0.5 hour</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell monolayer</ENAMEX> was then washed
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and the fluorescent staining of the oxidized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascade Blue</ENAMEX>-conjugated
          dextran were then recorded by low-light level
          fluorescence microscopy with appropriate filters. The
          fluorescent intensity of the oxidized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST</ENAMEX> in the
          lysosomes was then quantified using the staining of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascade Blue</ENAMEX>-conjugated dextran as a mask, as described
          previously [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . The average fluorescence intensity
          (gray level/pixel area) in the mask region was then
          calculated and represents the relative oxidative activity
          in lysosomes. This procedure was repeated on images
          collected from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> different cells in the same
          culture dish.
        
        
          Measurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lysosomal</ENAMEX> pH
          The pH of the lysosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in the J774A.1
          cells was measured by a dual excitation ratiometric
          measurement according to established procedures using the
          fluorescein-conjugated dextran [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 8</NUMEX> ] . Namely, cells
          were incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-5 mg/mL fluorescein-conjugated</ENAMEX>
          dextran for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 18 hours</TIMEX> in culture medium.
          Cells were washed and then incubated for an additional
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">0.5 hour</TIMEX> in fresh culture medium in the presence or
          absence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>. Samples were then washed with cold
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4Â°C</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MES</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-morpholineethanesulfonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>) buffer
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> mM MgSO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 and 25</NUMEX> mM MES twice, and then
          observed under fluorescence microscope. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> low light
          level images of each cell were obtained at green emission
          region (Î» 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">em</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">515</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">565</NUMEX> nm), under sequential
          excitation by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î</NUMEX>» 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ex 485</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nm</ENAMEX>, and then at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î</NUMEX>» 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ex 440</ENAMEX> nm (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-nm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> width).
          Background fluorescence was corrected by images of blank
          region of the same culture dish at both excitation
          wavelengths.
          Imaging analysis to calculate the ratio of green
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorescence</ENAMEX> in lysosomes under excitation by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485 and 440</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nm</ENAMEX> (" [F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX> )/F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> )]") was carried out as previously
          described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . The ratiometric data were converted to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pH</ENAMEX> using a calibration curve from the lysosomes of
          ionophore-clamped cells. These cells were treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Î¼M Monensin</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigericine</ENAMEX> and equilibrated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MES</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-morpholineethanesulfonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>)
          calibration buffer with pHs from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX> prior to
          image acquisition.
        
        
          Selective staining of acidic lysosomes
          In order to stain acidic lysosomes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LysoTracker Red</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DND-99</ENAMEX> was used. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LysoTracker Red DND-99</ENAMEX> is a
          fluorescent analog of chloroquine, which selectively
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulates</ENAMEX> in lysosomes [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . Cells were incubated
          with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> nM concentration of the dye at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min.
          Afterwards, excess <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dye</ENAMEX> was removed by washing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>.
          The fluorescence distribution was then viewed using a
          rhodamine filter.
        
        
          Fluorescence microscopy and image processing
          Fluorescence microscopy was performed with an inverted
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">microscope</ENAMEX> (DIAPHOT-TMD, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon</ENAMEX>) equipped with a Plan Apo
          60X (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.A.</ENAMEX>) objective and epifluorescence optics for
          various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fluorophores</ENAMEX> including fluorescein (also for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascade Blue</ENAMEX> and rhodamine. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCD</ENAMEX> camera
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantix, Photometrics Ltd.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>) was used to obtain the
          microscopic images. Thirty-two fluorescence video images
          of cells were digitized (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16 bits</NUMEX>) and averaged using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metamorph Image Processing</ENAMEX> system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Imaging</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Spectrofluorimetric analyses
          Stock solutions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HFF BSA were prepared in phosphate
          buffered saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) and stored under nitrogen at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>.
          The HRP-catalyzed oxidation of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> was
          determined spectroscopically as follows. To a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼g/mL of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX> was added to a final
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 Î¼g/mL.</ENAMEX> The resulting solution was
          incubated at room temperature for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX> to consume
          any endogenous H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . Afterwards, H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was added, with stirring, to a final
          concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM. The spectral change in emission
          resulting from the oxidation of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> was then
          recorded on a spectrophotometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-4500</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitachi</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Instruments, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>).
          To study the effect of pH on the fluorescence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oxidized OxyBURST Green H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFF BSA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-(and
          -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>)-carboxyfluorescein, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">78 Î</NUMEX>¼g/mL of the oxidized dye or
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.2 Î</NUMEX>¼M <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-(and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX>)-carboxyfluorescein were prepared in MES
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-morpholineethanesulfonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>) buffer solutions
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">containing 5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">115</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> mM MgSO 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 and 25 mM MES</TIMEX> (pHs from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.5 to 7.5</NUMEX>).
          The fluorescence emission ratio at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î</NUMEX>» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> by excitation with Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX> over that by excitation with Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> was then measured (i.e. F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX> )/F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> )). The effect of pH on the
          fluorescence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LysoTracker Red DND-99</ENAMEX> (final
          concentration is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼M</NUMEX>) was similarly performed, except
          that the emission fluorescence at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î</NUMEX>» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">592</NUMEX> was recorded upon excitation at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î</NUMEX>» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">574</NUMEX> .
          The effects of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 â€¢-</ENAMEX>on the fluorescence of LysoTracker
          Red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DND-99</ENAMEX> were studied by preparing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Î¼M solutions of
          the dye in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MES</ENAMEX> buffer solutions at pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.5</NUMEX>,
          containing various concentrations of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . After incubation at room
          temperature for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>, the emission fluorescence at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î</NUMEX>» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">592</NUMEX> was recorded as previously
          described.
          The effect of oxidation on pH-dependency of
          fluorescein-conjugated dextran was tested 
          in vitro by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP/H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> oxidant-generating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          fluorescein dextran (final concentration at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">30 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) was
          prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MES</ENAMEX> calibration buffers with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pHs</ENAMEX> ranging from
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.3</NUMEX>. These solutions were then incubated at 37Â°C
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, in the absence or presence of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX> (final concentrations are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Î¼M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4 Î¼g/</ENAMEX>mL, respectively). The fluorescence emission
          ratio, F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX> )/F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">535</NUMEX> (Î» 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> ), was then measured using SPEX
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fluorolog</ENAMEX> 3 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jobin Yvon Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>).
        
      
    
  
