
  
    
      
        Introduction
        
        c-fos is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of
        immediate early genes, and its transcription is transiently
        induced in response to mitogenic signals [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. The serum
        response element (SRE) is located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 300 bp</NUMEX>
        upstream of the transcriptional start site in the 
        c-fos <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> and is necessary for
        serum induction of 
        c-fos [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> binds a
        transcription factor named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">serum</ENAMEX> response factor (SRF)
        which was found to be necessary, but not sufficient, for
        serum induction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3, 4, 5</ENAMEX>]. 
        In vivo footprinting analysis shows
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> is constitutively bound to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> in both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quiescent</ENAMEX> and growth factor stimulated cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. This
        suggests that it is the transcriptional activation of a
        complex of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> and its accessory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that is regulated
        rather than regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRF DNA</ENAMEX> binding.
        The ternary complex factors (TCFs) are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ets</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of transcription factors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> members
        Elk-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAP-1</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>], and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAP-2/ERP/NET</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9, 10</ENAMEX>] have
        been found to have a role in regulating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>. TCFs
        cannot bind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> autonomously, but require
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-protein</ENAMEX> interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> in order to bind the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 12, 13, 14, 15</TIMEX>]. The TCFs contain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> conserved
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motifs</ENAMEX> termed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX>, B, and C boxes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal
        A-box (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> (aa) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-90 of Elk-1</ENAMEX>) is necessary to bind
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, while the central B-box (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">aa 148-168</ENAMEX>) is the SRF
        interaction domain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-terminal C-</ENAMEX>box (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">aa 352-399</ENAMEX>),
        harboring the transactivation domain, contains several
        consensus mitogen activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> (MAPK)
        phosphorylation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. Accordingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCFs</ENAMEX> have been
        found to be targets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ras-Raf</ENAMEX>-MAPK signal transduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCFs</ENAMEX> have been found to be
        targets for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of MAPKs: the extracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX>-regulated kinases <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/2</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>), the jun-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal
        kinases/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinases</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JNK/SAPK</ENAMEX>), and
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p38</NUMEX> kinase [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 18</TIMEX>]. The transcriptional activity of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCFs</ENAMEX> are stimulated by phosphorylation of the
        C-terminal MAPK sites [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 17</TIMEX>].
        regulation of the 
        c-fos <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCAAT/Enhancer</ENAMEX> binding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-beta (C/EBPβ). C/EBPβ (also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-IL6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAP</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-M, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AGP/EBP</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CRP2</ENAMEX>) is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the basic-leucine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">zipper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of transcription factors [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 20</TIMEX>]. The
        C/EBPβ mRNA contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in-frame methionines which give
        rise to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different translation <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p35</TIMEX>, and
        p20<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>]. p38 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> both contain an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal transactivation domain and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">binding/dimerization</ENAMEX> domain. p20<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> lacks the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal transactivation domain and therefore acts as a
        repressor of transcription. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> has previously shown
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> activates an SRE-driven <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> construct
        while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p20-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> inhibits serum stimulation of the same
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. We have also shown that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and
        p20<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> could interact with SRF 
        in vivo and that the interaction
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>, but not between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> and
        p20<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>, is stimulated by activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ras</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> for
        this Ras stimulation is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Thr235</NUMEX> in a consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> site in
        C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBPβ</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> is a target of a
        Ras-dependent signaling pathway that regulates its
        interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>.
        Based on the observations that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> factors as well as
        p35-C/EBPβ: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) transactivate the SRE
        and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) are responsive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>-dependent signaling pathways,
        we tested the possibility that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> are
        necessary for maximal induction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> in response to
        mitogenic stimulation. In this study, we show that
        p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elk</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> synergize in
        transactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">transcription</ENAMEX> of both a
        Gal4 dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and an SRE-driven reporter
        construct, but only in response to mitogenic stimulation by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>. We further show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> interact 
        in vitro in a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glutathione-S-transferase</ENAMEX> (GST)-pulldown assay as well as
        in an 
        in vivo coimmunoprecipitation assay.
        The 
        in vivo interaction is dependent on
        the presence of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ras</ENAMEX>. Finally, we show that the
        C-terminal domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> is sufficient to interact with
        Elk-1 while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal A-box of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> is necessary to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">interact with C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>. These results suggest a cooperative
        role between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> transcription factors in
        regulation of the 
        c-fos <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> in response to
        Ras-dependent signaling pathways.
      
      
        Results
        
          Elk-1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> synergize in transactivation
          of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GAL4</TIMEX> dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
          Due to the common observations that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and
          p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> transactivate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>, interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>, and
          are responsive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>-dependent signaling pathways, we
          hypothesized that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> may both be
          necessary for maximal induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> dependent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX>. To begin to test this hypothesis, we used
          a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GAL4</TIMEX> dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> construct, in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CAT</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene is driven by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> copies of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GAL4</NUMEX> binding
          site upstream of the adenovirus <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E1B</ENAMEX> minimal promoter
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pG5CAT</NUMEX>). We constructed a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAL4 DNA</ENAMEX> binding domain-SRF
          fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, as has been described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>].
          GAL4-SRF binds to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GAL4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> construct, thereby
          making transcription of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene dependent on
          the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, when a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GAL4</NUMEX>-SRF
          fusion construct is transfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, there
          is no increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> activity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> transactivation
          domain is weak, as has been shown previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. When
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CMV-Elk-1</ENAMEX> is cotransfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and
          GAL4-SRF, there is little increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> activity in the
          absence of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ras</ENAMEX> (CMV-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ras</ENAMEX>.V12). This result is
          expected since the transactivation domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> is
          activated in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>. Therefore, when activated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX> is transfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GAL4-SRF</ENAMEX>, and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> activity increases to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-fold over basal
          levels. We cannot determine if the increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CAT</ENAMEX>
          activity in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX> also reflects a
          stimulation of the interaction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and SRF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>.
          When <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CMV-LAP</ENAMEX> (which encodes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>) is transfected
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GAL4-SRF</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> construct, we see a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-fold
          increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> activity that is potentiated to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>-fold
          when activated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ras</ENAMEX> is cotransfected. Therefore, C/EBPβ
          results in a much larger increase in transcription than
          Elk-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. We have previously shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX> does not
          activate the transactivation domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>].
          Thus, the increase in transcription in this assay is due
          to Ras stimulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SRF-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> interaction.
          Interestingly, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three constructs</NUMEX> - SRF, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ-</ENAMEX>are cotransfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
          construct, there is an average <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX>-fold increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CAT</ENAMEX>
          activity in the presence of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ras</ENAMEX>. The values of
          fold activation varied from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as low as 60-fold</NUMEX> to as high
          as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">725</NUMEX>-fold over basal levels, and we are unsure of the
          reason for this variability. However, regardless of the
          extent of activation, in every experiment there was a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synergy</ENAMEX> observed when both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> are
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transfected</ENAMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>. There is only a
          slight increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> activity in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>.
          Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> are working
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synergistically</ENAMEX> to transactivate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> construct
          in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>. This synergism is only observed
          in response to activation of mitogenic signaling pathways
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Elk-1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> synergize in transactivation
          of the SRE
          Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> synergize in
          transactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>-dependent transcription using a
          GAL4-dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>, we next tested if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and
          p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> could also synergize in transactivation of a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">native SRF</ENAMEX> binding site, namely the 
          c-fos <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>. To test this
          possibility, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3T3</NUMEX> cells were transiently transfected
          with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene driven by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> copy of the wild
          type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRE</ENAMEX> upstream of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rous</ENAMEX> sarcoma virus long terminal
          repeat minimal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, when
          p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> is co-transfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> construct,
          there is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>-fold increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> activity in the
          absence of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ras</ENAMEX> that is increased to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-fold
          when <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CMV-Ras</ENAMEX>.V12 is co-transfected.
          When <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CMV-Elk-1</ENAMEX> is co-transfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
          construct, there is no additional stimulation in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transactivation</ENAMEX> in either the absence or presence of Ras
          compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> alone. However, when both Elk-1
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> are transfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
          construct, there is a synergistic effect in
          transactivation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>, with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>-fold increase in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> activity over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> construct alone. As was seen
          with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Gal4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, this synergism is only observed
          in the presence of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ras</ENAMEX>. These data suggest that
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> are necessary for maximal
          Ras-stimulated transactivation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> interact in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitro</ENAMEX>
          We next tested the possibility that there could be a
          direct <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-protein</ENAMEX> interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and
          p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> based on the fact that they synergize in
          transactivation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>. Therefore, we used a
          GST-pulldown assay to determine if the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> could
          interact 
          in vitro . p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> was expressed
          as a chimeric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GST protein</ENAMEX> and immobilized on
          glutathione-agarose beads. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Beads</ENAMEX> containing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> alone were incubated with 
          in vitro -translated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> labeled
          with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35S</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">methionine</ENAMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3, lane 2,</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 35-45%</NUMEX> of the input <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> was retained on
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> beads. A small amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> bound
          to the beads containing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> alone (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3, lane 3</ENAMEX>) which
          we have been unable to eliminate even after blocking with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unprogrammed</ENAMEX> translation lysate. However, it is clear
          that the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> is substantially increased when
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is present on the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beads</ENAMEX>. These data indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> are
          capable of interacting 
          in vitro .
        
        
          Elk-1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> interact in vivo, but only in
          the presence of activated Ras
          Since we observed an 
          in vitro interaction between the
          Elk-1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, we next tested whether the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> could interact 
          in vivo as well. To do this, we
          used a co-immunoprecipitation approach. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells were
          transfected with an expression vector for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">6X</NUMEX> histidine
          tagged construct of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> carrying the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">φ 10</NUMEX> (T7 tag)
          epitope sequence either in the presence or absence of
          Elk-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Cell lysates were incubated with T7 tag <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX> agarose
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beads</ENAMEX> followed by immunoblotting of the precipitated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elk-1 Ab</ENAMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, there is no
          Elk-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> precipitated with the tagged <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> protein
          when both are transfected (lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). However, since the
          synergism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> is observed when
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activated Ras</ENAMEX> is present, we thought it likely that the
          interaction between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> could be
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras-dependent.</ENAMEX> Indeed, when activated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ras</ENAMEX> is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-transfected along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and histidine-tagged
          p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is precipitated with the
          p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> (lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possible explanation for this
          result is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX> increases the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> or
          Elk-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells, but Western blot
          analysis showed that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> protein
          levels are the same in the absence and presence of Ras
          (data not shown). Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elk</ENAMEX>-1
          interact in 
          vivo , but only in response to
          activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>-dependent signaling pathways.
        
        
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> is necessary to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">interact with Elk-1</ENAMEX> in vitro
          Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> interact, we next wanted to
          narrow down the domains of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that are required
          for their interaction. To determine the domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPβ
          that is necessary to interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>, a
          p20-C/EBPβ-GST fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was constructed. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p20-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>
          encodes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> kDa form of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>, which lacks the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal transactivation domain of the longer
          p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> isoform. This isoform, however, shares the
          C-terminal DNA binding and dimerization domain with
          p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, approximately the same
          amount of [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35S</TIMEX>]-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Elk-1</ENAMEX> is retained on both the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p20-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> beads (compare <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Therefore, deletion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPβ
          has no effect on its ability to interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>. This
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> demonstrates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal region of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> is
          sufficient to mediate interaction with Elk-1 
          in vitro .
        
        
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal A-box of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> is sufficient to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">interact with C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> in vitro
          In order to narrow down the domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> that is
          necessary to interact with C/EBPβ 
          in vitro , we made several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Elk</ENAMEX>-1
          deletion mutants (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6A) and tested these constructs in
          a pulldown assay with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>. Elk-1(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-209</ENAMEX>) is a
          C-terminal deletion mutant that lacks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>box.
          Elk-1(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-140</ENAMEX>) is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal deletion, but it lacks
          both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B- and C-</ENAMEX>boxes. Therefore, this mutant contains
          neither a transactivation domain nor an SRF binding
          domain. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89-428</NUMEX>) is a deletion of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal A-box. Glutathione agarose beads containing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> alone were incubated with 
          in vitro -translated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> mutants
          labeled with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35S</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">methionine</ENAMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6B, the
          C-terminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mutants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-209</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-140</ENAMEX>),
          bound to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> beads to the same extent as
          wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> (compare lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> of top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> panels).
          However, the A-box deletion mutant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89-428</NUMEX>), no
          longer binds to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">lane 3</ENAMEX>, bottom
          panel). Therefore, this data demonstrates that the A-box
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> is necessary to interact with C/EBPβ 
          in vitro .
        
      
      
        Discussion
        We have shown that the transcription factors <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and
        p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> synergize in transactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>-dependent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> using both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAL4</ENAMEX> and SRE-driven reporter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constructs</ENAMEX>. Interestingly, this synergy is only observed in
        response to mitogenic stimulation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>. We have also
        demonstrated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>
        interact using both 
        in vitro GST-pulldown and 
        in vivo coimmunoprecipitation assays.
        The 
        in vivo interaction, however, is
        dependent on the presence of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ras</ENAMEX>. Finally, we
        demonstrate that the 
        in vitro interaction domains of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elk</ENAMEX>-1.
        These results suggest a new mechanism for
        transactivation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>, where a competent
        transcriptional complex consisting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> participate in transactivation in response
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>. To this point, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have been
        thought to be the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX> signaling to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>,
        and activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX> has been shown to result in
        transactivation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. However, we show that Ras
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> alone does not result in maximal SRE
        transactivation, but instead, is greatly enhanced in the
        presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> have been shown to form a ternary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> at
        the SRE 
        in vitro . We as yet have not been
        able to observe a ternary complex between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> and
        p35<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> at the SRE 
        in vitro . The mechanisms of SRE
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transactivation</ENAMEX> described above may help to explain the 
        in vitro results. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/</ENAMEX>EBPβ
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> site in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> is a weak binding site [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>].
        Upon activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>-dependent signaling pathways, the
        presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> would be stabilized due
        to its strong <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-protein</ENAMEX> interactions not only with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>, as we have shown previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>], but also with
        Elk-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. It is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> are not
        sufficient to form a ternary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> with the SRE 
        in vitro , but Elk-1 may also be
        necessary. In addition, it is likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>,
        Elk-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, or both, may need to be activated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> for a multiprotein <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> to form with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>. Further studies utilizing the information
        from the 
        in vivo studies performed here may
        permit us to optimize the 
        in vitro conditions necessary to
        observe such a multiprotein <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>.
        We observe a direct interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elk</ENAMEX>-1
        in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> pulldown assay. Another ets family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ets-1</ENAMEX>,
        has previously been shown to interact with C/EBPβ 
        in vitro [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>]. We have not directly
        tested the ability of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> famlily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, SAP1
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAP2/ERP/NET</ENAMEX>, to interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>. We find that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">domain of Elk-1</ENAMEX> that interacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> is the ets
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">domain</ENAMEX>, which is conserved among the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX> family
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. We would therefore also expect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SAP1</TIMEX> and
        SAP2<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/ERP/NET</ENAMEX> to interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>. Interestingly, the 
        in vivo interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and
        C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBPβ</ENAMEX> is dependent on activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>-dependent
        signaling pathways. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>(s) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX> signaling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> is as yet unknown. It has been shown that
        transfection of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX> results in phosphorylation of
        Thr235 (numbering for human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal
        domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thr235</ENAMEX> could be phosphorylated
        by a partially purified MAPK preparation 
        in vitro [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. We have also shown
        that this same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> is necessary for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX> stimultion of
        the interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>. Therefore, it will
        be interesting to determine if this site is also critical
        for stimulation of the interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and
        Elk-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elk-1</ENAMEX> also has several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">domain</ENAMEX>, and therefore this region could also be a target
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras</ENAMEX>.
        We are currently investigating the mechanism of the
        observed synergy between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elk-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>. We have
        shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> interacts with the A-box of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>, while
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> has previously been shown to interact with the B-box [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>]. Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX> interact with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct
        domains of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>, as well as with each other, which could
        allow formation of a complex of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> transcription
        factors. This would create an active transcriptional
        complex at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> and result in enhanced transactivation.
        It is possible that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ-SRF-Elk-1</ENAMEX> complex could
        interact more strongly with coactivators and/or the basal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">transcriptional</ENAMEX> machinery than each individual
        transcription factor. It has been shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX>, and
        C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBPβ</ENAMEX> can all interact with components of transcriptional
        machinery such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p300/CBP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-1</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TFII-I</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 28, 29</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>]. There is most likely a large protein complex assembled
        at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX> composed of regulated transcription factors,
        coactivators, and the basal transcriptional machinery,
        resulting in rapid transcription of the 
        c-fos gene in response to mitogenic
        stimulation.
      
      
        Conclusions
        This report demonstrates a new model for 
        c-fos SRE activation in response to
        Ras-dependent signaling pathways. We show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Elk-1</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> are all necessary for maximal Ras-stimulated
        transactivation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Culture and Transfections</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3T3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> (from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX>
          Collection) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">COS-7 cells</ENAMEX> (kindly provided by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanderbilt University</ENAMEX>) were grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modified Eagle Medium</ENAMEX> (DMEM) with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> calf serum
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Serum Company</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.22%</NUMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bicarbonate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L-glutamine</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> of penicillin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> sodium per mL, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
          mg of streptomycin per mL.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell transfections</ENAMEX> were performed by the calcium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX> (CaPO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ) technique [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>]. Cells at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60-70%</NUMEX>
          confluence were exposed to the CaPO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA precipitate</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 h.</TIMEX> The medium
          was removed and replaced with complete medium for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> h
          before harvesting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3T3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">transfections</ENAMEX> were performed
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NovaFector</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venn Nova</ENAMEX>) or Trans-IT LT1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PanVera</ENAMEX>) as
          described by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NovaFector</ENAMEX> transfections, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ratio of
          NovaFector:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was used for each transfection. Cells at
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60-70%</NUMEX> confluence were exposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NovaFector</ENAMEX>:DNA
          complex for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6-7 h</TIMEX> in serum and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX> free medium.
          After the incubation, an equal volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> calf serum was added for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX>, bringing the final
          concentration of calf serum to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>. Cells were then serum
          deprived for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36-40</NUMEX> h in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> supplemented as above except
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> calf serum before harvesting. For
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TransIT</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-LT1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">transfections</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TransIT</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-LT1</ENAMEX>:DNA
          was used in each transfection. Cells at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60-70%</NUMEX> confluence
          were exposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TransIT</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-LT1</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> h in
          complete medium plus freshly added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/mL polymyxin B
          antibiotic [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was then removed and
          replaced with complete medium for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h. Cells</ENAMEX> were then
          serum deprived in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> calf serum for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">36-40 h</TIMEX> before harvesting. Cell extracts were prepared
          and chloramphenicol acetyl transferase (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX>) assays were
          performed on extracts containing equivalent cell protein
          as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>]. An internal control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX> to measure transfection efficiency could not be
          used because <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> regulates transcrption from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> plasmid, and thus makes the internal control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invalid</ENAMEX>. Therefore, the transfections were repeated
          multiple times to control for variability in transfection
          efficiency.
        
        
          Plasmids
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">pGAL4</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pG5CAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plasmids</ENAMEX> were obtained from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mammalian MATCHMAKER</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hybrid Assay Kit</ENAMEX> (CLONTECH).
          pGAL4-SRF was constructed as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>].
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SRE-CAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene was constructed as previously
          described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pGST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> was constructed by
          inserting the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,739</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bp EcoRI</ENAMEX> fragment from pRSETB-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EFII</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>] into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EcoRI</ENAMEX> cut pGEX-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4T</NUMEX>-1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham-Pharmacia</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pGST-p20-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> was constructed by inserting the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">581 bp</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BamHI/EcoRI</ENAMEX> fragment from pRsetA-LIP [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>] into similarly
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">digested pGEX4T-1</ENAMEX>. pcDNA3<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/Elk-1</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-209</ENAMEX>) and
          pcDNA3<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/Elk-1</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-140</ENAMEX>) were constructed by using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Erase-A-Base</ENAMEX> system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>) with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pcDNA3/Elk-1</ENAMEX> (gift of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Schwartz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>) as described by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pcDNA3.1/His-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> was constructed by
          inserting an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,739</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bp EcoRI</ENAMEX> fragment from pRSETB-EFII
          into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EcoRI</ENAMEX> cut pcDNA3.1/HisC vector (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CMV-LAP</ENAMEX> was a gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. Schibler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Univ</ENAMEX>. of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geneva</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Geneva</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV-Ras</ENAMEX>.V12 was a gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanderbilt Univ</ENAMEX>.).
        
        
          Analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELK-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX> interaction in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitro</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p35-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-p20-C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> alone was
          produced in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BL21 E. Coli</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> mM
          isopropyl-β<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-D-thiogalactopyranoside</NUMEX> (IPTG) induction
          overnight at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. Cells were harvested by centrifugation
          and washed once with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">phosphate-buffered</NUMEX> saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>)
          containing the following protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 mg/ml</ENAMEX>
          aprotinin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml leupeptin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM phenylmethylsulfonyl
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fluoride</ENAMEX> (PMSF), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> mM pepstatin. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> were
          lysed by sonication at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> oC in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing the
          protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> described above. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX> was
          added to a final concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>, followed by
          gentle mixing for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. The lysate was clarified
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> × g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. The supernatant was
          gently mixed with glutathione-sepharose beads
          (Amersham-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Beads</ENAMEX> containing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GST proteins</ENAMEX> were collected by low speed centrifugation,
          followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> successive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">washes</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">X-100</ENAMEX> and the protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> described
          above.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ELK-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELK-1</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-209</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELK-1</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-140</ENAMEX>), and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELK-1</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89-428</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were transcribed and translated in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitro</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T7</ENAMEX> coupled reticulocyte lysate system
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>) according to the manufacture's instructions.
          Translated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were radiolabeled with the EXPRE 35S
          35S <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein labeling mix</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dupont NEN</ENAMEX>). The GST-pulldown
          assay was done as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>].
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-Immunoprecipitation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cells were harvested in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mM
          sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vanadate</ENAMEX> and collected by low speed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centrifugation</ENAMEX>. Cells were resuspended in lysis buffer
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonidet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-40</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mg of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">aprotinin</ENAMEX>/mL, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mM
          sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vanadate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">molybdate</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM
          β-glycerol phosphate) and lysed by sonication with a
          microtip on setting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 and 20%</NUMEX> duty cycle for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> s. After
          clarification by centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> × g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>,
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> extract was incubated with T7 tag antibody
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX>)-agarose beads (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novagen</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h.</TIMEX> The beads were
          collected by low speed centrifugation and washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times
          with lysis buffer. All steps were performed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. After
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">washing</ENAMEX>, the beads were boiled for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 min</NUMEX> in Laemmli
          sample buffer.
        
        
          Immunoblots
          The samples from the coimmunoprecipitations described
          above were analyzed by electrophoresis on an SDS-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX>
          polyacrylamide gel for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 h</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.</ENAMEX> The gel was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equilibrated</ENAMEX> in transfer buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tris</ENAMEX> base, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">192</NUMEX> mM
          glycine, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX> before transfer of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immobilon</ENAMEX>-P membrane (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millipore Corp.</ENAMEX>). After
          transfer, an immunoblot was performed as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. A <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:2000</ENAMEX> dilution of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elk-1 Ab</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:5000</ENAMEX> dilution of goat
          anti-rabbit secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche Molecular Biochemicals</ENAMEX>)
          were used. The secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX> was detected using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SuperSignal Chemiluminescent Substrate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aa</ENAMEX>, amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bp</ENAMEX>, base <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>; CaPO 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , calcium phosphate; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPβ</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCAAT-enhancer binding protein</ENAMEX>-beta; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX>, chloramphenicol
        acetyl transferase; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco's Modified Eagle Medium</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX>, glutathione-S-transferase; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX>, mitogen activated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, phosphate buffered saline; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX>,
        phenylmethylsulfonyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRE</ENAMEX>, serum response element;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRF</ENAMEX>, serum response factor; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCF</ENAMEX>, ternary complex
        factor.
      
    
  
