
  
    
      
        Background
        Recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> national surveys [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] show that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18.9%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were frankly obese, a marked increase
        from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17.8%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, underscoring the fact that over the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few decades</TIMEX>, an emerging epidemic of obesity has
        become a major cause of preventable death [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] and disease
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . Recognizing the effects of obesity on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
        health, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and industry have vigorously pursued
        the genetic, metabolic and environmental roots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">obesity</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . Despite the effort, it remains true that little
        is known about prevention of obesity and its treatment
        remains no less difficult or failure prone than it ever was
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 10</NUMEX> ] .
        Attention <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder</ENAMEX> (ADHD) is also
        a common disorder, even if its prevalence is not precisely
        known. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the rate of occurrence has customarily
        been given as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>, but recent studies show the
        condition is present in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> or more of school age
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] . Persistence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> into adulthood
        has been shown to occur in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> (or more) of childhood
        cases [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] , depending on the criteria used [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . It
        is clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> with a history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> in childhood
        have greater difficulty functioning compared to their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">non-ADHD</ENAMEX> peers [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example is the higher rate of
        substance use disorders in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> compared to the
        general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , such use often viewed as a kind
        of "self-medication" of unpleasant emotions [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . In
        obesity, similar patterns of eating (seeking immediate
        gratification, using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to reduce dysphoria) have been
        observed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] , though not previously linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>.
        It is established that obesity has serious medical
        sequelae, and that both obesity and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> have psychiatric
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comorbidities</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20 21 22 23</NUMEX> ] , but surprisingly,
        searches found no existing literature describing comorbid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obesity</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>). However, one study [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ]
        reported a potentially relevant correlation between
        symptoms of conduct disorder (but not depression) during
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adolescence</ENAMEX> and obesity in early adulthood, attributed to
        common mechanisms underlying "impulsive aggression" and
        dysregulation of body weight. The role of impulsivity in
        this correlation is important, given that impulsive
        behavior is common in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>, pointing to a
        connection between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> and development of obesity, an idea
        consistent with our clinical observation that impulsive
        eating behaviors are common in adult and adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+ADHD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        With persistent effort some bariatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> have been
        able to achieve and maintain a reduced level of body fat.
        In the bariatric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Behavioral Medicine Center for</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treatment and Research</ENAMEX> (BMedCTR) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, among
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who failed, a subset was observed to have
        unusual difficulty adhering to diet and exercise plans, and
        as a result lost less fat mass than typically occurs.
        Diagnostic evaluation showed a substantial fraction of
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had Attention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>), a condition that was recognized in our clinical
        work as a risk factor for poor treatment outcome.
        Fortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> often responded to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pharmacological</ENAMEX> and behavior therapies, with results that
        included improved task persistence, decreased impulsivity
        and distractability, and for some, greater success with
        weight control efforts.
        Cumulative bariatric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> experience showed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+ADHD
        was commonly encountered, and a potent contributor to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">obesity</ENAMEX> treatment failure. In this context it became clear
        that more information about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> was needed and that
        wider exposure of this comorbidity would be valuable (and
        interesting) to clinicians treating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">obese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        Consequently, this report was constructed to begin
        exploring the basic characteristics of this heretofore
        unrecognized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        The primary working hypothesis was that the prevalence
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> among obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was higher than in the general
        adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. In addition, it was anticipated that ADHD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> would have less weight loss, fewer visits and
        shorter duration of treatment than their non-ADHD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>.
        Differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were not expected to be widely
        divergent.
        The method used to conduct a systematic examination of
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had been treated for obesity at BMedCTR
        during the period, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan 1, 2000 through Dec 31, 2000</TIMEX>, and
        enrolled in treatment by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov 30, 2000</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>'s
        scheduling database referenced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215</NUMEX> unique <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who
        were active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> during the study period.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> relevant to demographic and clinical status was
        collected from medical records including age, sex, body
        mass index (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>) at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and last visits, interval between
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and last visits, number of visits, and diagnosis of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> entered in the record during the course of obesity
        treatment. This diagnosis was not determined
        retrospectively, although the diagnosis was confirmed to be
        supported by the written record of behavioral observations.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215</NUMEX> records were were divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>: patients
        without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> (NAD), those with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> symptoms or behaviors,
        but not meeting diagnostic criteria for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> (ADSx), and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX>).
        Diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> was made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> during the
        course of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' obesity treatment, using
        semi-structured interviews over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more visits.
        Structure was in accord with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX> criteria, that is, a
        patient needed to have shown, or given substantial history
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> or more inattentive behaviors to be considered as
        having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> who had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 6</NUMEX>, but at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        inattentive symptoms were classified as having symptoms of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> but not diagnosed as having the disorder. None of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 6</NUMEX> hyperactive-impulsive symptoms.
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>' inattentive and hyperactive/impulsive behaviors
        were not separately tabulated during records review.) At
        the time diagnoses had been made, a behavior was not
        considered a symptom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> if occurring only in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> with obesity treatment, for example, trouble
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adhering</ENAMEX> to diet or exercise plans. A significant level of
        impairment associated with symptoms was required for ADHD
        to be diagnosed. While many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had current or
        past treatment for depression or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX>, these conditions
        were required to be in remission or insufficiently
        prominent to obscure or account for ADHD behavior or
        impairment for the diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> to be made.
        The interview method is termed semi-structured because
        in a clinical setting the approach to each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was
        necessarily individualized (at least to some degree).
        Within this constraint, information was gathered in a
        reasonably consistent manner, in that the same pieces of
        information were sought from each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, the same
        questions asked of each, even if the order of inquiry
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">varied</ENAMEX>, that is to say, the path through the "decision
        tree" reflected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' differences.
        During the period of treatment, and diagnosis, a single
        exception to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV ADHD</ENAMEX> diagnostic criteria was made
        regarding age of onset (nominally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 years</TIMEX>), for several
        reasons. Pragmatically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult patients</ENAMEX> were often uncertain
        about the precise age symptoms began, though often able to
        identify a time in early childhood when symptoms were
        already occurring, e.g., "in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2nd</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3rd</NUMEX> grade", making
        it impossible to be certain if symptoms were present before
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 7</TIMEX>. For middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> confirmation of
        early events was seldom available, leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s
        recall as the only data source. Recent studies have shown
        that patient memory was consistent enough with other
        information to be useful for diagnostic purposes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>' reports were likely to be accurate, but there
        were often "gaps" in memory of early experience, not
        inconsistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> in general, favoring an inference
        that they didn't remember their behavior rather than not
        having had the behavior. It was concluded that the risk of
        misdiagnosis by modifying the age of onset criterion was
        much lower than the risks of not diagnosing a condition for
        which treatment can make a great difference in life
        quality. In other words, for this population the risks of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underdiagnosing ADHD</ENAMEX> were judged to be far more
        consequential than risks of overdiagnosing the disorder.
        Accordingly, during treatment, diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> was made
        when all other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX> criteria were met and symptoms were
        clearly evident by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years of age</TIMEX>.
        A similar point was made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wender</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] , who argued
        that availability of low-risk treatments for debilitating
        conditions warrants clinicians using less specific criteria
        to avoid excluding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who may benefit. A different
        argument was made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barkley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biederman</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] , that
        requiring symptoms to have been present by a single,
        specific point in early childhood in order to diagnose ADHD
        is not rational, that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> is better conceptualized as
        a disorder arising in childhood generally.
        None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had a level of
        hyperactivity-impulsivity meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX> criteria,
        therefore all were classifiable as having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Inattentive Type</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were tested using Unix-based tools including xmstat
        and xlispstat. Significance was set at α = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>. Analysis
        of variance was applied to means of age, starting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>,
        difference between starting and ending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>, number of
        visits and length of treatment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi-square test</ENAMEX> was used to
        determine significance of differences among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> groups
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> categories. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> classification [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> was
        used, defining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obesity III</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extreme Obesity</ENAMEX>) as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI ></ENAMEX>=
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obesity</ENAMEX> classes <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">I and II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obesity</ENAMEX>) as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 to 39.9</NUMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Overweight</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 to 29.9</NUMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        Results are summarized in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in
        the sample were predominantly female, there was no
        significant difference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.52</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">212</NUMEX>, p =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NS</ENAMEX>) or gender distribution (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">chi-square</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.35</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, p =
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.31</NUMEX>) among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mean Starting BMI - Ending BMI</ENAMEX>
        was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.32</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.02</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, but the difference
        was not significant (unpaired t-test, t = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.73</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">192, 213</TIMEX>, p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.09</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subjects</ENAMEX> were characterized by a variable level of
        obesity, divided into one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three obesity</NUMEX> classes
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">overweight</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ov</ENAMEX>, moderate to severe obesity:<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I-II</ENAMEX>, and
        extreme obesity:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">III</ENAMEX>), and a range of symptoms (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX>, or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX>). These classifications were organized into a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 × 3</ENAMEX>
        array which was suitable for determining prevalence of ADHD
        in whole sample and looking at the differences in ADHD
        prevalence among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of obesity.
        The whole sample of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">215</NUMEX> obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, partitioned by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27.4%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI:<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21.1% to 32.9%</NUMEX>)
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33.5%</NUMEX> (CI:<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27.2% to 39.8%</NUMEX>) were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX>
        or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39.1%</NUMEX> (CI:<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32.6% to 45.6%</NUMEX>) were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi-square</ENAMEX> test of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX>) vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">obesity</NUMEX> classes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>,
        I-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ov</ENAMEX>) showed that differences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 × 3</ENAMEX> table were
        significant (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">chi-square</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.23</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.025</NUMEX>). The
        proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> in obesity class III
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ob-III</ENAMEX>) was significantly greater than for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Obesity I-II</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ob-I/II</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ov</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">chi-square</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.86</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.002</NUMEX>).
        However, the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ov</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> did not
        significantly differ from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ob-I/II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ob-III</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">chi-square</NUMEX> =
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.60</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.11</NUMEX>).
        There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ob-III</ENAMEX>, which is
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42.6%</NUMEX> (CI:<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36.3% to 48.9%</NUMEX>) of all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ob</ENAMEX>-III <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the
        sample. Similarly, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AD with Ob-I/II</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.8%</NUMEX>
        [CI:<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.6% to 31.0%</NUMEX>] of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">101 Ob-I/II</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> AD in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ov</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18.9%</NUMEX>
        [CI:<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.4% to 29.4%</NUMEX>] of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ov</ENAMEX>), though the value for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD/Ov</ENAMEX>
        was not statistically distinct from AD in other obesity
        classes.
        Analysis of variance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> at the start of
        treatment showed a significant difference among the group
        means (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.86</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,212</NUMEX>, p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.003</NUMEX>), with AD having a
        higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">39.2</NUMEX>) than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">35.5</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">34.6</NUMEX>). Further
        analysis with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fisher</ENAMEX> multiple comparison test found AD
        differed from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> were not
        significantly different (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>, AD-ADSx: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.001</NUMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD-NAD</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>, ADSx-NAD: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.49</NUMEX>).
        Body weight loss was calculated as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starting BMI - Ending</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> achieved nearly twice the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> loss as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX>,
        at means of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.6 and 2.3</NUMEX> respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.25</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> =
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,212</NUMEX>, p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.002</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> was distinct from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> and ADSx
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD-AD</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.009</NUMEX>, NAD-ADSx: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.001</NUMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD-ADSx</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.666</NUMEX>). As percent change from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starting BMI</ENAMEX>,
        mean loss was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.2%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.5% and 6.3%</NUMEX> respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.40</NUMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,212</NUMEX>, p =<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>), with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> being significantly
        different from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> which did not differ from each
        other (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD-AD</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.001</NUMEX>, NAD-ADSx: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.001</NUMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD-ADSx</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.93</NUMEX>).
        The subgroup of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obesity III</ENAMEX> showed a
        larger difference in mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> change, that is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> loss by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> status for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of this subgroup was: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NAD 7.0</NUMEX> (SD
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.0</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.9</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SD 4.5</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ADSx 3.4</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SD 2.8</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.09</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> =
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,58</NUMEX>, p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.004</NUMEX>). The weight loss for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> was again
        different from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obesity III</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were AD or ADSx,
        but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> were not significantly different (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD-AD</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.001</NUMEX>, NAD-ADSx: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>, AD-ADSx: p
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.657</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obesity III AD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> were analyzed by
        the non-parametric approximate randomization test (AR test)
        which also showed a significant difference between the two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.003</NUMEX> (CI:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0019</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.0041</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10000</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">randomizations</ENAMEX>).
        Among the whole sample of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">obese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, mean number of
        visits was greater in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.69</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,212</NUMEX>, p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.027</NUMEX>)
        with AD differing significantly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD-NAD</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX>, AD-ADSx: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>, NAD-ADSx: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.73</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AR</ENAMEX> test applied to the number of visits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> and NAD
        revealed a marginally significant difference (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.040</NUMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.036</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.048</NUMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4000</TIMEX> randomizations). The number of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> in treatment was not significantly different among
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.03</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">df</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,212</NUMEX>, p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.13</NUMEX>), though
        there appeared to be a trend toward alonger duration of
        treatment in AD. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AR</ENAMEX> test results for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> showed a
        nearly significant difference, remaining better described
        as trend toward a difference (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.054</NUMEX> (CI:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.050</NUMEX> to
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.058</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12000</NUMEX> randomizations).
      
      
        Discussion
        The most important results are the prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27.4%</NUMEX> in the sample, and the surprisingly strong
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obesity III</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly half</NUMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42.6%</NUMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obesity III</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>, that is, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was concentrated in the obesity class
        having the highest mortality and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> risks, and
        greatest need for effective treatment.
        Moreover, at all levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">obesity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with ADHD
        symptoms were less successful at losing weight than
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">non-ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. Compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> had a significantly
        higher starting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">39.6</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">34.2</NUMEX>), yet lost less weight
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.6</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.0 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2</ENAMEX>). Greater contrast is found in Obesity
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> in that class achieving more than twice the
        weight loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.0</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.9 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2</ENAMEX>), while mean weight
        loss for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> did not differ significantly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.3</NUMEX> vs.
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.6 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2</ENAMEX>), implying that the presence of even
        "subthreshhold" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> symptoms reduces the effectiveness of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">obesity</ENAMEX> treatment. In other words, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>, treatment
        outcome has stronger association with symptoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> than
        level of obesity. Effect size of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> for the whole sample
        was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 0.2</NUMEX>, but in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obesity III</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, effect
        size was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 0.5</NUMEX>, comparable, for example, to the
        moderate effect size of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSRI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> on panic symptoms [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ]
        .
        Impersistence was not the cause of worse results for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX>,
        who attended more visits than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">56.0</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39.4</NUMEX> mean total
        visits), over a longer span of time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> was no more
        successful than AD, but had fewer visits, comparable to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX>, in this respect, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> showing characteristics
        intermediate between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX>. The result is AD, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADSx</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NAD</ENAMEX> having similar rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> visits (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>
        visits/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ADSx 1.2 and NAD 1.4</NUMEX>), while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> had the
        highest rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> decrease (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, ADSx
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.075</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.067</NUMEX>). However, these statistics have limited
        utility, given the large variance in number of visits and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of treatment. The "slow" aspect of task performance
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> has been previously reported [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] , and could be
        described as a kind of "inefficiency", that is, taking more
        time to accomplish less.
        The reasons for a strong association between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obesity</ENAMEX> (particularly extreme obesity) are unknown, but
        there are a number of reported findings that appear to be
        relevant and certainly interesting. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, evidence
        exists that variations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dopamine receptor</ENAMEX> (DR) genes
        affect both conditions. In obesity, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DRD2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DRD4</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31</NUMEX> ]
        genes, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">DRD4</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX> ] gene, have been
        implicated in the transmission of, or predisposition to,
        the disorders, raising the possibility that similar,
        overlapping or shared DR functioning (or dysfunction) in
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX> is related to their co-co-occurrence.
        DRD2 and a range of dopamine and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> have been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with a "reward <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">deficiency syndrome</ENAMEX>" [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] in
        which insufficient dopamine-mediated "natural" reward leads
        to use of "unnatural" rewards, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>,
        gambling, risk taking and inappropriate eating. This
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX> is associated with obesity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] , and common in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">DRD4</NUMEX> gene has been associated with
        "novelty seeking" traits, said to be greater in substance
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abusers</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DRD2</ENAMEX> and DRD4
        genetic variations may be especially prone to multiple
        difficulties (e.g., having both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> and "reward deficiency
        syndrome") [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] , further suggesting obesity and ADHD
        could share neurobiological attributes.
        A recent study showed the availability of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">striatal</ENAMEX> DRD2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX> was decreased as a function of increasing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> ] , supporting the idea that reward-seeking behavior
        plays a role in the onset or continuation of obesity. In
        other studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">D2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">agonists</ENAMEX> resulted in
        decreases in hyperinsulinemia associated with obesity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>
        ] , and it is known that the brain is richly supplied with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin receptors</ENAMEX>, including the cortex and striatal areas
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] , suggesting an intriguing link between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        resistance, characteristic of obesity, and
        dopamine-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mediated</NUMEX> psychiatric symptoms, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>. No
        doubt, this hypothesis and many far more refined hypotheses
        will be studied in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming years</TIMEX> and will elucidate the
        complex neurophysiological connections hinted at by the
        above.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27.4%</NUMEX> prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> in obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> is
        considerably higher than found in the general adult
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, reported as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.7%</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barkley</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] .
        Across studies of other specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, prevalence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> or ADHD symptoms was also greater than in general, for
        example, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> abusers <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety disorders</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16%</NUMEX>
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] , panic disorder <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] , and substance abusers
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] . Considering the differing methods and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX>, the reported prevalences are difficult to
        compare, yet are fairly consistent with one another for the
        most part. The prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> in this report is
        plausibly within the range of these studies.
        The uniformity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inattentive</ENAMEX> subtype of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> in
        this adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was not unusual or unexpected,
        considering the well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attenuation</ENAMEX> of hyperactive and
        impulsive symptoms observed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> grow into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adolescence</ENAMEX> and adulthood, compared to the much stronger
        retention of inattentive symptoms [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . This is not to
        say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> don't behave impulsively, simply that
        with maturation, continuing hyperactive/impulsive (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H/I</ENAMEX>)
        behaviors are usually expressed in less obvious ways than
        among their school-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. That is, while ADHD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> frequently have impairing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H/I</ENAMEX> 
        symptoms , the number and types of
        these behaviors seldom meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IV</ENAMEX> diagnostic 
        criteria for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H/I</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Combined</ENAMEX>
        subtype of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV ADHD</ENAMEX> subtyping, strictly applied,
        is likely to have limited correlation to neurobiological
        processes (assuming processes reflect impulsivity or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disinhibition</ENAMEX>), since the level of symptomatic behavior
        required for diagnosing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DSM</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV H/I</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Combined</ENAMEX> subtypes is
        higher than nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> will display, even if
        substantial H/I behavior is evident.
        Another factor is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, have
        lower rates of H/I symptoms, which is associated with lower
        likelihood of being diagnosed in childhood, but if
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagnosed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> more frequently have the Inattentive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subtype</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . It would be expected that this difference
        would persist into adulthood, augmenting the likelihood
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inattentive</ENAMEX> symptoms would predominate the clinical
        presentation. In a sample in which most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are female
        and middle-aged, predominance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inattentive</ENAMEX> subtype is
        predictable.
        Inevitably, there are numerous caveats and limitations
        that apply to this preliminary work. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, results
        reflect the origin of data in clinical practice - hardly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> from a research perspective. Treatment settings may
        favor a higher case-finding rate because of the opportunity
        to observe and assess behavior is greater than the methods
        of prospective research designs. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> research
        instruments have a sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70-90%</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44</NUMEX> ] , and
        would likely identify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer</NUMEX> cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> than the "gold
        standard" of careful clinical assessment, expected to find
        most cases. For this report, diagnosis had been made
        primarily by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>, which could favor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consistency</ENAMEX>, but also leads to potential biases that skew
        results. In addition, the modification of age of onset
        criterion for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> may increase difficulty of comparing
        present results to those of studies using the unmodified
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">criterion</ENAMEX>. Clearly, for the purpose of comparing prevalence
        among diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, a prospective design is strongly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">advantageous</ENAMEX>, but likely not congruent with the goals of
        clinical practice.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bias</ENAMEX> could also be introduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> factors, such
        as comorbid conditions producing symptoms which might not
        be easily separable from those found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>, and
        erroneously diagnosed as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>. Several disorders common in
        obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> fit into this category, e.g., obstructive
        sleep apnea, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety disorders</ENAMEX>. While the
        differential characteristics of these conditions, e.g.,
        relative duration, pervasiveness and continuity of symptoms
        can help distinguish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from another, the nature and
        interactions of these comorbidities are not particularly
        well-delineated. While careful clinical practice requires
        effort to avoid diagnosing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> if symptoms are not
        sufficiently distinct from those of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">confounding disorders</ENAMEX>,
        reducing error requires further research into the effects
        of comorbidities intercurrent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>.
        Another form of bias originates in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>'
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">predisposition</ENAMEX> to endorse symptoms because of dysphoria,
        negative affectivity, or readiness to attribute distress to
        some preferred, rather than actual, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> when queried by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, the idea is
        that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> may have had a preference for endorsing
        ADHD symptoms, instead of accepting more accurate
        explanations for distress or lack of obesity treatment
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progress</ENAMEX>, e.g., failure to lose weight while being
        unwilling to exercise. ("I can't lose weight because I just
        get so distracted.")
        Some forms of endorsement bias are readily seen in
        medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who would rather
        talk about somatic events than discuss their <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxieties</ENAMEX> or
        depressed mood. Implications for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> are
        hard to assess, since this form of bias and its effects on
        research of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> prevalence have not received comparable
        study, nor are there reports of the frequency of
        encountering this bias in clinical work with adult ADHD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Moreover, no special measures were taken to
        reduce or account for such biases during the course of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diagnosing patients</ENAMEX> in the present sample, rendering it
        quite difficult to estimate how much and what kind of
        effect biases have had on the above reported prevalences of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>. At this point, it remains an open question,
        suggesting additional reasons for cautious interpretation
        of the results given in this report.
        are worth a few comments. Notably, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 90%</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, which obviously does not reflect the
        general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, but may not be surprising in this
        context because more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are concerned about
        weight gain, and are more likely to seek medical care than
        male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> as a group were also
        distinctly middle-aged, no doubt reflecting the fact that
        older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are more likely to be able to afford
        non-insured medical care (obesity treatment isn't covered
        under most policies), and the time to devote to their own
        needs.
        Some effects of demographic factors on diagnosis of ADHD
        were discussed above. Gender and age differences (e.g.,
        younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> or higher male to female ratio) could
        conceivably affect the range and intesity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> symptoms
        that are observed, prevalence findings, and individual as
        well as aggregate response to obesity treatment.
        In addition, generalizability of conclusions based on
        the data in this report are limited by a modest sample
        size, and uncertainty that the bariatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the
        sample were truly representative of the general obese
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Results could be misleading, for example, if
        the sample had a disproportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with serious
        medical or psychiatric problems, higher weight or greater
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> skill deficits, even if the sample is construed to
        be typical of those seen in similar practices.
      
      
        Conclusion
        This report is explicitly exploratory, and its findings
        need to be replicated in larger and more systematic
        studies. Nonetheless, these findings are already quite
        interesting and could have implications for the
        understanding of the etiology of obesity as well as the
        treatment of obesity. The nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX>, to the
        extent that they exist, between attention and obesity is of
        course not at all clear, but the results may point to forms
        of attentional components and impulsivity playing a role in
        the onset or continuation of obesity, or that attentional
        mechanisms are linked in some way to metabolic and energy
        storage regulation.
        Implications for clinical practice may be of more
        immediate consequence. Treatment of obesity has been
        marginally effective at best, particularly for extreme
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obesity</ENAMEX>. If an attentional disorder is present, conceivably
        its treatment could improve obesity treatment outcome,
        which makes awareness of the ADHD-obesity comorbidity
        pragmatically important. It has been shown that reduction
        of body weight as small as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> substantially reduces the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and mortality risks of obesity, so even if
        recognizing and treating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> is only a modest contributor
        to reducing body fat mass, it is worthwhile on that grounds
        alone. Moreover, the impairment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> is an intrinsic
        reason to diagnose and treat the condition, because even if
        comorbid obesity were not changed, normalizing brain
        function in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX> sufferers more often than not provides
        substantial benefit and improved quality of life.
        The apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>, relatively poor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">obesity</ENAMEX> treatment outcome and high prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OB</ENAMEX>+ADHD
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27.4%</NUMEX>), especially in the extremely obese (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42.6%</NUMEX>), argue
        that comorbid ADHD increases the health risks of obesity,
        and that extreme obesity, itself a stressful condition,
        adds burden to the profound impairments common in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADHD</ENAMEX>. The
        chance that more knowledge could lead to reduction of
        suffering, disability and economic cost offers compelling
        reasons for further investigation of this subject.
        Inclusion of more diverse and non-clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obese</ENAMEX> and extremely obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, and using research
        designs that better account for rater and subject biases,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inter</ENAMEX>-rater reliability, and diagnostic methodology, will
        likely give more definitive answers to this report's
        questions and implications.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JRA</ENAMEX> developed and wrote this report.
      
    
  
