
  
    
      
        Background
        Follicle stimulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> (FSH) regulates
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spermatogenesis</ENAMEX> through the somatic Sertoli <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Sertoli cells act as "nursing" cells and
        supplies germ cells with energy and controls the
        biochemical environment in which they develop [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Among
        the FSH-regulated functions are increased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> uptake
        and oxidation. In response to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, transcription of
        several glycolytic and lipogenic genes are activated
        through the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carbohydrate</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> response element
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIRE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ChoRE or IRE</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] . Upstream stimulatory factors
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX> are characterized by a basic/helix loop
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">helix/leucine zipper</ENAMEX> domain responsible for dimerization
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding, and are major components of the GIRE
        complex [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6 7 8</NUMEX> ] .
        The main <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USF isoforms USF1</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">43 kDa</NUMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF2</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">44 kDa</NUMEX>)
        are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ubiquitously</ENAMEX> expressed and encoded by separate genes [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 10 11</NUMEX> ] . In addition, more isoforms of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USF2</ENAMEX> are produced
        due to alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">splicing</ENAMEX> and utilization of different
        translation start sites [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> factors exist as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">homo</ENAMEX> and heterodimers, and the heterodimer of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">USF1/</ENAMEX>USF2a
        seems to dominate, although there are cell-type specific
        variations [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . USF1 and USF2 show different
        transactivating potential, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF2</TIMEX> appears to be the
        functional transactivator of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIRE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, although
        both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF1 and USF2</TIMEX> are important for sustained
        dietary-induced expression of the fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> synthase gene
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> isoforms are important for expression of several
        genes involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> cell growth and differentiation.
        Among genes that are stimulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX> during the
        period of maturation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 to 20 days</TIMEX> of age
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>), are several subunits of cAMP-dependent protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> (PKA), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">serine</ENAMEX>/threonine kinase mainly
        responsible for the downstream effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
        Expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subunit</ENAMEX> of cAMP-dependent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> is highly induced (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-fold</NUMEX>) at the mRNA
        level in primary cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat Sertoli</ENAMEX> cells as a late
        response to cAMP peaking at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . We have
        demonstrated that expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAAT/Enhancer</ENAMEX> binding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protein Î²</ENAMEX> (C/EBPÎ²) is induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX> with rapid kinetics
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> is responsible for
        induction of late response genes like the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RIIÎ²-gene</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ]
        . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> contains a conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-box/HLH</ENAMEX> element
        in the basal promoter localized at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-280</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-275</NUMEX> relative to
        the functional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATG</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . This element is shown to be
        important for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>-responsiveness in granulosa cells, and
        it has been shown to bind both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myc</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CHO</ENAMEX> and NB2a
        cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19</NUMEX> ] . In this work, we show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> isoforms
        may regulate cAMP responsiveness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> by
        modulating the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP</ENAMEX>, and that the formation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> isoforms may be regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> are formed on the RIIÎ²
          promoter
          A specific complex that formed a Dnase I footprint
          (-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">306</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-265</NUMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>-responsive region of the RIIÎ²
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> in granulosa cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] , covers a consensus
          E-box (CACGTG) known to bind helix-loop-helix (bHLH)
          transcription factors. Electrophoretic mobility shift
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> (EMSA) with extracts from Sertoli cells
          demonstrated specific binding to the conserved element
          using the footprinted region as probe [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . When
          incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> nuclear
          extracts at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> were formed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1,</ENAMEX>
          complex I to V). We found that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USF2 antibody</ENAMEX> shifted
          complex I and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1lanes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 and 4</NUMEX>), whereas complex
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> were completely shifted with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USF1 antibody</ENAMEX>,
          suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> contained homodimers.
          Complex V was not shifted by antibodies directed against
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF1</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF2</TIMEX>, but with antibodies
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-binding region of
          USF2 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Thus, this complex contained
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">truncated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2</ENAMEX>. A small shift in mobility of this complex
          was observed in extracts prepared from Sertoli cells
          treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-CPT-cAMP for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 h</TIMEX> (data not shown).
          Experiments using various protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> indicated
          that the changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> mobility were due to
          inhibitory effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX> on the protease calpain. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">truncated USF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes forming complexes</ENAMEX> III to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> were
          abolished in the presence of calpain inhibitor I (ALLN)
          (unpublished results).
        
        
          A <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31-kDa</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">isoform</ENAMEX> is induced by cAMP
          In order to study the existence of different variants
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> expressed under stimulated and basal conditions,
          we performed immunoblotting experiments with antibodies
          against C-terminal regions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF1 and USF2</TIMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF1</TIMEX>, we
          observed that a new immunoreactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 31</NUMEX>
          kDa was formed only in nuclear extracts from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">cAMP-stimulated Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A). This isoform was
          not soluble, but associated with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX> extractable
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fraction</ENAMEX> (not shown). In contrast, we found no
          significant changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USF2 protein</ENAMEX> levels or mobility
          following stimulation by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B). Other truncated
          USF1 or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">isoforms</ENAMEX> could not be detected in this
          assay, which may indicate that the levels of isoforms
          forming complex V (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) are very low relative to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">full-length protein</ENAMEX>. We were not able to relate the
          appearance of the novel <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31 kDa</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">isoform</ENAMEX> to changes in
          USF complex formation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSA</ENAMEX>. Formation of the truncated
          USF1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isoform</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>-treated cells was not affected by
          addition of calpain inhibitor (unpublished results).
        
        
          USF2 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">inhibits cAMP</ENAMEX>-mediated induction of the RIIÎ²
          promoter
          We investigated the function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> isoforms in
          regulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>, using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> reporter
          containing the basal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> including the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consensus E</ENAMEX>-box (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A) and expression vectors for
          USF1, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2a</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2b</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">isoforms</ENAMEX>. We found that none of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> isoforms affected basal transcription from the RIIÎ²
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">promoter</ENAMEX> (not shown) whereas both splice variants of USF2
          (a and b) reduced cAMP-stimulated levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
          expression to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX>. USF1, however, had no inhibitory
          effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>-mediated induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3Bshows a dose-dependent reduction of cAMP responsiveness
          with increasing amounts of USF2a expression vector with a
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> activity at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> ng of USF2a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> inhibition at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> ng of USF2a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          USF2 inhibits <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP-</ENAMEX>mediated induction of the RIIÎ²
          promoter
          We have previously reported that some of the late
          induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> by cAMP depends on the rapid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cAMP</ENAMEX>-mediated increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . To
          test the effect of different USF isoforms on
          C/EBPÎ²-mediated induction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>, we
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transfected</ENAMEX> combinations of the transcription factors
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). As previously reported, the full-length
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAP</ENAMEX>-form of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> induced the RIIÎ² promoter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-fold,
          whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ² LIP</ENAMEX>-form lacking the transactivating
          region had no effect. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co-transfecting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF1</ENAMEX> had no
          significant effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²-</ENAMEX>mediated induction, but
          USF2a (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1, USF2a</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> expression vectors) reduced
          induction by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX>, indicating that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF2a</TIMEX> may interrupt the
          ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> to transactivate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of several genes induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> in Sertoli
        cells and granulosa cells, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">c-Fos</ENAMEX>, transferrin,
        follicle stimulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> receptor, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> gene, contain functional E-box elements [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22 23 24</NUMEX>
        ] . We found that several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> containing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">full-length USF1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2</ENAMEX> as well as truncated versions,
        are formed at the consensus E-<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">box</ENAMEX>/HLH-binding element in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> nuclear extracts.
        USF1 and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">USF2</NUMEX> display identical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dimerization</ENAMEX> and DNA
        binding domains, but the transactivating regions differ [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ] . USF1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2</ENAMEX> obviously serve different, yet
        overlapping functions, and regulating the relative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">USF1/USF2</ENAMEX> levels may be decisive for the pattern of
        USF-mediated gene expression, which has been shown in
        studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">USF knockout mice</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2 -/-</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> has
        obvious growth defects and reduced fertility [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] ,
        whereas the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">USF1</NUMEX>-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> are viable and fertile with
        minor behavioural disturbances. A severe delay in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glucose</ENAMEX>-mediated regulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIRE</ENAMEX>-containing fatty
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid synthase</ENAMEX> (FAS) gene is found in both USF-deficient
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, although <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> response was unaltered, indicating
        that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF1/USF2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">heterodimer</ENAMEX> is implicated in FAS
        expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] .
        We have previously shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> functions as a
        secondary effector of cAMP signaling on slow response genes
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-</ENAMEX>box is shown be involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX> responsiveness
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> gene [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18</NUMEX> ] .
        Our present results indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2</ENAMEX> disturbs this
        C/EBPÎ²-mediated transactivation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX>. No consensus
        C/EBPÎ² binding site is found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> construct
        responsive to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX>, but a possibility exists
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> attach to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein/protein</ENAMEX> interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF1</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
        the transcriptional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> formed at the E-box. C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBP</ENAMEX> is
        previously reported to be an important accessory factor for
        transactivation by several other transcription factors [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>
        ] . C/EBPÎ² was shown to transactivate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î±1</NUMEX>-acid
        glycoprotein gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> even when mutated in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-binding domain, and this activation appeared to depend
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-protein</ENAMEX> interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucocorticoid</ENAMEX> receptor
        through the leucine zipper <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . Recently, a
        conserved domain in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> was shown to mediate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cAMP</ENAMEX> responsiveness, strengthening the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP</ENAMEX> may
        be characterized as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>-responsive nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] . On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COX-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> in granulosa cells,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cAMP</ENAMEX>-mediated regulation was shown to be mediated primarily
        by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-</ENAMEX>box that bind <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF1 and USF2</TIMEX> isoforms in a manner
        resembling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] .
        Transactivation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> in skin carcinoma cells
        is highly dependent on this E-box together with a C/EBP
        binding site that bind <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ´</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . These
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> strengthens a model of formation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>-responsive
        unit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRU</ENAMEX>) containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP</ENAMEX>. We propose a model of
        interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> by which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF2</TIMEX> inhibits
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP responsiveness</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²</ENAMEX>, either through
        interacting with the domain mediating the cAMP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">responsiveness</ENAMEX> or by competing with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF1</TIMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>-regulated formation of a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31-kDa</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF1</ENAMEX> isoform
        may also play a role in formation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ² CRU</ENAMEX>. This
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">truncated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF1</ENAMEX> isoform may result from proteolytic cleavage
        or may be a novel splice variant. In granulosa cells, it
        has previously been shown that the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminally
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">truncated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2</ENAMEX> is regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>. Binding of truncated
        USF2 to a HLH element in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prostaglandin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G/H</ENAMEX> synthase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PGHS-2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> was abolished in extracts from cells
        stimulated by human chorionic gonadotrophin (hCG) which
        signals through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] .
        Other reports have suggested a role for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> in
        inhibition of transcriptional activation mediated by other
        transcription factors. An inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> on
        Myc-mediated cellular proliferation has been demonstrated
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HeLa</ENAMEX> cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] , and a non-canonical HLH element
        inhibits expression of the fibroblast growth factor binding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (FGF-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX>) in several carcinoma cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] .
        Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2</ENAMEX> inhibits binding of hypoxia-inducible
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-1</ENAMEX> (HIF-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) to the plasminogen activator <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">inhibitor -1</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PAI-1</ENAMEX>) gene in hepatocytes in order to disturb
        transcriptional activation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . Our results add
        C/EBPÎ²-mediated activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> to the mechanisms
        inhibited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX>. An opposite role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBP</ENAMEX> could
        also be explained by the counteracting effects these
        transcription factors have on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose metabolism</ENAMEX>. Whereas
        USF induces expression of enzymes involved in glycolysis,
        C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBPÎ²</ENAMEX> regulates gluconeogenesis mainly by activating
        It has recently been reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> is implicated in
        transcriptional activation of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1a</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of the RIÎ±
        gene in skeletal muscle cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . Regulating the
        relative levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIÎ±</ENAMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> is physiologically
        important eg. in lipid metabolism [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39 40</NUMEX> ] , and a
        possible function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> in tuning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIÎ±/RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> ratio by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activating RIÎ±</ENAMEX> transcription and inhibiting RIIÎ²
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> is an interesting target of further
        investigation.
      
      
        Conclusions
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. USF1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2</ENAMEX>, as well as truncated USF isoforms,
        bind to a consensus E-box in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> in Sertoli
        cells.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclic</ENAMEX> AMP induces expression of a novel <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31-kDa</NUMEX> USF1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isoform</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Overexpression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF2</TIMEX>, but not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF1</TIMEX>, inhibits
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cAMP</ENAMEX>-mediated and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C/EBPÎ²-</ENAMEX>mediated induction of the RIIÎ²
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Antibodies
          USF antibodies specific for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF1</TIMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">83 to 157</TIMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">USF1N</NUMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF2a</TIMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids 1</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">49</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">USF2N</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USF2a/b</ENAMEX>
          amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">298 to 346</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">USF2C</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Preparation and stimulation of cell cultures
          Primary cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat Sertoli</ENAMEX> cells were made from
          testes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 days</TIMEX> old Sprague-Dawley <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> (B&K
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal AS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nittedal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>) according to the method
          of Dorrington 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">et al.</ENAMEX> with some modifications [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>
          ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturing</ENAMEX> and transfections were performed as
          described elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days</TIMEX> after
          transfections, the medium was changed, and incubation was
          continued in the presence or absence of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î</NUMEX>¼M
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-chlorophenyl</ENAMEX>)thio-cAMP (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-CPT-cAMP) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">St</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Preparation of nuclear extracts
          Nuclear extract from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 Ã— 10 6</NUMEX>) were
          prepared by solubilization of nuclei in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M NaCl</ENAMEX> as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA-Protein</ENAMEX> complex analysis
          Electrophoretic mobility shift assays (EMSAs) were
          performed using a double stranded [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32P</TIMEX>]-end-labeled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligonucleotide</ENAMEX> covering the consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-box/HLH</ENAMEX> element
          (underlined) and flanking sequences from the RIIÎ²
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">promoter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-305, 5</ENAMEX>'-GATCGCCGGGTTGCCATGGTTT CCGGGGAT
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CACGTGGGCGCGCGG-3</ENAMEX>', <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-268</NUMEX>). For each reaction, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 3cpm
          of labeled probe was incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼g</NUMEX> of crude nuclear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.0 Î¼g</NUMEX> of poly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dI</ENAMEX>:dC in a
          buffer containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hepes</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.9</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 %</NUMEX> glycerol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM
          MgCl at room temperature for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> min. Supershift
          experiments were performed by incubation of nuclear
          extract/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼l</NUMEX> USF <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>.
          Samples were run in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 %</NUMEX> non-denaturing polyacrylamide
          gels at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX>-150 V in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tris</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">glycine</NUMEX> buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX> pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">380</NUMEX> mM glycine, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM EDTA) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 to 5</TIMEX> h at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>.
          Subsequently, gels were dried and subjected to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoradiography</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Immunoblotting
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼g</NUMEX> of nuclear extract from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sertoli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> were loaded
          in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS PAGE</ENAMEX> gels and immunoblotting was performed as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] . Equal loading was
          determined by coomassie staining.
        
        
          Plasmids
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> construct containing the basal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> RIIÎ² <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-flanking region (-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">394</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-123</NUMEX>) upstream
          of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene (pCATbasic; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>)
          was used for assaying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIIÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
          Expression vectors for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">USF2a and USF2b</TIMEX> inserted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>'
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pCRâ„¢3</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen, Groningen</ENAMEX>, The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>) were used to overexpress <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isoforms</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ]
          . C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBPÎ² LAP</ENAMEX> (full-length) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-binding domain)
          expression vectors created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pCMVâ„¢3</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA) were appreciated gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shizua Akira</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyogo College of Medicine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hyogo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>). The luciferase
          expression vector pGL3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.25 Î¼g</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>) was used as an internal marker for
          transfection efficiency.
        
        
          Transfections, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luciferase</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX>-assays
          After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> of culture in serum free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>,
          lipofectamine-mediated transfections of primary cultures
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat Sertoli</ENAMEX> cells were performed (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Î¼g <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> per well in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well plates) and assayed as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GrÃ¸nning et al</ENAMEX>
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        List of abbreviations
        C; catalytic subunit, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX>; cyclic adenosine
        monophosphate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX>; chloramphenicol acetyl transferase,
        C/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EBP; CAAT</ENAMEX>/enhancer binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ChoRE</ENAMEX>; carbohydrate
        response element, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX>; cytalomega virus, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-CPT-cAMP;
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-chlorophenyl</ENAMEX>)thio-cAMP, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CREB</ENAMEX>; cAMP-response element
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding protein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSA</ENAMEX>; electrophoretic mobility shift
        assay, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAS</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acid synthase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX>; follicle stimulating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hormone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIRE</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose/insulin</ENAMEX> response element, hCG; human
        chorionic gonadotrophin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLH</ENAMEX>; helix-loop-helix, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRE</ENAMEX>;
        insulin response element, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX>; major histocompability
        complex, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGHS; prostaglandin G/H</ENAMEX> synthase, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKA</ENAMEX>;
        cAMP-dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>; regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subunit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USF</ENAMEX>;
        upstream stimulating factor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB; Western blot</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria K. Dahle</ENAMEX> (author <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) performed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSA</ENAMEX> and
        expression experiments and drafted the manuscript. Kjetil
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TaskÃ©n</ENAMEX> (author <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) participated in the design and
        coordination of the study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin A. TaskÃ©n</ENAMEX> (author <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
        initialized, planned and coordinated the study, performed
        the immunoblotting and contributed to all experiments. All
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
