
  
    
      
        Background
        The secreted glycoproteins in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt/Wingless</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX>)
        family serve diverse functions in developmental processes,
        ranging from cell fate specification and cell proliferation
        to cell migration and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> polarity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] , and
        deregulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> signaling pathway can lead to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] . In a simplified model of the canonical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wnt/Î²-</ENAMEX>catenin signaling pathway, the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnts</ENAMEX> to
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors activates</ENAMEX> a downstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dishevelled</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX> in turn inhibits glycogen synthase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> (GSK)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3Î²</NUMEX> in the Î²-catenin destruction complex, which
        mainly consists of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GSK-3Î²</ENAMEX>, adenomatous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polyposis coli</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX>) and Î²-catenin. Consequently, the level of cytoplasmic
        Î²-catenin rises, and stabilized Î²-catenin, together with
        the transcriptional factor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEF/TCF</ENAMEX>, regulates the
        transcription of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> target genes.
        The mechanism by which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> signal is transduced
        through its transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> is not clear. Wnt
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> have been shown to bind to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frizzleds</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fzs</ENAMEX>), which
        are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . The binding of
        Wnts occurs within an aminoterminal cysteine-rich-domain
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRD</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fzs</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least 11</NUMEX> vertebrate and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drosophila Fz</ENAMEX> genes
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stanford</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">edu/~rnusse/wntwindow.</ENAMEX>htmlhave been
        identified. However, their functions and ligand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specificities</ENAMEX> remain to be understood. Recently, it was
        reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two single</NUMEX>-transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LDL-receptor</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (LRP) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LRP5 and LRP6</TIMEX>,
        are also involved in receiving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> signal [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9</NUMEX> ] . 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila Arrow</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX>), which is
        homologous to murine and human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LRP5</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LRP6</ENAMEX>, was shown to
        be essential for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> signaling. Genetic data from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LRP6</TIMEX> play a positive role in Wnt
        signaling [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 9</NUMEX> ] . A genetic epistasis experiment placed
        Arr between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] , acting in parallel or
        downstream of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DFz</ENAMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LRP6</ENAMEX> has been reported to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bind Wnt-1</ENAMEX> and to associate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fz</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX>-dependent
        manner [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . Taken together, these results support a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-receptor model: upon exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wnts</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LRP5</TIMEX> or LRP6
        forms a complex with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fzs</ENAMEX>, transducing the Wnt
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> downstream to stabilize cytoplasmic Î²-catenin.
        Consistent with this, it has been demonstrated that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dickkopf-1 inhibits Wnt/Î²-</ENAMEX>catenin signaling by binding to
        LRP5 or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LRP6</NUMEX> to prevent Wnt-receptor complex formation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] .
        Alternatively, however, it is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt/Wg</ENAMEX> can
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP/Arr</ENAMEX> in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fzs</ENAMEX>. In agreement
        with this possibility, an intracellular domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LRP5</ENAMEX> was
        reported to interact directly with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axin</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] , and Wnt
        signaling appears to stimulate the recruitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axin</ENAMEX> to
        LRP5 at the membrane, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axin</ENAMEX> is degraded. Furthermore,
        it was reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP</ENAMEX> signaling can be activated in a
        Dsh - independent fashion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . These data suggest that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt/Wg</ENAMEX> could signal through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP</ENAMEX> directly to the Î²-catenin
        destruction <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fz</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX>-independent
        fashion.
        To evaluate whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fzs</ENAMEX> are required for the
        transduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt/Wg</ENAMEX> signaling in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRPs</ENAMEX>,
        we have established a sensitive method to measure Wg
        signaling activities using a LEF-luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S2</ENAMEX> cells. We show that
        DFz2 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP/Arr</ENAMEX> cooperate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> to activate the
        signaling pathway. Using a double-strand <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> interference
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dsRNAi</NUMEX>) technique designed to eliminate specific proteins
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] , such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dsh</ENAMEX>, we have developed
        strong evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> requires both types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> to
        transduce a signal efficiently through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX> to stabilize
        Î²-catenin.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors Arr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> can activate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEF</ENAMEX>-dependent transcription
          We wished to ask whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt/Wg</ENAMEX> can signal through
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP/Arrow</ENAMEX> in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fz</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> have
          been identified in 
          Drosophila , compared to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> Fz
          genes in vertebrates, we decided to use 
          Drosophila <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">S2 cells</ENAMEX> for these
          experiments. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> blot
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> failed to detect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX>, and
          DFz3 in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 17 18</ENAMEX> ] . Using a one-step RT-PCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> to measure the expression levels of all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DFzs</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">S2 cells</ENAMEX> used by Yanagawa 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1A</NUMEX>), we detected
          DFz2, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz3</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> mRNAs, but not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz1 and DFz4</TIMEX> mRNAs
          after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of amplification. In contrast, in mbn-2
          cells all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DFzs</ENAMEX> mRNAs were detected by this procedure.
          No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were found when reverse transcriptase was
          omitted from the reactions, eliminating the possibility
          that the results were due to contamination with genomic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. All of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were gel-purified and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequenced</ENAMEX> to confirm that they contain the expected Fz
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> (data not shown). Thus S2 cells express mRNAs
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2 and DFz3</TIMEX>, but mRNAs for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz1 and DFz4</TIMEX> are
          either absent or below levels required for detection with
          our RT-PCR assay.
          Previous studies have measured the abundance of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armadillo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arm</ENAMEX>), a 
          Drosophila homologue of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î²-catenin</NUMEX>,
          to assess Wg signaling in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells. We adapted a
          LEF-luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> system [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] to monitor
          Î²-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">catenin-mediated Wg</ENAMEX> signaling in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells, a more
          quantitative and convenient assay. The luciferase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter plasmid</ENAMEX>, which has multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LEF-1</ENAMEX> binding sites,
          was cotransfected into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells with the coding sequence
          for mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LEF-1</ENAMEX> in the 
          Drosophila expression vector
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pPacPL</ENAMEX>. 
          Renilla luciferase was included as
          a transfection control. The activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> signaling
          by various effectors in pPacPL was then determined by
          measurement of relative luciferase activity (Figure
          1B).
          Transient transfection of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> expression plasmid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activated LEF</ENAMEX>-dependent transcription <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34-fold</NUMEX>; this
          result was not changed by co-transfection with an Arr
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX> (which also had no effect in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX>),
          implying either that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> levels were not limiting or that
          Arr was not required for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> effects. In contrast,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-transfection with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">DFz2</NUMEX> plasmid augmented Wg
          signaling more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>-fold above control levels and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 30-fold</NUMEX> above levels observed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> alone,
          suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> was required for efficient Wg
          signaling and, although detectable in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells, was
          present in limiting amounts. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">DFz2</NUMEX> plasmid had a small
          but significant effect without addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX>, but the
          addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plasmid</ENAMEX> had little or no effect on DFz2
          activity in the presence or absence of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Wg plasmid</NUMEX> (Figure
          1B).
        
        
          Wg signaling is impaired with the loss of function
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> or Arr
          Results in the preceding section indicate that DFz2
          has an important role in transducing a Wg signal in S2
          cells, but do not reveal whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arr</ENAMEX> also has a role in
          concert with, or independent of, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fz</ENAMEX>-mediated signaling.
          To explore these issues, we used dsRNAi to reduce the
          levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> and DFz2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAs</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">S2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in which Wg
          signaling was stimulated, since others have shown that
          the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endogenous genes</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> can be
          eliminated or reduced by direct application of
          T7-transcribed dsRNAs [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] . Using this approach
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), we found that the previously observed,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>-fold stimulation of luciferase activity
          by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> expression plasmid was reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> or more
          when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells were co-transfected with inhibitory RNAs
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX>, or both (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2A</NUMEX>), implying that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous</ENAMEX> levels of both types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> are required
          for an efficient response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX>. The extensive inhibition
          with either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> species favors the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> signaling
          requires coordinated rather than independent actions of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endogenous Arr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DFz2 receptors</ENAMEX>. However, the failure
          to eliminate signaling entirely with inhibitory RNAs
          against both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> cannot be readily interpreted,
          since it is unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> production was
          eliminated in every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in the cultures.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, the synergistic effect of co-transfected
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plasmids</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 1000</NUMEX>-fold, was also
          dramatically reduced by addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitory RNA</ENAMEX>
          against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arr</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2B</NUMEX>), implying that endogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> is
          required for the stimulatory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">exogenous DFz2</ENAMEX> on
          Wg signaling. This result also suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> and Arr
          work cooperatively to transduce a Wg signal. As
          additional controls in these experiments, we showed that
          inhibitory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dsh</ENAMEX>, a cytoplasmic phosphoprotein
          believed to mediate Wg signaling via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, blocks
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 60%</NUMEX> of signaling produced by co-transfection with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plasmids</ENAMEX>. Moreover, we found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells
          treated with dsRNAi against both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX> further
          impaired the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> signaling activity <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 95%</NUMEX>
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2B</NUMEX>). As expected, inhibitory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAs</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> and
          DFz2 have no effect on luciferase synthesis promoted by a
          degradation-resistant mutant of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î²-catenin</NUMEX> (Figure
          2C).
        
        
          The synergy between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> requires the CRD
          domain of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX>, but not the carboxyterminus
          DFz2, like other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fz</ENAMEX> protein <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
          contains a cysteine-rich domain (CRD) near the
          aminoterminus, followed by a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven-transmembrane</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7-TM</ENAMEX>)
          domain and a cytoplasmic carboxyterminal tail. DFz2
          reportedly binds to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wg</ENAMEX> through its CRD domain [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] , but
          it is not known which proteins interact with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carboxyterminus</ENAMEX> or with cytoplasmic loops in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-TM
          region of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">DFz2</NUMEX> to transduce the signal to the cytoplasmic
          signaling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX>. However, a short conserved
          cytoplasmic motif in the carboxylterminal region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fzs</ENAMEX>,
          including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX>, was reported to be important for the
          activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wnt/Î²</ENAMEX>-catenin signaling in mammalian cells,
          based on mutational analysis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] .
          To determine which domains in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX> are important for
          its synergistic activity with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">S2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell assay</ENAMEX>, we
          deleted the regions encoding the CRD domain (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DFz2Î”CRD</NUMEX>) or
          the cytoplasmic tail (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DFz2Î”C</NUMEX>) in pPacPL (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3A</NUMEX>) and
          tested the deletion constructs shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> A in the
          luciferase assay described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3B</NUMEX>). In this
          experiment, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> plasmid activated the luciferase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-fold</NUMEX> above the vector control; wild-type
          DFz2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plasmid</ENAMEX> alone stimulated luciferase levels <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-fold,
          but neither deletion mutant of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX> had any effect,
          consistent with an earlier report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX> with a
          truncated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carboxyterminus</ENAMEX> fails to induce the expression
          of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xnr/Siamois</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . However,
          DFz2Î”C stimulated signaling over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX>-fold when delivered
          in concert with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX>, a synergistic effect nearly as strong
          as observed with wild type DFz2 (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 1700</NUMEX>-fold in this
          experiment). In contrast, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2Î”CRD</TIMEX> showed no synergistic
          effect, a result that can most likely be explained by a
          loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> binding capacity. The result with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2Î”C</TIMEX>,
          however, implies that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> signal can be transduced
          through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX> in a carboxyterminus-independent manner,
          either through the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-TM domain or through the interaction
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> that was implied by the previous experiments. In
          addition, the synergistic effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2Î”C</ENAMEX> was
          blocked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX> dsRNAi (data not shown), implying that Dsh
          is required to transduce the signal from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wg</ENAMEX> through
          DFz2Î”C to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î²-catenin</NUMEX>. Therefore, the interaction between
          DFz2 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dsh</ENAMEX> does not depend solely on the
          carboxyterminus of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX>.
        
        
          LRP6 and an aminoterminal mutant of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LRP6</ENAMEX> can
          stimulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> signaling pathway, but the ability of
          LRP6 to replace the requirement for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX> in the synergy
          between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> requires the aminoterminus of
          LRP6
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRPs</ENAMEX> have been shown to bind to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt/Wg</ENAMEX> through the
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> EGF repeats of their extracellular
          domain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . Our unpublished work in mammalian cells
          and results from others [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 13</NUMEX> ] demonstrate that the
          expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LRP6</ENAMEX> or an aminoterminal truncation mutant
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">LRP6Î”N</NUMEX>), which should no longer bind to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wnt</ENAMEX>, can
          activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> signaling pathway.
          To investigate whether these constructs can also
          function in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells and whether their activities can
          synergize with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX>, we transferred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LRP6</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LRP6Î”N</ENAMEX> into
          the 
          Drosophila expression vector pPacPL
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4A</NUMEX>) and tested them alone and with various
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">combinations of Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4B</NUMEX>).
          Results with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">DFz2</NUMEX> alone or together were similar
          to those observed in other experiments (e.g. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>),
          but both wild-type and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mutant LRP6</ENAMEX>, unlike the LRP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">homolog Arr</ENAMEX>, activated signaling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10- to 15</NUMEX>-fold
          alone, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2- to 4</NUMEX>-fold when co-transfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-
          to10-fold when co-transfected with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX>.
          Since we have been unable to measure Arr or LRP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> directly in transfected cells, we cannot
          distinguish between more efficient expression or greater
          inherent activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRPs</ENAMEX> as an explanation of the
          different effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRPs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX>. Signaling via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP6Î”N</ENAMEX>,
          however, while dependent on Arm as expected, is not
          dependent on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX>, as judged by the use of dsRNAi
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5A</NUMEX>). Similar results were observed for
          full-length LRP6 (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5B</NUMEX>). These results are
          consistent with claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRPs</ENAMEX> can signal through an
          interaction of the carboxyterminus with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axin</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] .
          To ask whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LRP6</ENAMEX> can replace the requirement for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous Arr</ENAMEX> in the synergy between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX>, as
          observed earlier in Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2B</TIMEX>, we again used Arr-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dsRNAi</ENAMEX> to try to block the strong activation of signaling
          by Wg plus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DFz2</ENAMEX>, in the presence and absence of the LRP6
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constructs</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5C</NUMEX>). Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> dsRNAi markedly
          inhibited signaling by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX>, but no inhibition was
          observed in the presence of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">LRP6</NUMEX> plasmid, implying
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LRP6</ENAMEX> could substitute for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> in these synergistic
          events. In contrast, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LRP6Î”N</TIMEX> cannot effectively substitute
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX>, presumably reflecting a need for an interaction
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> to achieve synergy. Some
          residual activity in this experiment may reflect the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inherent Wg</ENAMEX> signaling activity of wild type and mutant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LRPs</ENAMEX> observed in Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4B</TIMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        In this report, we describe a convenient cell
        culture-based assay for assessing the contributions made by
        candidate components of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> signaling pathways to the
        activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Î²-catenin-mediated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>. We have
        attempted to alter the concentrations of components by
        transient transfection with plasmids encoding wild type and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mutant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and/or with dsRNAi that can block
        production of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> from endogenous or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">exogenous genes</ENAMEX>.
        Pathway activity was then assessed by measurement of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luciferase</ENAMEX> expressed from a co-transfected plasmid
        containing firefly luciferase-coding sequence under the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEF</ENAMEX> binding elements.
        The assay makes use of 
        Drosophila <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">S2 cells</ENAMEX> in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> fly Frizzled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are undetectable by a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sensitive PCR</ENAMEX> assay. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> others (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) are detectable
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1A</NUMEX>), but <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> is in limiting quantities, since
        signaling by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wg</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> ortholog of mammalian
        Wnt-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, can be dramatically stimulated by co-transfection
        with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">DFz2</NUMEX> expression plasmid (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1B</NUMEX>). This effect
        requires the aminoterminus of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DFz2</TIMEX>, implying a requirement
        for binding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fz CRD</ENAMEX>, but not the carboxyterminus,
        suggesting that the signal may be, in part, transmitted
        through an interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wg-Frizzled</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> with another
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX>, the fly homolog of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRPs</ENAMEX>, which are thought to
        be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wnt</ENAMEX> co-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in mammalian cells, is an obvious
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for such an interactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. Experiments with
        Arr dsRNAi clearly establish a requirement for endogenous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> to generate the synergistic response to exogenous Wg
        plus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DFz2</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). We have also found that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mammalian LRP6</ENAMEX> can replace the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> in this context
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) and that the aminoterminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LRP6</ENAMEX> must be
        maintained for most or all of the effect. Therefore it is
        most likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP/Arr</ENAMEX> form a trimeric
        ligand-receptor complex to activate the signaling pathway.
        However, it was recently reported that no direct
        interactions between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> were detected [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . It
        is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP</ENAMEX> aminoterminus is required for
        interacting with another extracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> rather than
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fz</ENAMEX>.
        It is known that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX> is a key component in transducing a
        Wg signal [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24 25</NUMEX> ] . However, the mechanism by which
        Dsh transmits a signal to the Î²-catenin destruction complex
        is not clear. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fzs</ENAMEX> can recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dsh</ENAMEX> to the plasma membrane [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 26</NUMEX> ] , but it is not known whether this recruitment is
        essential in signaling. While the functions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fz</ENAMEX> and Dsh
        remain to be clarified, it is possible that upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wnt</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">signaling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fzs</ENAMEX> recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dsh</ENAMEX> to the membrane and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Dsh</ENAMEX> brings
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axin</ENAMEX> to the carboxyterminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRPs</ENAMEX>. If the carboxyterminus
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LRP6</ENAMEX> can interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axin</ENAMEX> independently of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DFz2</ENAMEX> and
        Dsh, it might reduce the cytoplasmic level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axin</ENAMEX> and help
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">stabilize Î²-catenin.</ENAMEX> The observation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LRP5Î”N</ENAMEX> activates
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt/Wg</ENAMEX> signaling pathway in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX>-independent manner [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> ] , and our data with overexpressed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LRP6Î”N and LRP6</TIMEX>,
        further support this proposal.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEF</ENAMEX>-dependent luciferase assay in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">versatile</ENAMEX>, dynamic, rapid and can provide important clues
        about interactions important for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt</ENAMEX> signaling. The use of
        dsRNAi helps to refine the nature of such interactions and
        their effects on downstream events in the signaling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circuitry</ENAMEX>. Because we have not, however, measured the
        concentrations of the relevant signaling components or
        studied interactions of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> with more
        sophisticated tools, the conclusions we draw are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">provisional</ENAMEX> and require additional support. However, they
        are consistent with the prevailing model in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wg</ENAMEX> forms
        a trimeric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DFz2</ENAMEX> that transduces a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX> to activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEF/TCF</ENAMEX>-responsive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        We conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt/Wg</ENAMEX> signaling requires functional
        interactions of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LRP/Arr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fz</ENAMEX> classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>,
        and the cytoplasmic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dsh</ENAMEX>. The extracellular
        regions of both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are crucial for receiving the Wg
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX>, while the carboxyterminus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DFz2</ENAMEX> is not absolutely
        required for reception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wnt/Wg</ENAMEX> signal.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Cell culture, transfection and luciferase
          assay
          S2 cells were cultured at room temperature in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drosophila Schneider</ENAMEX> medium
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> heat-inactivated fetal bovine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX>. The following plasmids were used in each
          experiment: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> Î¼g LEF-luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>
          Î¼g mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LEF-1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.1 Î</NUMEX>¼g 
          Renilla luciferase. 
          Renilla luciferase was included in
          each transfection to control the efficiency of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transfection</ENAMEX>. All 
          Drosophila expression constructs
          were cloned in the vector pPacPL [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 28</NUMEX> ] . Cells grown
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well plates were transfected with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 Î¼g</NUMEX> of
          indicated plasmid together with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmids
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cellfectin</ENAMEX> reagent (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen Life Technologies</ENAMEX>).
          The final amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was adjusted to an equal level
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pPacPL vector DNA</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48 hours</TIMEX> after
          transfection, cells were lysed in a lysis buffer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>) by shaking at room temperature for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>.
          The luciferase activities of the lysates were then
          analyzed by a luminometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EG&G Berthold</ENAMEX>, lumat
          LB9507) to measure the dual luciferase activities of
          LEF-luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and 
          Renilla luciferase using the
          Promega Dual-Luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> assay system. All the
          experiments were performed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> times, and each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in triplicates.
        
        
          RT-PCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells and mbn-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cells was prepared using
          Qiagen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA miniprep</ENAMEX> columns and was treated with RQ1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNase-Free DNase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.1 Î</NUMEX>¼g <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> from each cell
          line was used as a template for one-step RT-PCR (One-step
          RT-PCR kit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>). The following primers were
          used in the reactions: 
          DFz1 : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATGTGGCGTCAAATCCTG-3</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TGGACATCATCTGCAGGC-3</ENAMEX>'. 
          DFz2 : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AGACACAATCGACTGAAGG-3</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AGTGAGGTTCATGTACCAG-3</ENAMEX>' (These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two primer</NUMEX> pairs are
          based on [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] ). 
          DFz3 : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACAGTGAAGAGTAGTGGTCG-3</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCACCTCCTGTGGAATCTGC-3</ENAMEX>', 
          DFz4 : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TACATTCGCTAAGGCTAC-3</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GACCTTCCATACACATCG-3</ENAMEX>' and 
          Arr : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAAGATGTGACAACGAAAGC-3</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CATGCTCTGACAGAGTTCG-3</ENAMEX>'.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAi</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells
          The method was adapted from the procedure published by
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reactions were performed
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">primers</ENAMEX> containing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">T7</NUMEX> polymerase binding site.
          We used dsRNA against a gene unrelated to the Wg
          signaling pathway, i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aconitase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aco</ENAMEX>), as a negative
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. The primers used are:
          
          Aco : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGACTCTGTCCAAGTTCGACTCG-3</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>'
          primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGAGATAGAGTCAACACCCTTGC-3</ENAMEX>'; 
          DFz2 : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGAGATCACCATACCAATGTGTCG-3</ENAMEX>';
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGAGTATGCCGCAGTTTGGAACG-3</ENAMEX>'; 
          Arr : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGACAGATCGATGTGATCGTTAGG-3</ENAMEX>';
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGACCATGCTCTGACAGAGTTCG-3</ENAMEX>'; 
          Dsh : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGACCATCACCAGAAGATGATGG-3</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>'
          primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGACCTTAACGATCTCCTCGAGG-3</ENAMEX>'; 
          Arm : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGACAGCTAAGCCAGACACGTTC-3</ENAMEX>'; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>'
          primer,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATTAATACGACTCACTATAGGGAGAGCTTTCCTGGTTGCCGTAGG-3</ENAMEX>'.
          A megascript <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T7</ENAMEX> transcription kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambion</ENAMEX>) was used to
          generate both sense and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antisense strand RNA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">annealed</ENAMEX> to form double strand <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 Î¼g</NUMEX> of each dsRNA
          was then added to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">S2</NUMEX> cells in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well plates containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          6cells per well. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 to 16 hours</TIMEX> after dsRNAi treatment,
          cells were transfected with different constructs and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> after transfection, cells were lysed
          and luciferase activity was measured as above.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        LS designed and performed the experiments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HV</ENAMEX> supervised
        the work. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
