
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amprenavir</ENAMEX> (APV) is a potent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">protease inhibitor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>)
        that is used in combination with other antiretroviral drugs
        for the treatment of antiretroviral-na√Øve and -experienced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5</NUMEX> ] . APV
        offers the convenience of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice-daily</TIMEX> (BID) administration
        with no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or fluid restrictions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] . Preclinical
        and clinical data suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> has a lower potential to
        cause lipodystrophy and metabolic abnormalities than other
        currently available <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PIs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 10</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> has a distinct
        resistance profile that permits it to be considered as a
        treatment option for either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PI-na√Øve</ENAMEX> or PI-experienced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">64-week</TIMEX> trial in treatment-na√Øve
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">NZTA4002</TIMEX>; n = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">302</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1200</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>, administered BID
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">APV1200</NUMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> abacavir <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> mg tablet and one
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">lamivudine 150 mg/zidovudine 300</ENAMEX> mg combination tablet
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combivir ¬Æ</ENAMEX>), was as effective as nelfinavir <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">750 mg three</NUMEX>
        times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> plus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combivir</ENAMEX> BID, with regard to the
        proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> achieving HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> copies/mL
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at week 64</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX> (as-treated analysis) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] .
        However, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in this trial withdrew prematurely
        because of adverse events that may have been, in part,
        related to the high pill burden (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> large <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mg
        soft-gelatin capsules <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>) associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> dosing and
        excipients contained in the APV formulation available at
        the time of the trial.
        To reduce APV pill burden and possibly improve
        tolerability of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">APV</ENAMEX> treatment, pharmacokinetic research
        efforts have been directed at combining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ritonavir</ENAMEX> (RTV), which inhibits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CYP3A4</NUMEX>-mediated hepatic
        metabolism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX>, thereby enhancing plasma APV exposure [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14 15</NUMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTV</ENAMEX> at the clinically
        sub-therapeutic dosage of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mg BID was found to boost APV
        plasma exposure to such a degree as to permit halving the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> daily pill burden from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 to 8</TIMEX> capsules/day, in
        addition to maintaining the minimum plasma APV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentration</ENAMEX> (C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> ) over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 hours</TIMEX> well above the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>
        inhibitory concentrations (IC 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ) of patient-derived HIV-1 isolates [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> ] . A pharmacokinetic study in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> HIV-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
        PROF1004, showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> at the lower dosage of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> mg BID
        combined with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100</ENAMEX> mg BID (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX>) resulted in a
        geometric mean steady-state APV C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.92</NUMEX> Œ<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ºg/mL</ENAMEX>) over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-fold higher than
        the C 
        min resulting from APV1200 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.3</NUMEX> Œ<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ºg/mL</ENAMEX>) [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> ] . This C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 13-fold</NUMEX> higher than
        the IC 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> of
        antiretroviral-na√Øve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (mean, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.146 ¬± 0.125 Œ</NUMEX>ºg/mL)
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 2</NUMEX>-fold higher than the IC 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">multi-PI</ENAMEX>-resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (mean, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.903 ¬± 0.846 Œ</NUMEX>ºg/mL) (IC
        
        50 s adjusted for the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> observed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX>). Following APV600<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/RTV</ENAMEX>, the APV
        maximum serum concentration (C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max</ENAMEX> ) has been reported to be slightly
        lower (by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX>) than that observed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV1200</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] ,
        which may account for the RTV-boosted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> regimen being
        less likely to cause certain adverse events (e.g.,
        oral/perioral paresthesia and headache) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        Since the above pharmacokinetic studies and others
        involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharmacokinetic</ENAMEX> modeling predictions were
        conducted over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a short period</TIMEX> (generally ‚â§ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 days</TIMEX>)
        and in a small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, there remained a need to
        evaluate low-dose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV/RTV</ENAMEX> combinations in large populations
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">HIV-1</NUMEX>-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> over a therapeutically relevant
        period. The purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ESS40011</ENAMEX> was to compare the
        efficacy, safety, and tolerability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">600</ENAMEX> mg BID plus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100</ENAMEX> mg BID (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> mg BID (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">APV1200</NUMEX>)
        over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks</TIMEX> in antiretroviral-na√Øve or -experienced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV-infected</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were receiving other background
        antiretroviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Late in the study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had
        not yet completed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks</TIMEX> of treatment were given the
        option to continue treatment in a subsequent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-week</TIMEX>
        extension phase to assess the durability of virologic
        response.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>
          Male and non-pregnant, non-lactating female
          outpatients were eligible for study enrollment if they
          were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 18 years of age</TIMEX>; had HIV-1 infection
          documented by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 antibody</ENAMEX> enzyme-linked immunosorbent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>) and confirmed by Western blot test,
          positive HIV-1 culture, positive HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serum antigen</ENAMEX>, or
          plasma viremia; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ cell counts <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚â• 50/mm 3</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> of
          childbearing potential had to have a negative serum
          Œ≤-human chorionic gonadotropin (HCG) pregnancy test at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screening</ENAMEX>, and had to be willing to use an adequate
          method of contraception during the study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> could
          be either antiretroviral-na√Øve or -experienced. If
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were antiretroviral-experienced, they had to be
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">na√Øve</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX>, have a plasma HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> ><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> copies/mL,
          show susceptibility to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> and ‚â• <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> other antiretroviral
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and remain on their most recent treatment regimen
          until completion of the screening visit. For all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>,
          susceptibility was defined as an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> isolate with
          <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.0</NUMEX>-fold change in IC 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> (determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIRCOGEN‚Ñ</ENAMEX>¢
          [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tibotec-Virco NV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mechelen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>], a virtual
          phenotype assay) in comparison to the control virus.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> were excluded if they had active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disease Control</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX>) Class C status; could not comply
          with the study schedule; were in another investigational
          drug study; were undergoing opiate detoxification; had a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malabsorption syndrome</ENAMEX> or pre-existing condition that
          interfered with normal gastrointestinal transit; had
          clinically significant laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">abnormalities</ENAMEX>, required
          radiation therapy or cytotoxic chemotherapy, or had
          received immunomodulating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 weeks</TIMEX>
          pre-study; or had received an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HIV-1</ENAMEX> immunotherapeutic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 months</TIMEX> pre-study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> were allowed
          to take pravastatin, fluvastatin, cerivastatin, or
          atorvastatin for hyperlipidemia at the cautionary
          discretion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, but were not allowed to
          take lovastatin, simvastatin, or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> known to
          significantly affect metabolism by the cytochrome P450
          CYP3A4 enzyme system.
        
        
          Study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design</ENAMEX>
          In this multicenter, open-label clinical trial,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were first stratified according to prior
          antiretroviral therapy exposure (i.e., na√Øve or
          experienced), then randomized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to treatment for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> with either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV 600</ENAMEX> mg BID plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RTV 100</NUMEX> mg BID or
          to APV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> mg BID in combination with ‚â• <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> non-PI
          antiretroviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> was supplied as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mg
          soft-gelatin capsules of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agenerase ¬Æ</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GlaxoSmithKline</ENAMEX>,
          Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangle Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>); thus, eight
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">capsules</ENAMEX> were given for each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200 mg</TIMEX> dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">capsules</ENAMEX> for each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> mg dose. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTV</ENAMEX> was supplied as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mg
          soft-gelatin capsules of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norvir ¬Æ</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbott Laboratories</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>). Late in the study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who
          had not yet completed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks</TIMEX> of treatment were given
          the option to continue treatment in a subsequent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-week</TIMEX>
          extension phase to assess the durability of virologic
          response.
          During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 6-week</TIMEX> period prior to the start of the
          study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> were screened for study eligibility,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demography</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> classification, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> risk factors, mode of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> transmission, antiretroviral therapy history, and
          medical history, and given a physical examination. Prior
          to study initiation, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ESS40011</TIMEX> study protocol was
          approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Review Boards</ENAMEX> at each
          participating study site. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> provided
          written informed consent before any study-related
          procedures were commenced. The initial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-week</TIMEX> portion of
          the study was conducted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between June 13, 2000 and October</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 2001</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Efficacy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safety Assessment</ENAMEX>
          The primary efficacy parameter was the proportion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with plasma HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> levels <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at week 24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Plasma HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> was assessed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amplicor MONITOR Ultrasensitive</ENAMEX> assay (version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>; lower
          limit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">quantitation</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LLOQ</ENAMEX>] <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> copies/mL and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quantitation</ENAMEX> range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 to 75,000</NUMEX> copies/mL, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostics, Branchburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> were
          classified as having reached a virologic endpoint if, at
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 24</TIMEX>, plasma HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> levels were ‚â• <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL; or
          if the plasma HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> had not decreased by at least
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>-log 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> from baseline at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 8</TIMEX>, with
          confirmation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 12</TIMEX>.
          Secondary efficacy measures included assessment of the
          proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> achieving HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">copies/mL</ENAMEX> (using the above mentioned assay); changes in
          CD4+ cell counts (measured by flow cytometry) compared
          with baseline values; and progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV disease</ENAMEX> from
          baseline status to the occurrence of the first new event
          involving a change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> who remained at their entry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> were
          considered to be clinical non-progressors.
          Change from baseline in plasma HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> levels was
          assessed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 4, 8, 12</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> in all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, as
          well as at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 32, 40 and 48</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who
          participated in the treatment extension phase. CD4+ cell
          counts were assessed at baseline, and at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 12 and 24</TIMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> had plasma collected for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">genotype</ENAMEX>/virtual
          phenotype at screening (for experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> only)
          and at the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virologic failure</ENAMEX> (results to be
          reported elsewhere).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          The study was powered to evaluate whether the
          virologic efficacy (proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with plasma
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 24</TIMEX>) in the APV
          600/RTV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> was at least as good (non-inferior) as in the
          APV1200 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. Non-inferiority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> regimen to
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> regimen was established if the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> lower
          confidence limit (LCL) for the difference in proportion
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> achieving HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL at week
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">600/RTV minus APV1200</ENAMEX> was ‚â•-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.12</NUMEX>. The
          non-inferiority margin of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.12</NUMEX> was chosen based on
          previous regulatory studies and was pre-specified in the
          protocol. Target enrollment was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">198</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> arm
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. The primary analysis was made
          in the intent-to-treat (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, which consisted
          of all eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were randomized into the
          study regardless of what treatment was actually received
          and the eventual outcome of study participation. Two
          types of analyses were performed: an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: observed
          analysis, in which only available assessments were used
          (no imputation for missing values), regardless of whether
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was still receiving their original therapy;
          and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: missing = failure (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M = F</ENAMEX>) analysis, in
          which all missing values constituted failure. Comparisons
          between treatment arms regarding proportion of patients
          achieving HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL and <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          copies/mL were made using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochran-Mantel</ENAMEX>-Haenszel
          test controlling for prior antiretroviral drug
          experience. Changes from baseline in plasma HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          (log 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> copies/mL) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count, and
          average area under the curve minus baseline (AAUCMB) in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plasma HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX>, were tabulated by treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> and
          visit, then analyzed using analysis of variance (ANOVA).
          The safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> consisted of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who
          consumed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 1</TIMEX> dose of study <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. Safety parameters
          included incidence of treatment-limiting toxicities
          (clinical and laboratory adverse events); and change from
          baseline in selected laboratory variables at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8,</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 and 24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>'s exact test was used to compare
          adverse event rate and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX> was used to compare change
          from baseline for laboratory variables between the two
          treatment arms. A 
          P value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.05</NUMEX> was considered
          statistically significant. Statistical analyses were
          performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX> version <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.12</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS Institute, Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          Cary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patient Characteristics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disposition</ENAMEX>
          A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">211</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> enrolled; they were
          predominantly male (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87%</NUMEX>), ethnically diverse (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48%</NUMEX>
          Caucasian, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African American</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>), and had a
          mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 42 years</TIMEX>, median baseline HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> level of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.33</NUMEX> log 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> copies/mL, and median baseline <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+
          cell count of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">257</NUMEX> cells/mm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Most of the study
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> was antiretroviral-experienced (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX>). One
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hundred</ENAMEX> and fifty-eight (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">158</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were randomized to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> regimen and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> regimen. The
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> treatment arms did not differ with respect to any
          baseline characteristic (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). The most common
          background antiretroviral regimens taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV1200</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">treatment arms</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">stavudine/didanosine</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Combivir</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX> for both
          arms), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abacavir</ENAMEX>/stavudine (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX> for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">lamivudine/stavudine</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">abacavir</ENAMEX>/didanosine
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>). A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX>) completed all
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks</TIMEX> of the study, including a similar proportion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72%</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV1200</ENAMEX> arm
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68%</NUMEX>). Reasons for premature withdrawal from treatment
          were also similar between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> and APV1200
          arms, except for fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> arm
          withdrawing due to protocol-defined virologic failure (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vs</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antihyperlipidemic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were used by
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in each treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, neither of whom had
          taken this type of medication pre-study. No deaths or
          clinical progressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV disease</ENAMEX> occurred. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> enrolled into the extension phase, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virologic Measurements</ENAMEX> of Efficacy
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">At week 24</TIMEX>, the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX>
          <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV1200</ENAMEX> arm
          was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">73/158</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20/53</NUMEX>), respectively, in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> = F analysis (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">73/118</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20/38</NUMEX>), respectively, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: observed analysis
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> regimen proved to be similar
          to or better than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the APV1200</TIMEX> regimen because the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> LCL
          for the difference in proportions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> achieving
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> minus APV1200
          was ‚<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">â• -0.12</ENAMEX> (-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.04</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> = F analysis] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-0.06</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>:
          observed analysis]). The proportion of
          antiretroviral-na√Øve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who achieved HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> was twice that
          for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the APV1200</TIMEX> arm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> = F analysis (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX>
          [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19/30</NUMEX>] vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/10</NUMEX>], 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.141</NUMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26%</NUMEX> higher in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: observed analysis (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19/25</NUMEX>] vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/6</NUMEX>], 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.320</NUMEX>). In contrast, the
          proportions in antiretroviral-experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were
          similar in the treatment arms in both analyses (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> =
          F analysis: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54/128</NUMEX>] vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17/43</NUMEX>], 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.859</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: observed analysis:
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54/93</NUMEX>] vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17/32</NUMEX>], 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.682</NUMEX>).
          Virologic findings using the more stringent virologic
          suppression endpoint of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> copies/mL
          paralleled those with the <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL endpoint,
          although differences attained statistical significance.
          Thus, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 24</TIMEX>, significantly more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the
          APV600<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the APV1200</TIMEX> arm achieved HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> copies/mL (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> = F analysis: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57/158</NUMEX>] vs
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/53</NUMEX>], 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.039</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: observed analysis:
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57/118</NUMEX>] vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/38</NUMEX>], 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.042</NUMEX>) (Figures <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1and 2,</ENAMEX>
          respectively). The proportion of antiretroviral-na√Øve
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who achieved HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> copies/mL was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47%</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14/30</NUMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10</NUMEX>) in the
          APV1200 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.141</NUMEX>), whereas the proportion
          of antiretroviral-experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who achieved HIV-1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> copies/mL was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">43/128</NUMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX>
          arm and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9/43</NUMEX>) in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.119</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> = F analysis). In
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: observed analysis, mean reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX>
          from baseline was significantly greater at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 24</TIMEX> in the
          APV600<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> (-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.21</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-1.59</NUMEX> log 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> copies/mL, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.028</NUMEX>) (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), as was the
          mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAUCMB</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> in both the total population
          (-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.56</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-1.25</NUMEX> log 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> copies/mL, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.045</NUMEX>) and antiretroviral-na√Øve
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subgroup</ENAMEX> (-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.40</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-1.60</NUMEX> log 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> copies/mL, 
          differences were observed between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> and
          APV1200 treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> with respect to mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAUCMB</ENAMEX> in
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> for the antiretroviral-experienced subgroup
          (-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.40</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-1.20</NUMEX> log 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> copies/mL 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.209</NUMEX>), or proportion of
          antiretroviral-na√Øve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> achieving HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">copies/mL</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX>, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.394</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: observed
          analysis).
          Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> in
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>) enrolled into the extension phase, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> APV600<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/RTV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 APV1200</ENAMEX>) had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
          copies/mL at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 24</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8 APV600/RTV, 3 APV1200</ENAMEX>) of
          these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> continued to have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> levels
          <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mL</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between week 24 and week 48</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          rebounded, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> discontinued at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 32</TIMEX>. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> ><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 24</TIMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> discontinued when an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">186</NUMEX> copies/mL was
          measured at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 32, 1</TIMEX> missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 32 and 40</TIMEX> visits (but
          had an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">878</NUMEX> copies/mL at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 48</TIMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          continued to have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> ><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL from week
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 to week 48</TIMEX>. In these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> levels
          ranged from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">316 to 3645</TIMEX> copies/mL, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1247 to 5175</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">copies/mL</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">143 to 12,149</NUMEX> copies/mL, respectively,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between weeks 24 and 48</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immunologic Measurements</ENAMEX> of Efficacy
          At baseline, the median <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count in the
          APV600<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/RTV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV1200</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271 and 255</NUMEX> cells<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/mm 3,</ENAMEX>
          respectively. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 24 weeks</TIMEX> of the study, the median
          CD4+ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count remained higher than baseline, with
          median elevations above baseline peaking at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 12</TIMEX> in
          both treatment arms (+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51 and +52</NUMEX> cells<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/mm 3,</ENAMEX>
          respectively) (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">At week 24</TIMEX>, the median change
          from baseline in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> and
          APV1200 arms was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+35 and +46</NUMEX> cells/mm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, respectively,
          and the final median <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">321 and 346</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cells/mm 3</ENAMEX>, respectively. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who participated in
          the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-week</TIMEX> extension phase, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the
          APV600<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> had a median
          change from baseline in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at week 48</TIMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+156 cell/mm 3</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+143</NUMEX> cell/mm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, respectively. The
          final median <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">404</NUMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">407</NUMEX> cells/mm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, respectively. The remaining patients
          did not have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ data reported.
        
        
          Safety
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2shows</ENAMEX> the drug-related adverse events that were
          reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">‚â</ENAMEX>• <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Nausea</ENAMEX>, diarrhea, vomiting,
          and fatigue were the most common adverse events in both
          treatment arms. The incidence of drug-related
          oral/perioral paresthesia was lower in the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX>
          treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX>). No
          differences between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV1200</ENAMEX> treatment
          arms were observed regarding the frequency of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">drug-related grade 1-4</ENAMEX> adverse events (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX>),
          frequency of discontinuing treatment due to adverse
          events (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX>), incidence of hyperglycemia (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 vs 0</ENAMEX>
          patient), nonspecific lipodystrophy (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 vs 0</ENAMEX>), buffalo
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hump</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 vs 0</ENAMEX>), or hypercholesterolemia (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 vs 0</ENAMEX>). More
          cases of hypertriglyceridemia were reported as adverse
          events in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX>] vs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>). However,
          review of laboratory changes revealed that the incidence
          of grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">hypertriglyceridemia</ENAMEX> was the same (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>) in
          each treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The virological results of this study indicate that over
        a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-week</TIMEX> treatment period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the APV600</TIMEX>/RTV regimen was
        statistically similar to or better than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the APV1200</TIMEX> regimen
        according to the <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL endpoint criterion.
        However, a significantly greater proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV600</NUMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RTV</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> achieved HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">copies/mL.</ENAMEX> Greater reductions in plasma HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> levels
        were also observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> receiving APV600/RTV BID
        than those using APV1200 BID. The greater magnitude of
        virologic suppression in the study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> as a whole
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> regimen was expected in view of the
        results of earlier clinical pharmacokinetic studies showing
        a ><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-fold higher C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> level with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APV600</TIMEX>/RTV BID compared
        with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> BID regimen [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . Higher C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> values achieved with RTV-boosting
        may be critical in treating antiretroviral-experienced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, particularly those with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> isolates having
        increased IC 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> values.
        The proportion of antiretroviral-na√Øve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who
        achieved HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> arm
        was twice that for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.141</NUMEX>). No differences in
        virologic efficacy between treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> were evident in
        the antiretroviral-experienced subgroup (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42%</NUMEX> vs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.859</NUMEX>). It is possible that
        proportionally more treatment-na√Øve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> may have
        responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> due to poorer or more difficult
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adherence</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> regimen, but no adherence checks
        were included in this study to verify this. Although the
        <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> copies/mL endpoint criterion also showed a higher
        proportion of antiretroviral-na√Øve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> responding to
        were not statistically significant, possibly due to the
        small size of this subgroup. In another study of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX>
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">antiretroviral-na√Øve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arasteh et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ]
        reported a higher proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> achieving plasma
        HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> copies/mL (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX>) than in the present study,
        perhaps due to the use of only lamivudine and abacavir as
        background antiretroviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> and to differences in
        their study population relative to ours.
        The proportion of antiretroviral-experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV600</NUMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RTV</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> who achieved HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
        copies/mL at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>:observed analysis]; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42%</NUMEX>
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> = F analysis]) was comparable to that reported in
        antiretroviral-experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks</TIMEX> in the
        studies by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schooley et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ESS40006</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEARL</ENAMEX>]) (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69%</NUMEX>
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>:observed analysis]), but much higher than that
        reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katlama et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ITT</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> = F
        analysis]). Differences in virologic suppression between
        the present study and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katlama</ENAMEX> study may stem from the
        use of other background <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and the far greater
        antiretroviral experience and well-documented PI mutations
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Katlama</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-week</TIMEX> extension phase showed that most patients
        who had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> copies/mL at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 24</TIMEX> maintained
        this level of virologic suppression through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 48</TIMEX>. Thus,
        some indication of durability of viral suppression might be
        gathered from these data, although the number of patients
        evaluated in this study phase was small. The durability of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">virologic</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> was also suggested in an
        earlier study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katlama et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] .
        The increase in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ cells observed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks</TIMEX> in the
        APV600/RTV BID arm was not different from that in the
        APV1200 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. It was lower in magnitude than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ cell
        count increases reported for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks</TIMEX> in
        antiretroviral-experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ESS40006</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] ,
        and similar to that reported in heavily pre-treated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katlama et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> population
        with comparable baseline disease characteristics (median
        HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX> log 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 /mL</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ count of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">227</NUMEX> cells/mm
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        The safety profile of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> regimen was similar
        to that of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">APV1200</NUMEX> regimen with respect to the main
        adverse events, which were gastrointestinal (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI</ENAMEX>) in nature
        in both treatment arms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> adverse events reported in the
        APV600<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> were possibly due to the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTV</ENAMEX> to
        the regimen, or because the reduction in pill burden and,
        hence, in excipients was not great enough to improve <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GI</ENAMEX>
        tolerance. The higher incidence of oral/perioral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paresthesia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the APV1200</TIMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> was most likely
        due to the higher APV C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max</ENAMEX> that occurs following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APV1200</TIMEX> dosing
        compared with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APV600</TIMEX>/RTV BID dosing [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . Although the
        incidence of headache has been shown to increase with
        higher APV C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max</ENAMEX> values [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] , the incidence of
        this adverse event did not differ between treatment arms in
        this study. The higher incidence of hypertriglyceridemia in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> was probably due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTV</ENAMEX>, because this PI
        has been reported to cause elevations in serum
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triglycerides</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . Other studies of RTV-boosted APV
        regimens have also reported that triglyceride elevation is
        usually grade <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX> in magnitude, and, as in the present
        study, seldom necessitates treatment discontinuation or the
        addition of antihyperlipidemic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s
        treatment plan [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 19</NUMEX> ] .
        This study evaluated a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient population</ENAMEX> that was
        ethnically diverse, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just over half</NUMEX> of the patients
        being either <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African American</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>. The inclusion of
        a large proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was deemed important because these are the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> epidemic is increasing the most
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . Earlier clinical trials have tended to
        underrepresent these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
        One limitation of our study was that no pharmacokinetic
        analyses were performed to validate whether the RTV dosage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regimen</ENAMEX> co-administered with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APV600</TIMEX> was effectively
        boosting plasma APV exposure or C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> levels. However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ESS40006</TIMEX>, which
        also evaluated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> regimen over a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-week</TIMEX>
        period, did conduct a pharmacokinetic evaluation showing
        steady-state serum APV C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> values of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.49 Œ</NUMEX>ºg/mL (i.e., over
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-fold higher than that usually achieved after the APV1200
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regimen</ENAMEX>). Thus, plasma APV levels well above the IC 
        50 s of most <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV isolates</ENAMEX> were most
        likely achieved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ESS40011</TIMEX>. Higher RTV doses of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> mg BID
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> mg BID co-administered with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APV600</ENAMEX> have resulted in
        no greater virologic suppression than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mg BID [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] ,
        and raising the dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> mg BID to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> mg BID
        does not improve efficacy either, although it may increase
        the incidence of adverse events [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] .
        In conclusion, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">APV600</TIMEX>/RTV BID was similar to or better
        than APV1200 BID based on virologic results using the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200-copies/mL</ENAMEX> HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA endpoint</ENAMEX>. Of note, a significantly
        greater proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the APV600</TIMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RTV</ENAMEX> treatment
        arm achieved HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> copies/mL at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 24</TIMEX>, which
        was a secondary endpoint. Other beneficial features of the
        APV600<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/RTV</ENAMEX> regimen, such as improved dosing convenience and
        reduced pill burden, need to be factored into decision
        making when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APV600/RTV</ENAMEX> is being considered by clinicians as
        a therapeutic option for the treatment of either
        antiretroviral-na√Øve or -experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        infection.
      
    
  
