
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fibronectin</ENAMEX> can control many aspects of cell behavior,
        including cell growth, migration and differentiation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ]
        . Fibronectin exists in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> as a dimer, but in
        tissues it is in the form of an insoluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibrillar matrix</ENAMEX>.
        The fibrillar form of fibronectin is thought to be the most
        relevant form in vivo because this is the form with which
        most cells interact [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Various lines of evidence
        suggest that the fibrillar matrix form of fibronectin
        exerts effects on cells that are not duplicated by the
        dimeric form of fibronectin. For example, high
        concentrations of dimeric fibronectin enhance cell
        migration whereas high concentrations of fibrillar
        fibronectin reduce cell migration [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Also, inhibition
        of fibronectin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">matrix assembly</ENAMEX> has been shown to inhibit
        cell growth in various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5</NUMEX> ] . These findings
        suggest that fibrillar fibronectin may stimulate signal
        transduction pathways in cells that are either not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulated</ENAMEX>, or only marginally stimulated, by dimeric
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibronectin</ENAMEX>.
        Fibronectin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">matrix assembly</ENAMEX> is a cell-mediated process
        that requires the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">integrins</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 6 7 8</NUMEX> ] . The
        integrin that is primarily responsible for assembling
        fibronectin into the matrix is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î±5Î²1</NUMEX>, although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Î±vÎ²3</TIMEX>, Î±llbÎ²3
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Î±4Î²1</ENAMEX> can also function in this capacity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 10 11 12 13</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> ] . In addition to integrins, fibronectin matrix
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assembly</ENAMEX> also depends on self-association sites within
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibronectin</ENAMEX>. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX> kDa region, the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> sttype III repeat and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> thtype III repeat are
        thought to be important for the proper alignment of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fibronectin</ENAMEX> molecules during matrix assembly [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17 18</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21 22</NUMEX> ] . We and others have shown that a recombinant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> representing a portion of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> type III repeat
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein III1-C</ENAMEX>) can affect fibronectin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">matrix assembly</ENAMEX> and
        cell growth [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 16</NUMEX> ] . Moreover, a mutant recombinant
        fibronectin molecule that is lacking the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> type
        III repeats has been shown to lead to defective fibronectin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">matrix</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> in cell culture and in vivo, and to
        inhibition of cell proliferation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24</NUMEX> ] . Although the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">matrix</ENAMEX> produced with fibronectin lacking the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
        type III repeats was somewhat aberrant, this study does
        show that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">matrix assembly</ENAMEX> can occur without the first
        type III repeat. Therefore, several approaches reveal that
        the fibronectin type III repeats, and especially the first
        type III repeat, play important roles in the regulation of
        fibronectin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">matrix assembly</ENAMEX> and cell growth.
        III1-C is known to inhibit cell proliferation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] .
        Recently, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> (also known as anastellin) has been shown
        to inhibit angiogenesis, and tumor growth and metastasis [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ] . In the present study we examine how cells interact
        with and respond to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>, with a particular focus on
        signaling through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras/ERK</ENAMEX> pathway. We find that cells
        can adhere and spread on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> classes of
        receptors function in cell adhesion to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>; integrins
        and cell-surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteoglycans</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        
          Cell attachment and spreading on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> type III
          repeat of fibronectin
          III1-C is a recombinant fibronectin fragment that
          encompasses most of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> type III repeat, but is
          missing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B Î²</ENAMEX>-strands of the repeat [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . We
          had previously found that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">III1-C</ENAMEX> inhibited the growth of
          normal diploid smooth muscle cells (SMCs) in culture [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          ] . During these experiments we noticed that the presence
          of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> in the culture medium affected the morphology
          of cells at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early times</TIMEX> after plating. As shown in Figure
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, cells plated onto fibronectin coated dishes attached
          and spread well, typically containing numerous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lamellipodia per</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> FN). Cells seeded
          onto fibronectin coated dishes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> in the culture
          medium spread more extensively and in a more circular
          pattern at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early times</TIMEX> after plating than cells plated on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibronectin</ENAMEX> in the absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A, panels FN
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>+C, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B). Cells cultured on fibronectin for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> show approximately the same extent of spreading
          as cells on fibronectin plus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B), indicating
          that III1-C accelerated the rate of spreading of the
          cells but did not affect the eventual extent of
          spreading. The effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell morphology</ENAMEX> was specific for
          III1-C because the negative control protein <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C (a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">recombinant protein</ENAMEX> derived from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> thtype III repeat
          in fibronectin, which, similar to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>, is missing the
          A and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B Î²</ENAMEX>-strands of this repeat) had no effect on the
          morphology of the cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> FN+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11C</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1B). Interestingly, the effect of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> on cell
          morphology was seen even when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">plates</ENAMEX> had 
          not been coated with fibronectin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> C, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B), indicating that intact
          fibronectin was not required for cell attachment and
          spreading when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> was in the culture medium. Again,
          the negative control protein <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C had no effect on
          cell morphology; cells seeded onto uncoated plates with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C in the culture medium remained rounded and did
          not appreciably spread over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A, panel
          11C, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B). These results indicated that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C
          had an effect on the morphology of freshly plated cells.
          Moreover, the plates did not need to be coated with any
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adhesive protein</ENAMEX> prior to seeding the cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C
          in the culture medium, indicating that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> may have
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adsorbed</ENAMEX> onto the tissue culture plastic and that cells
          then attached and spread on the adsorbed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>.
          To directly test whether cells were able to bind to
          III1-C coated on a dish, various concentrations of either
          fibronectin, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C were coated onto dishes
          and cell attachment to these substrates was measured. As
          shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, cells attach well to fibronectin and
          to III1-C, but not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C coated on a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX>. On a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">molar</ENAMEX> basis, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> was less effective at supporting cell
          attachment than fibronectin, however, it was clear that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> do attach and spread well on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> coated on a
          dish. The morphology of the cells seeded onto the
          III1-C-coated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> was indistinguishable from the
          morphology shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> C.
        
        
          Role of integrins in cell attachment to
          III1-C
          The attachment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> was analyzed
          further to determine the role played by integrins as
          potential adhesive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. Various
          integrin-blocking reagents were tested for their ability
          to block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMC</ENAMEX> attachment to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and to fibronectin.
          The adhesion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMCs</ENAMEX> to fibronectin is mediated through
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">integrins</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1 26</ENAMEX> ] . We confirmed these previous
          findings for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX>, by showing a complete block of
          cell attachment to fibronectin by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> (an agent that
          blocks all integrins), anti<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-Î²1</NUMEX> blocking mAb, and RGD
          peptide, but not by the negative control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAD</ENAMEX> peptide
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A). Anti-fibronectin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> also effectively
          blocked RASMC attachment to fibronectin (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heparin</ENAMEX> did not inhibit cell attachment to fibronectin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A), however, it did modestly reduce cell spreading
          on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fibronectin</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> inhibition of cell spreading, data
          not shown). These results indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMC</ENAMEX> adhesion to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibronectin</ENAMEX> is mediated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX> integrins.
          Blocking studies indicated that cell attachment to
          III1-C was partially mediated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX> integrins. For
          example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMC</ENAMEX> attachment was partially blocked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>,
          anti<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-Î²1 mAb</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGD</ENAMEX> peptide (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3B), indicating the
          involvement of integrins. However, cell attachment was
          also partially blocked by heparin, which did not inhibit
          cell attachment to fibronectin (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3Aand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3B</TIMEX>, Hep
          samples), indicating that a non-integrin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> also
          mediated cell attachment to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. A complete block of
          cell attachment to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> was only observed when heparin
          was combined with integrin blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>; e.g., heparin
          + anti<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-Î²1 mAb</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">heparin</NUMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGD</ENAMEX> peptide (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3B).
          Anti-fibronectin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies modestly</ENAMEX> inhibited cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attachment</ENAMEX>, but anti-III 1-C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> effectively
          blocked cell attachment to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3B). These
          results demonstrate that cell attachment to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mediated</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">both Î²1</TIMEX> integrins and another class of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way in which integrins were originally shown to be
          fibronectin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> was by affinity chromatography of
          radioiodinated cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> on a fibronectin
          column [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 28</NUMEX> ] . Consistent with these earlier studies,
          cell surface radioiodination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> followed by
          affinity chromatography on fibronectin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sepharose</ENAMEX> and
          elution with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> revealed the binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major bands
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> kDa and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> kDa (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4,Elane under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>). These
          sizes match those of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1 and Î±5</NUMEX> integrin submits,
          respectively, that have been shown by affinity
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chromatography</ENAMEX> to bind to the cell binding domain (i.e.,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> thtype III repeat) of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibronectin</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 28 29 30 31</NUMEX> ] .
          Affinity chromatography on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sepharose</ENAMEX> column
          revealed the binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major bands of sizes 120
          kDa, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> kDa and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> kDa (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4,Elane under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kDa</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> kDa bands likely represent the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1 and Î±5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subunits</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as above</NUMEX>), while the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> kDa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> may represent
          either the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î±2</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î±3</NUMEX> integrin subunits, which are known to
          be expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VSMCs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . Affinity chromatography on
          the control <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C column yielded no radioiodinated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that were eluted from the column (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4,Elane
          under 11C). These results are consistent with the
          hypothesis that one or more pi integrins act as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
          for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. Taken together with the integrin-blocking
          results described above, it is clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMC</ENAMEX> adhesion
          to III1-C is partially mediated through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX> integrins.
        
        
          Cell adhesion to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C activates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>
          Integrins are known to activate signaling pathways in
          cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33 34 35</NUMEX> ] . Among the most well-studied
          signaling pathways is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras/MAPK</ENAMEX> pathway leading to
          activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ERK1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ERK2</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . We therefore decided
          to test the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> adhesion to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> on ERK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX>. As expected, treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> with PDGF
          resulted in activation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plating RASMCs</ENAMEX> onto a fibronectin coated dish in the
          absence of growth factors yielded moderate activation of
          ERK1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>, which peaked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min then decreased somewhat
          over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 30</TIMEX> min of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, bottom
          panel). However, plating cells onto a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C coated dish
          gave strong activation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>, which peaked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min
          and remained relatively constant for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the subsequent 30</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>). The control protein <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C did
          not appreciably stimulate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> phosphorylation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5,</ENAMEX>
          11C <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panels</ENAMEX>). Thus, the adhesion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> to
          III1-C resulted in robust activation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> that was
          comparable to the activation obtained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGF</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> is dependent on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX>
          integrins
          As shown above, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> that block <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX> integrin
          function partially inhibit cell attachment to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. We
          therefore tested the effects of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>
          activation by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. The results obtained with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>
          activation closely paralleled the results obtained with
          cell attachment to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>, except that the individual
          blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were relatively more efficient at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibiting</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> activation. For example, heparin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>,
          anti<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-Î²1 mAb</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGD</ENAMEX> peptide all significantly inhibited
          ERK1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX> activation by cell adhesion to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
          Heparin was most effective and completely blocked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). In contrast, the negative control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX> did not inhibit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> activation by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>, C+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RAD</NUMEX> lane). These results indicate that both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrins</ENAMEX> and the class of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> inhibited by heparin
          were required for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> mediated activation of
          ERK1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>.
        
        
          Role of heparan sulfate proteoglycans in cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adhesion</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> activation by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C
          Because heparin was able to inhibit the attachment of
          cells to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and the activation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>,
          we tested the effect of other glycosaminoglycans on
          III1-C stimulated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> activity. Heparin, heparan
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sulfate</ENAMEX> and dermatan sulfate blocked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> activation by
          III1-C (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> adhesion to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> (not shown).
          In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hyaluronic acid</ENAMEX>, chondroitin-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-sulfate and
          chondroitin-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-sulfate had no effect on the ability of
          III1-C to stimulate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) or on the
          adhesion of cells to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> (not shown). It is possible
          that heparin, heparan sulfate and dermatan sulfate
          inhibit III1-C mediated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell adhesion</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>
          activation due to common chemical features. For example,
          heparin, heparan sulfate, and dermatan sulfate all
          contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">iduronic acid residues</ENAMEX> whereas chondroitin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sulfate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hyaluronic acid</ENAMEX> do not. The results presented
          above indicate that a heparan sulfate proteoglycan (HSPG)
          or dermatan sulfate proteoglycan on the surface of RASMCs
          may serve as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>.
          To further explore the possibility that a cell surface
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteoglycan</ENAMEX> serves as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> were
          treated with the glycosaminoglycan-degrading enzymes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seeded</ENAMEX> onto <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>, and analyzed for the activation of
          ERK1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Heparitinase</ENAMEX> treatment, but not chondroitinase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> treatment decreased the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> activation
          by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Heparitinase</ENAMEX> treatment also inhibited
          cell adhesion by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25-40%</NUMEX>, while chondroitinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
          treatment did not inhibit cell adhesion to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> (not
          shown). This result is consistent with the idea that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX> but not chondroitin sulfate proteoglycans serve as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">signaling receptors</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>.
          To identify the cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteoglycans</ENAMEX> that may
          serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> were labeled with
          35SO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysates</ENAMEX> were applied to
          III1-C and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C columns. The most highly labeled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">band</ENAMEX>, migrating in a smear at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 450</NUMEX> kDa, bound
          efficiently to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the III1-C</TIMEX> column (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9A, compare flow
          through and elution <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX>). This proteoglycan resisted
          elution by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> urea but was eluted by boiling the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sepharose beads in SDS (Fig</ENAMEX>. 9A). This same proteoglycan
          did not bind appreciably to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C column (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          9A). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heparitinase</ENAMEX> and chondroitinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> treatment of the
          35SO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> labeled samples revealed that the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> kDa proteoglycan was composed mostly of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          9B). These results indicate that most of the cell surface
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> can bind to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> in affinity
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chromatography</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">RASMC HSPGs</ENAMEX> were analyzed further by immunoblotting
          with the monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody 3G10</ENAMEX> which specifically
          recognizes desaturated uronates on the heparan sulfate
          stubs that remain associated with core <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> after
          heparitinase digestion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] . Complete digestion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMC</ENAMEX> lysates with heparitinase reveals major bands at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kDa</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> kDa, indicating that these are the sizes of
          the major HSPG core <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (not shown). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMC</ENAMEX> lysates
          were subjected to partial heparitinase treatment (full
          digestion was not performed in order to allow some GAGs
          to remain associated with the core <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>) then applied
          to either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sepharose</ENAMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> kDa and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> kDa HSPGs bound to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C
          Sepharose but not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sepharose</ENAMEX>. In addition, the
          presence of heparin in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lysate</ENAMEX> inhibited the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> kDa
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> kDa HSPGs from binding to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the III1-C</TIMEX> column (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, compare C and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Câ€¢H</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX>). The inhibition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> kDa
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> kDa binding to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> by heparin suggests that
          these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX> may serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> in cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adhesion</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> signaling.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        We have found that cells can interact with a portion of
        the fibronectin first type III repeat, leading to cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adhesion</ENAMEX> and activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX>, and that this signaling
        requires both cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSPGs</ENAMEX> and integrins. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> are
        able to adhere to and spread on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adhesion</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C
        results in robust activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX>; comparable to that
        seen with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGF</ENAMEX> stimulation. Several independent lines of
        evidence indicate that cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSPGs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX> integrins
        act as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and are required for cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adhesion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. For example, various
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX> integrin blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> inhibit cell attachment to
        III1-C and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. In addition,
        inhibition by heparin, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">heparan-sulfate</ENAMEX>, and heparitinase,
        but not by chondroitin sulfates or chondroitinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> all
        point to the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. Affinity
        chromatography with 125I surface labeled proteins resulted
        in the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> of the appropriate sizes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrins</ENAMEX> to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C columns. Moreover, affinity
        chromatography with 35SO 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> -labeled cells suggests that HSPGs
        with core protein sizes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> kDa and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kDa</ENAMEX> serve as
        III1-C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. Taken together, these results indicate
        that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> type III repeat of fibronectin can serve as
        a cell binding domain and that both integrins and cell
        surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSPGs</ENAMEX> function as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for this type III
        repeat.
        Our results demonstrate that both integrins and cell
        surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSPGs</ENAMEX> are required for robust <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK 1/2</NUMEX> activation
        when cells adhere to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. These results are one of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> demonstrations that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX> can activate the ERK
        signaling pathway. Another example of this closely
        parallels our findings [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . The adhesion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat T</ENAMEX>
        cells to thrombospondin-1 has been shown to require the
        cooperation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX> integrins,
        CD47 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . Adhesion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat T</ENAMEX> cells to
        thrombospondin-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> stimulates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> activation and the
        binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX> to thrombospondin-1 is required for this
        signaling. The particular HSPGs that mediate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat T</ENAMEX> cells have not been identified,
        however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> speculate that syndecans may
        participate in the adhesion and signaling in that system [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> ] . This may also be the case in our system, as
        described below.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSPGs</ENAMEX> is the syndecan
        family. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in the syndecan family
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">syndecan-1</ENAMEX> through<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-4</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39 40</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Syndecan-1, -2</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-4</NUMEX>
        are known to bind to extracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">matrix proteins</ENAMEX> and
        syndecan-1 and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-4</NUMEX> have been shown to support stress fiber
        formation in conjunction with integrins [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41 42 43 44 45</NUMEX> ]
        . The HSPGs we have identified as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">III1-C receptors</ENAMEX> have
        core <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that migrate at the approximate sizes of
        syndecan-1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~69</NUMEX> kDa core <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>) and syndecan-2 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~48</NUMEX> kDa
        core <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . It is therefore possible that our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kDa</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> kDa HSPGs represent syndecan family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. As
        described above, the syndecans may cooperate with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Î²1</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">integrins and CD47</TIMEX> to activate the ERK signaling pathway in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . A similar mechanism may apply to the
        adhesion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. Future studies will determine
        the identity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX> that act as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">III1-C receptors</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ras/MAPK</ENAMEX> pathway is typically thought to be a part
        of a mitogenic pathway [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . However, we and others have
        shown that prolonged treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C can inhibit cell
        proliferation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] , and here we show that cell adhesion
        to III1-C can activate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possible explanation for
        this apparent discrepancy is that although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> are often
        involved in mitogenesis, in SMCs ERK activation can lead to
        inhibition of proliferation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] . This occurs through
        ERK-mediated stimulation of PGE 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> production, which then inhibits the
        proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMCs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] . Further experiments will
        determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> produce PGE 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> after treatment with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. Another
        possibility is that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> stimulates other signaling
        pathways apart from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> pathway, and that one of the
        other signaling pathways inhibits proliferation of the
        cells. The relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation, stimulation
        of other signaling pathways and growth inhibition by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C
        will be elucidated by future experiments.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">III1</NUMEX>-C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> has recently been shown to inhibit
        angiogenesis, tumor growth and metastasis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . Those
        findings, along with our present findings reveal some
        intriguing parallels between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and the angiogenesis
        inhibitor endostatin [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX> ] . For example, both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and
        endostatin are fragments of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">matrix proteins</ENAMEX> and can inhibit
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angiogenesis</ENAMEX> and tumor growth. In addition, recent work has
        shown that cells interact with endostatin through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
        classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>; integrins and glypicans (cell surface
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48 49</NUMEX> ] . This parallels our findings in this
        present report, that cells interact with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrins</ENAMEX> and cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSPGs</ENAMEX>. Therefore, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and
        endostatin may inhibit angiogenesis through related
        mechanisms involving both integrins and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPGs</ENAMEX>. Future work
        will determine the relative contributions of these two
        classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in the biological effects of
        III1-C.
      
      
        Conclusions
        We have found that cells can interact with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibronectin</ENAMEX> first type III repeat, leading to cell adhesion
        and activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX>, and that this signaling requires
        both cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HSPGs</ENAMEX> and integrins. Results from various
        independent types of experiments indicate that the first
        type III repeat of fibronectin can serve as a cell binding
        domain and that both integrins and cell surface HSPGs
        function as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for this type III repeat.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Materials
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> and glutamine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pen-Strep</ENAMEX> were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies, Inc.</ENAMEX> FBS was purchased from HyClone
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratories, Inc. Plasma</ENAMEX> fibronectin was purified from
          human plasma by gelatin-agarose affinity chromatography [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> gradient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE gels were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Novex</ENAMEX>.
          Anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">phospho</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p44/42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> and
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p44/42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Biolabs</ENAMEX>. Anti<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-Î²1</NUMEX> blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ha2/5</NUMEX>)
          was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PharMingen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peptides GRGDSP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRADSP</ENAMEX> were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies, Inc. Texas</ENAMEX> red and FITC
          labeled secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> and 35SO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICN</ENAMEX>. Heparitinase,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chondroitinase ABC</ENAMEX> and mAb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">3G10</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seikagaku</ENAMEX>.
          Anti-FN <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were a gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erkki Ruoslahti</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burnham Institute</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECL</ENAMEX> plus reagent and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyperfilm</ENAMEX> were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amersham</ENAMEX>. Completeâ„¢ protease inhibitor
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail tablets</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehringer Mannheim</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biochemicals</ENAMEX>. The expression vector pQE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> was obtained
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Qiagen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heparin</ENAMEX> and all other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>.
          The purified glycosaminoglycans used in this study
          were a generous gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Schwartz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Univ</ENAMEX>. of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>). The glycosaminoglycans were produced under a
          contract from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute of Arthritis</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musculoskeletal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skin Diseases</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>) and serve as
          reference standards. The tissue sources of the
          glycosaminoglycans were as follows: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hyaluronic acid</ENAMEX>,
          human umbilical cord; heparan sulfate, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> lung;
          dermatan sulfate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog mucosa</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">chondroitin-4-sulfate,</ENAMEX>
          notochord from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river sturgeon</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">S. platorhynchus</NUMEX>), and
          chondroitin-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-sulfate, cranial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> of river
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sturgeon</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Cell culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Primary rat</ENAMEX> aortic smooth muscle cells (RASMCs) were
          isolated from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-16 week</TIMEX> old Sprague-Dawley <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> were cultured in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> and glutamine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pen-Strep</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> were typically between passages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 7</NUMEX> for
          experiments.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Recombinant protein</ENAMEX> production
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Proteins III1-C</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C (previously called III 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> ) were produced in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> and
          purified as described previously [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . III1-C
          encompasses fibronectin amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids 600</ENAMEX>-674
          (Asn-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro-Gln-...Thr-Ser-Thr-Pro</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C amino
          acids <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,532</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,599</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Leu-Pro-Ser-Ser-...Thr-Ala-Val-Thr</ENAMEX>),
          according to the previously published numbering method [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX> ] . The recombinant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were expressed by the
          pQE-12 vector, which places a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-His coding sequence at
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX> of each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were
          purified on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ni</ENAMEX>-agarose columns and were ><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX> pure as
          judged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE and coomassie staining. Stock protein
          solutions were typically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> Î¼M for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">520 Î</NUMEX>¼M for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>.
          Anti-III1-C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were produced by immunizing
          rabbits with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> the rabbits were
          boosted and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serum samples</ENAMEX> were collected every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>.
          The rabbit serum was applied to an affinity column to
          purify the anti-III 1-C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. In order to avoid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">purifying antibodies</ENAMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-His tag in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX>, the
          affinity column was made with a GST fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sttype III</ENAMEX> repeat of fibronectin was expressed as a
          fusion protein coupled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX>, and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-3FN1</ENAMEX> fusion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was coupled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sepharose</ENAMEX> and used in affinity
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purification</ENAMEX>. Bound <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were eluted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM
          triethylamine, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.5</NUMEX> and the pH was neutralized with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>; (the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> concentration was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml) was added to stabilize the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> for
          subsequent handling. The antibody prep was dialyzed
          extensively against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> before use.
        
        
          Cell attachment and spreading assays
          For the cell spreading assay shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibronectin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">20 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) was coated onto <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well dishes for
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> before
          adding cells. Growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RASMCs</ENAMEX> were harvested by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trypsinization</ENAMEX> and collected into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> +
          soybean trypsin inhibitor. Cells were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, then resuspended at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Ã— 10 5cells/ml</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, in the absence or presence of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î</NUMEX>¼M
          III1-C or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C in the medium. Cells were seeded
          onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ml</ENAMEX>/well, ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> confluence), placed in
          a 37Â°C <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> and allowed to adhere for either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7, 15</TIMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 60, 120</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">min. Cells</ENAMEX> were then fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.7%</NUMEX>
          paraformaldehyde, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> mM sucrose in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>, followed by
          staining with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coomassie Blue</ENAMEX> dye (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mg/ml Coomassie</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brilliant Blue</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeOH</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> acetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>). Cells were
          destained with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, air-dried, then photographed with a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leica DM IRB</ENAMEX> phase microscope connected to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCD</ENAMEX>
          camera and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Macintosh</ENAMEX> computer for capturing
          images. To quantitate the amount of spreading, each image
          was analyzed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Image 1.61</ENAMEX> application to
          determine the total amount of area covered by cells and
          this number was divided by the total number of cells in
          the image to give an average area per cell (in pixels
          2/cell).
          Cell attachment assays shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3were</NUMEX> done
          essentially as described previously [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          fibronectin, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C at various concentrations
          were coated onto <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well dishes for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX>. The wells
          were then washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> before adding cells.
          Growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RASMCs</ENAMEX> were harvested by trypsinization and
          collected into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> + soybean trypsin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibitor</ENAMEX>. Cells were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, then resuspended at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 Ã— 10 5cells/ml</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> with or without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, as indicated in the
          figures. Cells were seeded onto the coated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> and
          allowed to adhere for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. The cells were then
          fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.7%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> mM sucrose in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>,
          followed by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX>, and staining in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> crystal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">violet</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX>. Stained cells were washed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and the dye was solubilized with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> sodium
          citrate, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attachment</ENAMEX> was quantitated
          by measuring the absorbance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> nm.
        
        
          125I cell surface labeling and affinity
          chromatography
          The procedure was a modification of the procedure used
          to isolate the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibronectin receptor</ENAMEX> and other integrins [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 28</NUMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">affinity resins</ENAMEX> were prepared by coupling
          fibronectin, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C to CNBr-activated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sepharose</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CL-4B</ENAMEX> according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          recommendations. The concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was
          typically <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-5 mg fibronectin/ml</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">resin</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8-10</ENAMEX> mg
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">protein/ml</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">resin</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten 15</NUMEX>-cm
          dishes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASMCs</ENAMEX> were washed twice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, then
          harvested by detachment of cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>. The
          cells were washed twice more with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, then resuspended
          at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 Ã— 10 7cells/ml</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. Cells were labeled with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mCi
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Na 125I</ENAMEX> and lactoperoxidase-H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
          After labeling the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell pellet</ENAMEX> was washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> + NaN 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> , then lysed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> volumes of OG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lysis Buffer</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> mM octylglucoside, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. The lysate was
          spun at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> Ã— g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, and the supernatant
          was used for affinity chromatography. Lysate was applied
          to the affinity columns (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> ml lysate was applied to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>
          ml affinity matrix bed volume), flow through fractions
          were collected and passed over the columns twice more.
          Columns were washed with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> column volumes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash Buffer</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> mM octylglucoside, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX>), before elution of bound
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash Buffer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Samples</ENAMEX> from the
          final wash and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eluted samples</ENAMEX> were separated on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gradient Novex</ENAMEX> gels, the gels were dried and exposed to
          phosphorimager cassette and the radioactive signal was
          measured with a Storm phosphorimager instrument.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> assay and immunoblotting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well plate were coated with either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml fibronectin, 25 Î¼M III1-C</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          hr at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> before
          adding cells. Growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RASMCs</ENAMEX> were harvested by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trypsinization</ENAMEX> and collected into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> +
          soybean trypsin inhibitor. Cells were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, then resuspended at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 Ã— 10 5cells/ml</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> with or without integrin blocking agents
          or other additions, as described in the figure legends.
          Cells were either left in suspension (for suspended and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF stimulated samples</ENAMEX>) or were seeded onto the coated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ml</NUMEX> per well) and allowed to adhere for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at
          37Â°C, or for the times indicated in the figure legend
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). The cells stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 ng/ml</ENAMEX>
          PDGF-BB) received the growth factor <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> before
          collecting the cells for lysis, while the other samples
          received no growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> or serum. After the adhesion
          period plates were placed on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>, unattached cells were
          collected and spun down, while cell monolayers were
          washed once with ice cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> then lysed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE
          sample buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼l/well</ENAMEX>). Centrifuged <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> of
          unattached cells were combined with the appropriate
          monolayer lysate sample and the samples were heated to
          100Â°C for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Samples</ENAMEX> were separated on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> gradient
          Novex gels, transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immobilon P</ENAMEX> membranes, blocked
          with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat dry milk</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS-Tween</ENAMEX>, then probed with
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">phospho</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p44/42</NUMEX> MAPK antibody according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s recommendations. Blots were then stripped
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stripping Buffer</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM Î²-mercaptoethanol,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.7</NUMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> times
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS-Tween</ENAMEX>, blocked with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat dry milk</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS-Tween</ENAMEX>, then probed with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p44/42</NUMEX> ERK antibody
          according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s recommendations. All
          blots were developed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECL</ENAMEX> plus reagent and
          exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyperfilm</ENAMEX>. For both antibodies the typical
          exposure times were under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Heparitinase</ENAMEX> treatment of cells and lysates
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well plates</ENAMEX> were coated with either fibronectin,
          III1-C or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C as described above. Growing RASMCs
          were harvested by trypsinization and washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + BSA
          as described above. For <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">GAGase</ENAMEX> treatment of intact cells,
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> remained in suspension and received either no
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enzyme</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.1</NUMEX> u/ml heparitinase or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.1</NUMEX> u/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chondroitinase ABC</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> with constant gentle
          rotation. Cells were then plated onto precoated dishes
          and processed for immunoblotting with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-phospho</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p44/42</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAPK antibody</ENAMEX> as described above. Alternatively, after
          heparitinase digestion cells were lysed directly in SDS
          sample buffer and analyzed by immunoblotting with the
          3G10 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> (essentially as described above for
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">phospho</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p44/42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> immunoblotting).
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">GAGase</ENAMEX> treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysates</ENAMEX>, cells were lysed
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> in NP40 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lysis</ENAMEX> buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonidet P</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM
          NaCl, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>) plus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protease inhibitors</ENAMEX>
          (Completeâ„¢ protease inhibitor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail</ENAMEX>) at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6cells/ml.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insoluble</ENAMEX> material was removed by
          centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> Ã— g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. Lysate
          was prepared for heparitinase treatment by adding CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 to 10</NUMEX> Î¼M final concentration.
          Heparitinase was added to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> u/ml final concentration
          and the lysate was incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr. The lysate
          was then applied to affinity chromatography columns as
          described below.
        
        
          35SO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4labeling</ENAMEX> and affinity chromatography
          Growing RASMCs labeled for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> hr at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼Ci/ml 35S04</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> dialyzed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pen-Strep</ENAMEX>.
          Cells were placed on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>, washed once with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, then
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysed</ENAMEX> in NP40 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lysis</ENAMEX> buffer as described above. III1-C and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C columns were produced as described above. Cell
          lysates were applied to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">III1-C</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-C columns
          (typically <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 Î¼l</NUMEX> lysate was applied to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> Î¼l affinity
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">matrix</ENAMEX> bed volume), flow through fractions were collected
          and passed over the columns twice more. The final flow
          through fractions were then collected. Columns were
          washed with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> column volumes of NP40 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lysis</ENAMEX> buffer, then
          bound material was removed by boiling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sepharose</ENAMEX> beads
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> column volumes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> sample buffer. Alternatively,
          the bound material was first eluted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> column volumes
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8 M</ENAMEX> urea buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8 M urea</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M NaH</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 PO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>), followed by
          washing with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> column volumes of NP40 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lysis</ENAMEX> buffer, and
          then removing any remaining bound material by boiling the
          Sepharose beads in SDS sample buffer. Samples were
          separated on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novex SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE gels, the gels were
          fixed and dried and the radioactive material was detected
          by using a phosphorimager.
        
      
    
  
