
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron</ENAMEX> is one of the essential nutrients required by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> to be able to multiply and invade a vertebrate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. However as a defense mechanism, availability of iron
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> is limited in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> as most of it
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">complexed</ENAMEX> to ferritin, transferrin, hemoglobin, heme and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hemosiderin</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4</NUMEX> ] . For <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pathogenic bacteria</ENAMEX> to be
        able to establish an infection, it must compete with and
        obtain iron from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>'s iron <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding protein</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] .
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> have evolved a number of diverse mechanisms
        utilize the host iron. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the methods of achieving
        this, is by secretion of low molecular weight high affinity
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chelators</ENAMEX> termed siderophores and their specific cell
        surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron Regulated Outer Membrane Proteins</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX>). These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are expressed under iron
        restricted conditions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7 8 9</NUMEX> ] . The role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uptake</ENAMEX> have been reported for other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> like 
        Pseudomonas aeruginosa and 
        Neisseria gonorrheae . Antibodies
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> against these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> associated with iron uptake
        exert a bacteriostatic or bactericidal effect, by blocking
        siderophore mediated iron <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uptake pathways</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11 12 13 14</NUMEX>
        ] .
        
        A. baumannii is widely recognized as
        an emerging nosocomial pathogen and is of particular
        concern due to the spread of multi-drug resistant strain [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] . 
        A. baumannii has also been shown to
        produce siderophores and expresses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> under iron
        restricted conditions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alpar</ENAMEX> had shown
        the specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> in patients
        suffering from 
        A. calcoaceticus septicemia in the
        convalescent sera [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] .
        We carried out the present study to characterize the
        IROMPs 
        A. baumannii <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">19606</ENAMEX> by producing
        monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against them. Western blot analysis
        was performed to study their specificity. These monoclonal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were tested for their 
        in-vitro bactericidal activity and
        opsonizing activity. Apart from this their role in blocking
        the siderophore mediated iron uptake system was also
        studied.
      
      
        Results
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> and effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron</ENAMEX> on
          growth
          OMP profiles of 
          A. baumannii grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM-Fe</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fe</ENAMEX> were compared on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE and it was seen that in
          absence of iron, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> developed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> new outer membrane
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> which were absent in iron replete conditions.
          These new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are in the range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX> kDa to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX> kDa
          and were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> production
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> best reactive monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were selected
          out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX> clones after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> fusions based upon their
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivity</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>. These monoclonal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were named as 3D 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABIR</ENAMEX>, 1D 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 ABIR</TIMEX>, 2G 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABIR</ENAMEX>, 1F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABIR</ENAMEX>, and 5D 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABIR</ENAMEX>. All of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> monoclonal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IgM isotypes</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). These
          monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were tested in Western blots. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2shows the results of western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immunoblots</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX>. All
          the monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> reacted with one or more OMP
          bands corresponding to the range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> but none
          reacted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fe</ENAMEX> media.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (5D 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABIR</ENAMEX> and 1F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> ABIR) did not show any reactivity on
          Western blot this may be due to conformational changes of
          epitope of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>. All of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were tested
          against 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E.coli</ENAMEX> and 
          Pseudomonas aerugionsa and none of
          them were cross reactive with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> of these two
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Characterization of monoclonal antibodies
          
            Bactericidal activity
            All these monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were tested for
            their bactericidal activity against 
            A. baumannii <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ATCC 19606</NUMEX> in-vitro.
            It was found that all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> monoclonal antibodies
            are bactericidal and they specifically kill the
            bacteria grown in CDM-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fe</ENAMEX> media. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">The %</NUMEX> of reduction or
            killing was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80-90%</NUMEX>, and various controls gave <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10-20%</NUMEX>
            reduction in bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
          
          
            Opsonising activity
            It was found that human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PMNs opsonize bacteria</ENAMEX> more
            readily when <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> is preincubated with monoclonal
            antibodies as is evident by counting the bacteria
            within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMNs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>) as compared to controls. The
            opsonization activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMNs</ENAMEX> was increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> folds
            by prior incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibodies</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            Uptake of Iron through siderophore
            The siderophore was secreted by 
            Acinetobacter buamnnii <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX> 19606
            was catechole type as determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnow</ENAMEX>'s method. The
            uptake of radiolabeled iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">siderophore complex</ENAMEX> by the
            bacterial whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM-Fe</ENAMEX> was significantly more
            than that in case of bacterial cells obtained from
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fe</ENAMEX> medium (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The control tubes incubated
            only with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55Fe</TIMEX> without siderophore showed negligible
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iron</ENAMEX> uptake. Total radioactivity bound to the filter in
            case of iron <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">deficient bacteria</ENAMEX> with radioactive
            siderophore <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 85%</NUMEX> out of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>
            radioactivity taken of the neat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55Fe</TIMEX>. In control as
            well as with iron rich <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> it was not more than
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15-25%</NUMEX>. This suggests that the iron <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uptake</ENAMEX> is mediated
            through siderophore. The data was analyzed by
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonparametric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Willcoxan Rank Sum Test</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
            It was found that iron uptake by iron deficient cells
            was significantly more as compared to iron rich cells
            (p value <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). Similarly there was a significant
            difference in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPM</ENAMEX> reading of iron deficient cells for
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uptake</ENAMEX> through siderophore (p value <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>) as
            compared to the control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in which no siderophore
            was added.
          
          
            Binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">59Fe-Siderophore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> to OMP
            The outer membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> prepared from cells
            grown in the absence of iron bound significantly higher
            amount of radioactive iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">siderophore complex</ENAMEX> as
            compared to that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMP</ENAMEX> prepared from cells grown
            in iron rich conditions (p value <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). Similarly
            there was no binding of radiolabeled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59Fe</TIMEX> alone to the
            filters in absence of siderophore which was put up as
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. This strongly indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMP</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM-Fe</ENAMEX>
            grown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> contains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> and that they bind
            to the iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">siderophore complex</ENAMEX>, hence they may be the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> for siderophore iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). That
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding receptor</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was proved by preincubating
            the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX> with proteinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> that abolished all the
            binding activity of the iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">siderophore complex</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>).
          
          
            Role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibody</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron</ENAMEX>
            pathway
            The iron uptake by 
            A. baumannii <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ATCC 19606</ENAMEX> when
            grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM-Fe</ENAMEX> was inhibited <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 90%</NUMEX> by
            monoclonal antibodies directed against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> of 
            A. bauamannii, as compared to
            bacteria grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, p value <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>).
            Similarly, monoclonal antibodies resulted in almost
            complete inhibition of binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">55Fe</ENAMEX> siderophore
            complex to its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor IROMPs</ENAMEX>, which are the component
            of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX> (p value <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). But there was no effect on
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> and uptake of iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">siderophore complex</ENAMEX> in
            absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibodies</ENAMEX> or with control sera
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>).
          
        
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron</ENAMEX> is an important nutritional requirement of living
        cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron</ENAMEX> is not readily available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microbes</ENAMEX>, which
        invades the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] as a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> defense
        mechanism against bacterial infections. In iron starved
        conditions, bacterial growth rate is reduced and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">morphological</ENAMEX> changes such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">filament</ENAMEX> formation takes
        place which suggests an inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX> or cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22</NUMEX> ] . Besides these the concentration of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> whose synthesis is regulated by iron are also
        observed to get changed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        To acquire the iron essential for their growth and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">metabolism</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microbes</ENAMEX> have evolved the ability to
        compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> iron binding factors. This is achieved by
        producing powerful iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chelators</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siderophores</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25 26 27</NUMEX> ] . Siderophores are secreted in the external
        melieu where they compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> iron binding proteins
        to capture iron by forming iron-siderophore <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. This
        gets internalized through the specific outer membrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein receptors</ENAMEX>, termed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iron Regulated Outer Membrane</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proteins</ENAMEX> (IROMPs).
        We found that when 
        A. baumannii was grown in iron
        deficient medium, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> were expressed on their outer
        membranes with molecular weight of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">88, 84, 80 and 77</TIMEX> kDa.
        We also found that 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baumannii</ENAMEX> secreted catehcol type
        of siderophore in the external melieu. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel et</ENAMEX>.al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ]
        also reported the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> and siderophore
        during different phase of growth cycle in iron starved
        medium by 
        A. baumannii . The molecular weight
        of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> described by them were in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 70-80</NUMEX>
        kDa of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75 and 80</NUMEX> kDa are expressed more strongly in
        iron <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">repressed bacteria</ENAMEX>. They have also cloned and
        characterized the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fur regulator gene</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX>.
        Apart from these, some other high molecular weight
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> in 
        Acinetobacter have also been
        identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echenique et al. on SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpar</ENAMEX> also demonstrated the reactivity by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunoblotting</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> using the sera of
        convalescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> recovering from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Acinetobacter</ENAMEX> infection sera by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpar</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        In order to further characterize the biological
        properties of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> and role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> produced
        against them, we raised monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> to the IROMPs
        by hybridoma technology. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> best reactive and
        specific clones, which were selected after subcloning,
        belonged to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. On western blot however only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clones</ENAMEX> reacted with the bands corresponding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX>. The
        reason for none of the clones reacting, could be due to the
        fact that monoclonal antibodies recognize only an epitope
        whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tertiary structure</ENAMEX> might be changed during
        denaturation conditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IROMPs antibodies</ENAMEX> showed significant 
        in-vitro bactericidal activity
        against 
        A. baumannii grown in absence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iron</ENAMEX>. Also being IgM subtype, these were efficient in
        complement mediated lysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>. They also enhanced
        the phagocytosis of 
        A. baumannii <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6-8</ENAMEX> folds more as
        compared to preimmune sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">invitro</ENAMEX> experiments.
        These results showed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> are surfaced exposed
        immunodominant antigens, which play significant role in
        virulence. Earlier also the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> kDa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> of 
        Neisseria meningitidis have been
        shown to be bactericidal [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> may have
        a role as protective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> in the course of infection
        inside a human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. The antisera against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tbp1</ENAMEX> and Tbp2
        killed the homologous as well as majority of heterologous
        strains examined, with varying efficiency [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sokol</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woods</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] have pointed out that the antibodies
        against pyoverdin and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pyochelin receptor proteins</ENAMEX> in 
        Pseudomonas aeruginosa, enhances the
        opsonization process by polymorphonucleocytes. They have
        also shown that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were protective in a burn
        mouse model system.
        We observed that these antibodies significantly reduced
        the uptake of iron by 
        A. baumannii cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Meyer</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX> . [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] and Pintor 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX> . [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] have shown the
        specific block of iron <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uptake</ENAMEX> via siderophore and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transferrin</ENAMEX> using polyclonal and monoclonal antibodies
        against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pseudomona sp</ENAMEX>. and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neisseria sp</ENAMEX>. respectively. We also
        observed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> raised against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> of 
        A. baumannii also inhibited the
        binding of iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">siderophore complex</ENAMEX> to purified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX>. The
        blocking in the uptake of iron resulted ultimately in the
        growth inhibition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX>.
        This mechanism of iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">uptake</ENAMEX> may constitute an
        important virulence <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX>, which can help in establishing
        infection in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . The study of this virulence
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> may help in the better understanding of the
        bacterial pathogenesis especially in an opportunistic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathogen</ENAMEX> like 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Acinetobacter sp</ENAMEX>. 
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bacterial strains</ENAMEX> and growth conditions
          The 
          Acinetobacter baumannii <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX> 19606
          strain was procured from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Cell Culture</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>.
          It was grown in Iron depleted chemically defined media
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM-Fe</ENAMEX>) and in iron rich (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fe</ENAMEX>) media. Outer membrane
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were prepared as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goel et</ENAMEX>.al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ]
          , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> concentration was measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradford</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX> were resolved on SDSPAGE
          according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lugtenberg</ENAMEX>'s protocol [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Production of monoclonal antibodies
          For immunization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Balb/c</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, the area of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE gel corresponding to the bands representing the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> were cut and used as an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . First
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dose</ENAMEX> was given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intraperitonealy</ENAMEX> mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">250 Î¼l</NUMEX> of
          complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s adjuvant followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> doses in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Incomplete Adjuvant</ENAMEX> at an interval of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX>.
          Final booster was given in normal saline,
          intraperitonealy, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> before fusion. The
          spleen cells were fused with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> myeloma cell line Sp2O
          14/Ag as described previously by using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEG</ENAMEX> (polyethylene
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">glycol 1450</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36 37</NUMEX> ] . Screening of hybridomas was done
          by testing culture supernatants in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ELISA</ENAMEX> using two
          different antigens.
          (A) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX> expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM-Fe</ENAMEX> medium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">i.e. antigen</ENAMEX> A
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX> expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fe</ENAMEX> medium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">i.e. antigen</ENAMEX> B
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hybridoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supernatants</ENAMEX> reacting with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> A alone
          without any signal with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> B were selected and
          subcloned thrice by limiting dilution. Clones of interest
          were expanded and cultured in the peritoneal cavities of
          pristane primed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Balb/c</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> to obtain ascitic fluid.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antigen A</ENAMEX> and B were diluted to final concentration of
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> was
          added to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> well ELISA plate (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High binding ELISA plates</ENAMEX>,
          Costar, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and were allowed to adsorb for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16-18</NUMEX> hrs at
          4Â°C. The plates were washed thrice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tween 20</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Co. USA</ENAMEX>). The nonspecific binding
          sites on the plate were blocked by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat milk powder</ENAMEX>
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> hrs. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was added to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> and the plates were further incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> hrs
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. The rabbit antimouse (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dakopats Switzerland</ENAMEX>)
          peroxidase conjugated immunoglobulin was used at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">working</TIMEX>
          dilution of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O-Phenyalenediamine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Inc.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was used as chromogen and substrate,
          respectively. The optical density were taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">492</NUMEX> nm. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> reactivity of the monoclonal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX> was checked against 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> and 
          Pseudomonas aeruginosa <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> as described above.
        
        
          Determination of immunoglobulin isotype
          The isotyping of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibodies</ENAMEX> was done using
          commercially available isotyping kit based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Immunoblotting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE were transferred
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrophoretically</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nitrocellulose</ENAMEX> paper (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.45</NUMEX> Î¼m
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) using semidry blotter (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) as
          described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> by a modification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Towbin</ENAMEX>'s [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> ] procedure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> paper was washed twice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> paper was stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ponceau S</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merck</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>) for staining the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> to check the
          transfer efficiency and for marking the position of
          molecular weights. The other part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> paper was used
          for immunoblotting. Nonspecific binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> were
          blocked by incubating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> bovine serum
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">albumin</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat milk powder</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 hours</TIMEX>. NC
          paper was washed thrice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> Tween
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> paper was incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> for overnight with
          either monoclonal or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polyclonal antibodies</ENAMEX>. The rabbit
          antimouse peroxidase conjugated immunoglobulin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dakopats</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>) was used at a dilution of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> and
          incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 h.</TIMEX> The blots were developed using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAB</ENAMEX> (diaminobenzimidine) and H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> as chromogen and substrate,
          respectively.
        
        
          Bactericidal assay
          Bactericidal assay of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibodies</ENAMEX> was
          carried out as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poolman et</ENAMEX>.al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] .
          Briefly, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 7cells</NUMEX> of 
          A. baumannii <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ATCC 19606</NUMEX> (grown in
          iron deficient medium) in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î¼l volume were taken in an
          eppendrof, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibodies</ENAMEX> culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatant</ENAMEX> (undiluted) was added to it and incubated at
          37Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX>. The human complement from immunoglobulin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deficient patient</ENAMEX> was added (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtesy of Medical</ENAMEX> Oncology
          Unit, AIIMS <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Delhi India</ENAMEX>) to a final concentration of
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , incubated further for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> at
          37Â°C. The reaction mixture were appropriately diluted,
          plated on to nutrient agar plate and incubated at 37Â°C
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bacterial colonies</ENAMEX> were counted the next
          day to look for percentage reduction. The percentage
          reduction was calculated as follows
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control-Test X100/Control</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Opsonophagocytic assay
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assay</ENAMEX> described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speert et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] was used
          to measure opsonophagocytic activity of monoclonal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. The polymorphonuclear leucocytes (PMN) were
          isolated from pooled normal healthy human blood by Ficoll
          Hypaque density gradient centrifugation. 
          A. baumannii <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ATCC 19606</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          7bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/100 Î¼l</ENAMEX>) grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM-Fe</ENAMEX> medium were
          incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibody</ENAMEX> culture
          supernatant for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. To this <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 6PMN</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î¼l
          volume was added and kept in orbital shaker (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100 rpm</NUMEX>) at
          37Â°C for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> min. A duplicate set of assay was incubated
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Â°C</NUMEX> to measure the nonspecific attachment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>.
          After incubation the tubes were centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX> and
          cell pellet was washed gently in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX>'s balanced salt
          solution (HBSS) at least thrice. The pellet was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuspended</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> drop of it was
          placed on glass slide, air-dried heat fixed and stained
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gram Stain</ENAMEX>. The slide was seen under oil immersion
          field of light microscope. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> within
          the, cytoplasm of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMNs</ENAMEX> were counted. The mean number
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">PMN</ENAMEX> obtained from 4Â°C <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assay</ENAMEX> was
          subtracted from the number obtained from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> assay to
          get the final results. Same set of experiments was
          repeated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fe</ENAMEX> medium.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electron</ENAMEX> microscopy
          For electron microscopy modified procedure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Root et</ENAMEX>.
          al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] was followed. Mixture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7bacteria</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          6PMNs were combined and processed for opsonization as
          mentioned above except the last wash, which was in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
          sodium cacodylate buffer pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX>. To the pellet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5%</NUMEX> glutraldehyde (made in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> sodium cacodylate
          buffer) was added and centrifuged at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1150</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">g for 10 min</ENAMEX>,
          supernatant was decanted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell pellet</ENAMEX> was fixed by
          adding <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5%</NUMEX> glutraldehyde for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> h and the pellet was
          washed in sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cacodylate</ENAMEX> buffer. The pellet was post
          fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> osmium tetraoxide, embedded in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> agar. The
          embedded sample was dehydrated in graded series of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and finally embedded in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Araldite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">resin</ENAMEX>. It was
          sectioned, poststained with uranyl acetate and lead and
          samples were viewed with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philips</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> electronmicroscope
          to look for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phagocytosed bacteria</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Blocking of iron uptake by bacteria
          For studying the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibodies</ENAMEX> in
          blocking of iron uptake pathway, we purified the
          siderophore by a modified method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
          Briefly the culture supernatant of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> grown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM-Fe</ENAMEX> medium was extracted twice with ethyl acetate. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethyl</ENAMEX> acetate was reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> ml by rotary evaporation
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buchi</ENAMEX> rotary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">evaporator</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30Â°C</TIMEX> under reduced pressure.
          This sample was loaded on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Whatman 3</ENAMEX> mm chromatography
          paper and developed using solvent system of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>:Acetic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Acid</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acetone</ENAMEX> in ratio of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90:10:1.</TIMEX> One portion of the
          chromatogram was stained with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M FeCl</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M HCl</ENAMEX>. The corresponding band
          was excised and siderophore was eluted in ethyl acetate
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> hrs at room temperature. After evaporation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethyl</ENAMEX> acetate, purified siderophore was re-suspended in
          distilled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-80Â°C</TIMEX>. The type of
          siderophore was determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnow</ENAMEX>'s [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Csaky</ENAMEX>'s
          method [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] . The concentration of siderophore was
          determined using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> dihydroxybenzoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> as a standard
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Chemical</ENAMEX> assay as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwyn</ENAMEX>'s [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>
          ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼l</NUMEX> purified siderophore was incubated with
          either <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> 55FeCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> (specific activity <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.068</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mci/g of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iron, Bhabha Atomic Research Center Trombay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>) or
          59FeCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> (specific activity <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250.49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GBq/g of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iron, Bhabha Atomic Research Center Trombay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>). The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mixture</ENAMEX> was incubated at room temperature for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>.
          At the end the unbound radiolabelled iron was removed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chromatography</ENAMEX> using sephadex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-10</ENAMEX> as described by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] . The uptake of radiolabelled iron
          siderophore was studied by the method described by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] . Briefly 
          A. baumannii was grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM-Fe</ENAMEX>
          medium also in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDM</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fe</ENAMEX> medium to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid</TIMEX> exponential phase
          and was washed twice with uptake medium (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> mM Na 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HPO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HPO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ) 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 SO</TIMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 ,1</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 40</NUMEX> Î¼M CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.9</NUMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> and re-suspended in
          the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> at a density of A 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">470</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX>. The washed cells were
          incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>. The uptake was
          initiated by adding equal volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">radiolabelled</ENAMEX> 55Fe
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">siderophore</ENAMEX> to the bacterial suspension and shaken at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rpm</ENAMEX>. Aliquots of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 Î</NUMEX>¼l were withdrawn after every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> interval and filtered immediately on glass
          microfiber filter and washed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ml of uptake medium.
          The membranes were dried at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> and measured as counts
          per <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> on Î²-scintillation counter (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>) on the
          3H <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. In parallel, bacterial cells were also
          incubated with radiolabelled iron alone and unlabelled
          siderophore as a control.
          To look for the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibodies</ENAMEX> against
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IROMPs</ENAMEX> in blocking the iron uptake the bacterial cells
          were pre-incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of undiluted monoclonal
          antibody culture supernatant for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h at 37Â°C</TIMEX> before
          addition of radiolabelled iron <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">siderophore complex</ENAMEX>. After
          incubation with antibodies the bacterial cells were
          washed twice with uptake buffer to remove unbound
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. Similarly as like in uptake, radioactivity
          retained on the filter was counted on Î²-scintillation
          counter on 3H <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Binding of radiolabelled iron siderophore complex
          to OMPs
          Binding of radiolabelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">55Fe</ENAMEX> siderophore <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX> was carried out as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ]
          . <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼g</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMPs</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.125</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M Tris HCl</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.8</NUMEX> was mixed
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siderophore</ENAMEX> labeled with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55Fe</TIMEX> (as
          described above). The total volume of the mixture was
          adjusted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml with uptake medium and the reaction
          mixture were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. This was
          filtered through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.22</NUMEX> Î¼m filter and washed twice with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          ml of uptake medium. The radiolabeled iron retained on
          the filter was counted as counts per <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> on
          Î²-scintillation counter on 3H <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. To determine the
          nature of the binding receptor, the OMP preparation was
          subjected to digestion with proteinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 mg/ml</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          hr at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> prior to the incubation with iron siderophore
          complex.
          To test the blocking of iron siderophore to OMP 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">s</ENAMEX> , it was preincubated with
          monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> as described in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uptake</ENAMEX> experiment and then binding assay was
          performed
        
      
    
  
