
  
    
      
        Background
        The synthesis of the neurotransmitter acetylcholine
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1in</TIMEX> cholinergic neurons is dependent on the
        availability of its precursor, choline, most of which is
        derived from the circulation (reviewed in [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] ) and
        enters cholinergic neurons via a process catalyzed by a
        specific transporter [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] . Some of the choline used for
        ACh synthesis is stored in membrane phosphatidylcholine
        (PC). Previous studies have shown that this choline is
        liberated from PC in a one-step reaction, thus indicating
        that it is produced by a phospholipase <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1.4.4</NUMEX>)
        -an enzyme that hydrolyzes the phospholipid into choline
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphatidic acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . However, the molecular
        identity of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> remains to be determined.
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct PC-specific mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLDs</ENAMEX>,
        designated as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> and encoded by separate genes [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> enzymes share <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid</ENAMEX> identity,
        however, regulation of their activity and cellular
        localization are different. PLD1 is an extracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX>-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phospholipase</ENAMEX>; its activity rises when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for certain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>, growth factors,
        neurotransmitters, cytokines, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activated</ENAMEX>, and upon treatment of cells with phorbol esters
        (reviewed in [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] ). Studies using recombinant PLD1
        tagged with green fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Flu</ENAMEX>-epitopes
        indicate that it is localized in the endoplasmic reticulum,
        Golgi apparatus, late endosomes, and plasma membrane ( [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
        ] , reviewed in [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] ). In vitro, basal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD1</TIMEX> activity is
        usually low and can be stimulated by a variety of factors,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX> (PKC), and several
        small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTPases</ENAMEX>, e.g. ADP ribosylation factors (ARF) and Rho
        (reviewed in [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] ). Regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> is less well
        understood. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enzyme</ENAMEX> exhibits a high constitutive
        activity in vitro, but it too can be activated by ARF
        (reviewed in [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] ), and by phorbol esters, in intact
        cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 9</NUMEX> ] . Several reports have suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> is
        mainly localized to the plasma membrane [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 10</ENAMEX> ] , possibly
        in lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rafts</ENAMEX> and caveolar membrane microdomains [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ]
        . Most studies on the physiological functions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLDs</ENAMEX> have
        focused on the product <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX> involved in
        mitosis, cellular morphological changes and vesicular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trafficking</ENAMEX> (reviewed in [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7 13</ENAMEX> ] ). However, the
        downstream events that occur as a consequence of
        PLD-generated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> production, and the identity of target
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that are directly regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> remains to be
        determined. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> can be further metabolized to diacylglycerol
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAG</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lysophosphatidic acid</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> phosphohydrolase and
        phospholipase A 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , respectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAG</ENAMEX> is an activator of
        certain isozymes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lysophosphatidic acid</ENAMEX> acts as
        an intercellular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX> for many cell types.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> product of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD-catalyzed</ENAMEX> PC hydrolysis,
        choline, is used by all cells as a precursor of PC, and
        uniquely by cholinergic neurons as precursor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX>.
        Previous studies have shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">choline</ENAMEX> derived from PC is
        indeed used for ACh synthesis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 14 15 16</ENAMEX> ] and that this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">choline</ENAMEX> is generated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 14</ENAMEX> ] . This pathway may
        become particularly important when extracellular
        circulating choline concentrations are low (e.g. during
        dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">choline deficiency</ENAMEX>) or when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> synthesis and
        release are accelerated by high neuronal activity, thus
        generating a high demand for choline [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
        In the present study, we used a cholinergic cell line,
        SN56 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] , which is derived from the fusion of septal
        neurons of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">postnatal day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">N18TG2</ENAMEX> murine
        neuroblastoma cells, as a model for cholinergic neurons, in
        order to determine the possible role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> in
        generating choline for ACh synthesis. We found that the
        cells express exclusively <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> and that downregulating PLD2
        expression reduces ACh synthesis, while overexpressing
        and/or stimulating PLD2 activity increases the synthesis of
        the neurotransmitter, indicating that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PLD2</NUMEX>-catalyzed
        hydrolysis of PC generates choline for ACh synthesis in
        cholinergic cells.
      
      
        Results
        PLD2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was present in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A) while PLD1
        message was undetectable either by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Northern blot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A)
        or RT-PCR (data not shown). Consistent with these results
        an <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 90 kDa</NUMEX> PLD2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was found in SN56
        cells by Western blot; however, no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PLD1 protein</ENAMEX> could be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detected</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B). Positive controls for these studies
        showed that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> were robust in
        detecting this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> isoform in rat brain (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). These
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> show that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> cells express exclusively <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> and thus
        experimental manipulations of the activity of this PLD
        isoform were subsequently employed to determine if this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enzyme</ENAMEX> is capable of producing choline for ACh synthesis in
        cholinergic cells. In order to reduce PLD2 activity in SN56
        cells, we sought to inhibit its expression. The cells were
        treated with a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25-mer</NUMEX> antisense oligonucleotide at
        different concentrations and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> mRNA levels were
        measured. Northern blot showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> mRNA expression
        was reduced by the antisense oligonucleotide in a
        concentration-dependent manner (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A), and that, at the
        maximally-effective concentration of the oligo (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 nM</NUMEX>),
        this inhibition reached <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B,C). In contrast, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">oligomer</ENAMEX> was inactive (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B,C). Consistent with
        these findings. Western blot showed that the antisense
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">oligomer</ENAMEX> decreased the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PLD2 protein</ENAMEX> level by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 28%</NUMEX>,
        whereas the control oligomer had no significant effect on
        PLD2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2D,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>). Given the fact that
        the transfection efficiency obtained in these experiments
        was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 30%</NUMEX> (as determined with fluorescent
        dye-labeled oligonucleotides; data not shown), the results
        indicate that, in cells that had taken up the antisense
        oligomer, the inhibition of PLD2 expression was
        complete.
        Treatment of a variety of cell types with phorbol esters
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 12 18 19</ENAMEX> ] . Thus we hypothesized that
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> cells would elevate
        intracellular concentrations of its product, choline, and
        result in increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> production. We tested the effects
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> on PLD activity and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACh</ENAMEX> content in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> cells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in a choline-free medium. Under these conditions
        the choline precursor used for the synthesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> is
        derived entirely from the intracellular pool, which
        includes the choline in PC [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 15</ENAMEX> ] . Consistent with
        previous studies, treatment of the cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> activated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PLD (Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A). The maximal effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX> fold
        increase in the amount of its product [
        3H]phosphatidylpropanol relative to controls) was observed
        after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 minutes</TIMEX> (data not shown), a time period employed
        in subsequent studies. Free choline accumulation was also
        significantly increased by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>. The magnitude of this
        effect tended to be small (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 15%</NUMEX>), presumably
        because free choline is a rapidly turning over metabolic
        intermediate that does not accumulate in cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3B).
        Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> stimulated ACh accumulation by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3C),
        in the cells. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increased both PLD activity
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACh</ENAMEX> content provided the initial evidence for a
        relationship between the endogenous PLD activity (i.e.
        PLD2) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> production. In control studies performed in
        the presence of choline (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 μM</NUMEX>) in the medium <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> had no
        effect on ACh levels (data not shown), indicating that it
        did not stimulate the process of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> synthesis but only the
        supply of choline.
        Next the effect of downregulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> activity on
        ACh levels was studied in cells transfected with either
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> or antisense oligomer and treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>. In the
        absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, the antisense <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">oligomer</ENAMEX> decreased PLD2
        activity by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX>. Although small, this change was
        statistically significant (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). In the presence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, antisense <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">oligomer</ENAMEX> decreased PLD2 activity by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A). Concomitantly the cellular choline content was
        decreased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> both in the presence and absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> by
        the antisense oligomer (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3B). Moreover, the antisense
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">oligomer</ENAMEX> decreased the cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACh</ENAMEX> content by
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 30%</NUMEX> compared to control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oligomer</ENAMEX> treated
        cells both in the presence and absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3C).
        These results indicate that downregulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> activity
        by antisense oligomers in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> cells decreases not only the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> activity but also the intracellular choline
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACh</ENAMEX> content. These results are consistent with the
        hypothesis that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> can generate choline for ACh synthesis
        in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> cells.
        To further confirm this hypothesis, we transiently
        transfected the cells with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> PLD2 expression plasmid.
        Overexpression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PLD2</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> in the cells caused a
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74%</NUMEX> increase of basal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> activity and this activity was
        further increased by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.2</NUMEX>-fold (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A). To examine
        the ACh synthesis and choline turnover in these PLD2
        transfectants, the cells and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were collected and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> and choline content were measured. In the absence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, overexpression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> alone increased intracellular
        ACh levels by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26%</NUMEX> and choline concentrations in the medium
        by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57%</NUMEX>. In the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, intracellular ACh levels
        and choline concentration in the medium rose further in the
        PLD2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">transfectants</ENAMEX> reaching values more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold
        higher than those in the control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B,C).
        Together with the data presented above, these results show
        that up-regulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> activity by overexpression
        and/or stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increases intracellular ACh
        levels.
        A recent immunohistochemical study of PLD1 expression in
        rat brain showed that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> isoform was expressed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurons</ENAMEX> in medial septum, cranial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motor nuclei</ENAMEX> and ventral
        spinal cord [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , all areas of the central nervous
        system enriched with cholinergic neurons. These data raised
        the possibility that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of cholinergic
        neurons may express PLD1 in addition to, or instead of,
        PLD2. Therefore we transfected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> cells with PLD1
        expression construct, in order to determine if choline
        generated by this enzyme could be used as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> precursor.
        Transfection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PLD1</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> resulted in increased
        PLD activity and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> synthesis in a fashion similar to that
        observed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> transfectants (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) indicating that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">choline</ENAMEX> generated by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD1</TIMEX> was converted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Discussion
        In the present study, we sought to establish which PLD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isoform</ENAMEX> is the endogenous enzyme that generates the choline
        precursor for ACh synthesis in cholinergic neurons using,
        as a model, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> basal forebrain cell line. We found
        that these cells expressed exclusively <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX>, a property
        that facilitated subsequent experiments. First, antisense
        oligonucleotides were used to down-regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">endogenous</ENAMEX> PLD2
        activity. Although <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 30%</NUMEX> of the cells took up the
        oligonucleotides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expression, and
        activity were reduced proportionally to the transfection
        efficiency of the antisense oligomer, demonstrating high
        efficacy of this technique in the transfected cells.
        Significantly, intracellular choline and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACh</ENAMEX> content were
        similarly decreased by the antisense oligonucleotides,
        indicating that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PLD2</NUMEX>-catalyzed hydrolysis of PC provides
        choline for ACh synthesis. Next, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> activity was
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up</NUMEX>-regulated by either overexpressing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> PLD2 protein
        and/or by stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>. Both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> overexpression
        and stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> increased PLD activity, choline
        production, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> accumulation. Moreover, PLD2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transfection</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PMA</ENAMEX> treatment had a synergistic effect on
        PLD activity and ACh levels.
        Our observation that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> but not PLD1 was present in
        SN56 cells raised the possibility that the former might be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preferentially</ENAMEX> expressed in cholinergic neurons. The data
        are consistent with the report that a variant of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PC12</NUMEX> cells
        also express exclusively PLD2 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] and this expression is
        stimulated by nerve growth factor [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] , a treatment
        known to upregulate the cholinergic phenotype of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PC12</NUMEX> cells
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22</NUMEX> ] . PLD2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> is abundant in many regions of the
        adult rodent central nervous system [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 23</ENAMEX> ] , including
        cerebellum, frontal cortex, hippocampus, hypothalamus,
        midbrain, brainstem, striatum, and spinal cord [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . The
        latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> regions are enriched with cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of
        cholinergic neurons. PLD1 is also highly expressed in brain
        tissue [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 23 25</ENAMEX> ] , notably in neurons in medial septum,
        cranial motor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nuclei</ENAMEX> and ventral spinal cord [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , all
        of which are likely cholinergic. However, no data are
        currently available on the possible coexpression of PLD1
        and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> and cholinergic markers (e.g. choline
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acetyltransferase</ENAMEX>) in vivo. Transfection of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PLD1</ENAMEX> into SN56
        cells resulted in increased PLD activity and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> production
        suggesting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD1</TIMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX>, could potentially be used
        to supply choline for ACh synthesis. Thus, while the
        catalytic activities of both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD1 and PLD2</TIMEX> appear to be
        equivalent in generating choline for ACh synthesis in
        transfected cells, it is possible that the modes of
        regulation of their activity might specify which one is
        expressed in a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of cholinergic neurons
        in vivo. It will be important to determine the mechanisms
        that control the expression of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> isoforms and
        their possible relationships with the mechanisms that
        regulate the cholinergic phenotype.
        Stimulation of PLD activity by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and the resulting
        increase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> synthesis from PLD-generated choline
        indicates that this pathway is regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>-responsive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> isozymes. In vivo, this form of regulation of ACh
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synthesis</ENAMEX> would be controlled by neurotransmitters released
        by neurons that innervate particular cholinergic cells.
        There are multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neurotransmitters</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are
        coupled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-dependent activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , and thus
        this mode of regulating the availability of choline for ACh
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synthesis</ENAMEX> is likely to be widespread. Significantly, among
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> subtypes of muscarinic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACh receptors</ENAMEX> (MAChRs), Ml
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">M3 receptors</ENAMEX> have been shown to efficiently activate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>) in various cell types [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27 28 29 30</NUMEX> ] ,
        whereas activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">M4 receptors</ENAMEX> is less
        robust [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . These observations suggest that in a
        cholinergic synapse, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> released into the synaptic cleft
        might stimulate PLD activity leading to a release of
        choline that could be used for ACh synthesis. Since these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAChRs</ENAMEX> may be present on the pre- and postsynaptic neurons
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] , this choline may be derived from PC residing in
        the membranes of either. However, while the
        presynaptically-derived choline released into the cytoplasm
        can be converted directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX>, the choline released by
        the postsynaptic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> must be initially taken up by the
        cholinergic nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX>. Our previous results in
        cholinergic human neuroblastoma <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA-N</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cells indicated that
        the choline moiety from PC breakdown was released directly
        into the cytoplasm [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] and a kinetic study using [
        3H]choline in BHK cells also showed that choline was
        initially released inside the cells by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>-activated PLD
        and then rapidly appeared in the medium [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . Consistent
        with the latter study, we also observed a rise in the
        medium choline levels in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> cells transfected with either
        PLD1 or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> and treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>.
        Although it is clear that the PLD-generated choline is
        efficiently utilized by cholinergic cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA-N-2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SN56</ENAMEX>)
        as a precursor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX>, the quantitative significance of
        this pathway and mechanisms that regulate it remain to be
        fully determined. Studies on a variety of preparations
        indicate that most of the choline used for ACh synthesis is
        derived from the extracellular space (reviewed in [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] )
        and therefore the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> pathway has to be considered as an
        accessory process. Interestingly, PLD activity is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upregulated</ENAMEX> in the hippocampus of rats whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
        consumed a choline-supplemented diet during pregnancy [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>
        ] . Given that prenatal choline <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">supplementation</ENAMEX> improves
        memory and attention [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cognitive functions that
        require the hippocampal cholinergic system, it is possible
        that the upregulated PLD pathway underlies, at least in
        part, the cognitive enhancement observed in the prenatally
        choline-supplemented <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abnormalities</ENAMEX> in the PLD-mediated release of choline
        would be expected to result in an impairment of cholinergic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurotransmission</ENAMEX> and/or in a generalized malfunction of
        cholinergic cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX>) is
        characterized by such a malfunction together with
        degeneration of basal forebrain cholinergic neurons, and it
        is thought that memory loss in this disease is partly
        caused by this cholinergic lesion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . In vitro studies
        point to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> novel mechanisms that might cause
        dysregulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> activity in AD. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is based on
        observations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> is inhibited by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">α-synuclein</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] ,
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of unknown function that accumulates in the
        amyloid deposits in AD brain. Normally α-synuclein is
        present in the synaptic nerve terminals (including those of
        cholinergic neurons [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37 38</NUMEX> ] ) but in AD its processing is
        altered, causing it to be abnormally deposited in plaques
        composed primarily of aggregates of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">β-amyloid peptide</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>
        ] . However, how this abnormal turnover of α-synuclein
        contributes to the pathophysiology of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX> remains to be
        determined. Recent in vitro observations that α-synuclein
        is phosphorylated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coupled receptor kinases</ENAMEX>,
        and that this phosphorylation relieves its inhibitory
        action on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">PLD2</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] , suggest a novel mechanism by which
        neurotransmitter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">muscarinic receptors</ENAMEX>)
        might modulate PLD2 activity. Since multiple receptor
        classes are affected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pathophysiological</ENAMEX> processes of
        AD [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] , abnormal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> of α-synuclein may
        contribute to both altered α-synuclein turnover and
        abnormal regulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> activity. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> set of
        observations indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROS</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">activate PLD2</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-dependent manner [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . There is
        much evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ROS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> is upregulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX>
        brain [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] . Thus, it is possible that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> may be
        activated in this <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> resulting, perhaps, in
        dysregulation of PC metabolism. Indeed evidence of an
        accelerated PC turnover has been repeatedly observed in
        post-mortem samples of AD brain [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44 45 46 47</NUMEX> ] as well
        as in an in vitro model of this disease characterized by
        the generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ROS</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] .
      
      
        Conclusions
        Most of the previous studies on the physiological
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">functions PLDs</ENAMEX> have concentrated on the role of its
        product, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Our data show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> has a dual
        function in cholinergic cells, as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> product of its
        activity, choline, is used as a metabolic precursor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX>,
        and suggest that this pathway may be regulated by the type
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isoform</ENAMEX> expressed in a particular class of
        cholinergic neurons. In our basal forebrain-derived SN56
        cells, this isoform is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX>. However, our observations that
        PLD1 overexpression increases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> production form
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> suggest that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD1</TIMEX> may serve the same
        function as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PLD2</ENAMEX> in other cholinergic cells. Moreover, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> showing that this pathway is stimulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>,
        suggest that it is subject to regulation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-activating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurotransmitters</ENAMEX>. The physiological, and possible
        pathophysiological significance in neurological diseases,
        of this pathway remains to be determined. It will also be
        important to determine how cholinergic cells regulate the
        metabolism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> - a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> with multiple signaling and
        structural functions - when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> pathway is stimulated
        to meet the demand for choline.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Materials
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium (DMEM), fetal
          bovine serum (FBS) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipofectamine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> reagents were
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco BRL Life Technologies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phosphatidylpropanol</ENAMEX> (PP) was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avanti Polar</ENAMEX> Lipids
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabaster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AL</ENAMEX>). Silica LK6 <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thin Layer</ENAMEX> Chromotography
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TLC</ENAMEX>) plates were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whatman</ENAMEX>. [ 3H]Myristic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[α- 32P</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dCTP</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dupont-NEN</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Molecular</ENAMEX>
          biology reagents (except as noted) were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) and phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-myristate 13</NUMEX>-acetate was from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calbiochem</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA). Polyclonal anti-human PLD2-
          and anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PLD1 antibodies</ENAMEX> were kindly provided by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoshinori Nozawa</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gifu International Institute of</ENAMEX>
          Biotechnology, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Cell culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse septal neuron x neuroblastoma</ENAMEX> hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SN56</ENAMEX> cells
          were maintained at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37°C</NUMEX> in an atmosphere of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> air, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was changed every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-3 days</TIMEX>. Cells of passage
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 to 40</TIMEX> were used.
        
        
          Transient transfection with plasmids or antisense
          oligonucleotides
          The pCGN expression vector containing the cDNAs of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> PLD2 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">mPLD2</NUMEX>) or human PLD1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hPLD1</NUMEX>) driven by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> were described previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . An
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">influenza-epitope</ENAMEX> (hemagglutinin-tag) is inserted in the
          pCGN vector and is expressed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus</ENAMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLDs</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SN56</NUMEX> cells were grown to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50-70%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confluence</ENAMEX>, then transiently transfected with these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmids</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipofectamine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> reagent according to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions. The cells were assayed
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> after transfection. Additional cultures were
          transfected with a β-galactosidase expression plasmid and
          were stained on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the experiment (using staining
          kit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) to estimate transfection efficiency.
          The overall transfection efficiency was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10-15%</NUMEX>.
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> PLD2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antisense</ENAMEX> oligonucleotide was purchased
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sequitur, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Natick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>). The sequence of the
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mPLD2</NUMEX> oligonucleotide was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAUGUGCAACUGGCUGGAGUUCAGA-3</ENAMEX>' and corresponded to the
          sequence of mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PLD2 cDNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneBank</ENAMEX> accession number
          U87557) starting at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX>. A reversed control
          oligonucleotide was also used and its sequence was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AGACUUGAGGUCGGUCAACGUGUAC-3</ENAMEX>'. SN56 cells were grown to
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50-60%</NUMEX> confluence and washed once with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opti-MEM</ENAMEX> (Gibco
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRL</ENAMEX>). The oligonucleotides were diluted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> μl
          Opti-MEM to various concentrations, mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 μl</NUMEX> of
          Opti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 μl</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipofectamine</ENAMEX> and incubated
          at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> temperature for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>. The mixture was then
          added to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">800 μl</NUMEX> of serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> and the cells were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in this medium for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX> and then
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cultured</ENAMEX> in normal growth medium for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> before
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fluorescent-dye</ENAMEX> labeled oligonucleotide was also
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sequitur Inc.</ENAMEX> and used as a control to
          monitor transfection efficiency. The transfection
          efficiency was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 30-40%</NUMEX>.
        
        
          Northern blot analysis
          Northern blot analysis was carried out essentially as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] using <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 μg</NUMEX> of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> per
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lane</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde-agarose gel</ENAMEX> containing ethidium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bromide</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was size-fractionated by electrophoresis
          and transferred to a nylon membrane (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HyBond, Amersham</ENAMEX>).
          The PLD probes were: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">PLD1 661</ENAMEX> bp human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PLD1</ENAMEX> cDNA fragment
          (GenBank accession number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U38545</TIMEX>, pos. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">951-1611</ENAMEX>) isolated
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HeLa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> cDNA by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> accession
          number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">U87557</NUMEX>) excised from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pCGN-mPLD2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plasmid</ENAMEX> using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endonuclease Xbal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3000 bp</ENAMEX>). DNA probes were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">labeled with [α- 32P</ENAMEX>]dCTP with the random primer labeling
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia Biotech Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prehybridization</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization</ENAMEX> steps were carried out at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">65°C</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapid</ENAMEX>-Hyb
          solution according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions. The
          blots were washed and exposed to an x-ray film (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BioMax MS-2</ENAMEX> film, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) with an intensifying screen at
          -80°C for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signal</ENAMEX> intensities were quantified with
          ImageQuant software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Image</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.62</NUMEX>. Following <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Northern</ENAMEX> hybridization with these probes,
          the blots were stripped and re-probed with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> G3PDH
          probe for normalization purposes. For these experiments
          the results are expressed as units of band intensity
          normalized with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G3PDH</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Western blotting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX> isoforms
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein lysates</ENAMEX> from whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> and tissues were
          prepared with a buffer, which contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">v/v</ENAMEX>) Nonidet P40 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NP40</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-aminoethyl</ENAMEX>)benzenesulphonyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 μg/ml</ENAMEX>
          leupeptin, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 μg/ml</ENAMEX> aprotinin and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 μg/</ENAMEX>ml pepstatin.
          Lysates were mixed vigorously, incubated on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> and cleared by brief centrifugation. The
          extracts, normalized for total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> content, were
          separated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS/PAGE</ENAMEX> and transferred to a polyvinylidene
          difluoride membrane (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immobilon-P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millipore Corp.</ENAMEX>). The
          membrane was blocked with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> non-fat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> in
          Tris-buffered saline containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.15%</NUMEX> Tween-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>. The
          polyclonal anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PLD2 antibody</ENAMEX> and anti-mouse PLD1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> were used to detect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PLD2 and PLD1</TIMEX>, respectively.
          The membrane was then incubated with anti-rabbit IgG
          peroxidase conjugates, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were visualized using
          the chemiluminescence method (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luminol</ENAMEX> reagent, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>
          Biotechnology) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BioMax</ENAMEX> light film (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisher</ENAMEX>
          Scientific). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blots</ENAMEX> were stripped by incubating them
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing Tris-HCl <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62.5</NUMEX>
          mM, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.7</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM β-mercaptoethanol, and then
          probed with anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">actin antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) for normalization purposes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signal</ENAMEX> intensities of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein bands</ENAMEX> were quantified with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> Image <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.62</NUMEX>.
          Approximate molecular weights were estimated using
          prestained standards (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          In vivo assay of PLD activity
          For 
          in vivo assay, the cells were grown
          to subconfluence and prelabeled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 μCi/ml</ENAMEX> [
          3H]<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">myristic acid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> FBS <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>.
          Labeled cells were incubated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml HEPES-buffered
          saline <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBS</ENAMEX>, composition in mM: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">145</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>; MgSO 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 , 1</TIMEX>; CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>; pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.4</NUMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> min twice to wash out the
          unincorporated label. The labeled cells were then
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in the presence or absence of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX> 1-propanol
          with or without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM PMA at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> min. The
          reaction was terminated by adding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX> and
          the lipids were extracted in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">methanol/chloroform/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1:1 v/v</ENAMEX>). The lipids were
          dried and separated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TLC</ENAMEX> in a mobile phase, composed of
          the upper phase of a mixture of ethyl
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">acetate/isooctane/acetic acid/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">130:20:30:</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 v/v</ENAMEX>),
          and the phospholipids were visualized with
          l<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">,6-diphenyl-l,3,5,-hexatriene</NUMEX> in hexane. The spots
          comigrating with the appropriate phospholipid standards
          were scraped off and their radioactivity was measured by
          liquid scintillation spectrophotometry and expressed as a
          percentage of the radioactivity present in the total
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lipids</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Acetylcholine measurements
          The cells were preincubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> in a
          choline-free physiological <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt solution</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>)
          consisting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.75</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>. The
          cells were then incubated in the same buffer supplemented
          with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 μM</NUMEX> neostigmine (to inhibit acetylcholinesterase)
          with or without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 minutes</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were
          collected for subsequent assays of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> and choline. The
          cells were scraped into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX> and this mixture
          transferred to a tube containing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100 μl 1 M</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formic acid</ENAMEX>,
          vortex mixed and centrifuged. The pellet was collected
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein assay</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACh</ENAMEX> was extracted by mixing the
          supernatant fluid with chloroform and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:2:1 v/v</ENAMEX>).
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were vortex mixed and centrifuged for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000</NUMEX> rpm. The aqueous phase (containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACh</ENAMEX>)
          was collected and dried under a vacuum. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACh</ENAMEX> content was
          an enzymatic reactor containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acetylcholinesterase</ENAMEX> and
          choline oxidase and an electrochemical detector using a
          commercial kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bioanalytical Systems, Inc.</ENAMEX>) based on the
          method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potter et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] as described previously [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ] . Protein concentration was determined by the method
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> presented in the figures were derived from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-9
          independent experiments and were analyzed using Systat
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5.2.1</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPSS Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill</ENAMEX>) by t-test or analysis of
          variance as appropriate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tukey</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisher LSD</ENAMEX> were used
          for post hoc tests. Differences were considered to be
          significant at p < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>.
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        1ACh, acetylcholine; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARF</ENAMEX>, ADP-ribosylation factor; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAG</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diacylglycerol</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G3PDH</TIMEX>, glyceraldehyde <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-phosphate</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dehydrogenase; MAChR</ENAMEX>, muscarinic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acetylcholine receptor</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphatidic acid</ENAMEX>; PC, phosphatidylcholine; PIP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-bisphosphate; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase C; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLD</ENAMEX>, phospholipase
        D; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-myristate 13</NUMEX>-acetate; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphatidylpropanol; ROS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TLC</ENAMEX>,
        thin layer chromatography.
      
    
  
