
  
    
      
        Background
        Due to the current unavailability of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX>,
        other preventive methods have to be developed to control
        the ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS pandemic</ENAMEX>. This includes the design and
        application of safe and effective topical microbicides.
        Screening of pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">excipients</ENAMEX> revealed that
        cellulose acetate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phthalate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAP</ENAMEX>), commonly used for
        enteric coating of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tablets</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">capsules</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] , has
        anti-HIV-1 activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> in micronized form and formulated
        into a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX>, is a broad spectrum microbicide inactivating
        several sexually transmitted <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> (STD) pathogens [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ] , including HIV-1 [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 5</NUMEX> ] . It was of interest to
        explore the mechanism(s) whereby CAP causes inactivation of
        HIV-1. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> has a relatively high molecular weight (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX> ~ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60,000</NUMEX>; [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] ), its effect on HIV-1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">virions</ENAMEX> would be expected to be confined to the virus
        surface, i.e. to the envelope glycoproteins <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> and/or
        gp41. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> would be expected to affect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more
        steps required for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">HIV-1</NUMEX> entry into cells, i.e. binding to
        cellular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD4</TIMEX>, to the major <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HIV-1 coreceptors CXCR4</ENAMEX> or CCR5
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">X4 and R5</TIMEX> viruses [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] , respectively, and fusion with
        cell membranes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15</NUMEX> ] . Results
        presented here show that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAP pretreated HIV-1</ENAMEX> has a reduced
        capacity to bind to the coreceptors leading to impaired
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus infectivity</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Reagents
          The following monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (mAbs; the source
          is indicated in parentheses) were used: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2F5</ENAMEX> and 588D
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drs. T. Muster and S. Zola-Pazner</ENAMEX>, respectively); <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9305</TIMEX>
          and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9284</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEN Research Products</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Du Pont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>);
          b12, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2G12 and 17b</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIDS Research and Reference</ENAMEX> Reagent
          Program, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>; courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drs. D. Burton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katinger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.E. Robinson</ENAMEX>, respectively) and anti-p24
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ImmunoDiagnostics, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woburn, MA</ENAMEX>). Rabbit antibodies
          against peptides from HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120/gp41</ENAMEX> and against
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">V3</NUMEX> loop of HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX> (anti-V3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX>) were prepared as
          described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiserum</ENAMEX> to phthalate was prepared by
          immunization of rabbits with phthalic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anhydride</ENAMEX> treated
          rabbit serum albumin [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . Recombinant soluble CD4
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">sCD4</NUMEX>) was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genentech Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South San Francisco</ENAMEX>, CA.
          Recombinant HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biotinylated</ENAMEX> gp120
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biotinylated sCD4</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ImmunoDiagnostics Inc.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protein A</ENAMEX>, the protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors phenylmethyl</ENAMEX>-sulfonyl
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fluoride</ENAMEX>, leupeptin and pepstatin, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,3</NUMEX>-bis
          [<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-methoxy-4-nitro-5-sulfophenyl</NUMEX>]-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2H</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tetrazolium</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-carboxanilide
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XTT</ENAMEX>) were all from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO. Pelletted</ENAMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>-fold concentrates of HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.8</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 10virus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">particles/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BaL</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.8</NUMEX> Ã— <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 10virus particles/ml</ENAMEX>)
          were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Biotechnologies Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MD.</ENAMEX>
          Chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serum</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OEM Concepts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toms River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>.
          Horseradish peroxidase (HRP)- and phycoerythrin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>)-labeled streptavidin were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amersham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL and R & D Systems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>,
          respectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX> was quantitated using a kit from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkegaard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Laboratories Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MD.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enzyme</ENAMEX> linked immunoassays (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>) kits for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">HIV-1</NUMEX> p24
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> and for the Î²-gal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were from Coulter
          Immunology, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hialeah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime â†’ 3 Prime Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO. CAP</ENAMEX> was a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingsport</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>.
          H9 cells chronically infected with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX>,
          HeLa-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>-LTR-Î²-gal cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GHOST CXCR4</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CCR5</NUMEX> cells and
          PM1 cells were obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AIDS Research</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reference Reagent Program</ENAMEX> contributed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drs. R. Gallo</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Emerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Littman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. Lusso and M. Reitz</ENAMEX>,
          respectively. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centricon</ENAMEX> centrifugal ultrafiltration
          devices were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amicon/Millipore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Measurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HIV-1</ENAMEX> infectivity
          Serial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold dilutions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAP</ENAMEX> treated and untreated
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> (undiluted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/512</NUMEX>) in RPMI-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1640</NUMEX> medium
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum (FBS) were mixed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MT-2 cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 4cells/well) and placed into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well
          polystyrene plates. The mixtures were incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> and the volume was adjusted with RPMI-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1640</NUMEX> medium
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î¼l</NUMEX>. On the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> thand <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> thday
          after incubation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of culture supernatants
          were removed from each well and equal volumes of fresh
          medium were added. On the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> thday, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XTT</ENAMEX> dye (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mg/ml</ENAMEX>) was
          added to the cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intracellular</ENAMEX> formazan was determined
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectrophotometrically</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19</NUMEX> ] . Similar experiments
          were done with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX>, except that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PM1</NUMEX> cells were used
          instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MT-2 cells</ENAMEX>, and virus production was measured
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p24 antigen</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> after infection. The
          percentage of residual infectivity after CAP treatment
          was calculated from calibration curves relating
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">absorbance</ENAMEX> (corresponding to formazan for HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> and
          p24 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> for HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX>, respectively) to virus
          dilutions of untreated viruses. The results were plotted
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
        
        
          Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>)
          For virus capture assays, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well polystyrene
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immulon II; Dynatech Laboratories Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chantilly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>) were coated either with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sCD4</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/well</ENAMEX>)
          or with monoclonal or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polyclonal antibodies</ENAMEX>. For coating
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were first coated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> A
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/well</ENAMEX>) in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M Tris</ENAMEX> buffer, pH <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.8</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at 20Â°C
          followed by either mAbs (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/well</ENAMEX>) or rabbit antisera
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">diluted 1:100</ENAMEX> in phosphate buffered saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20Â°C</TIMEX>. Subsequently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed and
          postcoated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20Â°C</NUMEX> with bovine serum albumin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>) and gelatin (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M NaCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
          Tris, pH 7.0 [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX>]). Chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serum</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ch-PBS</ENAMEX>)
          was used instead in experiments with HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX>. The wells
          were washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX> and stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. HIV-1 virus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">particles</ENAMEX> suspended in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> were added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. Subsequently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Ã—</NUMEX> with
          ice cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:50</TIMEX> anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p24</NUMEX> mAb in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ch</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> for HIV-1
          BaL, and then treated with lysis buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> Nonidet P40
          [NP40], <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml BSA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. The
          supernatants were removed and tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p24 antigen</ENAMEX>
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ELISA kits</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coulter Immunology</ENAMEX> and following
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s protocol. In other experiments, wells
          were coated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> mM sodium acetate,
          pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX> and postcoated as described above.
          To detect binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> to CAP treated and control
          gp120, wells coated with graded amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp120</ENAMEX> and
          postcoated as described above were reacted with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biotinylated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sCD4</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/well</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> h at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX> and the bound
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biotinylated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD4</ENAMEX> was determined after adding
          HRP-streptavidin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gelatine</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> Tween 20 for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. The wells
          were washed and bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRP</ENAMEX> was detected using the test kit
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkegaard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX> and the absorbance read at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nm</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Flow cytometry
          To determine the binding of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gp120-biotinylated</NUMEX> CD4
          complexes to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">HIV-1</NUMEX> coreceptor expressing cells, CAP
          treated and untreated gp120 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼g</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biotinylated</ENAMEX> CD4
          (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼g</NUMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> were mixed
          for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 h at 20Â°C</NUMEX> and then added to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 6MT-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cells in
          RPMI-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1640</NUMEX> medium containing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotinylated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD4-gp120</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> were not added to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> cells. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at room temperature, the
          cells were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, and PE-streptavidin (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.1 Î¼g</NUMEX>) was added. After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20Â°C</TIMEX>, cells were washed and fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. Flow cytometry analysis was
          performed in a FACSCalibur flow cytometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson Immunocytometric Systems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA).
          Similar experiments were done with peripheral blood
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphocytes</ENAMEX> (PBL) isolated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isopaque</ENAMEX>-Ficoll
          technique [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Quantitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAP-gp120</ENAMEX> binding
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty Î</NUMEX>¼g of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> were mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 Î¼g</NUMEX> of CAP in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 M NaCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX> and incubated at 20Â°C
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min. The mixtures were transferred into a
          Centricon centrifugal ultrafiltration device with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX> cut-off of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> and centrifuged
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,500</NUMEX> Ã— g for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min. The filtrates were transferred
          to a similar device with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX> cut-off of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> and centrifuged
          under the same conditions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> retained on top of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filter</ENAMEX> was quantitated as a complex with ruthenium red [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> ] . The retentate on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX> cut-off filter was dissolved in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 M</ENAMEX> guanidinium hydrochloride and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> released from
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAP-gp120</ENAMEX> complex and retained on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX> cut-off filter was quantitated by
          the same method.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Modeling</ENAMEX>
          A cellulose chain consisting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> cellotetraose unit
          (composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four 1,4</NUMEX>-linked Î²-D-glucose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>) was
          created in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quanta</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of the hydroxyl groups
          at positions <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>- and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>- were modified to acetyl ester and
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of the hydroxyl <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> were modified to
          phthaloyl ester [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1 23</ENAMEX> ] . The acetylated and
          phthaloylated cellotetraose structure (CTAP) was
          minimized by the steepest descent method followed by the
          adopted basis <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton-Raphson</ENAMEX> (ABNR) method. The energy
          change of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> Kcal/mol between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> successive structures
          was used as the termination criterion in both the
          steps.
          The crystal structure of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1gcl</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] was
          retrieved from the pdb ( <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rcsb</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>) and the V3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loop</ENAMEX>, created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homology</ENAMEX> modeling {(based on the nmr
          structure of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">V3</NUMEX> loop from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1ce4</TIMEX>) using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWISS</ENAMEX>-MODEL
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] automated comparative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> modeling server (
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expasy</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ch/SWISS</ENAMEX>-MODEL.html} was attached to
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp120</NUMEX> crystal structure using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quanta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> design
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">module</ENAMEX>.
          The docking simulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> onto the entire gp120
          protein surface was performed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dockvision</ENAMEX> program [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ] . A grid box (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">125 Ã… Ã— 125 Ã… Ã— 125 Ã…</ENAMEX>) with grid
          stepsize of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> Ã… was created to cover the entire protein
          surface with enough area for the ligand to dock. The
          default forcefield (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Potential Function</ENAMEX>) was used
          to perform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monte Carlo</ENAMEX> runs for the docking. Both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligand</ENAMEX> and the target <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were kept rigid.
          Intermolecular energy criteria were used to identify the
          best possible dockings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Impaired infectivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAP</ENAMEX> treated HIV-1
          Results of earlier studies indicated that HIV-1
          infection of cells is inhibited in the presence of CAP
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 to 10</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml for HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">i.e. < 200 nM</ENAMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . However, the mechanism involved
          in the inhibitory activity and the possibility of virus
          inactivation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> have not been explored. Results shown
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1indicate that CAP in a dose dependent manner
          rapidly inactivates at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX>, an X4 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> and
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX>, an R5 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>, the latter appearing relatively
          more resistant.
        
        
          CAP retention on the surface of treated HIV-1
          particles
          Evidence for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAP-HIV-1</ENAMEX> binding was obtained from
          results of solid phase immunoassays in which attachment
          of HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">BaL virus particles</ENAMEX>, respectively
          (detected by subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">ELISA</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p24 antigen</ENAMEX> released
          from virus particles by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX> treatment) to wells
          precoated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> was measured (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A). CAP treated
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX> viruses, unlike control viruses, bound
          to wells coated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against phthalate (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2B). These results indicate that treated HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">particles</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">utilizing</ENAMEX> either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CXCR4</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> as coreceptors, retain CAP
          on their surface and suggest that this is responsible for
          the altered properties and impaired infectivity of the
          treated viruses.
        
        
          Identification of CAP binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> on HIV-1
          envelope glycoproteins
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attachment sites</ENAMEX> on the surface of HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> were determined from binding of control and CAP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">treated HIV-1</ENAMEX>, respectively, to distinct ligands (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The quantities of control virus and treated virus in
          these experiments were identical, as determined from the
          content of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p24 antigen</ENAMEX> in preparations of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">detergent</ENAMEX>-disrupted virus particles. CAP binding to HIV-1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> particles most profoundly affected their binding to
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">V3</NUMEX> loop specific mAbs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9284</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9305</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] and
          to the coreceptor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR4</TIMEX>, while binding to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sCD4</NUMEX>; to virus
          neutralizing mAbs specific for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD4</TIMEX> binding site on
          gp120, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">b12</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">588D</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] ; to mAb <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17b</NUMEX> specific
          for a discontinuous conserved epitope proximal to the
          binding site for both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD4</ENAMEX> and anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> binding site
          antibodies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] ; to mAb <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2G12</NUMEX> specific for an epitope
          centered around the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">C3/V4</ENAMEX> domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp120</ENAMEX> also involving
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-linked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">glycans</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] and to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">gp41</NUMEX> specific mAb 2F5
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] was less affected. In order to determine whether
          R5 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viruses</ENAMEX> are similarly affected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, the binding of
          HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of this virus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to
          anti-V3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX>, respectively, before and after CAP
          treatment was studied. The results shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3indicate that the CAP-treated HIV-1 BaL bound to these
          ligands much less than did untreated virus.
          The binding of control and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>-treated HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX> to
          antibodies against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX> derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120/gp41</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
          ] was also determined. In agreement with the results
          obtained using mAbs, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CAP</ENAMEX> treatment resulted in most
          pronounced decreases of virus binding to antibodies
          against peptide <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>-338 (= V3 loop) and the adjacent

          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">peptide 280-306</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Pretreatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CAP impairs</ENAMEX> gp120 binding to
          coreceptors
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> reported so far suggest that the lethal hit to
          HIV-1 caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CAP</ENAMEX> treatment involves the coreceptor
          binding site on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX>. To further support this
          conclusion, the binding of labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">gp120-CD4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coreceptor</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12 33</NUMEX> ] expressing cells was studied.
          First, it was determined from quantitative binding
          studies using CAP staining with ruthenium red [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] that
          pretreatment with CAP resulted in binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.90</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.13</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CAP molecules/gp120</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX>. The binding appeared augmented
          by ~ <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M NaCl</ENAMEX>. The binding capacity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp120</ENAMEX> for
          sCD4 was preserved after CAP treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). On the
          other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120-sCD4</ENAMEX> complexes containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAP</ENAMEX> treated
          gp120 bound to coreceptor expressing cells to a much
          lesser extent than similar complexes containing untreated
          gp120 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Negatively charged <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfated polymers</ENAMEX> were reported to
        have anti-HIV-1 activity and are being considered for
        development as topical microbicides. They include: dextran
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sulfate</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX> ] , carrageenans [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36</NUMEX> ] ,
        dextrin-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-sulfate [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37 38</NUMEX> ] , cellulose sulfate [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] and
        naphthalene sulfonate polymer (PRO <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>; [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] ). Except
        for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dextrin-2-sulfate</TIMEX> and PRO <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, which appear to have
        anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">HIV-1</NUMEX> inhibitory activities similar to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>,
        the other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfonated polymers</ENAMEX> are less inhibitory [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> ] . HIV-1 may develop resistance to the inhibitory
        effect of dextran sulfate and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">viruses</ENAMEX> were reported not
        to be inhibited by this polymer [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 43</NUMEX> ] . Dextran sulfate
        was shown to bind to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gp120</NUMEX> and to interfere with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gp120/CXCR4</ENAMEX> interactions but it did not bind to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gp120</NUMEX> of R5
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">viruses</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> in micronized form, providing an acidic environment,
        causes disintegration of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> leading to loss of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infectivity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>). Here we have shown that CAP directly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inactivates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HIV-1</ENAMEX> at neutral pH since treated virus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">particles</ENAMEX> after removal of excess CAP had reduced or no
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infectivity</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), in agreement with recent observations
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44 45</NUMEX> ] . Virus inactivation can be attributed to strong
        binding of CAP to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX>, preventing the access to virus
        particles predominantly of antibodies against the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp120</NUMEX> V3
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loop</ENAMEX>, known to be involved in coreceptor binding and
        specificity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 46 47 48 49</NUMEX> ] , and to epitopes located
        adjacent to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">V3</NUMEX> loop (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Indeed, CAP binding to
        HIV-1 resulted in blockade of sites involved in coreceptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). This was observed for both HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIB</ENAMEX>, an
        X4 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>, and HIV-1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaL</ENAMEX>, an R5 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>. In agreement with
        this finding, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAP</ENAMEX> inhibited infection by both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">X4</ENAMEX> and R5
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">viruses</ENAMEX> in 
        in vitro models for vaginal HIV-1
        infection [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45 50</NUMEX> ] . Sites on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the HIV-1</TIMEX> envelope other
        than the coreceptor binding domains may possibly be also
        involved in interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, contributing to
        inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> infection.
        Studies with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> allowed to determine the
        stoichiometry of the reaction between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>,
        resulting in the observation that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately one</NUMEX> CAP
        molecule binds to one molecule of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX>. Interestingly,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAP-gp120</ENAMEX> binding also occurs in 1M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX>, conditions under
        which binding of sulfated polysaccharides to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gp120</ENAMEX> is
        abolished [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] . This suggests that electrostatic
        interactions do not play an exclusive role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CAP</ENAMEX>-gp120
        binding [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> ] .
        Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> has an approximate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 4and its structure has not
        been determined, a model for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">CAP docking</ENAMEX> onto gp120 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">HXBc2</NUMEX>)
        was generated using a chemically modified cellotetraose.
        The entire <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp120</NUMEX> surface was considered for docking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acetylated</ENAMEX> and phthaloylated cellotetraose (CTAP) except
        the trimerization and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD4</ENAMEX> binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">gp120</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] .
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> optimally docked <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CTAP</ENAMEX> molecules were selected for
        further analyses. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (marked as 
        Dock1 in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) docked near regions
        corresponding to amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid residues</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">361-392</ENAMEX> (indicated in
        red) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">386-417</ENAMEX> (indicated in purple). The orientation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CTAP</ENAMEX> revealed that if extended to generate the larger CAP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">molecule</ENAMEX>, blockade of the coreceptor binding site
        (indicated in gray in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the V3</TIMEX> loop
        (indicated in yellow in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) would result. These docking
        results agree with the observation that capture of CAP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">treated HIV-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">virions</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against peptides from
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">303-338, 361-392, 386-417</ENAMEX>) was decreased
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> interacts primarily through several hydrogen
        bonds with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp120 residues K362</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">N386</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Q389</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">N392 and T394</TIMEX>.
        Though there were no hydrophobic or electrostatic
        interactions discernable, such interactions cannot be ruled
        out as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> represents only a small part of the CAP
        molecule. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> best docking positioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> near the
        V3 loop (marked as 
        Dock2 in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> in this
        position interacts with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gp120</TIMEX> through both hydrogen bonding
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues R311</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R315</ENAMEX>) and hydrophobic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">F317</NUMEX>) with
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> CH 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>- units of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX>. The interacting
        region is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGPGRAF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> neutralizing domain
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PND</ENAMEX>) of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">V3</NUMEX> loop [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] . Both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">R311</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">R315 residues</ENAMEX>
        are also in close proximity to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of the CTAP
        phthalic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid moiety</ENAMEX> and may take part in electrostatic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interactions</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTAP</ENAMEX> is only a partial
        representation of the CAP molecule, the docking simulations
        agree with the experimental results.
        Results presented earlier [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] combined with those
        presented here suggest that CAP acts on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> by several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mechanisms</ENAMEX>, depending on pH and the physical form and
        concentration of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>. The direct virus
        inactivating effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, the multiple mechanisms
        involved in prevention of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> infection, the broad
        spectrum activity against several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STD</ENAMEX> pathogens, the
        established safety record, low cost and availability in
        large scale suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> has advantages over other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polymeric substances</ENAMEX> considered as topical (vaginal)
        microbicides for prevention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STDs</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Cellulose acetate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phthalate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAP</ENAMEX>) is a pharmaceutical
        excipient which has been used for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over four decades</TIMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enteric</ENAMEX> film coating of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tablets</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">capsules</ENAMEX>. It is
        inexpensive and generally regarded as a nontoxic material
        free of adverse effects. As such, it is included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration Inactive Ingredients Guide</ENAMEX>.
        Our earlier studies indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAP</ENAMEX> inhibited infection
        by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> and several herpes viruses in vitro. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> was
        effective in blocking vaginal transmission of these viruses
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> model systems. The underlying molecular
        machanisms for these inhibitory effects remained to be
        established. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> presented here show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> remains
        bound to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX> after removal of unreacted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">impairing</ENAMEX> virus infectivity due to blockade of binding
        sites for cellular coreceptors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR4 and CCR5</TIMEX>. The
        industrial availability, history of safe use and mechanism
        of anti-HIV-1 activity (i.e. virus inactivation rather than
        reversible inhibition) suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX> is an ideal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> compound for a vaginal microbicide expected to
        prevent sexual transmission of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX>.
      
      
        List of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbreviations</ENAMEX> used
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CAP</ENAMEX>, cellulose acetate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phthalate</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STD</ENAMEX>, sexually
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">transmitted disease</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX>, enzyme-linked immunosorbent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX>; mAbs, monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>, fetal bovine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum; PEG</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polyethylene</ENAMEX> glycol <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HIV-1</TIMEX>, human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immunodeficiency</ENAMEX> virus type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIV</ENAMEX>, simian immunodeficiency
        virus; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HSV-1</TIMEX>, herpesvirus type <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSV-2</ENAMEX>, herpesvirus type
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, bovine serum albumin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, phosphate buffered
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saline; HRP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> radish peroxidase; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sCD4</TIMEX>, soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD4</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBL</ENAMEX>, peripheral blood
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphocytes; CTAP</ENAMEX>, cellotetraose acetate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phthalate</ENAMEX>; pdb.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protein Data Bank</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Competing Interests</ENAMEX>
        None declared
      
    
  
