
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Respiratory syncytial</ENAMEX> virus (RSV) belongs to the
        Pneumovirinae subfamily of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paramyxovirodae</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of
        enveloped single-stranded negative sense <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA viruses</ENAMEX>. RSV
        infection of the lower respiratory tract cells results in
        cell death and sloughing into the lumen of the respiratory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> is the leading cause of infant
        mortality from respiratory infections and is so highly
        contagious that by age <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nearly all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have been
        infected. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> infection in infancy cause severe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bronchiolitis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX> and may predispose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to
        the subsequent development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>, the most common
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chronic illness</ENAMEX> of childhood [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Many studies have
        indicated that chemokines can play an important role in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">onset</ENAMEX> and severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> and it has been shown that RSV
        infection of lung epithelial cells increases chemokine
        production, although the mechanisms involved are largely
        unknown [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5</NUMEX> ] .
        The chemotactic cytokines, or chemokines, compose a
        large superfamily of small structurally related
        polypeptides that play important roles in host defense by
        recruiting specific subsets of leukocytes to sites of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inflammation</ENAMEX> and injury [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . Chemokines have been
        conditions, including <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>, inflammatory bowel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, and adult respiratory distress syndrome [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9</NUMEX> ]
        . The chemokine superfamily can be divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> based on the position of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-conserved cysteine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> at the amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">terminus</ENAMEX>,
        which are either adjacent (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> subfamily) or separated by
        one amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (CXC subfamily). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokines such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> were originally identified as potent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">activators</ENAMEX> and
        chemoattractants for neutrophils, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> chemokines
        such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> mostly attract monocytes and
        eosinophils respectively [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . Chemokines are secreted
        in a stimulus-and cell type-specific manner [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12 13 14</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17</NUMEX> ] and are regulated primarily at the level of gene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20 21 22 23 24</NUMEX> ] . The
        transcriptional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCP-1</ENAMEX> contain
        binding sites for the redox-responsive transcription factor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX>, which has been shown to be important for their
        regulation by viral infections and cytokines [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 20 23 25</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34</NUMEX> ] .
        We previously demonstrated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokines IL-8</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> are differentially regulated in A549
        airway epithelial cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36 37 38</NUMEX> ] . To further
        elucidate the mechanisms of chemokine expression in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A549</TIMEX>,
        we have compared the induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> infection with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>. Our findings suggest that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> induction of chemokine gene expression involves a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redox-sensitive NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB signaling mechanism that differs from
        that mediated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and involving predominantly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX>
        subunit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-ÎºB.</ENAMEX>
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Materials
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco's Modified Eagle Medium</ENAMEX> (DMEM), fetal bovine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX> (FBS), <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Dulbecco's phosphate buffered saline</ENAMEX> (DPBS),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">antibiotic/antimycotic</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> trypsin<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/EDTA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks Balanced</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Solution</ENAMEX> (HBSS) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIZOL</ENAMEX> were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen Gibco Cell Culture</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-acetyl-L</ENAMEX>-cysteine, dexamethasone, glycerol and MTT
          tetrazolium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX> systems (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> kits were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX> Endogen
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>). Human CK5 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RiboQuant</ENAMEX> ribonuclease
          protection assay kit was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD</ENAMEX> Pharmingen
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[Î±- 32P</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">250 Î¼Ci</ENAMEX>) was obtained from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer Life Sciences</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>). Gel shift assay
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promega</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>). [Î³-
          32P]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 Î¼Ci</ENAMEX>) was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICN</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Mesa</ENAMEX>, CA).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Antibodies</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> line and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> Long strain
          were obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture Collection</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Virus stock growth and maintenance
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX>, Long strain, was grown on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEp-2</ENAMEX>, a human tracheal
          epithelial cell line. Cells were grown to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> confluence
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> antibiotic/antimycotic.
          After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> washes with 1X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPBS</ENAMEX>, a minimal volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX>,
          at a multiplicity of infection (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOI</ENAMEX>) of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> or greater,
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> was added. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> and
          cells were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>, after which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> was
          added to bring culture to normal growth volume and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>. Cultures were then incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX>. All
          plates were scraped and contents were transferred to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          ml conical tubes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>/cell cocktail was vortexed
          briefly and large debris was removed in a tabletop
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centrifuge</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> was purified by ultracentrifugation
          through <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> glycerol in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX>. RSV stocks were resuspended
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HBSS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> bovine serum albumin and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM
          magnesium sulfate and frozen at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-70Â°</NUMEX> C.
        
        
          Cell culture, infection and treatments
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> human <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II lung carcinoma</ENAMEX> cell line was
          grown and maintained in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">antibiotic/antimycotic.</ENAMEX> For treatment, cells were grown
          to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 75%</NUMEX> confluence, washed once with 1X DPBS
          and incubated overnight with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>.
          Cultures were then washed twice with 1X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPBS</ENAMEX> and
          pretreated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors DEX</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> in serum-free DMEM
          to final concentrations as indicated in the figures. RSV
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> were added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>/inhibitor mix to final
          concentrations as indicated in the figures. One hour
          after agonist addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> was added to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> concentration
          for the duration of the experiment.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein</ENAMEX> secretion
          After addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>, cells were cultured
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h. Supernatants</ENAMEX> were collected and spun at high
          speed to remove cellular debris. The resulting suspension
          was frozen at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-70Â°C until assayed</TIMEX> following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions by chemokine-specific ELISA
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endogen</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RNase</ENAMEX> protection
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RNase</ENAMEX> protection <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">assays</TIMEX> (RPA) were performed using an
          RPA kit purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD Pharmingen</ENAMEX>. In brief, total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          was isolated from stimulated A549 cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIZOL</ENAMEX>. The
          hCK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> multiprobe template set was used to synthesize <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          probes for the chemokines lymphotactin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î±</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î²</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-309</ENAMEX> as well as the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>-keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes L32</ENAMEX> and glyceraldehyde-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-phosphate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dehydrogenase</ENAMEX> (GAPDH) labeled with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[Î±- 32P</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTP</ENAMEX> using T7
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA polymerase</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 Ã— 10 5cpm</NUMEX> of labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> were
          hybridized with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼g</NUMEX> of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> h at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56Â°C</TIMEX>.
          MRNA-probe <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX> were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNase cocktail</ENAMEX> and
          phenol-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chloroform</ENAMEX> extracted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Protected hybrids</ENAMEX> were
          resolved on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> denaturing polyacrylamide sequencing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gels</ENAMEX> and exposed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics</ENAMEX> detection screen
          overnight. Laser <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">densitometry</ENAMEX> was performed using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics Storm scanner</ENAMEX> system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamics, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunny</ENAMEX> vale, CA).
        
        
          DNA binding studies
          Electrophoretic mobility shift assays (EMSA) were
          performed essentially as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] .
          Briefly, nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein extracts</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> Î¼g <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>) prepared
          form <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">A549 cells</ENAMEX> by the method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osborn</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] were incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 5cpm (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~0.1 ng</NUMEX>) of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32P end</TIMEX>-labeled consensus NF-ÎºB
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligonucleotide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AGTTGAGGGGACTTTCCCAGGC-3</ENAMEX>') probe
          contained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX> gel shift assay system for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20-30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> at room temperature in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 Î</TIMEX>¼l reaction volume using
          the kit provided reaction buffer. To demonstrate binding
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specificity</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-fold molar excess (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 ng</NUMEX>) of a specific
          or non-specific oligonucleotide
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATTCGATCGGGGCGGGGCGAGC-3</ENAMEX>') was included in the
          binding reaction. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein-DNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-DNA</ENAMEX>-antibody
          complexes were resolved in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> polyacrylamide gels
          preelectrophoresed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at room temperature in
          0.25X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBE</ENAMEX> buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22.5</NUMEX> mM Tris-borate and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.3</NUMEX>). Gels were dried and exposed to radiographic film
          with an intensifying screen at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-70Â°C</TIMEX>.
        
        
          NF-kappaB subunit specific ELISA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB subunits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">p65</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB1</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">p50</NUMEX>) were
          quantified using <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Trans-AMâ„</ENAMEX>¢ transcription factor assay kit
          from Active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motif</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA). The assay is
          essentially an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX> in which the consensus NF-ÎºB binding
          site (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGGACTTTCC-3</ENAMEX>') is immobilized onto the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96</TIMEX> well
          plate. Nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell extracts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 Î¼g</ENAMEX>) were added to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wells</ENAMEX> and assayed for either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rel A</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">p50 binding as</NUMEX> per
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions. Optical density was
          determined on a spectophotometer at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> nm.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> induction of chemokine expression differs from
          that induced by TNFalpha
          As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RSV</ENAMEX> infection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A549</ENAMEX> epithelial
          cells induces the production and secretion of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">chemokines IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A549</TIMEX> epithelial
          cells substantial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> was constitutively expressed
          whereas little or no spontaneous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> or RANTES was
          detected. However, upon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RSV</ENAMEX> infection (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOI</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) a
          significant increase in chemokine production and
          secretion was observed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hr post-infection for each of
          the chemokines.
          To determine whether the chemokine induction was
          mediated by increased chemokine gene expression we
          assessed the kinetics of mRNA synthesis by chemokine
          specific <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RNase</ENAMEX> protection. A549 cells were infected with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MOI</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) or stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) and
          total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolated at various times post-treatment over a
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hr time</TIMEX> course. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> rapidly
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">induced IL-8</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> with steady-state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> readily
          detected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 1</TIMEX> hr and continued to increase over
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hr time course. In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> mRNA was not
          detected until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hrs</TIMEX> post infection after which its
          expression rapidly increased also reaching a maximum at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hrs.</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> induction kinetics <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">differed</ENAMEX> dramatically
          from the induction kinetics for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> in the same
          experiment. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> induction of the chemokines did
          not reach a maximum until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hrs</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> induction was
          maximal between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 and 8</NUMEX> hrs and was either unchanged or
          lower at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs post-infection.
          The magnitude of induction also differed between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RSV</ENAMEX> infection. In general TNFÎ± was a stronger inducer
          of chemokine expression. This difference was also
          reflected in the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemokine</ENAMEX> secreted from the
          cells (data not shown). Together, these data indicate
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RSV</ENAMEX> infection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A549</ENAMEX> epithelial cells induces
          chemokine expression with distinct kinetics suggesting
          the mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RSV induction</ENAMEX> differs from that of
          proinflammatory cytokines.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-kappaB inhibitors</ENAMEX> differentially effect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFalpha</ENAMEX> induction of chemokine expression
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> gene expression are regulated
          by the redox responsive transcription factor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 23 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 41 42 43 44</NUMEX> ] . The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB signaling pathways have been shown to be
          differentially affected by antioxidants and
          glucocorticoid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . To determine whether RSV
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> induction of chemokine expression might be
          mediated by different NF-ÎºB signaling pathways we
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretreated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A549</ENAMEX> cells with the glutathione precursor
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-acetyl-L</ENAMEX>-cysteine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX>) or the synthetic glucocorticoid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dexamethasone</ENAMEX> (DEX). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> post infection,
          total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was isolated and steady state mRNA expression
          analyzed by chemokine specific <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RNase</ENAMEX> protection. As shown
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> had very different effects
          on chemokine gene expression. Most strikingly, RSV
          induced chemokine expression was more sensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX>,
          whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> induced chemokine expression was conversely
          more sensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEX</ENAMEX>. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NAC preferentially</ENAMEX> inhibited
          chemokine expression induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX>, while DEX
          predominantly inhibited chemokine expression induced by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Differential inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFalpha</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> induced
          NF-kappaB
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB binds to the chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> as either homo-
          or heterodimers composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">p65</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB1</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">p50</NUMEX>).
          Initially we detected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KA Roebuck</ENAMEX> and LR <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> unpublished data) but
          because multiple gel shift <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> were induced it was
          not possible to distinguish the individual contributions
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p50</ENAMEX> to the formation of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>.
          Therefore to assess the induction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX> and p50
          subunits individually in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">A549</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell extracts</ENAMEX>, we
          used a subunit specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB binding ELISA</ENAMEX> system that
          utilizes anti-Rel A and anti-p50 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. As shown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p50</ENAMEX> subunits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB are
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentially</ENAMEX> expressed and induced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A549</TIMEX> epithelial
          cells. In untreated cells, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX> (solid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bars</ENAMEX>) was
          detectable whereas in resting cells constitutive levels
          of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p50</TIMEX> were observed (open bars), suggesting that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unstimulated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A549</ENAMEX> epithelial cells contain p50
          homodimers, which with regard to transcriptional activity
          have been shown to be functionally inert or inhibitory.
          In contrast, cells stimulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A) or
          infected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B) markedly induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX>, the
          transcriptionally active subunit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-ÎºB.</ENAMEX> In addition,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> was also able to induce p50 by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5</NUMEX>-fold whereas
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> increased the constitutive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p50</TIMEX> level by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about</TIMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>. The induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p50</ENAMEX> were specific since
          competition with either wild type or mutant consensus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-ÎºB oligonucleotide respectively</ENAMEX> inhibited or not the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> induced binding activity. These data
          demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> is a potent inducer of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX>
          and p50 whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> primarily induces the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel</ENAMEX> A subunit
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-ÎºB.</ENAMEX>
          To determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> activate NF-ÎºB
          differently, we examined the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEX</ENAMEX> on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Rel A</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p50</ENAMEX> binding activity. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX>
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p50</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">subunits</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">differentially</ENAMEX> inhibited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEX</ENAMEX> which have been shown to inhibit <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> by distinct
          mechanisms. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEX</ENAMEX> were unable to inhibit TNFÎ±
          induction of either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rel A</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p50</TIMEX>. In contrast, in RSV
          infected cells both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEX</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NAC</ENAMEX> inhibited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX> and p50
          binding activity. However, the inhibitory effects were
          most striking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel</ENAMEX> A suggesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>
          primarily target the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A.</ENAMEX>
          The differential effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC on TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and RSV
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induced NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB binding activity correlated with its
          effects on chemokine gene expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) and protein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX> (data not shown) suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> induces
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> through redox-sensitive NF-ÎºB
          binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEX</ENAMEX> also showed differential effects
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB binding activity with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEX</ENAMEX> preferentially
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibiting RSV</ENAMEX> induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-ÎºB.</ENAMEX> However, the effects
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEX</ENAMEX> on NF-ÎºB binding induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> did not correlate
          with its effects on chemokine expression, suggesting in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> activation of chemokine gene expression <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">DEX</ENAMEX> targets
          another mechanism of chemokine induction not involving
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-ÎºB.</ENAMEX>
        
      
      
        Discussion
        In this study, we examined the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB in the
        activation of chemokine gene expression in response to TNFÎ±
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RSV</ENAMEX> infection. The inhibitor studies correlating
        chemokine gene expression and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB binding activity
        indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX>, in contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>, induces <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, MCP-1
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> expression in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A549</TIMEX> epithelial cells through a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redox-sensitive NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB signaling pathway that appears to
        involve predominately <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A. IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> are
        known redox regulated genes and our results are consistent
        with the findings that oxidant tone can regulate chemokine
        gene expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> infected airway epithelial cells [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 47 48</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-ÎºB activation</ENAMEX> is controlled by its inhibitory protein
        I-ÎºBÎ± which when phosphorylated on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ser32 and ser36</TIMEX> marks it
        for degradation by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">26S</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">proteosome complex</ENAMEX>. Thus I-ÎºB is
        a potential regulatory target for the differential
        induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-ÎºB.</ENAMEX> Although we have not directly examined
        the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I-ÎºB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiedler</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49 50</NUMEX> ] have reported
        differential effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> on I-ÎºB activity in
        A549 epithelial cells. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bitko</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barik</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> ]
        have demonstrated that another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I-ÎºB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I-ÎºBÎ²</ENAMEX>) may
        also contribute via a redox-sensitive pathway to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB
        activation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX>.
        In addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB dependent regulation there appears
        to also be NF-ÎºB independent activation of chemokine
        expression since <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DEX</ENAMEX> inhibited TNFÎ± induced chemokine
        expression but not NF-ÎºB binding activity. Along these
        lines, it has been shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> activation of chemokine
        gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> involves multiple inducible transcription
        factors including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52 53</NUMEX> ] , which is also a redox
        sensitive transcription factor important in chemokine gene
        expression [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 36 54</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> can also be inhibited by DEX
        and has been shown to cooperate with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB to mediate RSV
        induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 55</NUMEX> ] .
        The differential effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEX</ENAMEX> on chemokine
        gene expression and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> activation suggest that the
        mechanisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> and
        chemokine expression differ possibly involving distinct
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB signaling mechanisms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> rapidly and potently
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activates Rel A</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p50</ENAMEX> subunits of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> through a
        kinase-mediated phosphorylation cascade involving a high
        molecular mass signaling complex called the IKK complex [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> activation of the multiprotein IKK complex
        results in the serine phorsphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I-ÎºB</ENAMEX> and the
        subsequent activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX> ] .
        Consistent with the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> activating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distinct NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB signaling pathways, we found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibitor NAC</ENAMEX> had differential effects on chemokine gene
        expression. In contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> induced chemokine
        expression was sensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> particularly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A</ENAMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">p65</NUMEX>) subunit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> is an antioxidant thiol that raises the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intracellular</ENAMEX> pool of glutathione the major redox
        regulating mechanism in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the A549</TIMEX> epithelial cell line [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>
        ] . Interestingly, it has been reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> can have
        differential effects on NF-ÎºB binding activity suggesting
        only a subset of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> are redox
        sensitive [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58</TIMEX> ] . Moreover, it has been shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibits Rel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A/p50</ENAMEX> heterodimers but not p50 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homodimers</ENAMEX> and
        can inhibit NF-ÎºB binding to only certain variant ÎºB
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> which presumably interact with distinct redox
        sensitive NF-ÎºB binding complexes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">59</TIMEX> ] . These
        observations are consistent with our findings that indicate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX> predominantly <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">inhibits</ENAMEX> Rel A homodimers since that was
        the major <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-ÎºB subunit</ENAMEX> induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RSV</ENAMEX> infection of A549
        cells.
        Consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> inducing functionally
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distinct NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1 was recently shown
        to be the preferential cooperative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RSV-induced IL-8</ENAMEX> expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] , whereas in
        TNFÎ±-induced expression NF-ÎºB cooperates preferentially
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-IL-6</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 22</NUMEX> ] . Apparently, the
        stimulus-specific gene regulation of chemokines is complex
        involving differential cooperativity of redox sensitive and
        redox resistant NF-ÎºB <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> with other transcription
        factors to form unique higher order transcription
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complexes</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Taken together, our data indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSV</ENAMEX>, in contrast
        to the cytokine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>, activate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> and chemokine gene
        expression through a redox sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB signaling
        pathway involving predominately <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rel A.</ENAMEX>
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
    
  
