
  
    
      
        Background
        
        Streptococcus pyogenes causes a
        variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> ranging from mild suppurative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">throat</ENAMEX> and skin infections like pharyngitis and erysipelas
        to severe invasive conditions such as necrotizing fasciitis
        and streptococcal toxic shock syndrome [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
        most widely recognized putative streptococcal virulence
        factors is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>-stable hemolysin, streptolysin S
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX>). Despite the ease of measuring SLS activity the
        precise molecular nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> is not known. This is
        due, in part, to the assembly requirement of a carrier
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">molecule</ENAMEX>, e.g. double stranded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>, and a peptide to form
        the functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hemolysin</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Recent genetic and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunochemical</ENAMEX> studies have clearly identified the 
        sagA/pel gene as being responsible
        for the key peptide component of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5 6</NUMEX> ] .
        The precise biological role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX> in streptococcal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infections</ENAMEX> remains controversial [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . The original
        analysis of the 
        sagA gene demonstrated that
        inactivation of the gene encoding the polypeptide component
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX> rendered the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> less virulent in a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dermonecrotic</ENAMEX> mouse model [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . In a related series of
        studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li et al</ENAMEX> also isolated a mutant that not only
        lacked SLS activity but also affected other phenotypes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
        ] . The additional phenotypes included surface <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> as well as the secreted cysteine
        protease, streptococcal pyrogenic exotoxin B, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SpeB</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
        The disrupted gene was termed 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pel</ENAMEX> (pleotrophic effect locus). In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">isolate CS101</ENAMEX> the 
        pel gene acted as a transcriptional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] while in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an M6</TIMEX> isolate it displayed effects
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">secretion</ENAMEX> and membrane anchoring [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . The transposon
        inserted in the 
        pel gene mapped to the promoter
        region of the previously identified 
        sagA gene (SLS-associated gene A).
        Since the same gene is disrupted in all of the studies we
        will use the designation 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> throughout to define this
        regulatory region that also is directly related to the
        Î²-hemolytic phenotype.
        In this study we have further characterized the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant of isolate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CS101</NUMEX> and
        report that it is less virulent than the wild type
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>. The loss of virulence associated with the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant can be reversed by
        injection of this mutant into the skin of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and
        recovering a Î²-hemolytic positive variant from the kidney
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours later</TIMEX>. This kidney-recovered variant restored SLS
        activity, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related protein expression but not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeB</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">streptokinase</ENAMEX> (SK) secretion. This change in
        phenotype was achieved despite the continued presence of
        the Tn 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> transposon in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> region
        of the 
        sagA/pel gene.
      
      
        Results
        
          Selection of sagA/pelvariants by biological
          pressures in the mouse
          The 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant of isolate CS101
          fails to express Î²-hemolysin, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SpeB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK</ENAMEX> or surface <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . Based on prior studies from
          our laboratory [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10</ENAMEX> ] , we predicted that this isolate
          would be avirulent in the mouse skin air sac model. To
          test this possibility, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were
          injected with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Ã— 10 9cfu</NUMEX> of either wild type or an
          isogenic 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant isolate and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mice</ENAMEX> observed over a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hour</TIMEX> period. Surprisingly, at the
          conclusion of this study there was no statistically
          significant difference (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">> 0.05</NUMEX>) between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          injected with the wild type isolate and the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant (data not
          shown).
          This result was reminiscent of an earlier study
          conducted by our laboratory using the 
          mga mutant of isolate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64/14</NUMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
          In this case, although the 
          mga mutant failed to express <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, however, it was capable of causing a
          lethal infection [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . Detailed analysis of this system
          indicated that the mouse was capable of selecting an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> over-expressing variant despite the presence of
          the 
          mga mutation in an identical
          location [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
          To determine if selection for a phenotypic variant was
          also occurring with the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel mutant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were injected
          in a skin air sac and recovered at varying times post
          infection from either the spleen, liver or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mice</ENAMEX>
          were euthanized at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, 8</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 24, 48 and 72 hours</TIMEX> post
          infection with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9cfu</TIMEX>. Since the study was designed to
          select for revertants or phenotypic variants, studies of
          the wild type isolate were not included. At each time
          point, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were euthanized and spleen, kidney and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver tissue samples</ENAMEX> were obtained. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homogenized</ENAMEX> in sterile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and aliquots plated on blood
          agar plates containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">erythromycin</ENAMEX>. The results of these
          studies are presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>.
          At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX>, only one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> showed a
          significant bacteremia in any sample tested. In the other
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> were sterile. Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> only one mouse showed > <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> cfu in any sample and
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> were confined to the spleen. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> a
          low level of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> were noted in the spleen samples
          and by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> all <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were sterile at all sites
          tested. Surprisingly, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> could be
          recovered from the spleen, kidney and liver of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. It was of interest that the majority of
          recovered isolates at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX> post-infection were
          Î²-hemolytic (data not shown).
          All of these isolates were erythromycin-resistant
          indicating that the Tn 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> transposon was still present in
          these variants. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> died prior to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX> in this
          experiment. The Î²-hemolytic positive phenotype of these
          recovered variants was stable for over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> passages on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood agar plates</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">broth</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
        
        
          Analysis of the chromosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pelmutant</ENAMEX> and kidney-recovered variants
          To determine whether the Î²-hemolytic positive 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> variants recovered from
          the kidney of an infected mouse maintained the Tn 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> transposon in the original
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">location</ENAMEX>, we performed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XL-PCR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> blot analysis
          as well as sequencing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> near the Tn 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> insertion using chromosomal DNA
          from the parental 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> strain and the
          kidney-recovered isolates as templates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XL</ENAMEX>-PCR
          profile of the parental 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant and the Î²-hemolytic
          kidney-recovered variants was identical (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). In
          addition, there was no difference in the DNA sequence
          around the transposon- 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> junction between the
          original 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant and the
          kidney-recovered variant (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1C</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blotting</ENAMEX> confirmed that the location and size of the Tn 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> insertion was unaltered in the
          kidney-recovered variant compared to the parental strain
          and that only a single Tn 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> transposon was present (data
          not shown). Thus the restoration of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î²-hemolysis</NUMEX> cannot be
          due to loss, rearrangement or duplication of the Tn 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern blot</ENAMEX> and primer extension analysis of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX>
          The insertion site for the Tn 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> transposon is in the promoter
          region of the 
          sagA/pel gene and no 
          sagA/pel message was detected in
          the original mutant [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was isolated from the
          Î²-hemolytic positive kidney-recovered variant and the
          wild type isolate and analyzed for 
          sagA/pel message by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blotting</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> base message was detected in
          both the wild type and kidney-recovered variants but not
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolated from the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). In
          contrast to previous reports [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5</NUMEX> ] a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> smaller
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcript</ENAMEX> was detected in the wild type strain (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-2</ENAMEX>). This transcript was not seen in the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel mutant</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney</ENAMEX>-recovered
          variants grown under these conditions (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, lane
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-5</ENAMEX>).
          Primer extension analysis of the wild type and
          kidney-recovered variants demonstrated that the 
          sagA/pel message expressed in the
          kidney-recovered variant had an identical transcription
          start site to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> base message present in the wild
          type strain (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> transcript, present only
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolated from the wild type isolate (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lane 1</ENAMEX>), started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> bases downstream of the longer
          transcript. It is not clear whether this is a second
          transcription start site or a processed form of the
          larger transcript. It is interesting to note that two
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-base palindromes are located immediately downstream of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-end of the shorter transcript and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-base
          inverted repeat lies just upstream of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-end of the
          larger transcript (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Analysis of other sagA/pelphenotypes
          The presence of a 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> transcript is consistent
          with the Î²-hemolytic phenotype of the kidney-recovered
          inactivation of the 
          sagA/pel gene product also effects
          expression of other key streptococcal products, including
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">surface M</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">streptokinase</ENAMEX> (SK) and the secreted
          cysteine protease, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SpeB</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . Analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> was conducted to determine if
          restoration of the expression of the large 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> transcript also reverted
          the other phenotypes associated with the wild type
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>.
          Expression of surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibrinogen</ENAMEX>-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> was monitored by the ability of intact
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> to bind radiolabeled fibrinogen. The
          kidney-recovered mutant not only recovered fibrinogen
          binding potential, that was lost when the 
          sagA/pel gene was inactivated, but
          also the level of fibrinogen-binding exceeded that of the
          wild type isolate (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A). Analysis of culture
          supernatants for the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B) or SK
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4C) indicated that the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant and the
          kidney-recovered variant displayed a similar low level of
          expression when compared to the wild type. There were no
          significant changes in fibronectin binding among any of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">variants</ENAMEX> tested (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Consequently,
          restoration of expression of the larger 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> transcript (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) was
          not sufficient to revert all of the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> -associated phenotypes to
          wild type levels (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Restoration of virulence in the kidney-recovered
          pelmutants
          Based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> phenotypic
          characteristics of the Î²-hemolytic positive
          kidney-recovered variant of the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel mutant</ENAMEX> 
          in vitro , we predicted this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">variant</ENAMEX> would be virulent in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> skin infection
          model. To test this prediction the kidney-recovered
          variant, the wild type and the original 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant were tested for
          virulence using the skin air sac model. The results
          present in figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5indicate</TIMEX> that the kidney-recovered
          variant was significantly more virulent than the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel mutant</ENAMEX> from which it was
          originally selected (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.018</NUMEX>) despite not secreting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeB</ENAMEX> or SK in culture (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Inactivation of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> locus by insertion of a Tn 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> transposon into the promoter
        region leads to decreased expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SpeB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK</ENAMEX> as
        well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] and reduced
        virulence in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> model of infection using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytodex</ENAMEX> beads
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . In this paper we have shown that this mutation also
        leads to decreased or delayed virulence in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> air-sac
        model of infection. Although virulence of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant was decreased during
        the initial infection period, viable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> could be
        isolated from the spleen, kidney or liver <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX> after
        infection in the skin. What was surprising was when
        cultured on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood agar</ENAMEX> plates at 37Â°C these isolates were
        Î²-hemolytic yet remained erythromycin resistant.
        In this study we have analyzed a representative
        Î²-hemolytic positive kidney-recovered variant. Direct
        genomic sequencing of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel ::Tn</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">917 insertion</TIMEX> junction in these
        kidney-recovered Î²-hemolysis positive variants established
        that the transposon was present in the genome in exactly
        the same location as the parental Î²-hemolytic negative 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel mutant.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern blot</ENAMEX> and
        primer extension analysis confirmed that the 
        sagA/pel gene was transcribed in the
        Î²-hemolytic kidney-recovered variant, while 
        sagA/pel message was not seen in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parental Î²</ENAMEX>-hemolysis negative 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel mutant.</ENAMEX> Since the 
        sagA/pel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> was identical in
        both the parental and kidney-recovered isolates we conclude
        that the Tn 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> was inserted into a positive
        regulatory site and not into an essential promoter
        sequence.
        In previous studies only a single 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> transcript were observed [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5</NUMEX> ] . However, in this study we have identified two 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> transcripts present in
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> equal concentration in the wild type parent
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). We do not know if this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> shorter
        transcript represents a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> transcription start site or
        is a processed form of the larger transcript. What is
        intriguing is that only the larger transcript is present in
        the Î²-hemolysis positive kidney-recovered variant. This
        result would be consistent with the hypothesis that 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> transcriptional
        start sites and expression from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only one</NUMEX> site is restored
        after mouse selection. Other 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> have been
        shown to have multiple transcription start sites that are
        differentially regulated. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mga</ENAMEX>, a
        transcriptional activator of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, also
        has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> transcription start sites that are independently
        regulated [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct transcription start sites
        are associated with expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">streptokinase gene</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13 14 15</NUMEX> ] .
        The strain CS101 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel ::Tn</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">917</ENAMEX> has previously been rendered
        Î²-hemolytic negative by a transposon insertion. To recover
        a Î²-hemolysis positive variant, from the mouse kidney, with
        the transposon in its original position was unexpected.
        This result indicated additional levels of regulation of
        the Î²-hemolysis phenotype could be selected by biological
        pressures in the mouse. The selected Î² hemolysis positive
        variant was stable and retained this phenotype even after
        repeated passage on laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> in the absence of any
        additional selective biological pressures.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> selection process results not only in the
        restoration of a Î²-hemolytic positive phenotype, but also
        restored some, but not all, of the phenotypes known to be
        regulated by 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . For example,
        fibrinogen-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related protein expression was
        restored; however secretion of the cysteine protease, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SpeB</ENAMEX>,
        or SK was not. Previous studies from our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> have
        consistently demonstrated loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeB</ENAMEX> phenotype in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes isolates injected in a
        skin air sac and recovered from the organs of lethally
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">infected mice</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 16</NUMEX> ] . This selection was not associated
        with loss of Î²-hemolysis but was associated with
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, which in turn
        are predictive of the invasive potential of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> in
        a skin infection model [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . Based on the phenotypic
        characteristics of the kidney-recovered variant
        (Î²-hemolytic positive, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related protein positive and
        SpeB negative) we predicted that this variant would be as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">virulent</ENAMEX> or more virulent than the wild type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> skin infection model. This prediction was tested
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">experimentally</ENAMEX> and the Î²-hemolysis positive 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> variant was found to be as
        virulent as the wild type isolate in the skin infection
        model (see figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>).
        The genetic event(s) associated with the selection of a
        virulent variant of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant without changing the
        site or orientation of the Tn 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> transposon was reminiscent of
        earlier studies from our laboratory testing the virulence
        of 
        mga mutants of isolate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64/14</NUMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        In that study, injection of an 
        mga mutant, that failed to express
        any detectable surface <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, lead to
        selection of 
        mga variants over-expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that could be recovered from the spleen
        following a lethal skin infection. This reversion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> phenotype occurred without any change
        in the position or orientation of the
        spectinomycin-resistance cassette inserted into the 
        mga <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> to create the original
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mutant</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        Taken together, these studies suggest a complex network
        of positive and negative regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> controlling
        key virulence <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes that can be activated or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inactivated</ENAMEX> in response to certain biological pressures in
        the infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. Analysis of the selected phenotypes
        recovered following mouse passage cannot be explained by
        the activities of any known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> or combination of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> e.g. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mga</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24</NUMEX> ] , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nra</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CsrRS/CovRS</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27 28 29</NUMEX> ] , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rofA</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31 32</NUMEX> ] , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rgg</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34 35</NUMEX> ] 
        , fas <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X [ 36</ENAMEX> ] or 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luxS</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37 38</NUMEX> ] .
        It is unknown if there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> or a series of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> that are inactivated or activated after passage
        through the mouse; however, it is clear that key virulence
        factors are under a more complex pattern of regulation than
        previously envisaged. In related studies, the selection of
        stable variants of either wild type or mutant 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes isolates was not
        consistently observed when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> was injected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">i.p.</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> ] . This may relate to either the presence of unique
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> factors at the skin infection site or to the kinetics
        of clearance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>. In studies using a tissue
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX> model, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kotb</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have noted changes in
        expression of key virulence factors as a function of time [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> ] . Thus, it is possible that the 
        in vivo events leading to selection
        of stable 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes variants may require a
        dynamic interaction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> and that only under
        certain experimental conditions will the stable variant
        population be recovered.
        The unique biological pressures associated with
        infection in the skin and persistence in the systemic
        circulation seems to consistently select stable variants
        which over-express key surface <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>.
        Organisms selected in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> are consistently negative
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeB</ENAMEX> secretion. Selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeB</ENAMEX> negative variants
        have also been noted following sequential human blood
        passage of isolates or in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> skin infection model [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> ] . This selective pressure can also be associated with
        enhanced capsular expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SpeB</ENAMEX> negative variants [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
        ] .
        Several bacteriophage and transposons were identified in
        the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes genome [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] as well as
        a number of potential two-component regulatory systems
        whose precise function remains to be elucidated. The
        biological selection of phenotypic revertants of variants
        of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> with
        defined mutations in key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> or promoter regions of
        putative virulence <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> is likely to provide key insights
        into the pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>-bacterial interactions.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Selection of Î² hemolysis positive variants from a 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mutant of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pyogenes</ENAMEX> isolate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CS101</NUMEX> were
        identified. This change in phenotype occurred despite the
        presence of the Tn 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> transposon in an identical
        position in both the Î² hemolysis negative mutant and the Î²
        hemolysis positive selected variant. The ability of
        biological pressures in the mouse to select stable variants
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes expressing different patterns of virulence
        factors suggest the existence of more complex regulatory
        pathway than is currently envisaged.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chemicals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacteria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> used in this study were the opacity
          factor positive M49 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Streptococcus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pyogenes</ENAMEX> isolate
          CS101 and an isogenic Î²-hemolytic negative variant
          generated by transposon mutagenesis, CS101 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel ::Tn</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewitt broth</ENAMEX>
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> extract (THY) was obtained from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIFCO</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit MI</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood agar plates</ENAMEX> were obtained from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BBL (Fisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Mouse skin air sac procedure
          A skin air sac model was used to compare the virulence
          of isolate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CS101</NUMEX> and paired isogenic mutants [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
          Briefly an air- and liquid-tight connective tissue pouch
          was generated on the back of female, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six week old</TIMEX>,
          outbred CD1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Charles River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>) by slow
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dermal</ENAMEX> injection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.9</NUMEX> mL of air via an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> mm needle on
          a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> mL syringe. The syringe containing the air also
          contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mL of an appropriately diluted suspension
          of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes . <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> were provided
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and water ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libitum</ENAMEX>. For selection of
          bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">variants</ENAMEX>, experiments were continued for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> post-infection. For virulence studies death was
          used as the endpoint and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">144 hours</TIMEX> post-infection the
          experiments terminated. For bacteremia studies surviving
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> were euthanized at the times stated. Spleen,
          kidney and a section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> was removed from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. The tissue samples were homogenized in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mL of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sterile</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>. An <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼L</NUMEX> aliquot was cultured
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood agar</ENAMEX> plates to determine if 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> pyogenes were present. All
          animal studies were conducted in accordance with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protocols</ENAMEX> approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical College</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>'s
          Institutional Animal Use and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Committee</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> blot analysis and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">XL</ENAMEX>-PCR
          Analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chromosomal DNA</ENAMEX> for the presence of Tn 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> transposon insertion was
          carried out as described previously [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XL-PCR</ENAMEX> was performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneAmp XL PCR</ENAMEX> kit (PE
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Biosystems, Foster City</ENAMEX>, CA).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DNA Sequencing</ENAMEX>
          Chromosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was isolated as described previously [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> ] . Genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequencing</ENAMEX> was carried out on an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Biosystems 310 Genetic Analyzer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE/Applied</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosystems</ENAMEX>) using a big dye terminator cycle sequencing
          ready reaction kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE/Applied Biosystems</ENAMEX>) according to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s specifications. The oligonucleotide
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATAAATGGACCGCATATTGA-3</ENAMEX>' (corresponding to the DNA
          sequence just downstream of the SagA/Pel open reading
          frame), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATAAATGGACCGCATATTGA-3</ENAMEX>' (corresponding to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> from the right end of the Tn 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">917 insertion</TIMEX>) were used as primers
          for the sequencing reaction. The resulting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequences
          was compared using blast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for pair wise comparisons.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ncbi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nlm</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nih</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/blast/Blast.</ENAMEX>cgi
        
        
          Northern blot analysis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was prepared from wild type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CS101 wt</ENAMEX>, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CS101 sagA/pel ::Tn</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CS101 sagA/pel ::Tn</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">917</NUMEX> kidney-recovered (KR) variants
          grown <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> (37Â°C <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ml THY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. The bacteria
          were harvested <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 hours</TIMEX> post-exponential phase by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centrifugation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 min, 4000 g, 4Â°C</ENAMEX>) and resuspended in
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 Î¼L</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> lysis buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mM Tris</ENAMEX> pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400 Î¼L</NUMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 mg/mL</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysosyme</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO.</ENAMEX>) and mutanolysin (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼g</NUMEX>),
          was added and incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> were sedimented by centrifugation and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuspended</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trizol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco, Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          instructions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA concentration</ENAMEX> was determined
          spectrophotometrically by measuring absorbance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX> nm.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was electrophoresed in a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> agarose gel (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biology Certified Agarose, Biorad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">containing 0.66 M</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Ã—</NUMEX> MOPS
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-morpholino</ENAMEX>)-propanesulfonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>) buffer. Following
          electrophoresis, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was transferred to a nylon membrane
          (Hybond-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>+, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Millipore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions, and hybridized with
          digoxigen-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dUTP</NUMEX>-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> as described previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          ] . The primers used to generate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> were:
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-GGAATTCACCTGCTAATTACCTGA-3'and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CGCGGATCCGTTTACACATAGTTATTGATAGAATCT-3</ENAMEX>'
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Primer extension</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-end of the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sagA/pel</ENAMEX> mRNA was determined by the
          extension of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-end 32P-labeled oligonucleotides
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACCTTATTTTAAAAATAAAGTTAA-3</ENAMEX>' following the method of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sambrook</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . Oligonucleotides were labeled with [Î³-
          32P] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 mCi/mL</ENAMEX> in aqueous solution) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T4</ENAMEX> polynucleotide kinase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco BRL Life Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). SequiTherm
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EXCEL II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequencing kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epicentre Technologies</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>) was used according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          instruction for the corresponding sequencing reaction
          using the same primer.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streptokinase Assay</ENAMEX>
          Streptokinase activity was measured as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, aliquots of culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatants</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼L</ENAMEX>) were mixed with either <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼g</NUMEX> of
          purified human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plasminogen</ENAMEX> or buffer. The synthetic
          chromogenic substrate, S2251
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H-D-Val-Leu-Lys-paranitroanilide</ENAMEX>) obtained from Kabi
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>), was added to a final
          concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400 Î¼M</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plasmin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> was
          quantified by measuring product absorbance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">405</NUMEX> nm.
        
        
          Cysteine endopetidase assay
          Cysteine protease activity present in culture
          supernatants was assayed as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼L</NUMEX> of culture supernatant with or without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> Î¼M
          dithiothreitol, was added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of a microtiter
          plate. Following incubation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">37Â°C 150 Î¼L</ENAMEX>
          of the substrate buffer solution,
          Bz-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro-Phe-Arg-paranitroanilide</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemical</ENAMEX>) was
          added to each well. Cleavage of the substrate was
          monitored by measuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">405</NUMEX> over time. The cysteine protease
          specific inhibitor, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">E64</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), was included in parallel
          assays at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼M to determine if all the
          enzymatic activity being measured could be attributed to
          the presence of a cysteine protease.
        
        
          Binding assay for fibrinogen
          The ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> to bind fibrinogen was
          determined by their ability to bind the specific
          radiolabeled ligand. Human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibrinogen</ENAMEX> was radiolabeled
          with 125I (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) using Iodobeads
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] . Different
          numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> were incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20,000 cpm</NUMEX> of
          125I labeled fibrinogen for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. The bacteria
          were pelleted by centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> Ã— g for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> min
          and washed twice with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM veronal buffer pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.35</NUMEX>, containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M NaCl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> gelatin. The
          radioactivity associated with the bacterial pellet was
          quantified in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckman</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5500B</NUMEX> automatic gamma counter
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fullerton CA</ENAMEX>).
        
      
    
  
