
  
    
      
        Background
        Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> cancer registries that contract with the
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US National Cancer Institute</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Cancer</ENAMEX>
        Registry reports the lowest overall incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
        During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1995-1999</TIMEX>, age-adjusted (to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>) invasive cancer incidence rates in white men
        for the leading <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>-years, were
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">393.1</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">451.0</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SEER</ENAMEX> (without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>) [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ] . Lower rates in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> were observed for all sites
        except prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and melanoma of the skin (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">174.5</NUMEX> vs.
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">157.8</NUMEX> for prostate, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">42.7</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">81.9</NUMEX> for lung and bronchus,
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">48.8</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">63.9</NUMEX> for colon and rectum, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">31.7</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">38.8</NUMEX> for
        urinary bladder, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">22.4</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24.6</NUMEX> for non-<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hodgkin's lymphoma</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25.3</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23.4</NUMEX> for melanoma of the skin, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13.0</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16.3</NUMEX> for
        oral cavity and pharynx, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11.0</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15.5</NUMEX> for kidney and renal
        pelvis, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13.9</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16.7</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.9</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.2</NUMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pancreas</ENAMEX>). Comparatively high prostate cancer incidence
        rates in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX> among white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> have been
        reported previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latter-day Saints</ENAMEX> (LDS or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon</ENAMEX>) settled the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . Over the next several
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> settled over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>
        throughout the territory. Today, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 70%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is affiliated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX>
        ] . Over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s population is white,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . Low cigarette-smoking and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-drinking prevalence observed among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> helps
        explain the comparatively low rates for many of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> sites in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . Whether the high prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates reflect higher rates among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> is
        unclear.
        We linked electronic records from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX>
        membership files and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Cancer Registry</ENAMEX> to examine
        the magnitude and temporal trends in prostate cancer
        incidence rates among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> and nonLDS <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> for
        the calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 1985 through 1999</TIMEX>. Cases judged to have
        been incidentally detected through transurethral resection
        of the prostate (TURP), a procedure typically used to treat
        obstructive uropathy, were also identified and considered
        in the rate calculations to provide a clearer indication of
        the effect of screening on the incidence rates of prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. We also examined results from a statewide health
        survey to characterize prostate-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> screening
        patterns by religious affiliation.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Cancer Registry</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Cancer Registry</ENAMEX> (UCR) was
          established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> and has continuously participated in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidemiology</ENAMEX>, and End Results (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEER</ENAMEX>) program since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCR</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and local <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> registrars identify
          incident cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> through
          routine and systematic review of pathology reports,
          medical records, radiation therapy records, hospital
          discharge lists, and vital records. Tumor characteristics
          including histology, grade, and primary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> are coded
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oncology-Second Edition</ENAMEX> (ICDO-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Categories
          of stage of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> at diagnosis are documented in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summary Staging Guide</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SEER</ENAMEX> program of the National
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer Institute</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registry</ENAMEX> records also include
          information regarding treatment and patient
          characteristics such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at diagnosis, gender,
          race/ethnicity, and place of residence at diagnosis.
          Information regarding patient characteristics, cancer
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagnosis</ENAMEX>, and treatment is ascertained from specific
          statements in medical records, reports from private
          pathology <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> and radiotherapy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, and death
          certificates. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer</ENAMEX> surveillance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> is conducted in
          accordance with standards instituted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SEER</ENAMEX> program
          and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North American Association of Central Cancer</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Registries</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10</ENAMEX> ] .
        
        
          Linkage of cancer data with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> church
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCR</ENAMEX> records were linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX> membership
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> to determine membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX>. The
          linkage process took place under direct supervision of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCR</ENAMEX> and was conducted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Records Department</ENAMEX>.
          Confidentiality of record information was strictly
          enforced. After the records were linked, all personal
          identifying information was stripped from the
          database.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Records</ENAMEX> were linked using the probabilistic linking
          program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">LinkPro</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . The program calculates
          probabilities to identify whether a pair of records
          refers to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> variables that were common
          to both sets of records were used to link the records:
          first, middle, and last names; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">birth day</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">birth month</TIMEX>;
          birth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>; gender; zip code; vital status; and maiden
          name. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOUNDEX</ENAMEX> versions of the names were used in the
          matching process, while actual names were used in the
          review process.
          There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121,967</NUMEX> incident cases of cancer identified
          in the UCR database from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973 to 2000</TIMEX> and approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.6 million</NUMEX> records in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX> database. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Records</ENAMEX>
          were linked in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> stages. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> stage linked all
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> that matched exactly on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, middle, and last
          names; complete birth date; and gender. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,187</NUMEX>
          such records declared matches without review. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
          stage consisted of taking the remaining records and
          forcing them to link on last name and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least five</NUMEX>
          additional variables. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,652</NUMEX> records that linked on
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> additional variables were declared matches without
          review. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,587</NUMEX> records that linked on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
          additional variables, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,612</NUMEX> were declared matches
          without review, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">975</NUMEX> were reviewed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">859</NUMEX> declared
          matches. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21,146</NUMEX> records that linked on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
          additional variables, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,378</NUMEX> were declared matches
          without review, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,768</NUMEX> were reviewed of which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,812</NUMEX>
          were declared matches. Finally, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22,492</NUMEX> records
          that matched on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> additional variables, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,650</NUMEX> were
          declared matches without review, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,629</NUMEX> were reviewed with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,328</NUMEX> declared matches, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,213</NUMEX> were declared
          non-matches without review. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> stage of the
          linkage process consisted of taking the remaining
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unlinked</ENAMEX> records and forcing them to link on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least six</NUMEX> other additional variables. There were
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,338</NUMEX> such records. All were reviewed, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">380</NUMEX> declared
          matches. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stages</ENAMEX> resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81,617</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68%</NUMEX>) of the UCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> being linked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> record.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>
          All incident cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICDO-2</ENAMEX> site
          code C61<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>) that were diagnosed among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
          during the time period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985-99</TIMEX> were identified from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records of the Utah Cancer Registry</ENAMEX>. Lymphomas of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prostate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ICDO-2</ENAMEX> histologies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9590-9989</TIMEX>) were excluded
          from the study. Analyses were further restricted to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">histologically</ENAMEX> confirmed cases that were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> and
          older at the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosis. Stage
          categories of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> at diagnosis were local/regional,
          distant, and unstaged. Local and regional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stages</ENAMEX> were
          combined because of the large proportion of cases
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upsataged</ENAMEX> because of surgery [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incidental Detection</ENAMEX>
          Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCR</ENAMEX> has historically collected surgery
          information on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases, including whether a prostate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> case underwent a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURP</ENAMEX>, not until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> did they
          identify whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURP</ENAMEX> led to or was the result of a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosis. This change in the level of
          information collected was made among all the registries
          participating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SEER</ENAMEX> program. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCR</ENAMEX> during
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998-99</TIMEX>, the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TURPs</ENAMEX> performed among cases
          resulting in an incidental finding because of the surgery
          for benign disease was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.6786</NUMEX>. The log of the odds in
          favor of this event was then regressed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> using
          logistic regression. Age was not statistically
          significant (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi-square</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0237</NUMEX>, p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3116</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX>
          and age-squared terms were also fit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, but
          neither was statistically significant. Because the
          proportion of incidental detection among cases undergoing
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURP</ENAMEX> was not associated with age, we multiplied in each
          age category for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year 1985 through 1997</TIMEX> the
          proportion <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.6786</NUMEX> by the total number of age- and
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURPs</ENAMEX> recorded among cases to get an
          estimate of the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURPs</ENAMEX> that led to a prostate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosis.
        
        
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Status Survey</ENAMEX>
          The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Status Survey</ENAMEX> is a
          cross-sectional random survey sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup Organization</ENAMEX> collected
          the data by incorporating a telephone survey instrument
          into a computer-assisted, random-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">digit</NUMEX>-dialing software
          program called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SURVENT</ENAMEX>. Supervised interviews were
          conducted across twelve local health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> by
          trained interviewers. Although the survey questionnaire
          covered several topics, we only used data from questions
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening and religious status. The interview
          process occurred during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 31, 1996</TIMEX>.
          Interviews were conducted with one randomly selected
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 18 years or older</TIMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household</ENAMEX>. If
          required, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as nine</NUMEX> telephone attempts were made to
          contact a selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household</ENAMEX>. The response rate was
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66.3%</NUMEX>. In order to more accurately generalize the survey
          results to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, post-survey weighting
          adjustments were made. Adjustments weighted the sample to
          be proportionally consistent with age, sex, geographic,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> status distributions of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          Age-adjusted prostate cancer incidence rates were
          calculated for individual calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and for the
          following year <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985-88, 1989-92, 1993-96</TIMEX>, and
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-99</TIMEX>. These rates were calculated by the direct method
          with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> standard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> for the year
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . Rates were calculated for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> and
          nonLDS <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and are expressed per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person-years</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Records</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX> provided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> age- and
          sex-specific estimates of the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Elkington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Information Center</ENAMEX>, personal communication).
          Estimates for the nonLDS <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> were derived
          by subtracting the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Bureau of the Census</ENAMEX> [
          incidence rate ratio between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> and nonLDS [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
          Appropriate models reported below were selected based on
          the deviance goodness-of-fit test. Analyses were
          performed with standard packages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX>
          Analysis System (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Results
        A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,693</NUMEX> incident cases of histologically
        confirmed invasive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> and
        older were diagnosed among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> during the period
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985-99</TIMEX>. Based on linkage with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX> records, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,291</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76.8%</NUMEX>) of these cases were determined to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. There were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12,088</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82.3%</NUMEX>) with local/regional
        stage, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,009</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.9%</NUMEX>) with distant stage, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,594</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.8%</NUMEX>)
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">unstaged prostate cancer</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> cases had missing stage
        information.
        The frequency of cases is presented according to
        religious preference, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">calendar year</TIMEX>, and age in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>.
        For both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> and nonLDS, a shift occurred over time from
        cases being diagnosed at older ages to younger ages. For
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> time periods, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> compared with nonLDS
        cases were less likely to be diagnosed in their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> s and
        more likely to be diagnosed in their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> s. The frequency of
        cases is also presented according to religious preference,
        calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). A noticeable stage
        shift occurred from distant to local/regional disease over
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> and nonLDS cases. Only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1989</TIMEX>
        through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> do LDS cases have a significantly higher
        percentage diagnosed with local/regional disease.
        Local/regional-staged TURP- and nonTURP-detected
        age-adjusted prostate cancer incidence rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> 50
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years of age and older</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> are presented according to
        religious preference and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">calendar year</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        NonTURP-detected prostate cancer incidence rates are
        generally higher for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> across the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, particularly
        during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>-induced peak. Despite this observation,
        TURP-detected prostate cancer incidence rates are similar.
        Distant-staged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-</TIMEX>adjusted prostate cancer incidence rates
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> 50 years of age and older in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> are also
        presented by religious preference and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">calendar year</TIMEX> (Figure
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). These rates are generally similar.
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Poisson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">regression model</ENAMEX>, adjusted for age and stage
        at diagnosis, calendar time, and whether prostate cancer
        was TURP- or nonTURP-detected, indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> compared
        with nonLDS have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.31</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> confidence interval, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.26</NUMEX> -
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.36</NUMEX>) times the incidence rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> among men
        aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> and older in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>. The adjusted Poisson
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regression</ENAMEX> model gave rate ratios of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> to nonLDS of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.18</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.99</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.40</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985-88</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.20</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.12</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.29</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989-92</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.15</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.08</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.24</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-1996</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.13</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.04</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.22</NUMEX>) in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997-99</TIMEX>. Adjusted rate ratios also indicated significantly
        higher rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> compared with nonLDS for each age
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.13</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.01</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.27</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 50-59</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.48</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.38</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.58</NUMEX>) in
        ages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60-69</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.28</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.21</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.36</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 70-79</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.16</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.04</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.28</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 80 and older</TIMEX>] and for certain stage
        categories [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.36</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.31</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.43</NUMEX>) in local/regional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.97</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.84</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.11</NUMEX>) in distant stage, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.17</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.04</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.31</NUMEX>) in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unstaged</ENAMEX>].
        Finally, on the basis of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Status</ENAMEX>
        Survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> compared with nonLDS <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were more likely
        to have received a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
      
      
        Discussion
        Evidence that prostate cancer incidence rates are
        sensitive to screening is well established [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 17 18 19</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ] . Potosky 
        et al. examined the potential
        influence that adoption of transrectal ultrasound (TRUS)
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing had on increasing prostate needle biopsy
        rates in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SEER</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986 through 1991</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRUS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing rates, initially near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>,
        increased to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 2,000 and 20,000</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>,
        respectively. Their study further showed a correlation
        between increasing needle biopsy rates and prostate cancer
        incidence rates. Legler 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX> added to our understanding of
        the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates
        by showing that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> testing proportions, not the
        overall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> proportion, track closely with prostate cancer
        incidence rates [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . In a comparison of prostate cancer
        incidence rates among white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SEER</ENAMEX> areas
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puget Sound</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brawley</ENAMEX> showed that the rates were highest in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986 through 1991</TIMEX>, but then highest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1992 through 1994</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . In a consistent manner, the
        proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> receiving a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> tended to be
        highest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX> but highest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
        in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . Because <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76.8%</NUMEX> of diagnosed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> cases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> during our study period were
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, we may assume that the relatively high
        proportion of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> tests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> primarily
        reflects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
        The results, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poisson</ENAMEX> regression, indicate that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> compared with nonLDS <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> residing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, after
        adjusting for age and stage at diagnosis, calendar time and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURP</ENAMEX> experienced significantly higher prostate cancer
        incidence rates. Unfortunately, our broad stage categories
        limited our ability to adjust for this variable such that
        differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> could still be explaining some of the
        higher incidence among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Nevertheless, the higher
        rates among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> could be because they more readily
        adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRUS</ENAMEX> and digital rectal exams in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
        period, prior to widespread <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening, and then more
        readily adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening but to a lesser degree.
        Historically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> have used digital rectal
        examinations in early detection efforts [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] . In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, digital rectal examination has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> detection
        rate and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> test, which is relatively easy to perform,
        has a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> detection rate in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who are older than 50 years
        of age [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
        Screening is further implicated by the fact that the
        higher rate ratios of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> to nonLDS prostate cancer
        incidence occur in local/regional stage cases. Age- and
        stage-shifts in the data are also consistent with higher
        levels of screening among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, there is
        little screening data available to allow us to directly
        evaluate the role screening plays in the higher prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates observed among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
        Nevertheless, based on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Status Survey</ENAMEX>
        we showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> compared with nonLDS <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were more
        likely to have received a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> test in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>,
        overall and within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> categories. Yet the order of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
        received, whether a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> test, is
        unknown. In addition, we do not know whether higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
        screening use among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> remained higher prior to or
        after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
        Studies have shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> undergoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening are
        more likely to display an overall constellation of
        health-promoting behavior, such as not smoking and seeking
        health care regularly [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Smokers</ENAMEX> are less likely
        to use medical services [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 28</NUMEX> ] , with one study finding
        that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76%</NUMEX> of nonsmokers compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>
        receiving regular checkups [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> has historically
        experienced the lowest smoking prevalence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . Utah smoking prevalence is currently
        closest to the 
        Healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX> goal for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] , with smoking prevalence in the year
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.9%</NUMEX> compared with the next lowest prevalence in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17.2</NUMEX> and nationally of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23.2%</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . This
        low smoking prevalence is primarily explained by the over
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> who attend church <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>, among which
        less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> are current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> who are
        married and who have medical insurance have the highest
        levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> use in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . According to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah Health Status Survey</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74.7%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58.9%</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonLDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> were married, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92.2%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> men
        compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86.2%</NUMEX> of nonLDS <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were medically insured [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> ] .
        In a consistent manner, studies have found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who
        are generally healthier [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 33</NUMEX> ] , married [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX> ] , and
        more educated [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36</NUMEX> ] are more likely to be diagnosed
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with different
        characteristics. Yet these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> also tend to experience
        better survival [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 37 38 39</NUMEX> ] , indicating that they are
        possibly being diagnosed at earlier stages because of more
        aggressive screening. In addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LDS</ENAMEX> having
        comparatively low smoking prevalence, a higher proportion
        who are married, and a higher proportion who are medically
        insured, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89%</NUMEX> of nonLDS men
        reported having at least a high school education, according
        to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Status Survey</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] .
        In our study, adjusting for TURP-detected cases allowed
        us to better assess the influence of screening on prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> incidence trends. Frequent use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURP</ENAMEX> for benign
        prostatic hyperplasia in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s and 1980s</TIMEX> and the rapid
        introduction and widespread adoption of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening
        beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, tapped an extensive pool of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">latent</ENAMEX> and preclinical prostate disease [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 41</NUMEX> ] .
        Consistent with another study, we found that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX>
        1980s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 50%</NUMEX> or more of all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> cases were
        incidentally detected through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURPs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] . However, as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> with few side effects became available to treat
        benign prostatic hypterplasia and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening became
        widely adopted, TURP-detected cases declined from their
        peak in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987 through 1993</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] . Our results showed a
        similar decline in the TURP-detected prostate cancer
        incidence rates, followed by a leveling off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1994</TIMEX>
        and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> and nonLDS cases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>. We also
        found the level of TURP-detected rates to be very similar
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> and nonLDS.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> are not available to identify whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TURP</ENAMEX> rates
        differed between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> and nonLDS. However, if we assume they
        were similar or even higher among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX>, and given the
        similar TURP-detected prostate cancer incidence rates
        observed, there is no reason to believe that prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> is more common in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Indeed, an older study
        based on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> data covering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1971 through 1985</TIMEX>
        found that the age-adjusted (to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> standard)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>-years
        were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">76.3</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> compared with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">109.1</NUMEX> for nonLDS [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ]
        .
        One goal of screening is to identify the presence of
        disease before it becomes clinically evident. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>-based
        screening achieved this goal, we would anticipate dramatic
        increases in the number of cases diagnosed with early stage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>. The available data did not allow us to
        restrict our analyses to cases with just localized disease.
        Results from previous studies have demonstrated that choice
        of therapy for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> may influence subsequent
        determination of staging. Specifically, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clinically</ENAMEX> appeared to have localized <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> were
        determined to have regional stage disease based on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathological</ENAMEX> review of tissue that was obtained from
        radical prostatectomy [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44</NUMEX> ] . Similar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> that did
        not undergo aggressive surgical treatment would not have
        had the opportunity for a comparable evaluation of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>;
        the latter group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> would have remained classified
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">localized disease</ENAMEX>. Therefore, it was not possible in
        these data to distinguish between cases with true localized
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and those who received a clinical diagnosis of
        localized disease but actually had undetected regional
        stage disease. Hence, cases of local and regional stage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> were combined in the present study.
      
      
        Conclusion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> compared with nonLDS <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> may have adopted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> rectal and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening more readily. Higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
        screening was observed among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX>, both overall and within
        selected age groups according to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Status Survey</ENAMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX>
        tend to reflect a host of characteristics (i.e., low
        smoking prevalence, a high proportion married, a high
        proportion medically insured, and a high level of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>) that are associated with good general health.
        Previous studies have indicated that these characteristics
        are associated with more aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> screening and,
        because of the high prevalence of asymptomatic prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, subsequent prostate cancer
        diagnosis. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> adopted screening more readily, we
        may expect that they would have experienced higher prostate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates. Evidence in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> indicates
        that the comparatively high prostate cancer incidence rates
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> are likely due to, at least in part, more
        aggressive screening among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
