
  
    
      
        Background
        Chemokines are small, positively charged, secreted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that consist of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal region of variable
        conformation, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> antiparallel beta-pleated sheets
        connected by loops, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal alpha helix [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] .
        These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are multifunctional, with different regions
        of the molecules, in particular the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>termini,
        performing specific functions [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">e.g.</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4</NUMEX> ] ].
        Chemokines are best known for their functions in
        attracting and activating leukocytes. Shortly after injury,
        these small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytokines</ENAMEX> are primarily produced by
        fibroblasts, chemoattract leukocytes and activate their
        integrins causing them to adhere strongly to the
        endothelial cells as a prelude to their migration through
        the blood vessel wall to the underlying tissue and towards
        the source of the chemokine [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . In addition to these
        functions during the early stages of wound healing, these
        small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytokines</ENAMEX> are also known to be involved in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re-epithelialization</ENAMEX>, angiogenesis and granulation tissue
        development [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 6 7 8</NUMEX> ] , processes that are critical for
        proper healing.
        The first evidence that chemokines are associated with
        wound healing 
        in vivo was reported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> using
        the chemokine cCAF (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken Chemotactic</ENAMEX> and Angiogenic
        Factor; the product of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">9E3</NUMEX> gene), a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokine that
        is now known to be the ortologue for human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cCAF</ENAMEX> is expressed to high levels very shortly after
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wounding</ENAMEX> and during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 24-48 hours</TIMEX> after injury, and
        remains elevated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 16 days</TIMEX> after wounding [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 10</NUMEX>
        ] . It is primarily expressed by the fibroblasts of the
        granulation tissue, especially where interstitial collagen
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coll</ENAMEX>) is abundant, but the levels are also high in the
        endothelial cells of the microvessels, in the healing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epidermis</ENAMEX> and in the connective tissue beneath the skin [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> ] . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken chorioallantoic membrane</ENAMEX> (CAM) assay,
        low concentration of cCAF results in chemotaxis of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">monocyte/macrophages</ENAMEX> and lymphocytes and the formation of a
        granulation-like tissue beneath the chemokine-containing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pellet</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> of exposure to this
        chemokine, the ectoderm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAMs</ENAMEX> becomes thickened and
        the amount of fibrillar collagen in the tissue is markedly
        increased, strongly suggesting that cCAF is able to
        initiate some of the primary events that lead to
        granulation tissue formation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] .
        Fibroblasts are important cells in the healing process.
        Upon injury, they are activated by the cytokines and growth
        factors released during the coagulation process to produce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemokines</ENAMEX> and additional cytokines and growth factors that
        are important in setting up the cascade of events that lead
        to granulation tissue formation. Activated fibroblasts
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proliferate</ENAMEX> and migrate across the provisional matrix
        formed by the fibrin-plasma fibronectin (FN) clot. As the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clot</ENAMEX> is digested by plasmin, fibroblasts replace it with
        cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>, tenascin (TN) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coll III</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . These
        extracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">matrix proteins</ENAMEX> are critical for migration of
        endothelial cells, keratinocytes and additional fibroblasts
        into the wound and are important for proper generation of
        healthy healing tissue. Some of the fibroblasts
        differentiate into myofibroblasts, which contract to close
        the wound [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 14 15</ENAMEX> ] . Myofibroblasts are fibrogenic,
        showing elevated expression of interstitial collagens,
        laminin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of matrix
        metalloproteinases such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TIMP-1</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17 18 19</NUMEX> ] .
        Because cCAF is expressed highly in the granulation tissue
        of wounds in areas where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECM</ENAMEX> is abundant [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 6 11</NUMEX> ] , and
        it stimulates fibroblasts to differentiate into
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">myofibroblasts</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , we investigated whether this
        chemokine stimulates the production of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> major ECM
        molecules mentioned above, interstitial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, TN
        and cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>. Here we show that cCAF stimulates cultures
        of fibroblasts to produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Coll I</ENAMEX>, albeit with
        different dynamics and that these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ECM</ENAMEX> molecules are also
        increased in wounded tissues treated with cCAF.
      
      
        Results
        
          Effects of cCAF and its peptides on the production
          of TN
          In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>, specifically <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX>, is present almost
          exclusively in the granulation tissue of healing wounds [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 24</NUMEX> ] . In addition to providing a matrix for rapid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration</ENAMEX> of cells during wound repair, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> supports
          differentiation of fibroblasts into myofibroblasts [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ]
          , which then produce more TN than do normal fibroblasts [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 18</NUMEX> ] . Because cCAF stimulates fibroblasts to
          differentiate into myofibroblasts, we tested the
          possibility that this chemokine also affects TN
          production. Immunolabeling of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml of the chemokine showed that
          cCAF stimulates the cells to produce more TN than the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1B</ENAMEX>). We have previously
          determined, using dose-dependent studies, that this
          concentration is optimal for functions of this chemokine
          on these embryonic fibroblasts and in processes of
          granulation tissue formation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] ). Although
          chemokine concentrations of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -2-10</NUMEX> ng/ml can
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemoattract</ENAMEX> and activate leukocytes, chemokines acting
          on other cell types such as endothelial cells, smooth
          muscle cells and fibroblasts require concentrations in
          the range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 2ng/ml and higher [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 26 27 28</ENAMEX> ] . This
          is within physiological range; for example wound fluid
          from burn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGSA</ENAMEX> (a chemokine that is
          highly homologous to cCAF) concentrations of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 2-10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3ng/ml</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . Because both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> and
          C-terminal peptides of cCAF have been shown to be
          functional in culture and 
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vivo</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-4, 30</ENAMEX>), we also tested
          these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> peptides (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15aa</TIMEX> peptide
          produced an effect at least as strong as the whole
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">molecule</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C) whereas the effects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">28aa</NUMEX>) was closer to those of the control (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1D). Western blot analysis of extracts from treated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> confirmed that cCAF increases production of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> in culture, that this effect also can be accomplished
          effectively by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-peptide, but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptide
          produced an elevated, but substantially smaller, response
          than either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-peptide or the whole cCAF molecule
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1E). To determine whether cCAF stimulates TN
          expression we examined the levels of mRNA for this ECM
          molecule. RT-PCR analysis showed significant increased
          levels of mRNA for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> after treatment with either cCAF or
          its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-peptide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1F) but the increase stimulated by
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX> is much smaller correlating with the small
          increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels.
          To determine whether this effect is also observed 
          in vivo , excision wounds were made
          on the underside of wings of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 week-old</TIMEX> chicks. To avoid
          variations in genetic background, for each bird one wing
          was treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> and the other with cCAF, and
          treatments were applied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other day</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 days</TIMEX>. In
          normal wound healing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at days 2-3</TIMEX> and
          disappeared during remodeling which begins around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 10</TIMEX>
          after wounding. Therefore, tissues were collected at days
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 and 7</NUMEX> after wounding and analyzed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunostaining</ENAMEX> and western blot analysis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A&
          2B). Immunoblot analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> extracted from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> wounds confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> deposition begun by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and that it increased dramatically by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2C, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>). In contrast, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX>, cCAF-treated wounds
          already contained as much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> as the control at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX> and
          that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> is dramatically reduced by the
          ongoing processes of repair (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 2C</ENAMEX>, cCAF). Thus, the
          addition of the chemokine to wounds shifts the peak of TN
          in the wound tissues to earlier stages of wound healing
          than in control wounds.
        
        
          Effects of cCAF and its peptides on the production
          of FN
          Cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> is abundantly present in granulation
          tissue, is produced primarily by the wound fibroblasts
          and myofibroblasts. Fibroblast cultures treated as for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>, produced much more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>, as shown by immunolabeling
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3A& 3B</ENAMEX>) and immunoblot analysis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3E).
          Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>, this effect can only be accomplished by the
          whole cCAF molecule; immunolabeling and immunoblot
          analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-peptide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3C& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3E</ENAMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C-peptide</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3D& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3E</ENAMEX>) revealed
          similar FN levels to control. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>, cCAF did not
          affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> mRNA levels (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3F). 
          In vivo , immunostaining for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> after making excision wounds, showed that levels of
          this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> are high in the healing tissues and that
          treatment with cCAF increased FN accumulation in the
          granulation tissue (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4B</ENAMEX>). Immunoblot analysis
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FN</ENAMEX> extracted from excision wounds showed that by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> after injury the cCAF-treated wounds contained more
          FN than the control wounds but that the levels by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX>
          are similar to those of the control (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4C).
          Taken together the results in culture and 
          in vivo suggest that the chemokine
          does not stimulate FN gene expression but rather may
          directly or indirectly affect stability of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
          Therefore, we tested the possibility that cCAF treatment
          leads to stability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> by stimulating decrease
          in matrix degrading enzymes. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, plasmin
          generated from plasminogen by plasminogen activator (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>)
          degrades much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>. To investigate whether activity
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> might be decreased with cCAF treatment leading to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>, we examined the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>
          activity. Our results showed that there is no detectable
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> activity in untreated or treated fibroblasts whereas
          the activity is high in RSV-transformed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEFs</ENAMEX> (tCEFs; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          5A) which are known to produce high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] .
          Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> does not appear to be activated by cCAF, we
          tested the possibility that the stability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> is due to
          a decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMP</ENAMEX> production/activation. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-7</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-10</ENAMEX> (stromelysins) are the most
          active proteases for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>, but these molecules have not
          been isolated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>. However, we can test for
          general activity of these MMPs in the chicken system by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zymography</ENAMEX> using casein as substrate (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B). Whereas
          the positive control (trypsin) was able to digest the
          substrate at specific sites in the gel, the supernatants
          of our treated fibroblasts did not. This suggests that
          the stromelysins are not active in this system or that
          our test is not sensitive enough. To further investigate
          whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX> are involved in the cCAF induced high levels
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> will require evaluation of matrix-degrading enzymes
          specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and is an ongoing project in our
          laboratory as we obtain/develop probes for theses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX>.
          However, another possible mechanism for the cCAF-induced
          FN accumulation could be linked to an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>-C <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knockout mice</ENAMEX> show decreased accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> in
          wounded tissue and this decrease has been hypothesized to
          be due to disrupted incorporation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> into the matrix
          in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>-C [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX> ] . To determine whether
          cCAF-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> production is involved in the increase in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FN</ENAMEX> observed after cCAF treatment, we used antisense
          phosphothioated oligonucleotides to inhibit TN
          production. Sense oligonucleotides did not have an effect
          on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cCAF</NUMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FN</ENAMEX> production. However, the
          antisense oligonucleotides were able to significantly
          decrease the production of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5C).
        
        
          Effects of cCAF and its peptides on the production
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> and III
          To determine whether cCAF stimulates fibroblasts to
          produce increased levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, we treated
          cultures as for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>. Immunoblot analysis for Coll I showed
          that cCAF, but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>- or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>peptides, caused a small
          increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coll</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6A). Probing the
          same blots for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coll III</ENAMEX> revealed no cCAF-induced
          difference in the level of production of this protein
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6B). 
          In vivo, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coll</ENAMEX> I was also slightly
          increased by treatment with the chemokine at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX> after
          wounding but did not increase to higher levels than the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX>, whereas the same blots probed for Coll
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> showed similar levels in treated and control at both
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 and 7 days</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6C</NUMEX>).
          The effect on Coll I could be due to remodeling of
          this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> by proteases induced by the chemokine.
          Therefore, we tested whether cCAF affects the production
          or activity of the gelatinases <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX>, or the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagenase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-1</ENAMEX>, all of which digest collagens I and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>. Using zymography, we found that treatment with cCAF
          or the peptides does not alter the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proMMP-2</ENAMEX> and
          there was no detectable levels of proMMP-9 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7A).
          However, immunoblot analysis using a polyclonal antibody
          to human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> (this reagent is not available for the
          chicken homologue of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">matrix metalloproteinase</ENAMEX>)
          showed that cCAF treatment caused a decrease in the
          amount of the collagenase <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> detected, but neither
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TIMP-1</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TIMP-2</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of these MMPs)
          levels were changed, as evaluated by immunoblot analysis
          with a monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to the corresponding human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7B).
        
        
          Effects of cCAF on migration of fibroblasts
          During healing, fibroblasts migrate into and within
          the wounded tissue and lay down the extracellular matrix
          that forms the granulation tissue. These <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ECM</ENAMEX> molecules,
          especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> together, stimulate cell migration,
          thereby facilitating the entrance and movement of
          additional fibroblasts and of endothelial cells into the
          wound tissue. Because tissues treated with cCAF have more
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> at the time that these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> are entering the
          wound and chemokines are well known for their
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemoattractant</ENAMEX> properties [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX> ] , we tested whether
          cCAF stimulates chemotaxis of fibroblasts using transwell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assays</ENAMEX>. To avoid effects of gravity on cell migration,
          the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> was inverted, the cells were plated on
          the underside of the membrane, allowed to adhere to it
          and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> was turned right side up. The cells
          were incubated overnight in standard medium to allow
          expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cCAF receptor</ENAMEX>(s) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following day</TIMEX>
          cCAF was applied at increasing doses (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100-1000 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) to
          the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> only. The migration assays were carried
          out for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hrs.</TIMEX> We found that cCAF stimulated migration
          of the fibroblasts up the concentration gradient in a
          dose-dependent manner (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8A). To test whether the
          cCAF-induced effect is due to chemotaxis, we repeated the
          transwell assay and compared cell migration when cCAF is
          added to both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>. Placing cCAF in both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> abrogated
          cell migration, strongly suggesting that this protein
          chemoattracts fibroblasts (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 8B</ENAMEX>). We also tested the
          effects of the chemokine on migration by using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cloning</ENAMEX> ring assay. In a specified length of time, cells
          treated with cCAF moved a longer distance than did
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> cells, corroborating the previous results that
          the chemokine stimulates <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell motility</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8C). 
          In situ hybridization for cCAF
          showed that the migrating fibroblasts also express higher
          levels of cCAF (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8D& <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8E</TIMEX>; see also ref. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ]
          ).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The work presented here shows that cCAF, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">IL-8</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, stimulates expression of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECM</ENAMEX> molecules
        important in development of the granulation tissue. We show
        that: 
        (i) cCAF stimulates TN expression and
        that a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aa peptide</ENAMEX> containing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal sequence
        causes the same effects as the whole molecule; 
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) in contrast to its effects on TN
        production, cCAF-induced increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coll I</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> requires the whole molecule; 
        (iii) the increase in FN <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is not
        a result of a corresponding increase in mRNA, or increase
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMP</ENAMEX> production or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> activity but appears to be linked
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> production; 
        (iv) increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coll</ENAMEX> I correlates with
        decreased levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>; 
        (v) cCAF chemoattracts fibroblasts and
        accelerates their migration; 
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vi</ENAMEX>) treatment of excision wounds with
        cCAF increased the levels of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECM</ENAMEX> molecules in the
        granulation tissue of wounds albeit with different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dynamics</ENAMEX>. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> demonstration that treatment of
        wounds with a pro-inflammatory and angiogenic chemokine
        accelerates development of the granulation tissue during
        healing by stimulating the precocious deposition of ECM
        molecules that are critical for proper healing.
        We showed previously that cCAF is highly expressed in
        the granulation tissue of wounds [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 36</ENAMEX> ] , that this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemokine</ENAMEX> and several of its human homologues stimulate
        differentiation of fibroblasts into myofibroblasts both in
        culture and 
        in vivo, and that the latter effect
        can be achieved very effectively by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15aas</TIMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 37</ENAMEX> ] . In addition to cCAF, other CXC
        chemokines have been associated with wound healing events.
        In the granulation tissue of burn wounds, expression of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groα /MGSA</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR2</TIMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGSA</ENAMEX>) was associated
        with fibroblasts, smooth muscle cells/myofibroblasts and a
        subpopulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">macrophages</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groα/MGSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>
        have also been shown to enhance re-epithelialization of
        human skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">grafts</ENAMEX> in chimeric <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 38</NUMEX> ] . It has also
        been found that several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokines can modulate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angiogenesis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] , a process that is critical for proper
        healing. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokines, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> and cCAF, are
        angiogenic 
        in vivo [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3 39 40 41</ENAMEX> ] . Others, such
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">interferon-γ10</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PF-4</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">platelet factor-4</ENAMEX>), are
        anti-angiogenic. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX>, it has been shown
        that in transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> treated with this chemokine, wounds
        heal poorly and exhibit defects in angiogenesis and
        development of the granulation tissue [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] .
        Work of others has shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> is expressed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> with differentiation of myofibroblasts and is
        important in cell migration during healing [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 42 43 44</NUMEX> ]
        . Here we show that cCAF and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-peptide stimulate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> in culture to express <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> and that this increase
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> is due to an increase in mRNA levels. The increase is
        lower for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptide</ENAMEX> treated cells; after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX> in an
        environment mimicking the wound, these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> had lesser but
        significant tenascin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels, most likely due to the
        small increase seen in mRNA. In addition, in wounds treated
        with the chemokine, TN levels are much higher at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early</TIMEX>
        times after wounding but drop by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX> after wounding. At
        this stage, the wounds are closed and are beginning to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">remodel</ENAMEX> in the cCAF-treated wounds while the granulation
        tissue in the control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX> is still maturing. These data
        taken together strongly suggest that as chemokines induce
        the differentiation of fibroblasts into myofibroblasts they
        contribute to the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> in the granulation
        tissue. Our finding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal peptide is able to
        stimulate expression of TN much like the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is
        potentially important because this small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX> may be
        useful to develop therapeutic agonists or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> for
        wound healing.
        The effect of cCAF treatment on Coll I accumulation in
        culture and in wounded tissues is small but reproducible.
        Because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> levels were also decreased by cCAF treatment,
        it is possible that the small rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coll</ENAMEX> I levels is due
        to decreased degradation of this ECM molecule by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagenase</ENAMEX>. Another chemokine that has been associated
        with Coll I production is monocyte chemotactic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> 1
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCP-1</ENAMEX>). This chemokine belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> chemokine family
        and stimulates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coll</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> production both by lung fibroblasts
        taken from areas of inflammation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] and in kidneys that
        suffer from crescentic nephritis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . The former
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCP-1</ENAMEX> increases collagen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> not by decreasing the levels of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagenase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-1</ENAMEX>, but by stimulating the production of
        TGFβ1, a well-known stimulator of collagen expression and
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIMPs</ENAMEX>, the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX>. In
        addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGSA</ENAMEX> have also been evaluated
        for production of collagen [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] . These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
        reported that treatment of normal fibroblasts with these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemokines</ENAMEX> did not affect collagen levels. It is not clear
        from their results whether the elevation in collagen
        production in normal fibroblasts may have been small, like
        that observed with cCAF, and therefore gone unnoticed.
        FN accumulation due to cCAF treatment also differs from
        that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> mRNA levels are not affected by cCAF
        treatment but the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein accumulates</ENAMEX> in culture and in the
        granulation tissue of wounds upon exposure to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemokine</ENAMEX>. By analogy with the increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Coll I</ENAMEX>, we
        hypothesized that decrease in protease levels/activity is
        involved in the accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>. Plasmin resulting from
        cleavage of plasminogen by plasminogen activator (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>) is
        the major enzyme affecting FN degradation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>.
        However, testing for decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> activity showed that
        this enzyme is not activated even in the controls,
        therefore, it is unlikely that this would be a major
        mechanism involved in degrading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, there are
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX> that are known to degrade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>. We found that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> levels are unaffected by cCAF treatment and that
        there is no detectable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-3</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-7 and -10</NUMEX> activity as
        evaluated by casein zymography using tCEFs as control for
        production of these stromelysins. Another FN-degrading
        metalloproteinase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MT-MMP1</ENAMEX>, is unlikely to be involved
        because it also activates <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> and this enzyme is not
        activated by cCAF treatment.
        Another possible mechanism that may explain FN
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> could be an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>-C <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knockout mice</ENAMEX>
        show decreased accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> in wounded tissue and
        this decrease has been hypothesized to be due to disrupted
        incorporation on FN into the matrix in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX>-C
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX> ] . Therefore, our observation that inhibition of
        cCAF-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> production decreases the accumulation of FN
        supports the findings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knockout mice</ENAMEX>. However, this
        does not explain the unchanged FN levels with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-peptide
        treatment. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possible explanation for these findings
        could relate to the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> does not self-assemble.
        Therefore, it is possible that alterations in the
        activities of integrins or adhesive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> on other ECM
        molecules induced by the whole cCAF molecule, and not by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-peptide, could affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> accumulation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX> ] . We are
        currently pursuing studies to determine whether adhesion
        molecules or other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ECM</ENAMEX> molecules play a role in FN
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> due to cCAF-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> production.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migration</ENAMEX> of fibroblasts from the area surrounding the
        wound into the wound site is critical in order for
        contraction to occur. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>, especially in combination,
        promote migration, therefore cCAF may facilitate fibroblast
        migration by increasing TN and FN levels. However, this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemokine</ENAMEX> is also able to chemoattract fibroblasts and
        accelerate their migration in the absence of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">molecules</ENAMEX>, strongly suggesting that it contributes to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> independently of the deposition of
        these ECM molecule. These findings suggest that during
        wound healing, cCAF produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> fibroblasts
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemoattracts</ENAMEX> additional fibroblasts that contribute to the
        production of these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ECM</ENAMEX> molecules, which then support
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration</ENAMEX> of both fibroblasts and other cells in the wound
        tissue.
        TGFβ1 is another factor known to stimulate myofibroblast
        differentiation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECM</ENAMEX> production and accelerate wound
        closure and healing. However, this growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> has a
        strong inflammatory effect that leads to excess fibrosis
        and scarring. In addition to greatly increasing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation of Colls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TGFβ1</ENAMEX> has been shown to
        also increase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> production. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cCAF</ENAMEX> (and maybe other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemokines</ENAMEX>), on the other hand, may have a subtler, more
        controlled effect, promoting the earlier appearance of a
        normal granulation tissue without leading to excess matrix
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> and scarring.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Our results strongly suggest that cCAF plays an
        important role in wound repair by activating fibroblasts to
        form early granulation tissue, through cell migration,
        myofibroblast differentiation and production/accumulation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ECM</ENAMEX> molecules that are critical for proper development
        of the healing tissue of wounds. This is a previously
        unknown role for chemokines and, unlike other inflammatory
        factors that promote granulation tissue formation, cCAF
        does not appear to stimulate increased fibrosis. If similar
        behavior is seen in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokines</ENAMEX>, it could be a
        promising target in designing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that promote formation
        of granulation tissue in poorly healing wounds without
        causing excess scarring.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Reagents
          All tissue culture supplies and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIzol</ENAMEX> reagent
          were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco-BRL</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cCAF</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15a</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">a.</ENAMEX>) were synthesized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gryphon Sciences</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, CA) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX> peptide (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28a</TIMEX>.a) was
          made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milligen Biosearch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Rafael</ENAMEX>, CA). Secondary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> used: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and anti-rabbit horseradish
          peroxidase, anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Red</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) and anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FITC</ENAMEX> (DAKO: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carpinteria</ENAMEX>, CA). Primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> used: mouse anti-chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Coll I</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coll III</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX>,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hybridoma Bank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>), rabbit anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> TN
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemicon, Temecula CA</ENAMEX>). Rabbit anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TIMP-2</ENAMEX> and mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TIMP-1</ENAMEX> were the kind gift of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tai-Lan Tuan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECL</ENAMEX> reagents were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham; Vectashield</ENAMEX> mounting medium from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vector</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratories</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burlingame</ENAMEX>, CA); <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> assay kit from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biocoat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transwells</ENAMEX> from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biocclusive</ENAMEX> bandage from Johnson&Johnson
          Medical (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Cell culture
          Primary chicken embryonic fibroblasts were cultured as
          previously described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] . Briefly, primary
          fibroblasts were isolated from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-day-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> embryos
          and cultured for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 days</TIMEX>. These cultures were passaged
          once and used as secondary cultures at a density of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> ×
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX> cells<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/35</NUMEX> mm plate. Due to the use of primary cells
          rather than cell lines, there are variations in cellular
          responses between sets of cells. Therefore, internal
          controls were always included and results from different
          batches of cells were not averaged. Secondary cultures
          were treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml cCAF [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nM</ENAMEX>] or its terminal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptides</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">199/tryptose phosphate broth</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> donor
          calf serum. This dose of cCAF was chosen because it was
          the optimal dose for inducing differentiation of
          myofibroblasts, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> known to produce large amounts of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECM</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> was changed and new cCAF or peptides
          added <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 days</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Immunoblotting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Proteins</ENAMEX> were extracted from the cells after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 days</TIMEX> of
          treatment, using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIPA</ENAMEX> buffer containing protease
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein concentrations</ENAMEX> were determined using
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> assay kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were
          adjusted to contain equal amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proteins</ENAMEX>
          were separated on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5%</NUMEX> Doucet gels [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] and transferred
          to nitrocellulose was performed using a wet-transfer
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apparatus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>) at 100 V for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> min. The membranes
          were blocked for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTBS</ENAMEX> and then
          incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4°C</NUMEX> in primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:50</TIMEX>
          anti-Coll I, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coll III</ENAMEX> and anti-FN, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:100 TIMP-1,</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:500</TIMEX> anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TIMP-2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1000</ENAMEX> anti-TN), in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTBS</ENAMEX>. The membranes were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> each with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTBS</ENAMEX>, incubated in anti-mouse or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anti-rabbit HRP</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>) in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr and washed
          as above, the bands visualized using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham</ENAMEX>).
          Densitometry was performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BandScan</ENAMEX> software
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glyko</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Immunostaining
          At the end of treatment, the cells were rinsed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, fixed and permeabilized in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde with
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.15%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>. After fixation, the cells were washed
          and then incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> glycine for
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">min. Cells</ENAMEX> were blocked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> min with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> goat serum
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, incubated with primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:100</ENAMEX>) in
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA/PBS</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr at room temperature (RT), and washed
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA/PBS</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min each</TIMEX>. The cells
          were then incubated in secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA/PBS</ENAMEX>
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX>, washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> min with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and mounted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vectashield</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Zymography
          Zymography was performed using denaturing
          polyacrylamide gels according to the protocol of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ref.</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gels</ENAMEX> to test for gelatinolytic activity contained
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> gelatin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and those that tested for caseinolytic
          activity had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> casein (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 μl</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX>
          trypsin-EDTA (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco-BRL</ENAMEX>) was used as a positive control
          for the casein zymogram.
        
        
          Plasminogen activity assay
          A chromogenic plasminogen activator substrate
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Boc-Val-Gly-Arg-βNA</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AcOH</ENAMEX>) was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calbiochem</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 μl</NUMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM stock solution of substrate in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was
          added to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 μl 0.1 mM</NUMEX> HEPES buffer pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX> and heated to
          25°C. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 μl</NUMEX> fibroblast substrate was added to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">substrate</ENAMEX> and incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Absorbance</ENAMEX> was then
          read at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">405</NUMEX> nm. Positive control: Supernatant from Rous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sarcoma</ENAMEX> virus-transformed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEFs</ENAMEX> (tCEFs), which are known
          to produce high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PA.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> expression
          For these experiments we used phosphothioated
          antisense oligodeoxynucleotide (ODN), synthesized and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPLC</ENAMEX> purified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Genosys</ENAMEX>, to block the TN
          production. The sequences for the oligonucleotides were
          the same as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] except that we
          used phosphothioated oligos rather than morpholino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligos</ENAMEX>. The antisense sequence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ODN</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGAGTCCCATTGTAGTGCTCAGTTC-3</ENAMEX>'. The sense strand of this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ODN</ENAMEX> was used as control
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAACTGAGCACTACAATGGGACTCC-3</ENAMEX>'). When preparing the
          cell cultures, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 μM</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 μM</NUMEX> of antisense or sense ODN
          were added to the cells at plating. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> where
          treated with antisense or sense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ODN</ENAMEX> and cCAF every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs
          for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX> to allow accumulation of the ECM
          molecules.
        
        
          Northerns
          Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIzol</ENAMEX> reagent from
          untreated fibroblasts and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml</ENAMEX> cCAF for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4-48 hrs.</TIMEX> Transfer of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> to membrane was
          performed as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> probes
          were made using the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strip</ENAMEX>-EZ kit from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambion</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>). Membranes were prehybridized for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> hrs in Ambion
          Hybridization buffer at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62°C</TIMEX>, and hybridized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O/N</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62°C</TIMEX>.
          Membranes were washed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SSC/0</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62°C</TIMEX> and
          exposed to film for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6-48 hrs.</TIMEX>
        
        
          RT-PCR
          Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted as above. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> was performed
          using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promega Access RT-PCR System</ENAMEX>, following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>'s instructions. The first strand was synthesized
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48°C</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was amplified at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">95°C 45 sec, 55°C 1 min,</ENAMEX>
          68°C 1.5 min for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> μl <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum</ENAMEX> mRNA classic 18S
          primers from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ambion</ENAMEX> were used to quantify total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          levels. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primers</ENAMEX> used for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> amplification: sense
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>'AAATGCATCTGCGAGGGC, antisense
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGAAGCTTGTTATTGCAGTCCTTCGG</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wounding</ENAMEX> experiment
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX>-thickness excision wounds (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 0.5</NUMEX> ×
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.5 cm</NUMEX>) were made on the underside of the wings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week-old</TIMEX> chicks, using a scalpel blade. The left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> was
          treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> alone, and the right wing with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 </NUMEX>g
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cCAF</ENAMEX>. The wounds were photographed immediately after
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wounding</ENAMEX> and then covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biocclusive</ENAMEX> bandage. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 </NUMEX>l
          vehicle or cCAF were deposited through the bandage onto
          the wound using a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-gauge needle. This procedure was
          repeated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> thereafter on
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 3, 5 and 7</TIMEX>. Samples were collected at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 3 and 7</TIMEX>
          post-wounding for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECM</ENAMEX> analysis. All experimental work
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> reported here was done under full compliance
          with our animal protocol approved by appropriate campus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Preparation and staining of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> sections
          At the specified time points, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> were euthanized
          with sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pentobarbitol</ENAMEX>. The wounded wings were
          collected and fixed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> hrs in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde and
          decalcified for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> formic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. The tissue was embedded in paraffin
          and sectioned. Sections were stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masson</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trichrome</ENAMEX> to visualize interstitial collagen. Other
          sections were immunolabeled for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> or TN. Sections were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deparaffinized</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3</TIMEX> changes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hemo-De</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min each</TIMEX>
          and rehydrated in a descending ethanol series (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 min</ENAMEX>
          each: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>). After rinsing
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hr.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autofluorescence</ENAMEX> and non-specific staining were
          blocked for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> glycine in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, followed by
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evans Blue</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> to quench red blood cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autofluorescence</ENAMEX>. Sections were incubated with anti-FN or
          anti-TN <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:50</TIMEX>) in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> hr at
          room temperature. After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 min washes</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> min with
          anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alexa antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:200</ENAMEX>) in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. They
          were then washed and mounted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vectashield</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein extracts</ENAMEX> of wounds
          Wound tissues were immediately frozen on dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and
          stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-70°C</TIMEX>. To extract <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, the tissue was
          ground with glass beads in a mortar and pestle on dry
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. The powdered tissue was dissolved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RIPA</ENAMEX> containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> and a cocktail of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protease inhibitors</ENAMEX>, and
          vortexed vigorously. After centrifugation, the
          supernatant was used in immunoblots.
        
        
          Transwell assay for migration
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 × 10 6cells</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> μl <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX> medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> serum
          were plated on the underside of transwell membranes by
          inverting the insert. They were allowed to adhere for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> was turned right side up and both
          sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> were filled with serum-containing
          medium. The cells were allowed to recover for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs, and
          express the cCAF <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. Then the medium in the top
          well was changed to serum-free medium containing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-1000</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml cCAF</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 %</NUMEX> serum (positive control); serum free
          medium alone was placed in the bottom well. The cells
          were allowed to migrate towards the chemoattractant for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hrs.</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> on the underside of the membrane were
          removed with a cotton <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swab</ENAMEX>. The membranes were then fixed
          and stained with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> toludine blue in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX>. To
          determine the number of migrated cells, all cells on the
          upper side of the membrane were counted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> for
          chemotaxis was performed by adding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> ng/ml cCAF to
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transwell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cloning</ENAMEX> ring assay for migration
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 × 10 6cells</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> μl <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX> medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> serum
          were plated in a cloning ring in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> mm plate. They were
          allowed to adhere for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX>, then the ring was removed,
          the culture medium added to the plate and the cells
          photographed on a phase-contrast microscope to record the
          area of the cells and the edge of the ring. cCAF was then
          added at various doses (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0-1000 ng/ml</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following day</TIMEX>
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was changed and the cells were treated again.
          On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third day</TIMEX> after plating, the cells were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographed</ENAMEX> once more before the experiment was
          terminated. To determine the extent of cell migration, we
          measured the distance between the edge where the cloning
          ring was at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> and the edge of the culture
          delineated by the migrating front of the cells on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rdday</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          In situhybridization
          Fibroblast cultures and probes were prepared as
          described previously (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Martins</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bissell</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>).
          Briefly, probes were prepared as follows: <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 μg</NUMEX> of
          pGEM1/cCAF cDNA was transcribed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 1/2</NUMEX> h at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37°C</NUMEX> in a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> μM each of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-UTP
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Corp.</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTP</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> mM
          dithiothreitol, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> of T7 polymerase (Amersham
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corop</ENAMEX>.). The probe was separated from the free
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nucleotides</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sephadex G-50</ENAMEX> column equilibrated with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM tris(hydroxymethyl) aminomethane pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> mM
          NaCl, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>. For 
          in situ hybridization, cells were
          fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , incubated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> glycine for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX>, dehydrated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> min each in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 70</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>,
          and allowed to dry. Prehybridization was performed in a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> formamide, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> piperazine- 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>' -bis(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-ethanesulfonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>) pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M NaCl</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli tRNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>)
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">55°C</NUMEX> with gentle shaking. The hybridization
          solution was the same as the prehybridization solution
          but contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 6cpm/ml of the cCAF <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> or with the
          same number of counts of the vector <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> and incubated
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> h with gentle shaking. At the end of this
          period, the cultures were washed twice with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2×</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more washes with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1×</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100</TIMEX>, all at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">55°C</NUMEX> in the shaker.
          The cultures were allowed to dry, then covered with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emulsion</ENAMEX> and processed as described previously [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ]
          .
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX>'s contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JEF</ENAMEX> carried out all studies except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> antisense
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inhibition</ENAMEX> experiment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LW</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QJL</ENAMEX> initials carried out the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> antisense studies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMG</ENAMEX> initials conceived and designed,
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JEF</ENAMEX>, the studies, and contributed to manuscript
        preparation and submission.
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final manuscript.
      
      
        List of abbreviations used
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">cCAF chicken Chemotactic and Angiogenic Factor</ENAMEX>
        CEFs chicken embryo fibroblasts
        Coll collagen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECM</ENAMEX> extracellular matrix
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FN</ENAMEX> fibronectin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">interleukin</ENAMEX>-8
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1 monocyte chemotactic</ENAMEX> protein-1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGSA</ENAMEX> melanoma growth stimulatory activity
        MMP matrix metalloprotease
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> plasminogen activator
        TGFβ1 transforming growth factor β1
        TIMP tissue inhibitor of metalloprotease
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> tenascin
      
    
  
