
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytosolic</ENAMEX> PLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> specifically hydrolyzes 
        sn-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> arachidonate from phospholipid
        providing the precursors for many different lipid mediators
        including prostaglandins and leukotrienes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] . These
        lipid metabolites play a role in acute inflammatory
        responses and also regulate normal physiological processes.
        Certain prostaglandins are required for female reproduction
        and kidney function [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5</NUMEX> ] . Because of its important
        role in controlling levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arachidonic acid</ENAMEX> (AA), much
        attention has been focused on the regulation of cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> activation, with particular emphasis
        on the role of its phosphorylation and Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-mediated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">translocation</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7 8</NUMEX> ] .
        cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is regulated by controlling its
        cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">localization</ENAMEX> and access to membrane-phospholipid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">substrate</ENAMEX>. An amino <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX>, calcium-dependent lipid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CaLB</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C2</NUMEX>) domain regulates Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-mediated cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocation to intracellular
        membranes [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . In vitro, membrane docking via the C2
        domain is necessary and sufficient for catalysis and
        release of AA [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . Binding of calcium ions by the cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> C2 domain is essential for the lipid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> in vitro [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] and translocation in vivo [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] . In response to an increase in [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i , cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocates to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Golgi and ER</ENAMEX>,
        however translocation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> occurs at a lower [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein kinase</ENAMEX> pathways play major roles in cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> activation, and regulation by the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> has received particular attention. cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is phosphorylated by mitogen activated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX>) kinases, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p42/p44 ERKs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX>, on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">505in</ENAMEX> vitro [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ] and in response to receptor
        stimulation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 18 19 20 21</NUMEX> ] . In addition to
        phosphorylation by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX>, it has been shown that cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is also phosphorylated on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ser</ENAMEX> 727by
        MAPK-interacting kinase I (MNKI) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] and on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ser</ENAMEX> 515by
        Phosphorylation of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> may also play a role in
        regulating cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> function in certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> models.
        Phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">505has</ENAMEX> been extensively studied
        because it is readily detected due to a characteristic
        electrophoretic mobility shift when analyzed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 16</NUMEX> ] . The importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">505phosphorylation</ENAMEX> in
        regulating cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> has been demonstrated in different
        cells and in vitro <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> by using cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> containing a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">S505A</NUMEX> mutation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 22</NUMEX> ]
        . However, the mechanism whereby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> 505phosphorylation
        regulates cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> function has been elusive. In vitro
        studies have demonstrated that dephosphorylated cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is catalytically active and that Ser
        505phosphorylation increases activity by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only ~30 percent</NUMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> ] . In contrast, cells expressing the cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> S505A mutation fail to release AA in
        response to a low dose of calcium ionophore, but release
        similar amounts of AA as cells expressing wild-type cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in response to high dose ionophore [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> ] . From these studies, it has been suggested that cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Ser 505phosphorylation</ENAMEX> may have a role
        in regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">translocation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . A previous study
        demonstrated translocation of cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S505A</ENAMEX> in response to Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ionophore,
        but did not address the kinetics of translocation,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">translocation</ENAMEX> in response to a physiological agonist, or
        differences in targeting [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
        To better understand the regulation of cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX> pathway and Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+, we
        investigated the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MEK inhibitors</ENAMEX> on AA release,
        cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">505</ENAMEX>, cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocation kinetics, and [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madin</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darby</ENAMEX> canine kidney
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDCK</ENAMEX>) cells. We found that inhibition of MEK1 by U0126
        significantly inhibited AA release and this was correlated
        with inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> inhibition
        only partially affected cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> phosphorylation and had no effect on
        the kinetics of Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-mediated cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocation to membrane. In
        addition, using cells expressing wild-type cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 with S505A</ENAMEX> or S727A mutations, it was
        found that translocation kinetics and membrane targeting in
        response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> or ionomycin was similar to wild-type cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . These data suggest that MEK1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibition</ENAMEX> reduces cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> catalytic activity and AA release
        independently of phosphorylation and translocation.
      
      
        Results
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> inhibition on AA release, ERK
          activation, and cPLA <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2Ser</ENAMEX> 505phosphorylation
          To study the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX> pathway in cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> activation, quiesced MDCK cells were
          treated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">inhibitor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U0126</ENAMEX>, and the effect on
          AA release, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation, and cPLA 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 gel</TIMEX> shift determined (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). For
          equivalence with the imaging studies, cells expressing
          EGFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> were used in all experiments.
          EGFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was expressed to similar levels as
          endogenous enzyme but did not contribute significantly to
          AA release in stably transfected cells. However,
          EGFP-cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is functional since it
          dose-dependently catalyzes release of AA when expressed
          in cells that lack endogenous cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sf9 cells</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immortalized</ENAMEX> mouse lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> from cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Î± <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knock-out mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . In order
          to enhance AA release in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endogenous</ENAMEX> cPLA
          
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , it is necessary to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-express
          the enzyme several fold as previously reported [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytosolic</ENAMEX> PLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> has been shown to mediate Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-induced AA release in MDCK cells treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX> in experiments using the group <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Î±-specific inhibitor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pyrrolidine-1</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> ] . To measure cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 mediated</NUMEX> AA release, EGFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -transfected MDCK cells labeled with
          [ 3H]-AA were incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 or 10 Î¼M</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U0126</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> prior to stimulation with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX>, or
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX>. AA release was measured at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 min</TIMEX> because we
          have shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>- and IONO-stimulated AA release peaks
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 3 to 5</TIMEX> min post-stimulation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
          Agonist-induced AA release was inhibited dose-dependently
          by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A) with the highest U0126 concentration
          used (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX>) reducing AA release by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72-80%</NUMEX> with all
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agonists</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I</ENAMEX>). This inhibition was independent of
          the total amount of AA released, since AA release
          stimulated by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> IONO was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-fold greater than release
          stimulated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX> IONO or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, but the percent
          inhibition by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX> was similar. Treatment of MDCK cells
          with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 Î¼M</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PD098059</ENAMEX>, a less potent inhibitor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> ] , resulted in a ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> reduction in AA release in
          response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> IONO (data
          not shown). Thus, in MDCK cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1</ENAMEX> inhibition
          significantly reduces the ability of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 to hydrolyze</NUMEX> AA from membrane
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phospholipids</ENAMEX>.
          The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1</ENAMEX> inhibition on activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p42/</ENAMEX>p44
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ERK</ENAMEX> measured by immunoblot analysis using
          phospho-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> in cells treated with U0126
          and stimulated as above was determined (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B). Work in
          our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> has shown that recognition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> by
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">phospho</NUMEX>-ERK <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> correlates with an increase
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 30 31</NUMEX> ] . Interestingly, the
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">phospho</NUMEX>-ERK immunoblots revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX> were
          constitutively activated in untreated, quiesced MDCK
          cells and activation was not enhanced further by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IONO (Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B, left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation was diminished
          by increasing concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">U0126</ENAMEX> and was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">quantitatively</ENAMEX> inhibited after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX> incubation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 Î</TIMEX>¼M
          U0126. U0126 decreased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> or
          IONO stimulation in the same fashion as in unstimulated
          cells. Consequently, there was a direct correlation
          between the reduction of AA release (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A) and
          inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B) in MDCK cells
          treated with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX>.
          Because cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is a target of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX>
          signaling cascade, we assayed the effect of MEK1
          inhibition by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX> on cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> phosphorylation by analyzing gel
          shift of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . Phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ser</ENAMEX> 505results
          in a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX> of its electrophoretic mobility (gel
          shift) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 16</NUMEX> ] . In unstimulated cells, EGFP-tagged and
          endogenous cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> were nearly completely gel shifted,
          indicating that most cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was phosphorylated on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ser 505</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1C), which is consistent with the observation that ERKs
          are constitutively activated. Incubation with U0126
          resulted in a partial reversal of the gel shift although,
          at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U0126</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately half</NUMEX> of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> remained phosphorylated on Ser 505.
          Thus, unlike the quantitative effect of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX> on ERK
          activation, inhibition of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MEK1</TIMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX> only partially
          reversed the gel shift of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . The reversal of the gel shift was
          similar in cells treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 10</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX>.
          Due to the increased molecular weight of the EGFP-tagged
          cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forms of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> did not separate as well, making the
          gel shift more difficult to visualize, but generally
          mirrored the gel shift characteristics of the endogenous
          cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . These results suggest that, in
          response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">MEK1</NUMEX> inhibition, there is a quantitative,
          dose-dependent decrease in AA release that correlates
          well with the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation, but not with the
          extent of cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Ser 505phosphorylation</ENAMEX>.
          To further investigate whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX> pathway
          played a role in regulating AA release independent of Ser
          505phosphorylation, we treated cells with anisomycin,
          which activates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MAPK homolog p38</ENAMEX>, but not the
          MEK1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . Activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p38</ENAMEX> in response
          to anisomycin treatment was analyzed by immunoblotting
          using an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-phospho</ENAMEX>-p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A). The
          immunoblots demonstrate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min treatment in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
          anisomycin resulted in phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p38</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unstimulated</ENAMEX> MDCK cells and in cells treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and ionomycin treatment in the absence of
          anisomycin only weakly increased <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">p38</NUMEX> phosphorylation. As
          expected, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK inhibitor U0126</ENAMEX> did not significantly
          affect anisomycin-stimulated p38 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phosphorylation</ENAMEX>. In
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> experiments, anisomycin treatment did not induce
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation nor interfere with inhibition of ERK
          activation by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U0126</ENAMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B). We have
          previously reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX> is also selectively
          activated in anisomycin-treated macrophages [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] .
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, pretreatment of cells for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> min with
          anisomycin resulted in maintenance of the cPLA 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 gel</TIMEX> shift in the presence of U0126
          in unstimulated cells and in cells stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 10</NUMEX> Î¼M IONO (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C). AA release assays show
          that, in MDCK cells treated with anisomycin, U0126
          resulted in an AA release reduction of ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67-76%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2D)
          similar to the inhibition observed without anisomycin.
          These results demonstrate that activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> is required for AA release even under conditions
          where cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Ser 505phosphorylation</ENAMEX> is
          maintained, suggesting an alternative role for the
          MEK1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/ERK</ENAMEX> pathway in regulating cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> .
        
        
          [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">iincrease</ENAMEX> is independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX>
          pathway
          One explanation for the decrease in AA is that U0126
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibits</ENAMEX> [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i mobilization in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX>, thereby preventing translocation of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . In chick ventricular myocytes,
          inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1/ERK by PD98059</ENAMEX> inhibits
          zinterol-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mediated</NUMEX> AA release, but also inhibits
          zinterol-induced stimulation of [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i cycling in electrically stimulated
          cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . In MDCK cells, extracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> acts via
          P 
          2Y2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> to elicit an IP 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> -mediated [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i increase [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX> acts to
          increase [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i by permeabilizing cell membranes to
          Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+. To determine the effect of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX> on intracellular
          Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+mobilization by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX>, we
          utilized single-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluorescence</ENAMEX> microscopy on cells
          loaded with the calcium indicator <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fura2</TIMEX>. Analysis of the
          [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i increase in individual cells reveals
          the heterogeneity in the response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, although most
          cells exhibited [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i spikes of similar magnitude and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3Aand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3B</TIMEX>, thin lines). Analysis of the [Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i increase in several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3Aand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3B</TIMEX>, thick line) revealed that although the duration
          of the [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i increase elicited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> in control
          cells was the same as in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">U0126</NUMEX>-treated cells,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-4</TIMEX> min, the amplitude of the [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i increase was slightly higher (~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>)
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the U0126</TIMEX>-treated cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX> elicited a sustained,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supraphysiological</ENAMEX> [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i increase in cells that was also
          slightly enhanced by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3Cand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3D</ENAMEX>). These
          experiments demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U0126</ENAMEX> does not decrease [Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i mobilization, and the inhibition of
          AA release by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX> cannot be ascribed to a failure in
          [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i mobilization.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cPLA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2translocation</ENAMEX> is independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX>
          pathway
          The effect of inhibition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX> pathway by
          U0126 on translocation of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was investigated. Although there is
          no inhibition of [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i release by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX> and little effect
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">505phosphorylation</ENAMEX>, it is possible that MEK1
          inhibition by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">U0126</ENAMEX> prevents cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocation by another mechanism.
          To investigate this possibility, cells were transfected
          with a wild-type cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> fused to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EYFP</ENAMEX> (EYFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) and the distribution of EYFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was imaged in response to [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i transients elicited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and
          sustained [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i elevations elicited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX>, in the
          presence and absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U0126</TIMEX>. Following stimulation with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>, there was a rapid translocation of EYFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> that was unaffected by
          U0126 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A,4<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). In response to physiological agonists
          that elicit transient [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i changes, only a small fraction of
          the cPLA 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 translocates.</TIMEX> This observation is
          consistent with our previous results [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] and has been
          demonstrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirabayashi et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . Most studies
          of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translocation</ENAMEX> have utilized
          ionophore, which elicits a large, supraphysiological
          sustained increase in [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15 25 35 36 37 38</NUMEX> ] , or
          agonists that produce a sustained [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i increase [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . Under these
          conditions, a large proportion of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> binds to membrane. These studies
          show extensive translocation to the endoplasmic reticulum
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>), nuclear envelope and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15 35 36 38</NUMEX> ] . We
          found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U0126</ENAMEX> also failed to alter extensive EYFP-cPLA
          
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> in
          response <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 Î</TIMEX>¼M IONO (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4C,4<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>). These results
          demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> inhibition has no effect on cPLA 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 translocation.</TIMEX>
        
        
          Translocation of phosphorylation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site mutants</ENAMEX> S505A
          or S727A is similar as wild-type cPLA <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          Phosphorylation of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ser</ENAMEX> 505has been hypothesized to
          play a role in Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-mediated translocation since Ser
          505phosphorylation is required for cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mediated</NUMEX> AA release in response to
          low-dose, but not high-dose, ionophore [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] .
          Translocation of cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S505A</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> has been reported
          in response to ionophore stimulation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] , but the
          effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">505phosphorylation</ENAMEX> on the kinetics of
          translocation, targeting, and in response to a
          physiological agonist was not investigated. MDCK cells
          were co-transfected with EYFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and a cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">S505A</NUMEX> mutation fused to ECFP
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECFP</ENAMEX>-cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 S505A</ENAMEX>). Using dual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EYFP/ECFP</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imaging</ENAMEX>, we were able to directly compare translocation
          of both constructs in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. The resting
          distribution of EYFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was similar to that of ECFP-cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S505A</ENAMEX> and, in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>
          followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX>, the pattern of translocation of
          EYFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was similar to ECFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> S505A (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5panels A and B, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>).
          Analysis of the increase in fluorescence at the Golgi
          with respect to time demonstrates that the rates of
          translocation of cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S505A</ENAMEX> elicited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> followed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX> are very similar (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5C). As previously reported [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> ] , the cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> S727A mutation has a similar
          phenotype on AA release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as the S505A</TIMEX> mutation and Ser
          727was found to be phosphorylated in tandem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> 505.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imaging</ENAMEX> experiments were performed using EYFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and ECFP-cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S727A</ENAMEX> and we found that the
          distribution of EYFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was identical to that of ECFP-cPLA 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 S727A</TIMEX> before and after stimulation
          with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> IONO (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> panels A and B, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>). Analysis of
          the increase in fluorescence at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> with respect to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> demonstrates that the rates of translocation of cPLA
          
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and the cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S727A</ENAMEX> elicited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IONO</ENAMEX> are very
          similar (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6C).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX> regulates cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX> phosphorylate cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ser 505</ENAMEX>. The results of this study
        demonstrate that this pathway is required for cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mediated</NUMEX> AA release independent of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">505phosphorylation</ENAMEX> and extend our previous work in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] by demonstrating that this alternative
        role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX> pathway is not involved in regulating
        [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i change or cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocation kinetics or targeting,
        but is required for optimal hydrolytic activity and AA
        release.
        The results shown here demonstrate that inhibition of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U0126</ENAMEX> quantitatively inhibits both ERK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> and AA release in MDCK cells in response to
        [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i mobilization. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> inhibitor
        PD098059, a less potent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">inhibitor</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] , also
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibited ATP</ENAMEX>- and IONO-induced AA release (data not
        shown). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> was found to be constitutively phosphorylated
        in our study using MDCK cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX>, in contrast to
        what has been reported previously for MDCK-D 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> , a subclone of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDCK</ENAMEX> selected for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adrenergic</ENAMEX> receptor expression [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39 40</NUMEX> ] . However, a
        side-by-side comparison of MDCK cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDCK</ENAMEX>-D 
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 subclone</TIMEX> (kindly provided by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
        Insel, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSD</ENAMEX>) demonstrated constitutive activation of ERKs
        when both are grown at low density (not shown). However, at
        high density ERKs are less active and can be further
        activated by phorbol ester (not shown).
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDCK</ENAMEX>-D 

        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells, without constitutively active
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX>, AA release is delayed after [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i mobilization, and is temporally
        correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] , whereas in MDCK
        cells with constitutively active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERKs</ENAMEX>, AA release is rapid,
        with significant AA release measured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> s after [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i increase [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . This temporal
        correlation between AA release and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation has also
        been reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAF</ENAMEX> stimulation [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 41</NUMEX> ] . These results support the observations made here
        that ERK activity is required for phospholipid hydrolysis
        independently of cPLA 
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 translocation.</TIMEX>
        cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mediated</NUMEX> AA release must be preceded
        by translocation of the enzyme to its membrane substrate
        which is a Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-dependent process and is a function of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">calcium-dependent</ENAMEX> lipid-binding (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C2</NUMEX>) domain. cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocates primarily to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> in
        response to a transient [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i changes and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> in
        response to a sustained [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i increase [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . The reduction in AA
        release by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhibition</ENAMEX> did not involve a failure in [Ca
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i release or translocation. These
        results show that translocation is necessary but not
        sufficient for optimum hydrolytic activity.
        Measuring cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocation is not a trivial matter
        when investigating mechanisms of AA release. For example,
        cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> constructs with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">S505A</NUMEX> mutation have
        long been recognized as unable to support AA release in
        response to physiological agonists or low-dose ionophore
        when transfected in cells. In contrast, cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S505A</ENAMEX> is active in vitro and
        phosphorylation only modestly increases the activity of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enzyme</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17 24</NUMEX> ] . Interestingly, the inhibitory effect
        of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">S505A</NUMEX> mutation on AA release is obviated by a high
        [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i increase. In light of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observations</ENAMEX>, it is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ser</ENAMEX> 505phosphorylation
        may alter the [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i sensitivity of the enzyme, its rate of
        translocation, its intracellular targeting or, as has been
        previously suggested [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] , the ability of cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to release from a non-membrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequestering</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. Although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> report has shown that cPLA
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S505A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">translocates</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> in
        response to ionophore, we were able to directly compare
        rates of translocation between cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 S505A</NUMEX> to a physiological agonist and
        found no difference between translocation rates or
        intracellular targeting. We also demonstrated that there
        was no difference in translocation rates or intracellular
        targeting between wild-type cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S727A</ENAMEX>, which has the same phenotype as
        S505A with regard to AA release when transfected into
        cells. Thus, the role of cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> phosphorylation in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mediating</NUMEX> AA
        release remains unclear.
        Although the alternative mechanism whereby the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> regulates cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is not known, it is possible that it
        affects membrane properties and/or cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> conformation that promotes optimal
        hydrolytic activity. It is also possible that the
        alternative mechanism is due to phosphorylation of cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> on a novel site by a kinase that is
        downstream of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX> pathway or phosphorylation of a
        regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Translocation</ENAMEX> to membrane is a critical regulatory step
        for the action of cPLA 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> because it is necessary for access to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">substrate</ENAMEX>. In this study we demonstrate, however, that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> with membrane when phosphorylated on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">505is</ENAMEX> not sufficient for its full activity in vivo.
        This is demonstrated by the results showing that inhibition
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX> pathway significantly blocks AA release but
        has no effect on [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
        i mobilization or cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> translocation and targeting.
        Diminution of AA release by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK1/ERK</ENAMEX> is also independent of
        cPLA 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> phosphorylation on Ser 505.
        Consequently, our results demonstrate in living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> that
        the translocation process and subsequent catalytic activity
        on the membrane are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> independently regulated steps.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-cPLA 2fusion</ENAMEX> constructs
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> encoding the full-length human cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> was cloned into the vector pEGFP-C3
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>) to create pEGFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XbaI/PstI</ENAMEX> fragment from a cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Î± <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clone</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">S505A</ENAMEX> or S727A
          mutations [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] was inserted into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XbaI/PstI</ENAMEX> site in
          pEGFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> to generate pEGFP-cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S505A</ENAMEX> and pECFP-cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 S727A.</ENAMEX> Different fluorescent-protein
          tagged constructs were produced by exchanging the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NheI/BsrGI</ENAMEX> fragment containing the fluorescent protein
          coding sequence between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EYFP</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECFP</ENAMEX>. All
          constructs were confirmed by sequencing.
        
        
          Cell culture
          MDCK cells obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX> were cultured in DMEM
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 U/ml penicillin, 100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          streptomycin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.292</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml glutamine (growth medium) in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. Subconfluent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Ã— 10</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3cells/cm 2</ENAMEX>) were transfected with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼g</NUMEX> of the relevant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fugene-6</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehringer Mannheim</ENAMEX>) in DMEM
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 U/ml penicillin, 100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          streptomycin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.292</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml glutamine (serum-free medium)
          following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s protocol. Stable lines
          expressing EGFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> were generated by growing
          transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in growth medium for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> d, supplementing
          the growth medium with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geneticin</ENAMEX> (antibiotic
          G418-sulfate), and culturing for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional 2 wk</NUMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geneticin</ENAMEX>. Cells expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> fluorescence were
          selected using a fluorescence-activated cell sorter. The
          EGFP-positive cells were maintained in growth medium
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geneticin</ENAMEX>. For imaging studies,
          MDCK cells were plated on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>-bottomed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> mm culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dishes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MatTek</ENAMEX>) at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Ã— 10 3cells/cm 2in</ENAMEX> growth medium and
          incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>, transfected with the relevant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX>(s), changed into serum-free medium to quiesce the
          cells, incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>, and used <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Immunoblotting
          Stable EGFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> transfectants were grown on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mm
          dishes at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Ã— 10 3cells/cm 2in</ENAMEX> growth medium for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>,
          then quiesced in serum-free medium <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. Cells were
          scraped into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold lysis buffer: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chloride</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">magnesium chloride</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          glycerol, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î</NUMEX>¼M sodium
          vanadate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM tetrasodium pyrophosphate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM sodium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fluoride, 10 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> leupeptin, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml aprotinin.
          Lysates were centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX>, and protein
          concentration of the supernatant was determined by the
          bicinchoninic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> method. Laemmli electrophoresis sample
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5Ã—</ENAMEX>) was added to the lysates, and
          were performed using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> Î¼g <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lysate protein</ENAMEX>,
          phospho-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p38</ENAMEX>, and rabbit
          polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> for cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Dual imaging microscopy of fluorescent protein
          translocation
          In order to compare the characteristics of full-length
          cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S505A</ENAMEX> or cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 S727A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">translocation</ENAMEX>, while
          controlling for cell-to-cell heterogeneity, we used a
          dual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFP/YFP</ENAMEX> imaging approach. EYFP-cPLA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 /ECFP-</ENAMEX>cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> S505A- or pECFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> S727A-transfected MDCK cells grown
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MatTek</ENAMEX> plates were quiesced overnight in serum-free
          medium, washed with and incubated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX>'s balanced salt
          solution (HBSS) additionally buffered with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM HEPES pH
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.4</NUMEX> (HHBSS). Cells were imaged using an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympus</ENAMEX> inverted
          microscope equipped with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60Ã—</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NA oil</ENAMEX> immersion
          objective, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YFP</ENAMEX> emission filters (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chroma</ENAMEX>) in a
          Sutter filter wheel, a dual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFP/YFP</ENAMEX> dichroic mirror, and
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TILL Imago CCD</ENAMEX> camera (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TILL Photonics</ENAMEX>). Excitation
          light of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">430 and 510</NUMEX> nm for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YFP</ENAMEX>, respectively,
          was provided using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Polychrome IV</ENAMEX> monochromator (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TILL</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photonics</ENAMEX>). TILLvisION software was used for acquisition
          and analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bleach</ENAMEX> values for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECFP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EYFP</ENAMEX> were
          calculated by determining the background-corrected
          fluorescence for the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> with respect to time and
          normalizing each value to the initial value. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECFP/EYFP</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorescence</ENAMEX> changes with respect to time for regions of
          interest corresponding to an area of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> membrane were
          determined by calculating the F 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">t /F</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> , where F 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> is the background- and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bleach-corrected ECFP</ENAMEX> or EYFP fluorescence at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">time</TIMEX> = t
          and F 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0</ENAMEX> is the background-corrected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECFP</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EYFP</ENAMEX> fluorescence at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">time</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">s. Fluorescence</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">normalized</ENAMEX> to the F 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0</TIMEX> value, which resulted in F 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">t /F</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> representing the fraction of total
          cell fluorescence at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX>. Final images were produced
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe Photoshop</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Calcium imaging
          MDCK cells grown on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MatTek</ENAMEX> plates were quiesced
          overnight in serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX>, washed with HHBSS
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">containing 1</ENAMEX> mM probenecid and incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î</NUMEX>¼M
          Fura2-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calbiochem</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHBSS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM probenecid, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. Cells were then washed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HHBSS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM probenecid and imaged after a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min incubation for de-esterification</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fura2</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX>.
          Single-cell imaging was performed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympus</ENAMEX> system
          described above, but using a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40Ã—</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NA oil</ENAMEX> immersion
          objective and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fura2</NUMEX> dichroic mirror and emission filter
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chroma</ENAMEX>). Fura2 image pairs illuminated at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">340 and 380</NUMEX> nm
          were taken at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hz</ENAMEX>. The [Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+] 
          i increase is expressed as the ratio
          of the background-corrected Fura2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fluorescence</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">340</NUMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">380</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nm</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Measurement of AA release
          The protocol for determining AA release is essentially
          as described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 21</NUMEX> ] . MDCK cells stably expressing
          EGFP-cPLA 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> were plated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-well plates at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Ã—
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 3cells/cm 2and</ENAMEX> incubated in growth medium <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>.
          Cells were then washed twice with serum-free medium and
          incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.25 Î</NUMEX>¼Ci [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3H</TIMEX>]-AA/well in serum-free
          medium <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. U0126 or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> was added to each well
          and the cells were then incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 min at 37Â°C</NUMEX> in
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . Cells were washed to remove
          unincorporated [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3H</TIMEX>]-AA and then incubated in HHBSS
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> with either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U0126</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>.
          Cells were stimulated with the agonist of choice and the
          medium was collected at appropriate time points. The
          medium was centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">g for 5 min</ENAMEX>, and the amount
          of radioactivity in the supernatant was determined by
          scintillation counting. Cells were scraped in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> ml <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX> for determining the total cellular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">radioactivity</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JHE</ENAMEX> carried out the Ca and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FP</ENAMEX> imaging studies,
        participated in the design and coordination of the study,
        and drafted the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DJF</ENAMEX> performed the AA release
        and Western blot studies and participated in the design and
        coordination of the study. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCL</ENAMEX> conceived of the study,
        participated in its design and coordination, and
        participated in writing the draft. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and
        approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
