
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Stroke</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> leading cause of death in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, after heart disease and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and the leading
        cause of adult disability.[ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matchar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duncan</ENAMEX>
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] claimed that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> there are ≈ 550,000 strokes in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, causing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX> deaths and leaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors disabled</ENAMEX>. The 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart and Stroke Statistical Update</ENAMEX> [
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3, 4</ENAMEX>] of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heart Association</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995, 1997</TIMEX>) states
        that ≈ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> suffer a first-ever or recurrent
        stroke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> reports were based on the
        predominately white cohort study of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Framingham</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broderick et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>] hypothesized
        that the figure of approximately <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a million</NUMEX> strokes
        substantially underestimates the actual annual stroke
        burden for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. They claimed that there were
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 731,000</NUMEX> first-ever or recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> during
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.[ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>] This estimate was derived by extrapolating from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">first-ever strokes</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stroke Study</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart and Stroke Statistical Update</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>] of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heart Association</ENAMEX> adjusted their
        estimate to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">≈ 600,000</NUMEX> first-ever or recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> each
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>.
        Population-based stroke incidence studies such as those
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Framingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>
        have substantially increased the knowledge about stroke
        trends, subtypes, risk factors and incidence rates in both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. However, these studies were conducted among
        predominately white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. Recently, epidemiological
        studies have been focusing on differences in stroke
        incidence between racial/ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Of particular
        interest are rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>; however, there is little
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> regarding stroke risk in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>. Recent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Manhattan</ENAMEX> suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> are not
        alone in the higher risk category and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> also
        appear to be at greater risk than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.[ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]
        In order to get a more accurate estimate of occurrences
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] estimated the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incidence</ENAMEX>, occurrence and characteristics of total stroke
        based on a large administrative claims database
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inpatient</ENAMEX> discharges. They
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conservatively</ENAMEX> claimed that there were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">≈ 750,000</NUMEX> first-ever
        or recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
        The primary goal of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> was to replicate the
        recent estimates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broderick et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al</ENAMEX>, [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] and to examine the trend from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 to 1996</TIMEX>. This
        was accomplished by use of a large administrative claims
        database representing a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> representative sample of all
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inpatient</ENAMEX> discharges. The administrative database
        was supplemented by appropriate adjustments for the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">430-438</ENAMEX> derived by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] to correct for some
        of the inaccuracies of the diagnostic codes.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subjects</ENAMEX> and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample Database</ENAMEX>
          This study employed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCUP</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">release 5</TIMEX>, which is a large administrative claims
          database that is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> representative sample of all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inpatient</ENAMEX> discharges. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> release of the NIS
          contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.5 million</NUMEX> discharges from a sample of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">906</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> geographically dispersed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
          Compared to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> release,[ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> release
          uses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and contains <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.2 million fewer</NUMEX>
          discharges. Similar to those of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> release, these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> also represent a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> stratified sample of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
          inpatient discharges. Stratification variables included
          region, control, location, teaching status and bedsize.
          The software program SUDAAN [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>] was used to convert raw
          counts generated from the NIS database into weighted
          counts that represent national estimates.
          Inpatient records included clinical and resource use
          information typically available from discharge abstracts.
          The NIS database includes most commonly used data
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>: patient demographics, admission <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>,
          principal and secondary diagnoses and procedures,
          expected primary source of payment, discharge status,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> and discharge weights, length of stay and total
          charges.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Analysis</ENAMEX>
          We only used the first code reported to avoid double
          counting those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> reported
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ICD-9-CM</ENAMEX> code <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">430 to 438</NUMEX> at discharge. To obtain the
          estimated number of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> cases by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICD-9-CM</ENAMEX> code, we
          multiplied the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICD-9-CM</ENAMEX> code
          by its estimated positive predictive value (PPV) for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>.[ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] The total number of hospital strokes was
          calculated by summing across codes. A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> confidence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interval</ENAMEX> was computed by utilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monte Carlo simulation</ENAMEX>
          techniques [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>] (i.e., the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PPV</ENAMEX> distribution for each
          code was simulated by using 10,000 iterations of a
          binomial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distribution</ENAMEX> whose parameters were obtained by
          pooling data from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> published <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ICD-9</ENAMEX> stroke validation
          studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5, 11, 12, 13</TIMEX>]).
          Technically, an incidence rate should include only the
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode of the disease being studied. However,
          because this database does not distinguish between
          first-ever and recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>, total stroke
          (first-ever and recurrent) rates and occurrences were
          reported. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stroke</ENAMEX> (first-ever) incidence rates were
          estimated by reducing the total <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> rates by the
          expected number of recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>. The limited data
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> suggest that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25% to 35%</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> are recurrent.[ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5, 14, 15</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX>- and
          sex-standardized and stratified incidence rates of total
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> were also estimated. These were estimated by using
          the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> census <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> figures.[ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]
        
        
          Nonhospital stroke
          Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICD-9-CM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> and secondary diagnosis
          codes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">430 to 438</TIMEX> provide virtually complete ascertainment
          of hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>, not all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are
          hospitalized. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>-based stroke incidence
          studies, [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7, 17</ENAMEX>] reported that the proportion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> without hospitalization (nonhospital
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>) was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5% and 15%</NUMEX>, respectively.
          Therefore, to estimate the total number of strokes
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and nonhospital), an appropriate adjustment was
          made in the analysis. This adjustment conservatively
          assumed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> were nonhospital <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>.
          This was a simple mean of the proportions published in
          two <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> studies (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5% and 15%</NUMEX>). Several international
          studies of westernized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have reported
          proportions ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 to 30%</NUMEX>.[ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>] The two
          published <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> proportions (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5% and 15%</NUMEX>) were also used in a
          sensitivity analysis.
        
      
      
        Results
        The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> results were compared to those of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] (in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parentheses</ENAMEX>). The NIS database contained <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">384,968</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">377,544</NUMEX>)
        patient discharges with a principal or secondary (first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">code</ENAMEX> reported) diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cerebrovascular disease</ENAMEX>. This
        was extrapolated to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2,082,005</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,977,794</NUMEX>) patient
        discharges in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1uses</ENAMEX> the ICD-9
        code-specific pooled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPVs</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] to adjust for false
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">positives</ENAMEX> and reports that there were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">712,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">682,000</NUMEX>)
        hospital strokes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>
        confidence interval of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">688,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">660,000</NUMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">737,000</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">704,000</NUMEX>). We believe that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 71,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">68,000</NUMEX>)
        additional strokes were nonhospital <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of the
        total occurrences of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>. We thus estimate that there
        were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 783,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">750,000</NUMEX>) incident and recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>). The sensitivity
        analysis on the nonhospital <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> rate produced a range
        from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">748,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">716,000</NUMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">819,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">784,000</NUMEX>).
        Of the estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">712,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">682,000</NUMEX>) hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23,700</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23,400</NUMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.4%</NUMEX>) were subarachnoid
        hemorrhages, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74,100</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">71,600</NUMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.4%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.5%</NUMEX>) were
        intracerebral hemorrhages, and the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">615,000</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">587,000</NUMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86.4%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86.1%</NUMEX>) were ischemic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>.
        The overall incidence rate for total <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> (first-ever
        and recurrent) was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">269</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">259</ENAMEX>) per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> (age
        and sex-adjusted to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>). The
        average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> age and sex-adjusted incidence rate for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">first-ever stroke</ENAMEX> was estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">208</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200</ENAMEX>) per
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke incidence</ENAMEX> rates increased
        exponentially with age for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. In addition,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had higher age-specific total <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke incidence</ENAMEX> rates
        than did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, as illustrated in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICD-9-CM</ENAMEX> code. The mean age of
        all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">72.1</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">72.1</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX>)
        were male, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX>) were white, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX>) of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> died during the hospitalization. A
        disproportionately low percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        subarachnoid hemorrhage were male (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37%</NUMEX>] versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX>
        [<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX>]), and as expected, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with subarachnoid
        hemorrhage were much younger than the average stroke
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patient</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">56.4</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56.6</NUMEX>] versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72.1</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72.1</NUMEX>] <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>). The
        inpatient mortality rates for subarachnoid and
        intracerebral hemorrhages were significantly higher than
        for the overall stroke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26%</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX>), respectively. A surprisingly high percentage of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ICD-9-CM</ENAMEX> code <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">432</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were male (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61%</NUMEX>] versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX>
        [<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX>]), and most code <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">433</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were white (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91.6%</NUMEX>
        [<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92.5%</NUMEX>]).
        Table <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2also</TIMEX> presents data on resource utilization. For
        the index hospitalization, the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> population
        had a mean length of stay of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.0</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.8</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> (median <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>) and a mean total charge of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,022</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17,711</NUMEX>) (median
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,845</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,735</NUMEX>]). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with subarachnoid and
        intracerebral hemorrhages had much longer length of stays,
        averaging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13.9</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14.0</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10.3</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10.5</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, respectively.
        Their mean total charges were also higher, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$51,193</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46,711</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24,409</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23,097</NUMEX>), respectively. The majority
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had a routine discharge or were
        discharged to a skilled nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> with rates of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX>), respectively.
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] estimated that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750,000</NUMEX>
        first-ever or recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. We conservatively
        estimate that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">783,000</NUMEX> first-ever or recurrent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33,000</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.4%</NUMEX>) increase in first-ever
        or recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> may be due to chance, but it is
        probably due to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> gain (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">262,803,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
        versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">265,229,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.9%</NUMEX> increase), and the
        increase in aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">(≥</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years old</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> to
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33,619,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33,957,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0%</NUMEX>
        increase).[ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>] The aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> effect is more
        pronounced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> aged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>+ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> who are at greater
        risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14,863,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,266,000</NUMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.7%</NUMEX> increase).[ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>] We also estimate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> charged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12.4 billion</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> treatment and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, which translates to a society cost
        of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $7 billion</NUMEX>.
        It is worthwhile to notice the remarkable consistency in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> characteristics <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1995 and 1996</TIMEX>, as
        shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. The length of stay, however, was shorter
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, although the
        total charge was higher in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. It may be due
        to a combination of inflation and inpatient healthcare
        practice changes or healthcare reimbursement regulation
        changes.
        The present study may be associated with several
        limitations. First, the validity of conclusions drawn from
        analyses of large administrative databases depends on the
        accuracy of case-defining diagnostic codes. Therefore, the
        validity of the present study is highly dependent on the
        accuracy of the positive predictive values of the ICD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-CM
        codes, which has been addressed.[ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]
        The impact of the uncertainty in the PPV pooled
        estimates was examined by constructing a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> confidence
        interval around the number of hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>. The bounds
        of this confidence interval were tight (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">688,000</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">737,000</NUMEX>),
        indicating that the point estimate had reasonable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precision</ENAMEX>.
        Another limitation of the present study is the lack of
        documented information on the rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nonhospital stroke</ENAMEX>.
        Additional data are needed to produce a more reliable
        estimate of the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> without
        hospitalization. By intentionally choosing a low
        percentage, we were confident that our estimate of the
        total annual stroke burden was not inflated. We used
        sensitivity analyses to illustrate the potential impact of
        a different true percentage. In addition, race-specific
        information was not available, which limited our ability to
        adjust for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>.
        The methodology used in the present study was the same
        as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> used in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams et al</ENAMEX>, [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] but different from
        other studies published on the incidence, occurrence and
        characteristics of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>. All those studies used
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">state-of-the-art stroke</ENAMEX> registries based in relatively
        small geographical areas (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Framingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Cincinnati/Northern Kentucky</ENAMEX>).
        Our approach might have slightly reduced internal validity,
        but it should have far greater external validity, although
        this might be somewhat compromised by the reduced internal
        validity.
        In summary, this study supports the findings of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broderick et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] by
        conservatively estimating that there are approximately
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters of a million</NUMEX> strokes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. In addition,
        we observed that there is a slight increase, although not
        statistically significant, in occurrences of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> from
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 to 1996</TIMEX>. This is likely due to a combination of the
        population gain and the aging of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
        to 1996.
        In conclusion, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> is a significant problem in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. The importance of preventive measures for a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> that has identifiable and modifiable risk factors
        must be emphasized. The reduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and
        mortality among <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> must remain a public health
        priority.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared
      
    
  
