
  
    
      
        Background
        The retina, which is exposed to both sunlight and very
        high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>, is exceptionally rich in
        polyunsaturated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acids</ENAMEX>, which makes it a favorable
        environment for the generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX>.
        For example, retinal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pigment epithelium</ENAMEX> (RPE) generates a
        number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reactive oxygen</ENAMEX> species when illuminated with
        light [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Furthermore, phagocytosis of photoreceptor
        outer segments by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> causes an increase in intracellular [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ] and extracellular H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . Oxidative stress
        has been suggested as the cause of a number of retinal
        pathological conditions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5</NUMEX> ] .
        A number of 
        in vitro studies have attempted to
        characterize the effect of oxidative stress on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX>.
        Depending on the experimental conditions, treatment of RPE
        with H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> can cause an alteration of cellular
        functions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] or cell death [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytotoxic</ENAMEX> levels
        of H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> can cause significant mitochondrial [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ] and genomic [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] DNA damage in RPE simulating the
        features of programmed cell death [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 12</ENAMEX> ] . Studies from
        other cell types indicate that early cellular events
        following H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment include morphological
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alterations</ENAMEX> and actin re-organization [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . In addition,
        activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p42/44</NUMEX>, Extracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal-Regulated Kinase</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAP kinases</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitogen-Activated</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein kinases</ENAMEX>) can occur within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> following
        cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">oxidative</ENAMEX> stress. Depending on the cell type
        examined, inhibition of the ERK activity can either prevent
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] or enhance H 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -induced cell death [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . The
        involvement of actin re-organization and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation has
        not been examined in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> under oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>.
        Lipid peroxidation products, such as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-hydroxynonenal
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-HNE</ENAMEX>), have attracted considerable attention because of
        their potential involvement in aging and in a number of
        neuropathological conditions [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE was implicated
        in the etiology of some pathological conditions in the eye.
        For example, levels of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNE</ENAMEX> increased significantly in the
        vitreous of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with proliferative vitreoretinopathy
        compared with controls [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . Further, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNE</ENAMEX> forms a
        stable adduct with rhodopsin in the photoreceptor, which
        may interfere with its functions [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE even causes
        cataracts in cultured <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> lens [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> ] . Whether
        oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> can cause accumulation of cellular
        belong to a group of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> that include
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">steroid</ENAMEX>, retinoid, thyroid hormone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and others [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22 23</NUMEX> ] . There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> types of PPARs: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ±</ENAMEX> is
        expressed predominantly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>, heart, kidney, brown
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adipose</ENAMEX> and stomach mucosa, and is important for lipid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">catabolism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> is found in adipose tissues and is
        important for adipogenesis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ²</ENAMEX> is found in most tissues,
        but its role is less well defined. RPE cells express all
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARs</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ²</ENAMEX> is the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">isoform</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
        ] . There is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-fold</NUMEX> induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> mRNA that reaches
        a peak at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4-hour</TIMEX> after phagocytosis of photoreceptor outer
        segments. The levels of either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ±</ENAMEX> mRNA or PPARÎ² mRNA are
        not altered under the same conditions. Increases in PPARÎ³
        in RPE cells may be important for handling the lipids
        generated during the phagocytosis of photoreceptor outer
        segments [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . Since RPE cells generate large amounts of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> during the phagocytosis of
        photoreceptor outer segments, there is a possibility that
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> may assist in defending the oxidative
        stress associated with phagocytosis.
        This study was designed to examine morphological
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alterations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> during oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>, the involvement
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ERK MAP kinase</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNE</ENAMEX> and to test the hypothesis that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> activation can prevent oxidative damage on RPE cells.
        The human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RPE</ENAMEX> cell line, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ARPE-19</ENAMEX>, and primary cultures of
        adult human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RPE</ENAMEX> were used in this study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ARPE-19</ENAMEX> is a
        spontaneous occurring, non-transformed RPE cell line which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expresses RPE</ENAMEX> specific markers (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRALBP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RPE65</ENAMEX>)
        and exhibits morphological polarization and tight junctions
        similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native RPE</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] .
      
      
        Methods
        
          Materials
          WY14643, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , azelaoyl <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAF</ENAMEX> and ciglitazone were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cayman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann Arbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">171883</ENAMEX> was
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Biochemicals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA). AG126
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PD98059</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calbiochem</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>,
          CA). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Hydrogen peroxide</ENAMEX> and other pharmacological and
          general biochemical reagents were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) unless otherwise stated.
        
        
          Cell cultures
          
          ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] were obtained
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collection</ENAMEX> and grown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">DMEM/F12</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> heat-inactivated fetal bovine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> mM glutamine. 
          Human primary RPE cultures were
          established from donor eyes obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Eye Bank & Laboratory</ENAMEX>. The globe was sectioned
          at the ora serrata, and the lens and vitreous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> were
          removed. The eye cup was then filled with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> dispase
          (prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>) containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">1Ã— antibiotic</ENAMEX>-antimycotic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reagents</ENAMEX> (final concentrations: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> units/ml Penicillin
          G, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml Streptomycin</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.25 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amphotericin B</ENAMEX>)
          and incubated in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">~30 minutes</TIMEX>. RPE cells were then
          removed under a dissecting microscope, dissociated by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trituration</ENAMEX> using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasteur</ENAMEX> pipette, and then plated on
          poly-L-lysine (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/liter in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>) coated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>-cm
          2culture dishes. The cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was then expanded by
          sequentially subculturing into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25-cm</NUMEX> 2tissue culture
          flasks, then to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75-cm</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2tissue</ENAMEX> culture flasks. Cells of
          passages <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#3-#6</NUMEX> were used for this study. The culture
          medium consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> heat-inactivated fetal bovine
          serum, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> mM glutamine and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Ã—</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX>-antimycotic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reagents</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Cell viability
          Cells were plated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates (human primary
          RPE: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> cells/well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ARPE-19</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX>
          cells/well, unless otherwise stated) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>, fed with
          serum-free medium or treated with testing agents
          (prepared in serum-free medium) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> followed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment for a day, then the
          viability from each treatment was determined by the MTT
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bromide</ENAMEX>) assay [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . Culture medium was removed after
          treatment and then <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> MTT <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>) was added to each well. The cultures
          were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> in a tissue culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incubator</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> solution was then removed and the
          cells in each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> were lysed by the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î</NUMEX>¼l
          dimethyl sulfoxide. The plate was placed on a shaker for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> at room temperature to complete the lysing
          process, then the optical density of each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> was
          measured by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> with a filter setting
          at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">570 nm</NUMEX> (reference filter setting was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">630 nm</NUMEX>). When a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pharmacological</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> was used in the experiment, the MTT
          reading from cultures treated with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> alone was
          used <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as 100%</NUMEX> cellular viability.
        
        
          Actin staining
          This was performed as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carter et al.</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
          ] . Cells grown on coverslips were treated with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for various period of time as
          indicated in figure legends, washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX>-buffered saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>), then fixed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.7%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> (prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>). The
          cultures were then washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, extracted
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-20Â°C</ENAMEX> acetone for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX> followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> washes
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. Each culture was then stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
          Red-phalloidin (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR) prepared in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> bovine serum albumin for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> at
          room temperature in a lightproof box. The cultures were
          then washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, mounted with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GEL/MOUNT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biomedia, Foster City</ENAMEX>, CA). The slides were
          examined under a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon</ENAMEX> microscope <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Eclipse E600</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Instruments Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>). Cells were photographed
          digitally at a fixed exposure time by using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Photometrics CoolSNAP</ENAMEX> fx camera (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roper Scientific, Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AZ</ENAMEX>) and the software <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MetaVue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meta Imaging Series</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.5</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Imaging Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Downingtown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunohistochemical</ENAMEX> and immunofluorescent
          staining
          Cultures grown on coverslips were used in this set of
          experiments. Phospho-ERK was detected by mouse
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">phospho</NUMEX>-ERK <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA, used at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1500</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vectastain ABC</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vector Lab.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burlingame</ENAMEX>, CA) with diaminobenzidine
          as the chromogen. Cellular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein adducts</ENAMEX> were
          detected by rabbit anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calbiochem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, used at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:250</ENAMEX>) followed by anti-rabbit
          secondary antibody labeled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dako Corporation</ENAMEX>,
          Carpinteria, CA). The cultures were then mounted with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GEL/MOUNT</ENAMEX>. The slides were examined under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">microscope Eclipse E600</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon Instruments Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Melville, NY</ENAMEX>). Cells were photographed at fixed exposure
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon digital</ENAMEX> still camera DXM <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Instruments Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Melville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>) and the software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ACT-1</ENAMEX> version <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.11</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Nuclear staining
          Cells grown on coverslips were treated with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for various periods of time as
          indicated in figure legends, fixed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> with
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.7%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> (prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>), stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          bisbenzimide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst 33258</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> at room temperature, mounted with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GEL/MOUNT</ENAMEX>, then observed under a fluorescent microscope
          as described in the previous section.
        
        
          Western blot analysis
          RPE cells were plated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-150</ENAMEX> flasks <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>, fed
          with serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> for a day, then treated with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> as indicated in figure legends. For
          sample preparation, cultures were detached with a scraper
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> then centrifuged. The cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> were suspended
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> Î¼l <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RIPA</ENAMEX> lysis buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP-40</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          Na-deoxycholate, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM
          Phenylmethylsulfonyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX> (PMSF), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml
          Aprotinin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM Na 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> VO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ) and incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>.
          Each sample was further homogenized by passage through a
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>-gauge needle followed by an addition of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼l</NUMEX> PMSF
          (stock solution: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 mM</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were then incubated
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and subsequently centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPM</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. The supernatant from each sample
          was collected and an aliquot was taken for protein
          concentration determination by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro BCA Protein</ENAMEX> Assay
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagent Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein samples</ENAMEX> were
          stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-70Â°C until</TIMEX> ready for electrophoretic analysis.
          Equal amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein samples</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼g/well) were heated
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> min then loaded onto <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          polyacrylamide gels. BenchMark pre-stained <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> ladder
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Invitrogen</ENAMEX> life technologies, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>) was
          used as molecular weight standards. Following
          electrophoretic separation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were transferred
          to nitrocellulose membranes. Equal loading and
          appropriate transfer of each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lane</ENAMEX> was confirmed by
          staining the membrane with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ponceau S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). Membranes were blocked in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat</ENAMEX> dried
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX>, washed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> mM Tris-buffered saline
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pH 7.5</NUMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> Tween-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> (TBST) and probed with
          primary antibody <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. Membranes were washed
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX> and then incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> at room
          temperature with a secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> followed by washing
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX>, immersed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> western
          blotting detection system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Pharmacia Biotech</ENAMEX>,
          Buckinghamshire, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX> and then exposed to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> X-ray film (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>). The films were analyzed
          by densitometry using a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ChemiImager 5500</TIMEX> imaging system
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AlphaEaseFC</ENAMEX> software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpha Innotech Corporation</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Leandro</ENAMEX>, CA). Results, expressed as percentage of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, from replicate experiments were pooled and
          averaged. The primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> used in this set of
          experiments were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> (anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK 1/2</NUMEX>, used at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5000</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-phospho</ENAMEX>-ERK, used at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>; anti-PPARÎ³,
          used at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:2000</ENAMEX>) or from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calbiochem</ENAMEX> (anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE, used at
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          Unless otherwise stated, results of cell viability
          experiments were pooled from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">replicate samples</ENAMEX> derived
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> independent experiments, and expressed as mean Â±
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEM</ENAMEX>. Statistical analyses were performed by analysis of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">variance</ENAMEX> (one-way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX>) followed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bonferroni</ENAMEX> test
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Cytotoxicity of H 2O <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2toward</TIMEX> primary human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RPE</ENAMEX> and
          ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells
          Initial experiments analyzing the cytotoxic effect of
          oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> on primary cultures of human RPE cells
          indicated that H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 mM or less</NUMEX> did not affect
          cellular viability. Higher concentrations caused a sharp
          decrease of viability in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RPE</ENAMEX> such that a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX>
          treatment of cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> lowered the viability to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX> of
          controls (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A, squares). This concentration lowered
          the viability of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RPE</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62%</NUMEX> after a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4-hour</TIMEX>
          treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A, circles).
          In a set of analogous experiments, ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells
          treated with various concentrations of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours or 24 hours</TIMEX> showed that
          a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4-hour</TIMEX> treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> did not affect viability. An
          increase of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations beyond <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> decreased
          viability such as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> decreased the viability to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX> of
          controls in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B, circles). Treatment of
          cells with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> caused a dose-dependent
          decrease of viability with a LD 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~1.35 mM</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B, squares).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX> in RPE cells
          appears to be affected by the density of cells in
          cultures [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . To study this phenomenon, ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plated</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates with densities of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX>
          or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> cells/well were subjected to H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment. Cells grown in a
          high-density culture were indeed more resistant to H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> as compared to those grown in a
          low-density culture (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C). For example, H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> mM reduced cellular viability
          to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49% or 94%</NUMEX> of control in cultures with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000 or 40,000</NUMEX> cells/well, respectively.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2O 2induced</ENAMEX> morphological alterations and
          formation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE-adducts
          To analyze morphological changes of RPE cells treated
          with a cytotoxic concentration of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells were treated with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for various periods of time and then
          processed for actin staining. Without H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> appeared
          thin and diffuse in control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A, arrow). At
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-min</TIMEX> after treatment, these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> appeared to round up
          and significant ruffling occurred at the edge of their
          plasma membrane (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B, arrows). Overall thickening of
          stress fibers occurred at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> after treatment in
          addition to the membrane ruffling (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C, arrows).
          Additional morphological changes after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,2</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E,2F</ENAMEX>) included
          distinctive dense bands at the periphery of some cells
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2D, arrows), peri-nuclear staining of actin fibers
          in other cells (which made the nuclei prominent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2E,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arrows</ENAMEX>) and microspikes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2F, arrow) on the cell
          surface of some cells.
          Subsequent experiments with immunofluorescent staining
          indicated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment of ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> led to the formation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> adducts both
          in the cytoplasm and nucleus, presumably as a result of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lipid-peroxidation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A,3<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). Various <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> bands on
          Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blots</ENAMEX> were positive for anti-HNE antibody
          reactivity, further intensified as a result of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 3C</ENAMEX>). Densitometry
          measurements were performed to estimate the collective
          increase of band intensity in each lane between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kd</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kd</ENAMEX>. Results derived from a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> independent
          experiments indicated that treatment of cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> caused an increase of intensity to
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.7</NUMEX>- or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.1</NUMEX>-fold of control,
          respectively.
          Though there was significant cytoskeletal alterations
          and lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> after H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment, nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">staining</ENAMEX> using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bisbenzimide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33258</NUMEX>) indicated that most cells
          maintained normal nuclear morphology at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          4A, untreated cells; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> after treatment).
          Nuclear condensation increased with length of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> exposure, which was clearly evident
          at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> after H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 4C</ENAMEX>, arrows), and even
          more prominent at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX> after treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4D).
          These results suggest that H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment caused apoptosis in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX>.
          Nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condensation</ENAMEX> appeared to start at the edge of the
          culture (relatively lower density area, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4C, arrows)
          and spread to the center part of the culture (higher
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">density</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4D) over time. This phenomenon is
          consistent with the viability assay in which higher
          density cultures were more resistant to oxidative stress
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C).
        
        
          Effect of oxidative stress on PPARÎ³ protein
          expression
          During rod outer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> ingestion, there is a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] and an up-regulation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> mRNA expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX>, experiments were
          performed to determine if H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> could induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PPARÎ³ protein</ENAMEX>
          expression over the control levels. ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells were
          treated with various concentrations (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM)
          of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> and processed for
          Western blot analysis. Results indicated a slight
          induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PPARÎ³ protein</ENAMEX> levels in some experiments.
          This induction, however, was not apparent in other
          experiments (Results not shown). Densitometry analyses
          from a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> independent experiments indicated
          that treatment of these cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> caused an alteration of
          band intensity to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">108%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">113% or 104%</NUMEX> of controls,
          protein level after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-min or 12-hour</TIMEX> H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment, either (results not
          shown). A separate set of experiments also indicated that
          treatment of primary human RPE cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> did not induce PPARÎ³
          protein expression over the control levels (results not
          shown).
        
        
          Prevention of oxidative stress induced cytotoxicity
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> agonists
          Even though H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> did not increase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> protein
          expression significantly as indicated in the previous
          study, experiments were performed to determine whether
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> agonists could activate the existing PPARÎ³ thus
          preventing H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX> in RPE cells.
          Cells were pretreated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> agonist <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 overnight</TIMEX> followed by H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> (without 15d-PGJ 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) and processed for the MTT
          viability assay. Results indicated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> prevented H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX> in primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human RPE</ENAMEX> cultures in a dose-dependent manner (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A).
          Subsequent experiments with ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells also indicated
          this saving effect. While H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX> mM, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> mM or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM lowered
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ARPE-19</ENAMEX> viability to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46% or 28%</NUMEX> of control,
          respectively; pretreatment of these cells with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼M
          15d-PGJ 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> raised the viabilities to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84%</NUMEX>
          or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68%</NUMEX> of control, respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B). Cells stained
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst 33258</ENAMEX> indicated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> prevented H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced nuclear condensation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          4E; compare this with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4D). The other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> agonists,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ciglitazone</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] , azelaoyl <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAF</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LY171883</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> ] , however, were not effective (tested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 1-10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Î¼M</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> independent experiments for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, results not
          shown). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PPARÎ± agonist WY14643</ENAMEX> had some saving effect
          at a high concentration (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 Î¼M</NUMEX>), however, the difference
          was not statistically significant (results not
          shown).
        
        
          Activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> by H 2O 2
          A set of experiments was performed to determine the
          effects of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> on ERK activation. ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells
          were treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> and processed for
          immunohistochemical staining using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against
          phospho-ERK. Untreated cells showed a faint phospho-ERK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staining</ENAMEX> while there was an apparent increase of
          phospho-ERK staining in the cytoplasm and nuclei in H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treated cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6A,6<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). A
          separate set of cultures was treated with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> and then processed for
          Western blot analysis. This H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment of the cells caused only a
          slight alteration in ERK levels but led to a
          dose-dependent increase of phospho-ERK, with a maximal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulation</ENAMEX> observed at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.5 mM</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6C). Densitometry
          analyses from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> independent experiments indicated that
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> caused an increase of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p42ERK</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ERK2</NUMEX>)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.7</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18.8</NUMEX>- or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>- fold of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, respectively. Similar treatment caused an
          increase of p44 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ERK1</NUMEX>) phosphorylation to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>-,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15.7</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21.4</NUMEX>- or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX>-fold of control, respectively. The
          phospho-ERK in H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> remained higher than
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> after treatment (results not
          shown).
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> inhibition on H 2O 2induced
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX> in ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
          Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> appeared to be an early event
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX>, experiments
          were performed to determine if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of ERK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> could affect the cytotoxicity caused by H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells were pretreated with
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> PD98059 (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> inhibitor which functions upstream
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] ) followed by H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> challenge. Results from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          independent experiments indicated that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> could
          prevent low-dose (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> mM) H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced cell death slightly. In
          contrast, it enhanced high-dose (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX> mM) H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced cell death. These effects in
          either case were not remarkable (results not shown). This
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> at concentrations <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">higher than 10 Î</NUMEX>¼M was toxic to
          ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells by itself and could enhance H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> toxicity (results not shown).
          In a separate set of experiments, ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells were
          pretreated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> AG126 (a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> tyrosine kinase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibitor</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] ) followed by H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> challenge. The treatment of cells
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX> mM, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> mM or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> decreased the cellular viability to
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40% or 22%</NUMEX> of control, respectively. Pretreatment of
          cells with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AG126</TIMEX> raised the viability to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>
          compared to H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment only), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.005</NUMEX>)
          or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>) of control, respectively. AG126 at
          concentrations <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">higher than 10 Î</NUMEX>¼M was toxic to ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
          cells by itself and could enhance H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> toxicity (results not shown).
          Both AG126 (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) could prevent H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ARPE-19</ENAMEX>, a
          set of experiments was also performed to determine
          whether these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX> saving effects.
          While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment reduced the viability to
          ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> of control, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AG126</TIMEX> raised this viability to ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> raised the viability to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. A combination of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> did not raise
          the viability above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> alone (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
          Cytotoxicity of oxidative stress on RPE
          Results from this study indicated that both primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human RPE</ENAMEX> cultures and ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells were susceptible to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment. It is important to point
          out that H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> showed a very steep dose-response
          curve in primary RPE cultures under our experimental
          conditions such that an increase of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> mM
          for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> treatment caused a decrease in viability from
          ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100% to ~10%</NUMEX> of control (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). Though the H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> titration curve in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ARPE-19</ENAMEX> was not
          as steep as observed in primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> treatment of
          these cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> could decrease the cellular
          viability to ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of control while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> did not affect cellular viability
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B). The sharp dose-response curves demonstrated in
          this study suggests that it is important to have an
          effective cellular anti-oxidation mechanism to prevent
          the build-up of oxidative stress over a critical level.
          An increase of oxidative stress in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> is associated with
          an increase of cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">catalase</ENAMEX>, metallothionein [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ]
          and glutathione S-transferase [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] , which should serve
          as a protective mechanism to decrease the cytotoxicity
          caused by H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">reactive oxygen species</ENAMEX>.
          This protective mechanism declines with age because a
          study analyzing metallothionein levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> of macular
          region showed a dramatic decrease in aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> (mean
          age = <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80-yr</NUMEX>) as compared to those from younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>
          (mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">58-yr</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . A separate report concluded
          that there was also an age-dependent decrease of catalase
          activity in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] . These studies suggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> are more susceptible to oxidative stress induced
          damage, which may contribute to age-related RPE
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dysfunction</ENAMEX> and vision loss. The oxidative stress induced
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> cytotoxicity can be aggravated by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">zinc deficiency</ENAMEX>, as
          previously reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tate et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
          Significant morphological changes were observed in RPE
          cells treated with a cytotoxic concentration of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . Actin fiber re-organization was
          noticed as early as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> after treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
          Those images presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2D,2<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2Fare</ENAMEX> three
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of RPE cells at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hr</TIMEX> after H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment. The cells shown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2D</TIMEX> and
          2F are commonly seen at different locations on the same
          slide. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2D, the dense peripheral bands of actin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> were very prominent in some cells and the high
          intensity fluorescence caused an impression that the
          cells were relatively empty. The thickening of dense
          peripheral bands in this study was in contrast to
          previous observations in endothelial cells. For example,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhao</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> reported that cultured pulmonary
          endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> underwent a morphological change
          that was accompanied by an accumulation/increase in
          stress fibers running across the cells while the dense
          peripheral bands of most cells were disrupted or
          eliminated [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . Similar observations on endothelial
          cells were made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundqvist</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . The dense
          peripheral bands are important in cell-cell adhesion,
          which maintains the structural integrity. While it is
          apparent that endothelial cells used in those studies and
          epithelial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> used in this study respond differently
          to H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , the underlying reason for this
          difference is currently unknown. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> may speculate that
          RPE cells use this build-in mechanism to defend the
          oxidative stress that they are constantly exposed to. We
          currently have no data to support or dismiss this
          possibility. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2E, some cultures responded to H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment by a perinuclear
          distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">actin fibers</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2F, we observed
          microspikes at the periphery of the cells. A detailed
          study of microspikes by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> indicated that these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> consist of actin, the actin binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kd</ENAMEX>/fascin and myosin [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . The perinuclear staining
          and microspikes of cells under oxidative stress in this
          study are very similar to those observed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huot et</ENAMEX> al.
          in endothelial cells treated with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] . The functional significance
          of these structural changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> after H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment is not clear. There is a
          possibility that the appearance of microspikes around the
          cells under stressed conditions is an adapted behavior of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in order to attach to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">substratum</ENAMEX> firmly.
          Prolonged H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment led to cell death with the
          appearance of condensed nuclei is an indication of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4C,4<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>). This general finding is
          consistent with that observed by others [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 12</ENAMEX> ] .
          It is of interest to note that cultures with a reduced
          density are more vulnerable to H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C). One
          straightforward explanation for the vulnerability of
          low-density cultures treated with H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is that more molecules of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> were present in these
          low-density cultures, which caused a lower viability. If
          this were the case, a mathematic analysis of the H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> molecules per <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> should be able to
          estimate the cytotoxicity in this experimental system.
          For example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in a culture plated at a density of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX> cells/well should result in a viability close to
          twice of that generated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> cells/well and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
          times of that in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> cells/well. Results from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1Cindicated that the viability of each condition above
          was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49% or 11%</NUMEX>, respectively. It is apparent that H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> cells in cultures of
          lower density (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> cells/well) than expected. Because
          the result could not always be predicted by a mathematic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">estimation</ENAMEX>, there is a possibility that cell-cell
          contacts and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autocrine</ENAMEX>/paracrine production in a
          culture may alter the microenvironment thus determine the
          cytotoxicity caused by H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . Since cells with lower density are
          more susceptible to oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>, there is a
          possibility that a vicious cycle exists such that when an
          area of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> loses some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent</ENAMEX> cells by
          oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>, the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> will become even
          more vulnerable to this insult.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARs</ENAMEX> in RPE
          This study indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> agonist <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> could prevent H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> cell death (Figs.
          5A,5<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band Fig</ENAMEX>. 4E). This suggests that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> can
          prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">oxidative stress induced</ENAMEX> RPE damage. This finding
          is significant given prior reports that oxidative stress
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> is an important contributing factor of age-related
          macular degeneration [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5 42</ENAMEX> ] . An earlier report also
          indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> agonists could prevent laser
          photocoagulation induced choroidal neovascularization in
          rat eyes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> eyes, which suggests the possible
          application of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> on the exudative form of
          age-related macular degeneration [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] . It is important
          to note that the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agonists</ENAMEX> tested in this
          study (ciglitazone, azelaoyl <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LY171883</ENAMEX>) were
          ineffective in saving cells under the same experimental
          conditions. Since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agonists</ENAMEX> tested
          were ineffective, this raises the possibility that the
          saving effect of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> is not through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> activation. In
          this respect, it should be noted that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> has been
          shown to exert some biological effects that are
          independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARÎ³</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44 45 46</NUMEX> ] .
          We have previously shown that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> can prevent the cytotoxicity of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol oxides</ENAMEX>, end products of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> under
          oxidative stress [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . Together with results from the
          current study, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> may have a general protective
          effect against oxidative stress itself or against
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytotoxic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> generated by oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>. It is
          important to note that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> functions as a general inhibitor of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> activities. For example, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> is a potent
          inhibitor of microglia, the macrophage-like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the
          central nervous system [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47 48 49</NUMEX> ] and shown to be
          effective in reducing the symptoms of experimental
          autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">encephalomyelitis</ENAMEX> (EAE), an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> model for
          the human <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease multiple sclerosis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] . Together,
          these results suggest that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> may be useful in
          preventing ocular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> that result from oxidative
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> or inflammation.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein adducts</ENAMEX> formation
          as a result of oxidative stress
          Oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> is a potent stimulator of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX>
          kinase activities [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15 51</NUMEX> ] . Phosphorylation of ERK
          could be observed within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-60 minutes</TIMEX> after H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). There are
          conflicting results in literature regarding whether an
          increase of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> phosphorylation is beneficial or
          detrimental to cell survival. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bhat et</ENAMEX> al. demonstrated
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-25 Î¼M PD98059</ENAMEX> could prevent H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced cell death in an
          oligodendrocyte cell line [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . In contrast, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼M
          PD98059 was shown to enhance cell death caused by H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">HeLa</ENAMEX> cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
          This reagent had no significant effect on H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treated ARPE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> cells under our
          experimental conditions. AG126, on the other hand,
          appeared to reduce the cytotoxicity caused by oxidative
          stress (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). While this suggests that inhibition of
          tyrosine phosphorylation or ERK activation after H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment might be beneficial for
          the cells, results from PD98059 could not support this
          statement.
          There is a possibility that the saving effect of AG126
          is not related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> inhibition. Under the current
          experimental conditions, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AG126</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> Î¼M was protective
          but it enhanced H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> toxicity at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼M</NUMEX>. These results
          were consistent with those reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sagara et al.</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>
          ] . AG126 belongs to a group of tyrosine kinase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tyrphostins</ENAMEX>. Many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> can
          prevent cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">oxidative</ENAMEX> stress including that
          generated by glutamate. There is no correlation between
          the kinase inhibition and the observed protective effect.
          Overnight treatment of cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AG126</ENAMEX> can increase
          cellular glutathione levels. Furthermore, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> has
          some anti-oxidant effect based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trolox Equivalent</ENAMEX>
          Activity Concentration [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] . Collectively, this may
          explain the observation that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AG126</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> Î¼M could
          partially prevent H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> can
          also function as a mitochondria uncoupler, thus it
          actually enhances H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cytotoxicity at higher
          concentrations [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] .
          An accumulation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE-conjugated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> has been
          detected in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> of aging-related diseases, including
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's disease</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX> ]
          . It also accumulates in the affected neuronal tissues of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">experimental animals</ENAMEX> experiencing brain ischemia [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55 56</NUMEX>
          ] and traumatic spinal cord injury [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNE</ENAMEX> can
          impair synaptosomal membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, glutamate
          transport and importantly, mitochondrial functions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59</NUMEX> ] . Evidence indicates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE increases neuronal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">susceptibility</ENAMEX> to oxidative stress [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> ] and serves as a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> of oxidative stress that leads to neuronal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX> ] . As indicated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Introduction</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HNE</ENAMEX> has been implicated in some ocular pathological
          conditions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> ] .
          Several <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> have attempted to document the
          formation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein adducts</ENAMEX> during oxidative
          stress by Western blot analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uchida et al.</ENAMEX> first
          reported oxidative stress caused by t-butylhydroperoxide
          or iron/ascorbate could lead to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein adducts</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hepatocytes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX> ] . Further studies by these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
          attempted to identify the common epitope recognized by
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. However, no specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was
          positively identified [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63</TIMEX> ] . More recently, the
          formation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein adducts</ENAMEX> was also demonstrated
          by Western blot analysis from the heart [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">64</TIMEX> ] , the
          liver [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65</TIMEX> ] and the kidney [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX> ] under oxidative
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>. It is important to point out that the patterns of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein adducts</ENAMEX>, as shown by these Western blot
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">analyses</ENAMEX>, were different among these studies, probably as
          a result of tissue specificity. No particular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was
          identified as a specific target for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE adduct
          formation in these studies. Results from the current
          study indicate that H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> could lead to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein adducts</ENAMEX> in the cytoplasm
          and the nuclei of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). There was a
          dose-dependent increase of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein adduct</ENAMEX> after H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> treatment with a maximal intensity
          of ~7X control at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3C). This may partially
          contribute to oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress induced ocular disease</ENAMEX>.
          Even though ocular tissues, including the retina, contain
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glutathione S-transferases</ENAMEX> that can actively detoxify
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4-HNE</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 67</NUMEX> ] , adverse events may occur if aging or
          pathological conditions hinder this normal defense from
          functioning properly. It warrants further studies to
          identify those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> species that are modified by
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4-HNE</TIMEX>.
        
      
      
        Conclusions
        This study demonstrates that oxidative stress induced by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> could lead to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX> cell death, which is
        preceded by distinct morphological changes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX> activation
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-HNE <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein adduct</ENAMEX> formation. The cell death can be
        prevented partially by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AG126</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prostaglandin</ENAMEX>
        derivative, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15d</NUMEX>-PGJ 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> may be useful
        pharmacological tools in the future capable of preventing
        oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress induced</ENAMEX> RPE cell death in human ocular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing Interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' Contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TKG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JYC</ENAMEX> were both involved in the experimental
        design and data collection. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved
        the final manuscript.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        15d-PGJ 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15-deoxy</NUMEX>-delta <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prostaglandin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">J</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extracellular signal-Regulated</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinase; 4-HNE</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-hydroxynonenal, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAP kinases</ENAMEX>,
        Mitogen-Activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein kinases</ENAMEX>; MTT
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bromide</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, phosphate-buffered saline; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARs</ENAMEX>, peroxisome
        proliferator-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPE</ENAMEX>, retinal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pigment</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epithelium</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
