
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spermatogenesis</ENAMEX> is a complex developmental process in
        which male germ cells progress through mitotic
        proliferation, meiotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> and dramatic morphological
        changes to form mature <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX>. This process is vital for the
        propagation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, and involves a large portion of
        the genome of an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> to ensure the quality and
        quantity of the final products. It is estimated that
        mutations in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 11%</NUMEX> of all genes in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> might lead to male
        sterility [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . This is likely to be true for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>
        also, considering the extremely high incidence (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>) of
        infertility in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Among the genes associated with
        male infertility is the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DAZ (Deleted</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azoospermia</ENAMEX>) gene
        family. The family includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-linked 
        DAZ genes that are present only in
        great apes and old world monkeys [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , and the autosomal 
        DAZL1 (DAZ-like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BOULE genes</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5</NUMEX> ] in all mammals. Deletion of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZ genes</ENAMEX> is found in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 10%</NUMEX> of
        infertile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> with idiopathic azoospermia [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] , and
        disruption of 
        Dazl1 causes infertility in both male
        and female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . Mutations in the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZ</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elegans</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xenopus</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] also affect the
        fertility in either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, or both sexes.
        The 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZ</ENAMEX> gene family encodes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> binding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that are expressed specifically in germ cells. DAZ
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL</ENAMEX> are expressed in the nucleus and cytoplasm of
        primordial germ cells and spermatogonia, and in the
        cytoplasm of meiotic spermatocytes [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 10</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOULE</ENAMEX> is
        expressed later, in the cytoplasm of pachytene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spermatocytes</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetic</ENAMEX> and biochemical studies
        suggest a role for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in the regulation of mRNA
        translation. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drosophila Boule</ENAMEX> mutants was
        defective in the translation of the meiosis-specific CDC25
        homologue, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twine</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL</ENAMEX> was found to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with polyribosomes in mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">testes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . More
        recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL</ENAMEX> was shown both 
        in vitro and in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-hybrid
        system to bind specifically to oligo(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>) stretches
        interspersed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>-rich segment
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTR</ENAMEX> of mouse 
        Cdc25C <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] .
        In an attempt to elucidate the function of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZ</ENAMEX> gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and to understanding
        the mechanisms of its action, we used a yeast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid
        system to isolate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> human genes encoding DAZ associated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> (DAZAPs) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them, 
        DAZAP1, is expressed predominantly in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testes</ENAMEX>. It encodes a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> binding domains
        and a proline rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal portion. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">DAZAP1</NUMEX> protein
        interacted with both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZ</ENAMEX> and DAZL 
        in vitro. It also bound to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homopolymers</ENAMEX>. We now report our characterization of the
        mouse 
        Dazap1 gene and its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein product</ENAMEX>.
        The subcellular localization of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DAZAP1</TIMEX> suggests that it is
        not involved directly in mRNA translation.
      
      
        Results
        
          Characterization of the mouse Dazap1cDNA
          Mouse 
          Dazap1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cDNA</ENAMEX> clones were isolated by
          library screening, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' end of the cDNA was
          isolated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>' RACE [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . The near fall length cDNA
          consists of a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">53 bp 5</NUMEX>' untranslated region (UTR), an open
          reading frame for a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">405</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid residues</ENAMEX>,
          and a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">362 bp 3</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GenBank Accession No: AF225910</ENAMEX>). The
          coding region shares <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89%</NUMEX> similarity with that of the
          human orthologue. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' UTR sequence is remarkably
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conserved</ENAMEX>. It contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> segments of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35 bp</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">133 bp</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> bp that share <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97%</NUMEX> similarity with
          segments in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">3</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTR</ENAMEX>, respectively. These
          segments probably contain regulatory elements.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1 protein</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>-binding domains
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBDS</ENAMEX>) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal portion that is rich in proline
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). It is highly conserved evolutionarily. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> differ in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          only, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> substitutions and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> deletions/insertions.
          The mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> shares <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89%</NUMEX> similarity and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX>
          identity with 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xenopus Prrp</ENAMEX> (for proline-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding protein</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBDs</ENAMEX> are especially
          highly conserved. They share <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98% and 97%</NUMEX> similarity and
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97% and 92%</NUMEX> identity, respectively, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between DAZAP1</TIMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prrp</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> may therefore have a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          binding specificity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal proline-rich portions
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prrp</ENAMEX> are less conserved (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX> similarity and
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX> identity). There is an insertion of a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">58 bp</TIMEX> segment
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prrp</ENAMEX> cDNA that causes a change of reading frame and
          results in a shorter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prrp</ENAMEX> with a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal end
          sequence.
        
        
          Genomic structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dazap1and</ENAMEX> chromosomal
          mapping
          Several overlapping lambda clones containing mouse 
          Dazap1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genomic</ENAMEX> sequences were
          isolated. The locations of exons were determined by PCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amplification</ENAMEX> across exon-intron boundaries following by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequencing</ENAMEX>. All but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> exon were isolated and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mapped</ENAMEX>. The genomic structure of the human 
          DAZAP1 gene was also determined by
          blasting the human genome sequence at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for</ENAMEX>
          Biotechnology Information with the human 
          DAZAP1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX> sequence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and
          the human genes have very similar structures, consisting
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exons</ENAMEX> spanning <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 28 kb</NUMEX>. All intron insertion
          sites are conserved (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBDs</ENAMEX> are encoded
          by exons <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-8</ENAMEX>, respectively.
          A pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> primers was designed from 
          Dazap1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intronic</ENAMEX> sequences that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">amplified mouse</ENAMEX> but not hamster genomic sequences. Using
          a panel of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>-hamster radiation <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX>, the mouse 
          Dazap1 gene was mapped to
          chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> placed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">27.84 cR</NUMEX> from D10Mit260 (lod >
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.0</NUMEX>) (data not shown). This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> is syntenic to human
          19p13.3 where the human 
          DAZAP1 gene is located [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 17</NUMEX> ] .
          It contains no known mutant alleles that are associated
          with infertility.
        
        
          Expression of Dazap1
          Northern analyses of adult mouse tissues showed the
          presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> 
          Dazap1 transcripts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.75</NUMEX> kb and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4</NUMEX> kb, respectively (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Only the shorter
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcript</ENAMEX> has been isolated in cDNA clones. 
          Dazap1 was expressed most
          abundantly in the testis, much less in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>, heart and
          brain, and even less in other tissues. This pattern of
          expression is similar to that of the human 
          DAZAP1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14</NUMEX>). RT-PCR analyses showed
          that 
          Dazap1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was already present in
          fetal testes at embryonic day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>, similar to 
          Dazl1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The
          expression of both 
          Dazl1 and 
          Dazap1 persisted throughout testes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, in both the prenatal and postnatal periods. 
          Dazl1 and 
          Dazap1 transcripts were also
          present in the testes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W v/W</ENAMEX> vmutant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> which
          contained diminished number of germ cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
          However, only 
          Dazap1 was expressed in a mouse
          germ cell line GCl-spg [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sertoli</ENAMEX> cell line
          MT4. The results suggest that 
          Dazap1 is expressed in both somatic
          and germ cells in the testis.
          To study the expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1 protein</ENAMEX>, two
          antibodies against mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> were generated. The anti
          DAZAP1-C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was raised against a recombinant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> containing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal proline-rich portion,
          and the anti DAZAP1-P <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was raised against an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oligopeptide</ENAMEX> containing the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid residue</ENAMEX> at
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX>. Both antibodies recognized 
          in vitro synthesized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> in an
          immunoprecipitation assay (data not shown). Western
          blotting of mouse tissue extracts detected a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> kD
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that was present most abundantly in the testis,
          and to a lesser degree in spleen, liver, lung and brain
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was also present in the ovary.
          The expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> during germ cell development
          paralleled that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). It is present at a
          low level in the testes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 days</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> which
          contained only primitive type A spermatogonia. The
          expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> increased afterward, as the testes
          contained increasing number of proliferating and meiotic
          germ cells.
        
        
          Subcellular localization of DAZAP1
          Our previous fractionation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> testis extracts
          showed that most DAZL were present in the post
          mitochondrial fraction, and some of them were associated
          with polyribosomes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . Similar analyses showed that
          a majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> in adult mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">testes</ENAMEX> was also
          present in the cytoplasmic fraction (data not shown).
          However, sucrose gradient analyses of the post-
          mitochondria fraction showed that, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL</ENAMEX>, DAZAP1
          did not co-sediment with polyribosomes (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA-binding proteins</ENAMEX> have been found to participate in
        many cellular functions, including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA transcription</ENAMEX>,
        pre-mRNA processing, mRNA transport, localization,
        translation and stability [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . A role for the DAZ
        family in the regulation of mRNA translation is supported
        by lines of circumstantial evidence, including the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL</ENAMEX> with polyribosomes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . The absence
        of DAZAP1 from polyribosomes indicates that it is not
        directly involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein synthesis</ENAMEX>. This finding is
        different from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA-binding proteins</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FXR1P and FXR2P</TIMEX>,
        that were identified through their interaction with another
        polysomal-associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA-binding protein</ENAMEX>, the fragile X
        mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . Both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FXR1P</ENAMEX> and FXR2P
        are associated with the polyribosomes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] .
        The significance of the interaction between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DAZAP1</TIMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL/DAZ</ENAMEX> remains to be defined. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> may act
        together to facilitate the expression of a set of genes in
        germ cells. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> could be involved in the
        transport of the mRNAs of the target genes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL</ENAMEX>.
        Alternatively, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> may act antagonistically to
        regulate the timing and the level of expression. Such an
        antagonistic interaction between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> interacting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA-binding proteins</ENAMEX> is exemplified by the neuron-specific
        nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA-binding protein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nova-1</ENAMEX> regulates the
        alternative splicing of the pre-mRNAs encoding neuronal
        inhibitory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glycine receptor α2</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">GlyR α2</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . The
        ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to activate exon selection in neurons is
        antagonized by a second <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA-binding protein</ENAMEX>, brPTB
        (brain<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-enriched polypyrimidine</NUMEX> tract-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>),
        which interacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nova-1</ENAMEX> and inhibits its function [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
        ] . DAZAP1 could function in a similar manner by binding to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAZL</ENAMEX> and inhibiting its function. Comparing the phenotypes
        of 
        Dazl1 and 
        Dazap1 single and double knock-out
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> may provide some clues to the significance of their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX>. 
        Dazl1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knock-out mice</ENAMEX> have already
        been generated and studied [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . The spermatogenic defect
        in the male becomes apparent only after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 7</TIMEX> post partum
        when the germ cells are committing to meiosis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Cooke</ENAMEX>,
        personal communication). The genomic structure of 
        Dazap1, delineated here, should
        facilitate the generating of 
        Dazap1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">null</ENAMEX> mutation.
        DAZAP1 was shown to bind <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> homopolymers 
        in vitro, with a preference for poly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> and poly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G.</ENAMEX> Its natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substrates</ENAMEX> have not been
        identified. Recently, the 
        Xenopus orthologue of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DAZAP1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prrp</ENAMEX>,
        was identified and characterized [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . Prrp binds to a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">340</NUMEX> nt sequence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTR</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xenopus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vg1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX>. This Vg1
        localization element (VLE) is sufficient for the migration
        and clustering of 
        Vg1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> to the vegetal cortex of
        mature oocyte. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prrp</ENAMEX> also interacts through its proline-rich
        domain with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two microfilament</NUMEX>-associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> profilin
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mena</ENAMEX>, which may facilitate the anchoring of 
        Vg1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> to the vegetal cortex. The 
        Vg1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA encodes</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
        transforming growth factor-β <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that is required for
        generating dorsal mesoderm at the blastula stage of 
        Xenopus embryogenesis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
        Sequence conservation between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBDs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> and Prrp
        suggests that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> may bind to similar <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX>. However, a BLAST search of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> for the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">340</NUMEX> nt VLE sequence failed to identify any mammalian
        sequences with significant homology. Further mapping of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA sequence</ENAMEX> within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VLE</ENAMEX> that binds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prrp</ENAMEX>, and possibly
        DAZAP1, may help to identify the natural substrates of
        DAZAP1.
      
      
        Conclusions
        DAZAP1 is an evolutionarily <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">conserved RNA</ENAMEX>-binding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. It is present at variable levels in many tissues.
        Its predominant expression in testes suggests a role in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spermatogenesis</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse testes</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DAZAP1</TIMEX> was found both in
        the nuclei and in the cytoplasm. Its absence from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polyribosomes</ENAMEX> indicates that it is not directly involved in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mRNA</ENAMEX> translation.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> Dazap1cDNA clones
          
          Dazap1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cDNA</ENAMEX> clones were isolated
          from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> testis cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#937308</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stratagene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA) using a human 
          DAZAP1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX> as a probe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' end
          of the cDNA was isolated by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>' RACE [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] , using
          prdap11 (ttgcgggccatatccttg, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#749-732</NUMEX>) as the primer for
          cDNA synthesis from mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">testis RNA</ENAMEX>, and prdap37
          (ttgttgccacgtgggcg, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#734-718</NUMEX>) and an adaptor primer as
          the primers for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplification. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were
          cloned into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA</ENAMEX> cloning vector pCR2<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>-TOPO (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlsbad CA</ENAMEX>). 
          Dazap1 clones were identified by
          colony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hybridization</ENAMEX> and sequenced. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' RACE clone
          with the longest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">UTR region</ENAMEX> and the cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clone</ENAMEX> P21
          were ligated together through a unique 
          Pml I site at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"># 722</NUMEX> to generate a
          cDNA clone (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dazap1-C</TIMEX>) with a near full-length insert.
        
        
          Chromosomal mapping of Dazap1
          
          Dazap1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genomic</ENAMEX> clones were isolated
          from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> 129SV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">genomic library</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#946305</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stragagene</ENAMEX>),
          and sequences flanking each exons were determined. PCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prdap25</TIMEX>: cacctccaggatgtgttagc and
          prdazp26:gtcaccaagggtgtctgaag) were designed from
          intronic sequences flanking 
          Dazap1 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">exon 8</TIMEX>. These primers
          amplified a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">271 bp fragment</NUMEX> from mouse but not hamster
          genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA samples</ENAMEX> of a panel of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> radiation
          hybrids containing mouse chromosome fragments in a
          hamster background were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Genetics</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntsville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AL</ENAMEX>). The presence of mouse 
          Dazap1 in the radiation hybrids was
          determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> and the results were sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">server www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gonome</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wi</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mit</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">edu/mouse_rh/</ENAMEX>index.hlmlfor
          computerized physical mapping of the gene.
        
        
          Expression of Dazap1transcripts
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> hybridization was carried out according to
          standard procedures [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse Multiple Tissue</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Northern Blot #7762-1</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clontech</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, CA). The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blot</ENAMEX> was hybridized sequentially with 
          DAZAP1 and β-actin cDNA probes,
          with stripping of the bound probes in between.
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>) was carried out as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preciously</ENAMEX> described using an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">annealing</ENAMEX> temperature of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">54°C</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . The primers were
          prdap35: agctcagggagtacttcaaga and prdap24
          :ggagcttgattcttgctgtcc for 
          Dazap1 which generated a product of
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">211 bp</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prdaz71</ENAMEX>: atcgaactggtgtgtcgaagg and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prdaz72</ENAMEX>:
          ggaggctgcatgtaagtctca for 
          Dazl1 which generated a product of
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">245 bp</TIMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primer</ENAMEX> pairs annealed across intron
          insertion <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generation</ENAMEX> of anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">DAZAP1</NUMEX> antibodies
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Antibodies</ENAMEX> were generated against both a recombinant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> produced in 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> and an oligopeptide
          synthesized 
          in vitro. The insert of a 
          Dazap1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cDNA clone P21</ENAMEX>, which
          encoded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal portion of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">DAZAP1</TIMEX> (starting from
          aa <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#197</NUMEX>), was cloned in-frame into the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Eco RI/</ENAMEX> 
          Xho I sites of an expression vector
          pET32b (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>). Sequences at the junctions
          were verified by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequencing</ENAMEX>. Milligrams of fusion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> between thioredoxin and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> were prepared and
          purified on His-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bind metal chelation resins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novagen</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were mixed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjuvant</ENAMEX> and injected into rabbits to generate the
          anti-DAZAPl-C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. An oligopeptide containing the
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 19</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammo</ENAMEX> acid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> of the mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DAZAP1</ENAMEX> was
          synthesized 
          in vitro using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethyl Laboratories</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>). The peptide was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conjugated</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLH</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> and injected into a goat.
          The anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">DAZAP1</NUMEX>-P <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> thus produced was purified on
          an affinity column containing the oligopeptide
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Western blotting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse tissues</ENAMEX> were homogenized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIPA</ENAMEX> lysis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP-40</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mM Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>) at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> g tissue per
          ml of buffer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">homogenized samples</ENAMEX> were cleared of
          debris by centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> × g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX>.
          Protein concentration of the tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">extracts</ENAMEX> was
          determined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradford</ENAMEX> method using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Protein Assay</ENAMEX> system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 50</NUMEX> μg
          of tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">extracts</ENAMEX> were separated on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          SDS-polyacrylamide gels and blotted with either the
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">DAZAP1</NUMEX>-C <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a 1/2,000</NUMEX> dilution) or the
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">DAZAP1</NUMEX>-P <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a 1/5,000</NUMEX> dilution). After
          incubation with horseradish peroxidase-conjugated
          secondary antibodies, the binding of antibodies was
          detected using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECL Western Blotting System</ENAMEX> (Amersham
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia Biotech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Fractionation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> testicular extracts
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Adult mouse testes</ENAMEX> were homogenized in a buffer
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP-40</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml</ENAMEX> of Rnasin
          ribonuclase inhibitor (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>), and a
          mixture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> provided in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Protease Inhibitors Set</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche Molecular Biochemicals</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN). Homogenates were centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">× g</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> to pellet cell debris and nuclei.
          After an additional centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> × g for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to pellet the mitochondria, aliquots of the
          supernatant were applied to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15-45%</NUMEX> sucrose gradients in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> and centrifuged in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckman</ENAMEX> SW41
          rotor at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39,000</NUMEX> rpm for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>. Fractions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>
          ml were collected from the bottom of the tubes and
          analyzed by western blotting.
        
      
    
  
