
  
    
      
        Background
        Infection with human immunodeficiency vims (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>) elicits
        an acute <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retroviral syndrome</ENAMEX> characterized by fever,
        pharyngitis, lymphadenopathy, myalgia, rash, and headache [
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 3</ENAMEX>]. Sexual transmission of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection occurs
        mostly via the intestinal or vaginal mucosa but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-I is
        also effectively transmitted by the intravenous route [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5, 6, 7</ENAMEX>].
        Recent studies have shown that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-I or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SIV</ENAMEX> virus
        rapidly penetrates vaginal, rectal, or oral mucosa
        attaching to and infecting primarily <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> where it
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">replicates</ENAMEX> and consequently spreads to lymphoid tissue and
        systemic organs [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>] [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 10, 11, 12</TIMEX>].
        Accumulating evidence has implicated virus-specific CTL
        in containing primary <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SIV</ENAMEX> infection and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-I/SIV-specific CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX> have been documented during the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early weeks</TIMEX> following infection, before a neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX>
        response is demonstrable [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>] [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 15, 16</TIMEX>]. Despite the
        rapid dissemination of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-I by mucosal routes, productive
        mucosal transmission appears to be relatively inefficient
        and is estimated to occur once in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> or more high-risk
        exposures [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. Cell-mediated immunity and direct killing
        by cytotoxic lymphocytes from the vagina and colon lamina
        propria may be an important factor in containing viral
        infection at the site of primary infection [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>] [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mucosal T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lymphocytes</ENAMEX> appear to be functionally distinct
        from those present in the peripheral circulation. While
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activated T</ENAMEX>-cells reenter lymphoid tissues and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preferentially</ENAMEX> accumulate at the site of the initial
        activation, memory <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells migrate continuously and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">randomly</ENAMEX>, similar to naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>] [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. The
        implication in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection is that, in the
        initial phase of an immune response, once primed,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag</ENAMEX>-specific memory <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells randomly enter and leave various
        lymphoid compartments but preferentially are retained in
        the lymphoid compartment where the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> was presented at
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>] [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>].
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, it is unfeasible to evaluate the
        immunological events that occur shortly after infection in
        the mucosal compartments. However, in the SIV 
        mac251 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">macaque</TIMEX> model, some of these
        issues can be addressed. SIV 
        mac251 establishes persistent infection
        in rhesus macaques and causes an immunodeficiency syndrome
        closely resembling human <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>] [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 27, 28</TIMEX>]. As in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, the clinical course of SIV 
        mac251 infection varies considerably
        among macaques. Recent evidence from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> suggests that
        macaques that express the major histocompatibility class I
        Mamu-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">01</TIMEX> molecule restrict SIV 
        mac251 replication following intrarectal
        exposure, as reported for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-I-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express the HLA</ENAMEX> B*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5701</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>], further validating this
        animal model of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-I infection. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, virus
        strain, dose, and especially route of infection can be
        defined and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>-virus interactions under different
        conditions can be assessed. Here we used genetically
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">defined Mamu</ENAMEX>-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">01</TIMEX> rhesus macaques to study the extent of
        virus-specific CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> response and the trafficking of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphocytes</ENAMEX> to the gut during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 12 days</TIMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intrarectal</ENAMEX> or intravenous transmission of the same stock
        of SIV 
        mac251 .
      
      
        Materials
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> and procedure
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mamu</ENAMEX>-A*<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-positive macaques were involved
          in this study: animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">817</ENAMEX> that was infected by undiluted
          SIV 
          mac251<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/561</NUMEX> stock virus (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Pal</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, unpublished data) by the
          intrarectal route and animal 819 by the intravenous route
          with a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:3000</ENAMEX> dilution of the same viral stock. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX> was
          drawn before infection and at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 4, 8</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> after
          inoculation with the virus. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> were sacrificed at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day 12 postinfection.</TIMEX> The spleens and hilar, axillary,
          mesenteric, iliac, and inguinal lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX> as well as
          ileums, jejunums, and colons were collected in RPMI
          medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">penicillin/streptomycin.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Isolation of tissue lymphocytes
          Mononuclear cells were isolated from peripheral blood
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX>), lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>, spleens, and intestines. Mononuclear
          cells from spleens and lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX> were isolated by
          mechanical dissociation of the tissue and consecutive
          Ficoll gradient centrifugation. Tissues from ileums,
          jejunums, and colons were treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX> (ICN
          Biomedicals, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aurora</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> followed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubation</ENAMEX> in calcium/magnesium-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBSS</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> with stirring
          at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> temperature to remove the epithelial layer. At
          this stage, pieces of tissue were fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> neutral
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">formalin</ENAMEX> and embedded in paraffin and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were cut
          and stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H&E</ENAMEX>. Microscopic examination was
          performed to ensure that all of the epithelium was
          removed and the lamina propria was intact.
          Further, tissues were cut into smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> and
          incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isocove</ENAMEX>'s medium supplemented with
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal calf serum and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">penicillin</ENAMEX>/streptomycin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">containing 400 U/ml Collagenase D</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boerrhinghem</ENAMEX> &
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannheim GmbH, Mannheim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml</ENAMEX> DNAse
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Worthington Biochemical</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lakewood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2-3 hours</TIMEX>.
          containing dissociated cells by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Percoll</ENAMEX> gradient
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centrifugation</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Flow cytometry
          Fresh mononuclear cells were directly stained with
          PE-conjugated tetrameric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gag 181, Env 622</ENAMEX>,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tat 28</ENAMEX>. PerCP-conjugated anti-CD3e (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, CA) and FITC-conjugated anti-CD8 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA) were used in conjunction with
          the tetrameric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>. In addition, cells were stained
          with a combination of anti-CD3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PerCP</ENAMEX>, anti-CD8 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> and
          anti CD4 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA) . To assess
          their proliferative ability and to confirm the
          specificity of tetramer staining of 
          ex vivo <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX>+ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX>,
          lymphocytes were cultured at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          6/ml in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> enriched with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> human serum with addition
          of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml of the appropriate peptide and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml</ENAMEX> of
          IL-2 for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days</TIMEX>. Staining with tetrameric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> was
          done afterward as described above.
          Briefly, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Ã—</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">l0 5lymphocytes</ENAMEX> isolated by Ficoll
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diatrizoate</ENAMEX> or Percoll gradient centrifugation were
          incubated with tetrameric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> as previously
          described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>] and/or selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at room
          temperature. After washing the cells twice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX> buffered saline supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX> and
          fixation in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ph</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were
          analyzed by flow cytometry using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACScalibur</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA) instrument.
        
        
          Viral load (NASBA)
          SIV 
          mac251 viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> copies in plasma was
          quantified by nucleic-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-sequence-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">amplification</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>]. Briefly, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> extracted from plasma was subjected to
          isothermal amplification with SIV 
          mac251 -specific primers. A portion of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIV</ENAMEX> wild type Gag gene was used to generate internal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASBA</ENAMEX> amplification products were detected by
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemiluminescence</ENAMEX>-based probe hybridization system.
          The assay can measure accurately tenfold changes and is
          functional over a dynamic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">range</ENAMEX> spanning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 10 4-10</NUMEX>
          7copies.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Kinetics of viral appearance and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ T-cell
          decrease in the blood
          Since the knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamu</ENAMEX>-A*<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-restricted
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epitopes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>][ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>] allows for a quantitation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> response using the tetramer technology [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>],
          Mamu-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">01</TIMEX> macaques were chosen for this study. Following
          exposure to the same viral stock of SIV 
          mac251 of macaque <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">817</NUMEX> by the
          intrarectal route and macaque <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">819</NUMEX> by the intravenous
          route, the kinetics of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> appearance in the plasma
          was assessed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASBA</ENAMEX>. Plasma viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was detected as
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early as day 8</TIMEX> in animal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">819</NUMEX>, exposed by the intravenous
          route, and was highest at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> of euthanasia (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 12</TIMEX>), as
          demonstrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C. In contrast, in animal <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">817,</ENAMEX>
          exposed by the intrarectal route, the appearance of
          plasma virus was delayed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">to day 12 postinfection</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1A) and at that time plasma viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> logs lower in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">animal 817</ENAMEX> than in animal 819 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1Aand 1C</ENAMEX>). The
          absolute number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells/mm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3blood</TIMEX> decreased by
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> in both macaques by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 12</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1Aand 1C</ENAMEX>). However,
          the absolute number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD3+ T-</ENAMEX>cells
          decreased as well, indicating that the apparent depletion
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells may be due to redistribution rather than
          loss of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells at this stage of infection.
          Since animal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">817</NUMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> thousandfold more
          virus than animal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">819</NUMEX>, these data suggest that the
          kinetics of viral appearance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in primary SIV 
          mac251 infection may depend on the
          route of challenge rather than dose.
        
        
          Virus-specific CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> response in the
          blood
          Virus-specific CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells were quantitated in the
          blood of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 0, 4</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> postinfection
          using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> tetrameric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamu</ENAMEX>-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">01</TIMEX> molecules complexed with the
          SIV 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mac Gag</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">181</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Env</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">622</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptides</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.M. Alien</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, submitted).
          In the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, virus-specific tetramer-binding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX>+
          CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> appeared earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">macaque 817</TIMEX>, exposed to
          SIV 
          mac251 by the intrarectal route, than
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">819</NUMEX> for all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antigens</ENAMEX> studied (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1Band 1D</ENAMEX>).
          Overall, the size of the virus-specific CD8+ T-cell
          response in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> was higher in animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">817</ENAMEX> and,
          interestingly, a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tat</ENAMEX>-specific CD8+
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>-cells appeared in the blood <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as day 4</TIMEX>, whereas
          in the same animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD8</ENAMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells specific to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gag</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">181</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Env 622</ENAMEX> peaked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). These data are consistent
          with previous observations on the kinetics of appearance
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>-specific CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells that recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tat</ENAMEX> 28
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epitope</ENAMEX> and underscore the importance of the immune
          response to this early SIV 
          mac251 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>][ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36, 37</TIMEX>].
        
        
          Absence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T-cell</ENAMEX> depletion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALT</ENAMEX> of
          Mamu-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">01</TIMEX> macaques
          Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">macaques</ENAMEX> were euthanized at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 12</TIMEX> and the
          relative percentages of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD8+ T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> was
          assessed in various compartments. In contrast to previous
          reports [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>] [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>], depletion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> was not
          observed in any tissues, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALT</ENAMEX> of either
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). It is possible that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> could
          have controlled viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">replication</ENAMEX> or that the tissues
          were examined too early and that depletion would have
          occurred at a latter stage of the infection. Preservation
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T-cell</ENAMEX> depletion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALT</ENAMEX> during primary
          infection may be a key event in delaying disease
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progression</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Quantitation of ex <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">vivoCD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> response in
          tissues
          Virus-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gag</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">181 CD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> response in the
          blood of macaques exposed intravenously to SIV 
          mac251 appears to peak within the
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> following intravenous exposure [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>].
          Therefore, both macaques were euthanized at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 12</TIMEX> and
          lymphocytes were harvested from several systemic tissues
          as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALT</ENAMEX>. Quantitation of the 
          ex vivo <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> population
          specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gag</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Env</ENAMEX> in the systemic tissues of
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> revealed that, in contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, the
          highest virus-specific CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> response was found in
          most tissues of animal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">819</NUMEX>, challenged by the intravenous
          route (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3and 4and Table</ENAMEX>). In the same animal, the
          percentage of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tat 28</ENAMEX> was as
          high as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> in the axillary and iliac lymph
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nodes</ENAMEX> and the spleen, respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3Aand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>).
          The number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells with different specificities
          was also higher in animal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">819 than 817</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALT</ENAMEX> and
          particularly in the jejunum and ileum lamina propria
          (Figs. 4A<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B,4C</ENAMEX>) while the size of these virus-specific
          responses in the remaining tissues of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> did
          not differ significantly (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>). These data indicate
          that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gag 181</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> responses are codominant
          and suggest that the overall higher CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> response
          in animal 819 may be related to an ongoing higher viral
          replication in the tissues of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, as reflected
          by the higher level of plasma viremia present at the time
          of euthanasia.
        
        
          Differential proliferative ability of
          tetramer-binding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in tissues of animals <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">817</NUMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">819</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX>, lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>, and lamina propria lymphocytes
          were cultured 
          in vitro in the presence of IL-2
          and the virus-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gag 181, Tat 28</ENAMEX>, and Env 622
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptides</ENAMEX> to assess the ability of the tetramer-positive
          CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">T-cell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to expand upon antigen
          stimulation. In our experimental conditions, expansion of
          CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tat, Env</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gag</ENAMEX> occurred to a
          comparable extent in most tissues and was highest in the
          blood of animal 819 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B). In animal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">817</NUMEX>, the ability
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>-specific CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> to proliferate was highest
          in the jejunum and was higher than that observed in the
          same compartment in animal 819 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A). The finding
          that the highest level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells with proliferative
          ability was in the lamina propria of the jejunum of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">animal 817</ENAMEX> challenged intrarectally is suggestive of a
          qualitative difference of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells present at the
          site of induction and of heterogeneity in the
          virus-specific CD8+ response.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The impact that the route of viral entry of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>/SIV may
        have on the virus-specific immune response and control of
        viral replication to it is not yet fully understood. Here
        we conducted a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> study using genetically defined
        Mamu-A*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">01</TIMEX> macaques to study the vims-specific immune
        response following parenteral or rectal exposure to SIV 
        mac251 This study was designed to begin
        to investigate the specificity of the immune response and
        its kinetics as well as the kinetics of viral replication
        according to the site of primary exposure and viral
        entry.
        Within the limitation of the small number of animals
        used here, the mucosal barrier delayed the appearance of
        virus in the plasma whereas the decrease in the absolute
        CD4+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> counts was equivalent. In addition, in contrast
        to other reports [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>] [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>], depletion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GALT</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day 12 postinfection</TIMEX> was not observed in either
        animal regardless of the route of challenge. It is unclear
        what is the reason for this finding. It is possible that
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> could have controlled the infection or that
        the tissues were examined too early and that depletion
        would have occurred at a latter stage of the infection.
        The finding of a higher percentage of tetramer-positive
        CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> in tissues of macaque <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">819</NUMEX>, infected
        intravenously, than in animal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">817</NUMEX>, infected intrarectally,
        may reflect a higher rate of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">replication</ENAMEX> in tissues
        of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> at the time of sacrifice. Of interest, the
        intrarectal route of infection resulted in faster kinetics
        of appearance of virus-specific CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX>, particularly
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">epitope</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, indicating the importance
        of this immune response early in infection. In the same
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>, a higher number of tetramer-specific CD8+ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>cells
        able to proliferate in response to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epitopes</ENAMEX> tested (Gag
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">181, Tat 28</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Env 622</ENAMEX>) was found in jejunum lamina
        propria than in other tissues. Unfortunately, at present,
        it is not possible to assess whether the differences in the
        proliferative ability of these cells reflect functional
        status and/or differentiation differences (effector versus
        memory) or others, in part because markers to define
        accurately these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in rhesus macaques are not
        available.
      
      
        Conclusions
        In conclusion, this study, within the limitation of the
        small number of animals used, appears to suggest that
        exposure by the mucosal site, a natural barrier to
        pathogens, delays viral appearance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. The
        differences in the relative percentage of homing markers
        may not necessarily reflect a true qualitative difference
        in the overall lymphocyte trafficking related to the mode
        of viral encounter and may depend on the time of analysis,
        since the kinetic of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">replication</ENAMEX> was delayed in the
        macaque exposed intrarectally. Nevertheless, these data
        demonstrate that a short window of opportunity to contain
        viral infection following mucosal exposure exists and that
        potentiating the effectiveness of the mucosal natural
        barrier by local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immunization</ENAMEX> may further limit or halt
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">viral replication.</ENAMEX> In fact, in a previous study, we have
        observed that it appears to be easier to protect vaccinated
        macaques by intrarectal exposure than intravenous exposure
        to SIV 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">251</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>]. In particular, since a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tat</ENAMEX> appears to be the earliest, this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> may be a key component of a preventive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>, as
        suggested by other [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>][ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36, 37, 43</TIMEX>].
      
      
        List of abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> (human immunodeficiency <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEV</ENAMEX> (high endothelial venules)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> (peripheral blood mononuclear cells)
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Competing Interests</ENAMEX>
        Competing interests: none declared.
      
    
  
