
  
    
      
        Background
        A near-universal feature of cell signaling 
        via <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> transmembrane, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coupled receptors</ENAMEX> is attenuation of a cellular
        response upon prolonged exposure to an extracellular
        stimulus [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . This desensitization process is
        well-established for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX>-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion from
        pituitary gonadotropes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] , and occurs after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 6 h</TIMEX>
        of continued exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH</ENAMEX> in rats [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] ; removal of
        GnRH permits recovery from the profound suppression of LH
        secretion, albeit rather slowly (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-4 days</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>). The
        molecular mechanisms involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX>-induced
        desensitization are poorly understood, but they do not
        appear to be due to alterations in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor expression
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] or to changes in LH concentrations in the pituitary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gland</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] .
        Earlier, we presented evidence that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>
        protein signaling, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX>, might participate in the
        regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . The mechanism
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGS</ENAMEX> action is antagonism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gα</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> either by
        accelerating its hydrolysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTP</ENAMEX>, thereby prematurely
        terminating signaling due to reassociation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gα</ENAMEX> and
        Gβγ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] , or by antagonizing interaction of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gα</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with its effector such as phospholipase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cβ</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] . A large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS genes</ENAMEX> have been identified
        in mammals based on the presence of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> core
        domain [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14 15 16</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS proteins</ENAMEX> have been described
        that interact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        i α and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">qα</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> protein <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20 21</NUMEX> ] .
        Previously, we showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RSG3</ENAMEX> was expressed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenously</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> pituitary cells and, when
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">experimentally</ENAMEX> co-expressed together with GnRH <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in
        a heterologous cell line (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">COS1</NUMEX>), it suppressed
        GnRH-stimulated inositol trisphosphate production [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        Here, those studies have been extended to include
        GnRH-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion using adenovirus-mediated gene
        transfer of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3 complementary DNA</ENAMEX> into normal rat
        pituitary gonadotropes. RGS3 was found to profoundly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inhibit GnRH</ENAMEX>-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-inositol
        phosphate accumulation. However, a calcium ionophore
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stimulated LH</ENAMEX> secretion in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RGS3</NUMEX>-expressing gonadotropes,
        confirming a specific site of action occurring at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phospholipase Cβ</ENAMEX> or earlier in the signal transduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        The initial experiments were performed to confirm our
        earlier finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> suppressed GnRH-stimulated IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> production in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] and to
        test a truncated form of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3T</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">RGS3 314-519</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ]
        for suppressive activity in the same assay (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). cDNAs
        representing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH receptor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3T</TIMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-transfected into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">COS-1 cells</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">GnRH-A</ENAMEX> treatment <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> h
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>; intracellular IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> concentrations were measured at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 sec</TIMEX> after addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -7M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH-A</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). As
        expected, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX> exerted a profound suppression of IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> production at each of the time points
        during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the 30 sec</TIMEX> after agonist treatment (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>)
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). RGS3T is comprised primarily by the consensus RGS
        domain and was originally reported to decrease the growth
        rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> and to inhibit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8</ENAMEX> receptor mediated
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase</ENAMEX> by a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3-10</NUMEX> fold as
        compared to RGS3 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] and was subsequently reported to be
        a normally expressed variant of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] . Therefore, we
        compared it to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">RGS3</NUMEX> for attenuation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX>-stimulated IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> production in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). As
        reported by others [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 37</NUMEX> ] , we found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3T</ENAMEX> was more
        potent than RGS3 (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Identification of
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-terminal 205</ENAMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> variant of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX> that has equal
        or greater potency than the full-length 519 amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> RGS3
        will facilitate the identification of RGS3 functional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein domains</ENAMEX> that are important for its activity.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS proteins</ENAMEX> are established to interact
        with various <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gα</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein subunits</ENAMEX>, thereby antagonizing
        their activities [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14 15 16 17 18 24</NUMEX> ] . Indeed, we
        previously reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3 bound Gqα</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein subunit</ENAMEX> that mediates <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>
        ] . Here, we have extended those binding studies to include
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gα proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). An RGS3-GST fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was
        incubated with an 35S-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>-Gα-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, and the amount of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">labeled Gα</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was determined using glutathione-coupled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beads</ENAMEX> to "pull down" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3-GST/ 35S-Gα-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> complex
        that was then separated and quantified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS/PAGE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). More <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gqα</ENAMEX> was bound by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>,
        although its binding was not significantly different from
        that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gzα</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giα</ENAMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">> 0.05</NUMEX>). Significant (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.05</NUMEX>) amounts of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Gi2α</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Gi1α</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Goα</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gsα</ENAMEX> also were bound
        but were not as high as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gqα, Gzα</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Gi3α</TIMEX>. These results
        confirm our previous findings that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> interacts with Gqα
        but also show that it has significant interaction with all
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Gα</ENAMEX>-proteins studied.
        The findings of the current, and an earlier study [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ]
        , demonstrate clearly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> suppresses <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor
        signaling in a heterologous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell system</ENAMEX>. Because of the
        evidence that the signal transduction pathway for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH</ENAMEX> in
        gonadotropes involves the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gqα</ENAMEX>, phospholipase
        Cβ, and cellular IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> release [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39 40</NUMEX> ] , we determined the
        effect of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX> on GnRH-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion using
        adenoviral-mediated gene transfer in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> pituitary cells
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). In these experiments, we performed a
        dose-response test that included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uninfected</ENAMEX>, adeno-β galactosidase, and adeno<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-RGS3</TIMEX> infected.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Adeno-βgal</ENAMEX> infection was used for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of the
        fraction of cells infected at each dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3,</ENAMEX>
        top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>) and as a control for the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adeno</ENAMEX>-RGS3
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX>-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>).
        Cell viability, measured as trypan blue exclusion, varied
        from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98.5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100.0%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>). The fraction of cells
        infected by the adenovirus depended on viral dose (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.O.I.; 1 M.O.I.</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> viral particle/pituitary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>) and
        ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 2%</NUMEX> (no adenovirus) to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99.5%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.O.I.</ENAMEX>).
        Adeno-βgal had no effect on LH secretion at any dose
        compared to the uninfected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>). In
        contrast, an inverse dose-related effect was observed
        between adeno<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-RGS3</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX>-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, bottom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>). RGS3 <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.O.I.</ENAMEX> was the lowest dose to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibit LH</ENAMEX> secretion (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.O.I.</ENAMEX>
        exerted near complete inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion; i.e. LH
        concentrations in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">latter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GnRH</ENAMEX>-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> did
        not differ from their cohort controls (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">> 0.05</NUMEX>).
        The profound inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX>-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion
        observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3required verification that RGS3
        expression was induced by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">adeno-RGS3</TIMEX> infection. To address
        this issue, we performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX> immunoblots (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) which
        showed an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3 protein</ENAMEX> expression in adeno-RGS3
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.O.I.</ENAMEX>) infected pituitary cells as compared to low to
        negligible levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in the uninfected and
        adeno-βgal infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
        As evidenced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, the molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGS</ENAMEX> protein
        action is thought to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein α subunit</ENAMEX>,
        specifically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gqα</ENAMEX> in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor activation.
        The results shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5are consistent with this
        conclusion: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">adeno-RGS3</ENAMEX> infection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> pituitary cells
        profoundly suppressed GnRH-stimulated 3H-inositol phosphate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX>. These results are compatible with a molecular
        site of action for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> being at phospholipase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> or earlier
        in the signal transduction pathway.
        Another experiment conducted to test the specificity and
        molecular locus of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX> action in inhibiting
        GnRH-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion was treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adeno</ENAMEX>-RGS3
        infected cells with an agent that increases intracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">calcium</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calcium</ENAMEX> is an established stimulator of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion that is thought to act at sites downstream of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phospholipase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39 40</NUMEX> ] . Therefore, adeno<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-RGS3</TIMEX> infected
        pituitary cells were treated with a calcium ionophore
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">A23187</NUMEX>). Adeno<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-RSG3</ENAMEX> inhibited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion in the
        GnRH-treated control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as expected (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). However,
        the calcium ionphore stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion in
        RGS3-expressing gonadotropes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>), an effect that would
        be expected if the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">RGS3</NUMEX> inhibition was exerted at the level
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gqα</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
        In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> final control studies, we investigated the effect
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adeno-RGS3</ENAMEX> on LH concentrations in pituitary cells and
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor binding (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). In neither case did RGS3
        affect these parameters of gonadotrope function (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> >
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.05</NUMEX>).
      
      
        Discussion
        The quantity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secreted by the anterior pituitary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gland</ENAMEX> is the outcome of an interaction between the amount
        of hypothalamic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH</ENAMEX> secretion and the level of gonadotrope
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">responsiveness</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Quantitatively, gonadotrope
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">responsiveness</ENAMEX> is more important than the level of GnRH
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX>; for example, during the estrogen-stimulated
        preovulatory surge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> there is a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-fold increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX> secretion but a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-fold increase in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretion</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . Moreover, a quantity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH</ENAMEX> that will
        evoke a normal <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">preovulatory LH</TIMEX> surge during the period
        preceding ovulation will induce only a small increase in LH
        secretion at other stages of the estrous cycle [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] .
        Similarly, termination of the preovulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> surge appears
        to be due to desensitization of the gonadotrope to GnRH
        action; in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>, a decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion precedes
        the decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX> secretion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] , whereas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>,
        although the decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-incident [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , there is evidence that the gonadotrope
        is already desensitized to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 43</NUMEX> ] .
        The mechanisms that alter gonadotrope responsiveness to
        GnRH are unknown but they do not appear to be due to GnRH
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">receptor</ENAMEX> number or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in the pituitary gland [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6 7</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> ] . However, the fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> that is released by a
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">maximal</TIMEX> dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH</ENAMEX> does vary positively with gonadotrope
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">responsiveness</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , and elucidation of the mechanisms
        altering the fraction of releasable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> is likely to
        illuminate mechanisms of gonadotrope responsiveness to GnRH
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] .
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loci</ENAMEX> recently have been implicated as
        potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">modulators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> is the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> itself [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] , and the other is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> protein
        that transduces the signal generated by binding of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> to its agonist [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . With respect to the former
        locus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> protein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coupled receptor kinases</ENAMEX> (GRKs) act in an
        agonist-specific manner to phosphorylate intracellular
        regions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> thus permitting β arrestin binding
        that sterically inhibits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> protein association with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1 45</ENAMEX> ] . We have reported previously that
        experimental expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRKs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor-expressing
        heterologous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS-1</ENAMEX>) suppressed GnRH-stimulated IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> production, and that co-expression of
        GRK2 and β-arrestin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> suppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling
        more than that of either alone [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . Stronger evidence
        that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GRK/β</ENAMEX> arrestin paradigm may play a role in
        regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling is our recent finding
        that adenovirus-mediated gene transfer of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GRK2</ENAMEX> into normal
        pituitary gonadotropes suppressed GnRH-stimulated LH
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX> and IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> production [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . However, no
        evidence has been presented for a direct interaction
        between β-arrestin and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH receptor</ENAMEX>.
        With respect to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> as a locus for modulation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling, we reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> that
        experimental expression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX> but not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS1</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4</NUMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells suppressed
        GnRH-stimulated IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> production [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . In the current
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, we present evidence strengthening the hypothesis of
        a regulatory role for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling:
        adenovirus-mediated expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3</ENAMEX> in normal pituitary
        gonadotropes profoundly inhibited GnRH-stimulated LH
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3H</NUMEX>-inositol phosphate accumulation. Arguing
        for the specificity of this effect is the stimulation of LH
        secretion by a calcium ionophore and the failure of LH
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX>-receptor binding to be affected by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX>.
        Moreover, our finding that GnRH-stimulated IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> production was inhibited supports the
        locus of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the RGS3</TIMEX> effect as residing at phospholipase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> or
        earlier in the transduction pathway, most likely at the Gα
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> because of our studies both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] and here
        showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> binds Gqα 
        in vitro. Finally, the stronger
        inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3T</ENAMEX> than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RGS 3</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX> cell function
        was presumed to be true also for gonadotrope function and
        therefore was not tested here.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGS</ENAMEX> specificity for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein pairs</ENAMEX> are currently unknown; i.e., we and others
        have found that several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGSs</ENAMEX> interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gqα</ENAMEX> but only
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX>, has potent inhibitory activity on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor
        signaling. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS-GAIP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS2</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] , and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS7</TIMEX> (our unpublished findings) all
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bind Gqα</ENAMEX>, the established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that transduces GnRH
        receptor signaling [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ]
        , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGS-GAIP</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS7</TIMEX> (our unpublished data) are weak or
        null <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling. A recent report
        seems to have clarified this issue: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS4</ENAMEX> must bind not only
        Gqα but also selected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gq</ENAMEX>-coupled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> before it can
        inhibit receptor signaling [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47 48</NUMEX> ] . Based on this
        finding, we propose that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX>'s binding to the GnRH
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> as well as to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gqα</ENAMEX> accounts for its specific
        inhibiting of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling.
      
      
        Conclusions
        The results of the current investigation as well as
        those presented earlier [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] nominate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> molecular
        mechanisms as playing roles in setting the responsiveness
        level of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling; i.e., the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">RGS3</NUMEX> system
        acts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> protein transducing step and the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">GRK/β</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arrestin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> acts at the level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. Future
        studies must address whether both, neither, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> of
        these mechanisms are physiologically relevant.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          cDNA transfection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells and measurement of
          IP 3production
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX> representing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> GnRH <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> was cloned
          into pcDNA3 as described and validated previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX>
          ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cDNAs</ENAMEX> representing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3 and RGS3T</TIMEX> (RGS3 amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">314-519</ENAMEX>) were cloned into the eukaryotic expression
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX>, rcCMV, as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells cultured
          as detailed before [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] were co-transfected with GnRH
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor cDNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX> using Lipofectamine
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] , and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> h
          later, treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -7M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH</ENAMEX>-A for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0, 10, 20</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sec</ENAMEX> before being collected for IP 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> measurements [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] .
          IP 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> measurements were performed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COS-1</ENAMEX>
          cell cytosolic preparations using a radioreceptor assay
          in which IP 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 and 3H</NUMEX>-IP 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> compete for binding to IP 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> prepared from calf
          cerebellum membranes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] .
        
        
          RGS3 binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gα</ENAMEX>-proteins in vitro
          RGS3 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> fused to glutathione-S-transferase
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RSG3</NUMEX>-GST fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>) was produced in the pGEX-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5x</NUMEX>-1
          system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX> as detailed previously [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
          35S-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gα-proteins</ENAMEX> were prepared 
          in vitro using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transcription/</ENAMEX>translation protocol [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . cDNAs for Gqα
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gzα</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. I. Simon</ENAMEX>; for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gsα</ENAMEX> (ref. No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63315</NUMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Gi2α</TIMEX> (ref. No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63311</NUMEX>) were
          obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture Collection</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX>); for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gαo</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva G. Neer</ENAMEX>; for
          Gi1α, [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. R. Post</ENAMEX>; and, for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Gi3α</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. G. Farquhar</ENAMEX>. Binding studies of recombinant RGS3-GST
          fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35S</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>-Gα-proteins were performed as
          detailed [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . Glutathione-coupled beads were used to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">select 35S-Gα</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> bound to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RGS3</NUMEX>-GST, and were then
          eluted for separation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/PAGE</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . The amount and
          molecular size of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">35S-Gα</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were determined using a
          Phosphor imaging device (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Preparation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Adeno</ENAMEX>-RGS3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recombinant</ENAMEX> adenovirus containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3 cDNA</ENAMEX> was
          prepared using procedures previously described in detail
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becker</ENAMEX> 
          et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] and by us [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] .
          Human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3 cDNA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] was restricted from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pRC/CMV</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EcoRI</ENAMEX>, and then subcloned into the
          corresponding site of the pACCMVpLpa plasmid. The proper
          orientation of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">RGS3</NUMEX> cDNA was confirmed by nucleotide
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequencing</ENAMEX>. The procedure for preparation of the
          adenovirus was co-transfection of a human embryonic
          kidney cell line (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">HEK 293</NUMEX>) with the pACCMVpLpa plasmid
          and another plasmid (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pJM17</NUMEX>) containing most of the viral
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genome</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . A relatively rare recombination of the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> plasmids occurs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEK</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells that
          reconstitutes the adenoviral genome. The recombination
          event reconstituting adeno<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-RGS3</ENAMEX> was confirmed using PCR
          analysis to detect the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX>. Next,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adeno</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-RGS3</ENAMEX> was isolated by clonal selection in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEK</ENAMEX> 293
          cells followed by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> PCR to confirm the presence of
          RGS3 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX>. Finally, large-scale amplification and
          titering of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">adeno-RGS3</ENAMEX> was performed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEK</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells.
          This virus preparation was used for infection of rat
          pituitary cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Culture and infection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> pituitary cells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anterior</ENAMEX> pituitary glands were obtained from female
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles River</ENAMEX> CD rats that were maintained in accordance
          with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Guide for the Care</ENAMEX> and Use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratory</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> using an experimental protocol that had been
          approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Animal Care</ENAMEX> and Use
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>. The pituitaries were dispersed with trypsin as
          described before [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mono-</ENAMEX>dispersed cells were
          plated into poly-L-lysine coated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> mm plastic Petri
          dishes in DMEM<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">/10%</NUMEX> gelding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> serum containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -9M
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estradiol</ENAMEX> to optimize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GnRH</ENAMEX>-responsiveness of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gonadotropes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] , and incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37°C</NUMEX> in
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 -92%</NUMEX> air.
          Pituitary cells were infected using a volume of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adeno</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-RGS3</ENAMEX> or adeno-β galactosidase necessary to achieve
          the chosen multiplicity of infection (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.O.I.</ENAMEX>) diluted to
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> ml; this was further diluted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TS</ENAMEX> buffer
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gm/L NaCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">380 mg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/L KCl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 mg/L Na</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HPO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gm/L Tris HCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 mg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/L</ENAMEX> CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> · 2H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 mg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/L</ENAMEX> MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> · 6H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>; pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>). The pituitary cell
          culture medium was aspirated and replaced with the virus
          solution, and the cells were incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37°C</NUMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 72</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h.</ENAMEX>
          Next, the cells were collected by trypsinization and
          counted using a hemocytometer; then, they were checked
          for viability using trypan blue [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . The cells were
          replated for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 h at 37°C</NUMEX> in DMEM <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-0.1%</NUMEX> bovine serum
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">albumin</ENAMEX> (BSA) and subjected to x-gal staining for
          determination of the fraction of cells infected by the
          virus [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] , or to stimulation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH</ENAMEX>-A for
          measurement of LH release.
        
        
          GnRH-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion
          Pituitary cells that had been re-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">trypsinized 72</NUMEX> h
          after infection and then replated (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> cells/well in
          a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well poly-L-lysine coated plate) for a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 h</ENAMEX>
          preincubation were subsequently treated with a GnRH
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agonist</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -7M <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ala</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">des Gly</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>- GnRH
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethylamide; GnRH-A</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) or a calcium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ionophore</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A23187</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> h as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn</ENAMEX> 
          et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was
          removed and centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> × g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> to pellet
          any detached cells. The supernatant solution was either
          used immediately or stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-20°C</TIMEX> prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIA</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LH RIAs</ENAMEX> were performed using reagents and instructions
          provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. F. Parlow</ENAMEX> on behalf of the National
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Hormone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pituitary Program</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute of</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NIDDK-rLH-l-9</ENAMEX>) was radioiodinated, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> antiserum
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIDDK</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-rLH</ENAMEX>-S-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) was prepared in rabbits, and the
          reference standard was NIDDK-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">rLH</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RP3</NUMEX>. The mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of the standard curves (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>) was
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.59</NUMEX> ng with a coefficient of variation of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.4%</NUMEX>.
        
        
          GNRH-stimulated 3H-inositol phosphate accumulation
          in pituitary cells
          Total [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3H</TIMEX>] inositol phosphate accumulation was
          determined in [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3H</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">myoinositol-</ENAMEX>labeled pituitary cells
          as described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 h</TIMEX> after infection of
          the pituitary cells, the incubation medium was removed
          and replaced with a balanced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt solution</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hepes</ENAMEX>,
          pH7<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">135</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCL</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM CaCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM MgCL 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> mM NaH 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 PO4</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.6</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 -9M</NUMEX> estradiol) containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 μCi</NUMEX> of [
          3H]-myoinositol/ml of medium. After a further <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> h, the
          pituitary cells were recovered by trypinization, counted,
          and replated in balanced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt solution</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400,000</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX>
          cells/well in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well plate) for a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 h preincubation</NUMEX>.
          Then, the cells were stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH-A</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -7M for
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hr) in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LiCI</ENAMEX>. [ 3H]-inositol
          phosphate accumulation in the cells was then measured
          using ion exchange chromatography followed by liquid
          scintillation spectroscopy [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Immunoblots for RGS3
          An <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to hexa-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">histidine</NUMEX>-tagged human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3T</ENAMEX> was
          prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>. RGS3T [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] is the carboxy
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">terminal 206</ENAMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">a.a. 314-519</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3</ENAMEX> and is
          represented by nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1227-1847</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RGS3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX> (Genbank
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Accession #U27655</ENAMEX>). To prepare hexa-histidine amino
          terminally-tagged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3T</TIMEX>, we modified RGS3T <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ]
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> with primers containing restriction sites (the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' primer incorporated a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bam HI</ENAMEX> site, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primer</ENAMEX> bore an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nde 1</ENAMEX> site). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product was then
          cloned into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">pET15b</NUMEX> vector which carries an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal
          Histag sequence followed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BamH1</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nde 1</ENAMEX> cloning sites
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novagen Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>). The resulting plasmid DNA
          was nucleotide-sequenced to confirm the presence of RGS3T
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cDNA</ENAMEX>. The cDNA was then used to transform 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the BL21</TIMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DE3</NUMEX>) strain.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein induction</ENAMEX> was performed using
          isopropyl-β<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">-D-thiogalactopyranoside</NUMEX> (IPTG) as described
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novagen Inc. Inclusion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> containing the protein
          were prepared and then solubized in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> guanidine. The
          Histag <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3T protein</ENAMEX> was purified on a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ni</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+resin using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hi-Trap 1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ml</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chelating Column</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biotech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>).
          Antibodies to Histag <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3T protein</ENAMEX> were prepared in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aves Labs, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tigard</ENAMEX>, OR). A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> was
          injected with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">145 μg</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RGS3T</ENAMEX> into the breast muscle on
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> separate occasions; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> injection was in
          complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s adjuvant, whereas injections <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-4</ENAMEX> were
          made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 1</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX> dilution of complete and incomplete
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s adjuvant. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One week</TIMEX> after the last injection, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> were collected, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgY</ENAMEX> fraction purified
          from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> as well as from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> pre-immune eggs
          collected from the same hen.
          Immunoblots for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RGS3</TIMEX> expression in pituitary cells
          were performed as described previously by us [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] .
          In brief, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> pituitary cells at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 h</TIMEX> after adeno-RGS3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infection</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.O.I.</ENAMEX>) were collected by trypsinization,
          homogenized, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> determination made. Fifty μg
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein samples</ENAMEX> were heated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE sample buffer
          containing β-mercaptoethanol and then electrophoresed on
          a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> SDS-polyacrylamide gel. Separated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electroblotted</ENAMEX> onto nylon membranes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millipore Corp.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) which were then incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> h in a
          blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> non-fat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry milk</ENAMEX> in
          primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken IgY</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">g/ml</ENAMEX>) was diluted in
          blocking solution and incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4°C</NUMEX> with the
          nylon membrane. Blots were then incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at room
          temperature in alkaline phosphatase-conjugated goat
          anti-chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgY</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.1</NUMEX> μg/ml diluted in blocking solution;
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aves Labs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tigard</ENAMEX>, OR). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX> development was achieved by
          incubating the membrane in substrate
          [(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-bromo-4-chloro-3-indolyl</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nitrobluetetra</NUMEX>-zolium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chloride</ENAMEX>)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCIP-NBT</ENAMEX>)].
        
        
          Assay of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> contents in pituitary cells
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH RIA</ENAMEX> measurements of cell contents, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          5anterior pituitary cells infected, or not, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> h
          previously with adeno<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-RGS3</ENAMEX> or adeno-βgal were trypsinized
          and plated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h. LH</ENAMEX> was extracted from the cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>
          ] by removing and discarding the medium and adding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml
          extraction buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>,
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM bacitracin, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>) followed by freeze-thawing
          twice. After centrifugation, the supernatant was removed
          and subjected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH RIA</ENAMEX> as described above.
        
        
          Measurements of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GnRH receptors</ENAMEX> by receptor
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">radioassay</ENAMEX> (RRA)
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 3</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 6pituitary</NUMEX> cells infected, or not, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> h
          previously with adeno-βgal or adeno<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-RGS3</ENAMEX> were
          trypsinized, and cell membranes containing the GnRH
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> were prepared by placing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in a Dounce
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homogenizer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kontes Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vineland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) and disrupting
          them with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> strokes of the pestle. The cell membranes
          were pelleted by centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26,000</NUMEX> × 
          g and then resuspended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> mM
          Tris buffer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH RRA</ENAMEX> on the membranes was performed
          as described previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] . Cell membranes and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 5cpm [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GnRH</ENAMEX>-A were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> min.
          Nonspecific binding was determined as counts per min
          bound in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -6M unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GnRH-A.</ENAMEX> Bound
          and free [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GnRH</ENAMEX>-A were separated by filtration. The
          filters were counted by γ-scintillation spectrometry.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> analysis
          The results are presented as the mean ± SEM of at
          least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> independent experiments unless indicated
          otherwise. The statistical tests were one-way or two-way
          analyses of variance with significant differences (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.05</NUMEX>) identified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX>-Keuls method.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Software for Windows</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jandel Scientific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafael</ENAMEX>, CA).
        
      
    
  
