
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Elderly people</ENAMEX> show an increased incidence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infectious</ENAMEX>, neoplastic and inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> that may
        be linked to declining functional competence of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peripheral T</ENAMEX> cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5</NUMEX> ] . At the cellular level,
        this decline in immune response is reflected in aged T cell
        
        in vitro proliferation, decreased
        production of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">interleukin-2</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 6 7 8</NUMEX> ] and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 9 10</NUMEX> ] , and defective progression thought the cell cycle
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV +</ENAMEX>infection likewise induces a progressive
        suppression in proliferation of both CD4 +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells 
        in vitro that correlates with
        clinical severity, as well as diminished <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-2</NUMEX> production [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14 15 16</NUMEX> ] . However, even stronger parallels exist
        between immune phenomena in aging and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> than suppression
        of T cell proliferation and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-2</NUMEX> production. There is a
        relative increase in the memory cell repertoire [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18 19</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ] , and an increase in absolute counts in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD8</TIMEX> +CD28
        -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in both aged [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23 24</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> appears to
        be the major cytotoxic T cell (CTL) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] , but curiously,
        has shortened telemer lengths as well [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
        Previous studies indicate considerable inconsistency
        regarding production of the immune regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cytokine</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon-γ</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-γ</ENAMEX>) and the preinflammatory cytokine,
        tumor necrosis <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-α</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-α</ENAMEX>) from T cells of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HFV</ENAMEX> +and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aged individuals</ENAMEX>. The disparity in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ expression is
        reflected in reports of decreased [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29 30 31</NUMEX> ] , normal
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 32</NUMEX> ] or increased [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34 35 36 37</NUMEX> ] synthesis in both
        aged and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +T cells. Similarly, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α, there are
        contradictory reports of decreased [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37 38</NUMEX> ] , normal [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>
        ] , or increased [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 31 39 40</NUMEX> ] production in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aged T</ENAMEX> cells. Explanations for the divergent findings can
        be attributed to many factors including cell preparation,
        choice of activators, and quantitative methodology.
        Recently, we showed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ production in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        +-derived <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells was strongly stimulated by upon
        activation anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>. Using this mode of activation,
        we selected flow cytometry for analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged T
        cells in this study since this method obviates the inherent
        complications association with experimental variability of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cell purification and activation. Subsequently, the flow
        cytometric data, based on the percentage of active cells,
        was supported by cytokine mRNA and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ELISA</ENAMEX> data. We find by
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> methods that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNF-α</ENAMEX> production is
        enhanced several fold in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">+individuals</ENAMEX>, and it is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -subset, as shown by
        flow cytometry, which is primarily responsible. These
        findings assume clinical importance since they may explain
        in part the chronic and autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pathologies</ENAMEX> in the
        elderly, particularly rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crohn</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>, and myelodysplastic syndromes, which are
        exacerbated by the inflammatory cytokines IFN-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNF-α</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> ] . Likewise, the elevation of these cytokines,
        particularly TNF-α potentially may contribute to the
        deterioration in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> by promoting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wasting</ENAMEX> and cachexia [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] .
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Enhanced IFN-γ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNF-α</ENAMEX> production in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
          +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells
          Representative examples of the cytometric profile of
          aged and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human T</ENAMEX> cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +and controls
          (normal young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>) are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; the cells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">producing IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α appear in the upper quadrants.
          The percentages of either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells producing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokine</ENAMEX> (upper quadrant) are shown. In these studies,
          the peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) were
          prepared and activated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> hrs with anti-CD3 (plus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>) and processed with the appropriate
          fluorescent-labeled antibodies. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> color FC analysis,
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were first gated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD3</TIMEX> positive cells
          thus eliminating B cells, NK cells and macrophages, and
          then examined for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +and cytokine-containing cells.
          Based on past studies, the non <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells are primarily
          composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells and are designated as such.
          Controls (not shown) for every sample were also examined
          for cytokine-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (upper quadrants) in which
          no activators were added; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.0-0.6%</NUMEX> positive cells were
          observed. Previously we found [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] that activation by
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> was far superior to other activation
          modes such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Con A plus PMA</ENAMEX> in stimulating IFN-γ
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synthesis</ENAMEX>. Anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> alone did not induce cytokine
          production [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . In all instances with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> as
          coactivator, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α responses were low,
          rarely exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> of that produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>/anti-CD3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX>.
          The production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +T
          cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +) activated by anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> is
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I. The</ENAMEX> data were derived from the flow
          cytometric analysis of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cell profiles
          of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> aged, thirty-two <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +and forty-eight normal
          young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. Experiments with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HrV</ENAMEX> +-derived cells
          were performed separately from those with aged cells with
          24 control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> used in each case. The cytokine
          analysis relies on the intracellular accumulation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokines</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> compartment over the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> hr.
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">activation</TIMEX> period induced by either brefeldin A or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monensin</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> function and thus
          cytokine secretion, the former by inhibition of protein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vesicle</ENAMEX> transport [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] , the latter by inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Na</ENAMEX>
          +gradients [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] .
          Flow cytometric analysis of cells from the aged donors
          activated by anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ production
          is enhanced significantly (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 3</NUMEX> fold) in the
          CD8 +T cell compartment, in terms of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> of producing
          cells, compared to young control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I</ENAMEX>). Even
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Con A</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> activation, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged CD8</TIMEX> +T cell
          response was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> fold enhanced over young controls (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28.0%</NUMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.0%</NUMEX> respectively)(data not shown). The response of
          brefeldin-treated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +cells was somewhat greater than in
          the monensin-treated cells, for both aged and controls.
          For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HiV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ producing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T
          cells was similarly enhanced over normal controls with
          both types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Golgi inhibitors</ENAMEX>. Interestingly, although
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is a target for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ
          response is not significantly changed from the normal CD4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+T</ENAMEX> cell response. Likewise, with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged CD4</TIMEX> +cells,
          there is no significant difference with the responses of
          the cells from young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.
          The changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α production in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> are comparable to that for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ production (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I</ENAMEX>). Aged CD8 +T cells
          show a significant increase (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 3</NUMEX> fold) over
          young cells in the percentage producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF-α</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57.6</NUMEX>
          versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19.0%</NUMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV +</ENAMEX>cases also, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells
          show significantly enhanced TNF-α production (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> fold).
          However, in contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFN-γ</ENAMEX> data, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged CD4</TIMEX> +T
          cells are modestly, but significantly increased over the
          young <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50.3</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35.9%</NUMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> also are slightly more capable of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α
          production than the normal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51.0</NUMEX> versus
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42.0%</NUMEX>), a difference that is significant. Thus in the
          aging and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +scenario, it is apparent that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T
          cells show an enhanced capacity for both TNF-α production
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFN-γ</ENAMEX> production. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells show a small but
          significant capacity for TNF-α production in both
          scenarios.
        
        
          Comparative analysis of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -and CD8
          +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> +T cells by flow cytometry
          For each blood sample, a non-activated control was
          prepared in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> were incubated in the absence
          of activators (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD3</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>), and then examined by
          flow cytometry. Such controls showed no significant
          cytokine-containing cells, and these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were used to
          calculate the resting <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CD4 +/CD8</ENAMEX> +distribution and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CD28 +/CD28 -</ENAMEX>distribution. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Table III</ENAMEX>, there
          is a dramatic phenotypic change in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD8</TIMEX> +subsets in
          the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in relation to young healthy
          controls. In our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-γ</ENAMEX> studies, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -population
          accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61.3%</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70.0%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +) of the total
          CD8 +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. In healthy controls, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +CD28
          -subset accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 28-31%</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +cells. In
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-α</ENAMEX> studies, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -cells are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64.2%</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX>) to
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68.3%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +) of the total <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-γ</ENAMEX> studies were carried out separately. These results
          indicate that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the CD28
          -subset becomes dominant, assuming approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the total <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +cells whereas in the normal
          healthy state the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> +T cell subset accounts for
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX>. Thus, in terms of cell numbers,
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -cells constitute the majority of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T
          cells and explains our previous findings (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16,45</NUMEX>) that the
          mitogenic signal arising from coactivation by anti-CD28
          was greatly suppressed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>
          compared to normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.
          The data (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Table III</ENAMEX>) show that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T cells
          also account for the increased production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. In these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
          the percent of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -cells producing each cytokine
          dominates the normal young controls by a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:1 to 3:1</TIMEX>
          margin. Thus not only are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -cells greater in
          number, but they are proportionately much more active in
          cytokine production. As a consequence, the data show that
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> accounts for the majority of the
          cytokine-producing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79.6</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86.7%</NUMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">+</ENAMEX>and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. Typical examples of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +CD28
          -profiles are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. It is evident that the
          cells from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have a greater
          capacity for TNF-α and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFN-γ</ENAMEX> production compared to the
          normal control CD28 -or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Production of other cytokines (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">I1-2, 4, 6</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>)
          The ability of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">+donors</ENAMEX> to synthesize <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-2</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-6 and 11-10</NUMEX> were
          also studied by flow cytometry. Only in the case of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-2
          was an appreciable number of cytokine-producing cells
          observed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . For normal young cells at least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15-30%</NUMEX>
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +cells were positive for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-2</TIMEX> while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 3-6%</NUMEX> of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +cells were positive. With <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged T cells,
          there was a significant <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-2 response also, but it was
          generally smaller than from the young normal control
          cells (data not shown). The percentage of cells positive
          for production of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-6 and 11-10</NUMEX> was extremely low.
          The number of productive cells was often <<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> and only
          rarely exceeded <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD4</TIMEX> +or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> cells and those derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +or aged
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α mRNA determined by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Quantitative PCR</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> isolated from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> aged, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> controls were purified and used in these
          studies. The results, shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 3are</ENAMEX> expressed as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IFN-γ</ENAMEX> (or TNF-α) cDNA copies/ug total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>. CD8 +T cells
          were incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> hrs with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> prior to
          total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> extraction. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells from both
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> show a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> fold enhancement in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cDNA</ENAMEX> copies (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">32,000 and 47,000</NUMEX> respectively versus
          controls of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,400 and 9,100</NUMEX>). Likewise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α cDNA
          copies are enhanced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 4</NUMEX> fold in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD8</TIMEX> +T
          cells from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. In view of the flow
          cytometric data, we can infer that the enhanced mRNA in
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells derives primarily from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD8</TIMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T
          cells.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Secreted IFN-γ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> and purified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> were incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX> hrs, and
          the media examined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>. The results, shown in Table
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, demonstrate that production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ is upregulated
          over controls, from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> fold, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD8</TIMEX> +T cells from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α, the increase was also
          substantial, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> fold.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Our data show that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged conditions foster a
        change in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD8</TIMEX> +T cell repertoire characterized by
        expansion of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">phenotype</ENAMEX> capable of enhanced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNF-α</ENAMEX> production. These results contrast with
        other studies concluding that the production of these
        cytokines was downregulated or unchanged in T cells from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 28 29 30 31 32 37 38</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reliability</ENAMEX> in our findings derives from use of flow
        cytometric analysis which measures 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">de novo</ENAMEX> synthesis per cell and thus
        obviates numerous artifacts possibly associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
        or procedures that measure mRNA synthesis. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>,
        similar results were obtained with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> transport. Thirdly, of the cytokines examined,
        including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11-6 and 11-10</NUMEX>, only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α were
        enhanced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +or aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. Fourthly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells
        did not show a significant change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ production, but
        did show a small but significant increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α
        production in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +-derived cells. Fifthly, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ELISA</ENAMEX> studies support the conclusions of the flow
        cytometric data.
        The question arises whether or not our results have
        physiological relevance since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> was used to
        elicit the cytokine responses we observed. The question
        resolves into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts: are TNF-α and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ levels
        increased in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and do the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T
        cells show increased production of these cytokines. There
        is considerable evidence supporting both parts of this
        question. Regarding part one, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ levels are elevated in
        the sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV +</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serum</ENAMEX> levels of both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ were markedly higher in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> over
        controls, but varied depending on the skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>
        exhibited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> also showed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elevated TNF</ENAMEX>-α levels in the plasma [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX> ] . Studies of
        lymphocytes from aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> showed increase serum levels
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ that correlate with upregulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA-DR</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> +-lymphocytes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] .
        Regarding part <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, there are many studies showing that
        physiological activation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +or aged
        donors prompts increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and/or TNF-α production. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        +lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX> exhibit a large (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> fold) increase in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T
        cells, most of which are involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ production [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>
        ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amison et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ is secreted by
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +infections. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, stimulated with env peptide, both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNF-α</ENAMEX> production were increased over controls [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> from the elderly (almost healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>) showed
        upregulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α in unstimulated cultures [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] .
        HLA-DR activation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD57</NUMEX> +cells from elderly subjects
        strongly produced TNF-α [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] .
        Lipopolysaccharide-activation of T cells from aged donors
        induced higher levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α than controls in two
        separate studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53 31</NUMEX> ] . Finally, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +patients
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">receiving HIV</ENAMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">1 antigen</ENAMEX>, both INF-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α were
        significantly increased in memory T cells activated by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX> ] .
        Thus there appears to be considerable support for the
        enhanced presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INF</ENAMEX>-γ in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and the
        aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and for a physiologic role of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cell
        subset in their production. Our data shows that it is the
        CD8 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -cell that is primarily responsible. Why the CD8
        +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -subset should dominated in such apparently diverse
        conditions as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +and the aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> is not known.
        However, the notion that similarities exist between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">+</ENAMEX>and the aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with respect to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T cell
        has been presented previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55</TIMEX> ] . It has also been
        proposed that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is
        derived from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD8</TIMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> +cells by clonal expansion
        induced by massive antigenic stimulus (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>) since
        both showed the same epitope repertoire [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolad et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56</TIMEX> ] have shown that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -cell, not the CD8
        +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, comprises the major CTL activity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
        +<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, a finding confirmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vingerhoets et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX> ] ,
        who associated cytotoxic T cell activity with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +CD28
        -T <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV-infected</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Thus, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T
        cell assumes a crucial role in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection. Likewise in
        the aged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, we can speculate that chronic viral and
        bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">exposure</ENAMEX> over a lifetime may induce the clonal
        expansion of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>.
        There is evidence that the cytotoxic activity of the
        CD28 -cell can lyse and suppress HIV-infected cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58 59</NUMEX>
        ] and thus play a protective role in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection. Perhaps
        in the aged <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> as well, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -memory cell serves a
        similar protective role against a variety of viruses. The
        production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α can result in strong
        anti-viral consequences as shown with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> B virus [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> ] , but the cytokines have a dual role since they are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with inflammatory activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ, in its
        defensive role against infection, is a foremost factor in
        converting resting macrophages into the active state [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX> ]
        where they produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reactive oxidants</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX> ] , nitric oxide
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">63</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX> ] , and neopterin. Not only can these
        factors damage <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and host tissues but can modulate
        inflammatory reactions [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> ] and stimulate apoptosis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>
        ] , a major mechanism leading to loss of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>
        ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α also has the capacity to perturb the clinical
        condition in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> by strongly upregulating the
        transcription of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX> ] . In fact, it has
        been proposed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX> ] that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is in many ways a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease</ENAMEX> since this cytokine it is a potent activator of
        NF-kB, and an inducer of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV genome transcription</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV-infected T</ENAMEX> cells. Moreover, the wasting,
        weight loss, and cachexia associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> has also
        been related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] . Thus both IFN-γ and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α have the potential for a double role in the
        pathogenesis associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> i.e. antiviral and
        inflammatory responses.
        Based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> scenario, it is reasonable to propose
        that chronic viral and bacterial infections suffered by an
        individual over a lifetime may lead to similar consequences
        as those occurring in acute <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> infection, i.e., clonal
        expansion of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -subset at the expense of the
        CD8 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -subset. The data argue that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -cell may
        serve as a natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endpoint</ENAMEX> in the differentiation of CD8
        +cells, as proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Effros et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] , where aging
        represents a "normal endpoint" that occurs after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>
        of immune activity, while <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> represents an accelerated
        endpoint due to the increase rate in T cell formation
        during attempted compensation for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +loss induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>.
        By virtue of their inflammatory roles, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ
        likely contribute to the exacerbation of the inflammatory
        conditions associated with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged</TIMEX>. For example,
        autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> are more prevalent in the aged, where
        certain <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> are often associated
        with chronic debilitation. Interestingly, both IFN-γ and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α are prominent in the pathogenesis of autoimmune
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> in general; the former by activation of local auto
        antigen presentation to appropriate T cells, and the latter
        by mediation of inflammatory tissue damage [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX> ] .
        Apparently TNF-α plays a central role in the chronic
        release of highly arthritogenic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II-1</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">69</TIMEX> ] , and thus
        serves as a major factor in the pathogenesis of rheumatoid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">69</TIMEX> ] . Recent studies show that treatment
        with anti-TNF-α gives significant clinical improvement in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX> ] . Thus our findings in aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> of a
        prominent CD8 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T cell subset with enhanced ability to
        produce TNF-α, may assume clinical relevance. It is logical
        to infer that the increased susceptibility of aged
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and other autoimmune
        pathologies, may be due to increased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-α</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-γ</ENAMEX>)
        production by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. It should be noted
        that the action of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ on macrophages induces TNF-α
        production [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX> ] , thus amplifying the effects of the
        latter.
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ production in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> by the
        CD4 +T cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) has been emphasized [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 45 49</NUMEX> ]
        there appears to be little doubt that the production of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -cells may have greater clinical
        relevance as discussed above on the increased serum levels
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45 46</NUMEX> ] . With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α as well, our data suggest it is
        likely that the increased serum levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 47 48</NUMEX> ]
        may derive in part from increased numbers of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +CD28
        -cells. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α levels could also originate from
        monocytes stimulated by the enhanced IFN-γ production. In
        any case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is replete with antagonistic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX> of antiviral effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α on one
        hand, and their inflammatory effects on the other. Overall,
        our data presents an intriguing parallel between <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and
        the aging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> with regard to their cytokine and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T
        cell profiles, and the potential for new insight into aging
        mechanisms. It is noteworthy that our results are
        compatible with recent aging studies using gene arrays to
        measure gene expression in the neocortex and cerebellum of
        aged and young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX> ] found that in both
        brain regions, one hallmark of aging was enhanced gene
        expression of the inflammatory response, including
        proinflammatory peptides and many interferon-related
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>. Thus the advent of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in aging,
        with its potential for proinflammatory cytokines, could
        have profound effects not only on autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, but
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX> as well since cytokines may
        contribute to the neuropathology [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX> ] .
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Materials
          Con A, phorbol myristate acetate (PMA),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-acetylcysteine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAC</ENAMEX>), brefeldin A and monensin were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>), fetal calf serum
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlan Bioproducts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>), anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> and
          anti-CD3 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4E</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Diagnostics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flanders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>).
          Purified monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX> anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>, anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>, anti-CD <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> and
          anti-CD <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>, bound to magnetic beads (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioMag</ENAMEX>), were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perseptive Diagnostics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Interleukin 4, 8</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 and 12</TIMEX> were obtained from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genzyme Corp.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Study approval
          This study was approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Review</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ponce School of Medicine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ponce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Blood donors
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +population (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 22-34 years</TIMEX>, mean
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29.3 years</TIMEX>) used in this study had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> cells/mm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3and</TIMEX> fell in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the A2</TIMEX> and B2
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">classification</ENAMEX> recommended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>. Most (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">93%</NUMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> were receiving the
          anti-retroviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zidovudine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transmission</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">+donors</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 60%</NUMEX> from intravenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> from unprotected sexual activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX> from
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> (mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84.2 years</TIMEX>, range <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76-98</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) was collected for this study. The controls (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>
          young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hispanics</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 19-30 years</TIMEX>, mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23.7 years</TIMEX>, from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ponce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>), had no serious medical problems. All
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> was collected from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">+individuals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>) under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. Laroche</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Godreau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Diagnosis</ENAMEX> and
          Treatment, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ponce</ENAMEX>. The aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, recruited from the
          retirement home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Diamantes</ENAMEX>, had no serious medical
          problems in general. Some had minor <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and high
          blood pressure (medicated); one had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purified T</ENAMEX> cells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> were prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hypaque-Ficoll</ENAMEX> centrifugation of
          blood diluted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:1</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>). For preparation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purified T</ENAMEX> cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +) free of macrophages,
          granulocytes, B cells, and NK cells, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 × 10</ENAMEX>
          7cells) were centrifuged, and diluted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> ul with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. After addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ul of fetal calf serum
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ul of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> "mix" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cell negative isolation
          kit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynal Inc</ENAMEX>), the cells were incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX>
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4°</NUMEX>, washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and suspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> ul <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> ul of "depletion" beads (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynal</ENAMEX>). After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> at
          room temperature, the beads are magnetically removed
          leaving highly purified T cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purified</ENAMEX> in general). The yield varied from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40-50%</NUMEX> based
          on the starting number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX>. For the preparation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purified</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 7purified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells were
          incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioMag</ENAMEX> mouse
          anti-human CD8 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IgG1</NUMEX>) monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">500 ul</NUMEX>) in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX> ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX> (diluted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> with
          rocking. Similarly, to obtain purified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells, the
          same procedure was followed except <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioMag</ENAMEX> mouse
          anti-human CD4 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IgG2a</NUMEX>) monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">500 ul</NUMEX>) was used.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> suspension was brought to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ml with cold RPMI
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, and the desired T cell subset was obtained by
          magnetic removal of the contaminating cells. Flow
          cytometric analysis indicated that the T cell subsets
          were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">93-98%</NUMEX> purified. The yield of control and aged cells
          varied from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58-89%</NUMEX> generally, whereas the yield from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>
          +blood generally fell <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 24-68%</NUMEX>. Accessory cells
          were effectively removed during T cell isolation as shown
          by the failure of mitogen-induced proliferation in the
          absence of coactivators. All cell purification steps were
          completed and assays initiated within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 hrs.</TIMEX> after blood
          donation. The purified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells were used for the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> and quantitative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> studies.
        
        
          Flow cytometric analysis (FC)
          Prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FC</ENAMEX> analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.3</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 5</NUMEX>) suspended in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> ul <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">37°C overnight</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> with anti-CD3 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:500</ENAMEX> dilution of
          acetates fluid) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml) as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . Either monensin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 uM</ENAMEX>) or brefeldin A
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 ug/ml</ENAMEX>) was used in all cases to block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golgi</ENAMEX> function
          and allow cytokine accumulation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. For
          analysis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> (activated
          and non activated controls) were treated as described by
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PharMingen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flow Cytometry and Cell Analysis Catalog</ENAMEX>
          (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immunofluorescent Staining</ENAMEX> of Intracellular
          Cytokines for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flow Cytometric Analysis</ENAMEX>", <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pp415-417</ENAMEX>).
          Briefly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMCs</ENAMEX> were washed twice with staining buffer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> bovine serum albumin), and then fixed by
          suspending in cold <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde (PFA). After
          incubation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4°</NUMEX>, the cells were centrifuged,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decanted</ENAMEX> and resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFA</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4°</NUMEX>.
          Cells were then washed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of staining buffer, and
          incubated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4°</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ul permeabilization buffer
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> saponin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> azide). To the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell pellet</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ul
          of phycoerythrin (PE) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conjugated</ENAMEX> mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ
          or TNF-α monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ab</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen Inc.</ENAMEX>) was added and
          incubated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4°</NUMEX>. The cells were then washed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          ml permeabilization buffer, spun down, and gently
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuspended</ENAMEX>. Then <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 ul</NUMEX> of fluorescein isothiocyanate
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX>) mouse anti-CD8 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Leu-2a</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton-Dickinson</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          ul peridinin chlorophyll (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PerCP</ENAMEX>) mouse anti-CD3 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leu-4</ENAMEX>)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton-Dickinson</ENAMEX>) were added, followed by incubation in
          the dark for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> at room temperature. After washing
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ml of staining buffer, the cells were fixed with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> ul of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PFA</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 1 day</TIMEX> and then
          analyzed with a FACSCalibur flow cytometer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton-Dickinson</ENAMEX>) equipped with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">FL4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>.
          As an alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FC</ENAMEX> analysis of activated PBMC
          described above, we also studied activated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and CD8
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+T</ENAMEX> cells purified as described in the previous sections.
          These studies we carried out in order to completely
          eliminate the possibility, however remote, that our FC
          procedure did not discriminate between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells
          and NK cells, which have low density <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>.
          However, our FC procedure used a sufficiently high
          "anchor gate" to examine only the high density CD8
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">+receptors</ENAMEX> which are uniquely characteristic of the CD8
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+T</ENAMEX> cell. This is accomplished by using an "anchor gate"
          which is sufficiently high. As expected, our analysis of
          CD8 +T cells using either the purified cells or the PBMC
          were in complete agreement in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> experiments in which they
          were compared, i.e., both showed the same increased
          production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> +derived or aged
          CD8 +T cells.
        
        
          Analysis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells
          Four-color cytometric analysis was performed with a
          Power-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7600</ENAMEX> computer with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cellquest</ENAMEX> software.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> events (data points) per cell sample. To
          distinguish t cell subsets, a gate was drawn around
          lymphocytes by forward scatter and side scatter (region 1
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">R1</NUMEX>)). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells were identified as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD3</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">FL3</NUMEX>) positive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">R2</NUMEX>), thereby excluding CD3 -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> such
          as B cells, macrophages, and NK cells. In order to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analyze T</ENAMEX> cell subsets (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +cells) for each
          cytokine production, contour plots on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">FL1</NUMEX>)/
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokine</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">FL2</NUMEX>) of logical gate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> events (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R1</NUMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R2</NUMEX>) were
          obtained. The event numbers and percentages of each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quadrant</ENAMEX> event were recorded. For simplicity, the CD3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+CD8</ENAMEX> -T cell subset are assumed to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and labeled as
          such in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. In our experience, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +comprise
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> or more of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> -T cell subset in normal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, a few <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells may be masked by
          soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gp-120</ENAMEX>, but this would not affect the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> +CD8
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">+population</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Analysis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> +and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> -T cells using
          four-color cytometry
          For this study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> were treated as described above
          except that anti-human CD3 +(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">FL4</NUMEX>) coupled to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allophycocyanin</ENAMEX> (APC) was used along with anti-IFN-γ FITC
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">FL1</NUMEX>), anti-CD28 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">FL2</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-CDS PerCP</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">FL3</NUMEX>).
          Region <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">R1</NUMEX>) was drawn to identify lymphocytes by
          forward scatter and side scatter, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R2</ENAMEX> was drawn to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">identify T</ENAMEX> cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">FL4</NUMEX> positive). Logical gate 1 (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R1</NUMEX>+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R2</NUMEX>)
          was used to identify CD4 (<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">FL3</NUMEX> negative) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD8</TIMEX> (FL3
          positive) subsets that were designated as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R3</ENAMEX> and R4
          respectively. Logical gate 2 (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R1</NUMEX>+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R2</NUMEX>+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R3</NUMEX>) events were
          analyzed for cytokine production by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> +(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">FL2</NUMEX>) or CD28
          -subpopulations by plotting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dimensional contour
          plots. Logical gate 3 (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R1</NUMEX>+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R2</NUMEX>+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">R4</NUMEX>) events were similarly
          analyzed.
        
        
          Competitive PCR
          The competitive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed using both IFN-γ
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α mRNA detection kits from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioSource</ENAMEX> Corp.
          The mRNA was highly purified from purified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +cells
          activated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> hrs, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambion RNAqueous</ENAMEX> kit for
          total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro Poly</ENAMEX> (A) pure kit for mRNA.
          Generally the mRNA obtained was near <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>. The
          cDNA was obtained by use of reverse transcriptase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> ul final volume
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">containing: 1</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ul of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ primer; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 ul</TIMEX> 10X
          reaction buffer; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25 ul 200 uM NTP</TIMEX>'s; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44.5</NUMEX> ul H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ul cDNA; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ul <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calibration Standard</ENAMEX> (ICS) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> ul Taq polymerase.
          Components were gently mixed and centrifuged, then heated
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95°</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thirty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> were performed with a Perkin
          Elmer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9600</TIMEX> thermocycler as follows: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 min</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">95°, 1 min</ENAMEX>
          at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">55°, 1 min</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72°</NUMEX>. The reaction was next heated at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72°</NUMEX>
          for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> min following by cooling at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4°</NUMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> ul sample
          from each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reaction was analyzed on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> agarose gels
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ug</ENAMEX>/ml ethidium bromide along with
          molecular weight standards to determine the fragment
          size. Bands were visualized under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">UV</ENAMEX> light and
          photographed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid</ENAMEX> film.
          After cDNA amplification, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ul of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PCR mix</ENAMEX> was removed
          and transferred to a microcenterfuge tube. The same
          volume of denaturation solution (alkaline pH) was added
          to the tube and incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> at room temperature.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> was neutralized by the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> ul of
          hybridization solution prior to addition to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICS</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ oligonucleotide capture <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> (OCW). In order to
          acquire quantitative results the denatured amplicons were
          analyzed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/20</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/200</NUMEX> dilution in hybridization
          buffer.
          Following hybridization, unbound material was removed
          by washing the wells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> ul diluted wash
          buffer; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> ul of streptavidin - HPR was then added to
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> and incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at room temperature.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed again, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> ul of stabilized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chromogen</ENAMEX> (substrate) was added. After a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minute</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubation</ENAMEX> in the dark, the reaction was stopped by
          addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> ul stop solution and the observance was
          measured at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> nm. The optical density (OD) in each well
          is proportional to the amount of amplicon present, which
          can be related to the copy number of either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ICS</ENAMEX> or IFN-γ
          in the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reaction. The total OD is calculated
          as sample OD multiplied by the amplicon dilution. The
          number of copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ in each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reaction are
          calculated from the ratio of total OD for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ
          specific well to the total OD for the ICS well times the
          and input copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICS</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α secreted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +T cells into
          culture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> was quantitated using an Elisa kit from
          either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioSource</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Diagnostics</ENAMEX>. The CD8
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+T</ENAMEX> cells were incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37°</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">66 hours</TIMEX> in precisely
          the same way as for mitogenic assay except volumes were
          doubled and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> cells were used. Samples were run in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duplicate</ENAMEX>, the results were highly reproducible (S.D.
          <<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> for any given assay) and sensitive. However,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensitivity</ENAMEX> was not important since with most samples it
          was necessary to dilute the culture fluid by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:20 or</TIMEX>
          more. The procedure was followed as recommended by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. The standard curves for IFN-γ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α,
          which intersected the origin, was generally linear up to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 pg/ml</ENAMEX> for recombinant IFN-γ and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> pg/ml for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-α.</ENAMEX>
        
      
    
  
