
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mulberry</ENAMEX> ( 
        Morus spp.), is the most important
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop plant</ENAMEX> in sericulture as the mulberry silkworms ( 
        Bombyx mori <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.</ENAMEX>) are reared on them.
        Mulberries are a group of small <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX> belonging
        to the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moraceae</ENAMEX>, distributed in the temperate and
        subtropical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> in the northern hemisphere. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> are generally found, namely, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. alba L.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2x</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2n</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>), 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. indica L.</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. atropurpurea Roxb.</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. nigra L.</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. serrata Roxb</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6x</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2n</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX>) and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. laevigata Wall</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4x</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2n</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ] . There is, however, some confusion over the species
        identification and according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dandin</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] the first
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> species should be treated as synonyms or varieties of
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. alba L.</ENAMEX> while the other three
        should be retained as distinct species. Some species have
        also been introduced into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>,
        mainly for rearing silkworms, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past four</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mulberry</ENAMEX> bears different sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX>, i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>, female
        and bisexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> on the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> (monoecious) or on
        different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> (dioecious), with expression of sex often
        depending on several physiological and biochemical factors
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . Mulberry genotypes have been evaluated with respect
        to many parameters but very little work has been done on
        characterization of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mulberry DNA</ENAMEX>. The genetic identities
        and relationships of mulberry plants including cultivars,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diploids</ENAMEX> and polyploids have been determined using RAPD
        technology [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . Xiang 
        et al. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] also applied RAPD
        technique in systematics of the genus 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morus L.</ENAMEX> While these studies focused
        on variation among different species of 
        Morus very little is known about the
        intra-species genetic variation existing in mulberry.
        Furthermore, no molecular work has been reported on the
        genetic diversity amongst the mulberry plants grown in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> DNA-based markers allowing direct
        comparison of the genetic material of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> plants
        have been used quite extensively. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> technique [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 10</NUMEX>
        ] , provides a convenient and rapid assessment of the
        differences in the genetic composition of the related
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and has been employed in a large number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> for the determination and assessment of genetic
        diversity. The other technique, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Directed Amplification</ENAMEX> of
        Minisatellite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (DAMD) has been developed by Heath 
        et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] and reveals
        polymorphism due to minisatellites. Since this technique is
        carried out at higher PCR-stringencies, the patterns
        produced have a greater reproducibility than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX>. In this
        paper we report the results from the application of both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD PCR</ENAMEX> profiling, for the determination
        of differences amongst <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> varieties of mulberry. These
        included triploids and selected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">diploid</NUMEX> varieties of
        importance to moriculture.
      
      
        Results
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNAs</ENAMEX> isolated from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> varieties were found to be
        of high molecular weight as determined by agarose gel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrophoresis</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">DNAs</ENAMEX> were used for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> and DAMD
        reactions. RAPD conditions were optimized in a pilot
        experiment, varying concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mg</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ions, primer and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (data not shown). Similarly, in case of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> DAMD
        primers, annealing temperature was varied between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50Â°C</TIMEX> and
        55Â°C so as to determine the optimum temperature (data not
        shown). For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mg</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+titration, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> mM, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> mM, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX> mM
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> were included in each reaction.
        Similarly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0, 5, 10, 15 and 20</TIMEX> pMoles of primers and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.5</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 50, 100 and 200</TIMEX> ng of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA templates</ENAMEX> were also
        tested for amplification. Typically, in case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mg</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ions,
        a decrease in the concentration resulted in few or no bands
        due to the increase in stringency of the reaction. An
        increase in primer concentration resulted in an increased
        number of bands. However, variation in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> concentration,
        at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 200</NUMEX> ng of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> used per reaction, did not
        result in differences in the profiles. On the basis of
        these results <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.5 mM</NUMEX> MgCl 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> pMoles primer and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ng of
        template <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> were considered to be optimal for generation
        of consistent RAPD profiles in mulberry and were,
        therefore, used in all the subsequent reactions with all
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> primers. In case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD PCR</ENAMEX>, annealing
        temperature of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">50Â°C</ENAMEX> was found to be optimum for generating
        distinct profiles with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> primers.
        In order to have a comprehensive idea of the variability
        amongst the varieties of mulberry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> analysis
        was carried out. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> reactions, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> arbitrary sequence
        decamers were used as primers. Of these, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primers</ENAMEX> did
        not give any profile at all, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> primers (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>)
        gave consistent (when the profiles with these primers were
        reproduced with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> different preparations of
        the genomic DNAs) profiles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> data obtained with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> data for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primers</ENAMEX> were considered
        separately for the analysis of the relationship amongst the
        different varieties. The profiles obtained with the RAPD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OP-G16</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OP-G5</ENAMEX>, and the profiles with DAMD
        primers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33.6</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HVR</ENAMEX> in case of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all nine</NUMEX> mulberry DNAs are
        shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>(a-d respectively). The fragments produced
        by these primers varied in size from <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500-4200 bp.</ENAMEX> A total
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">177</NUMEX> bands were scored in RAPD profiles (of which <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26%</NUMEX> or
        44 bands were monomorphic) while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> bands were scored in
        DAMD profiles (of which <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> bands were monomorphic).
        Bands were considered monomorphic since the same sized
        fragments were produced in all the varieties (as indicated
        by small arrows in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a,c,<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>-wise distances
        were computed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> band data and these
        values are given in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> method, maximum
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distance</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.44</NUMEX>) was found between the varieties <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CW</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S34</ENAMEX>,
        and the least distance (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.24</NUMEX>) was between the triploid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">varieties TR8</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TR10</TIMEX>. Similarly, in DAMD method, the
        maximum distance (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.78</NUMEX>) was found <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between S146</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">varieties</ENAMEX>, namely, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S13 and S34</TIMEX>, while the least distance
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.13</NUMEX>) was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between S34 and S13</TIMEX>.
        The distance data were used to generate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">NJ trees</ENAMEX> for
        both methods after carrying out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> replicate bootstrap
        test. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">NJ tree</ENAMEX> for RAPD method is given in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2awhile
        that for the DAMD method is given in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2b. In both cases
        the varieties were grouped into clusters such that the
        topologies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> were broadly similar for some of
        the clusters of varieties. In the RAPD method, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX> tree
        revealed that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two triploid</NUMEX> varieties <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TR8 and TR10</TIMEX> were
        the closest to each other while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">K2</TIMEX> was in general the most
        distant from all other varieties (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a). When the RAPD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> were subjected to a bootstrap test with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>
        replicates, it resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">432</NUMEX> possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. The most
        frequently occurring tree amongst these grouped the
        indigenous variety (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">K2</NUMEX>), exotic introduced varieties (CW
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MAN</ENAMEX>), triploid varieties (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TR8 and TR10</TIMEX>) and the
        selection varieties (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S13</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S34</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S146 and S1531</TIMEX>) as separate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clusters</ENAMEX>. The RAPD method was thus found to have a good
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> to distinguish between the varieties. The NJ
        tree generated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> data was different from that
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> data. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> data, the varieties <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S13</ENAMEX> and
        S34 were found to be the closest to each other while the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triploid</ENAMEX> varieties grouped differently. The bootstrap test
        with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">replicates</ENAMEX> resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">374</NUMEX> possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. The
        most frequently occurring tree amongst these clearly showed
        the above clustering of the varieties (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2b).
      
      
        Discussion
        A large number of mulberry varieties are grown in
        several geographical regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> both for their edible
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fruit</ENAMEX> and for the silk industry. The identification of
        elite varieties or promising varieties of mulberry is
        important because it can ultimately have a direct effect on
        silk production and quality. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the important ways by
        which these can be identified is to screen the mulberry
        germplasm for range and extent of genetic diversity present
        in it. In the recent times such an analysis of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">germplasm</ENAMEX> has also been carried out using molecular
        techniques, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PCR</ENAMEX>-based screening
        techniques such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX>. With the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX>, genetic
        variations have been detected, both, within and between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13 14</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD-PCR</ENAMEX> has been applied
        for the fingerprinting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> including yeasts
        and fungi [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17 18</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] ,
        common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bean</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] and neem [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        In view of this, it was decided to employ the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> and
        DAMD techniques for the analysis of genetic variation in
        case of an important plant like mulberry. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
        varieties used in this study included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> indigenous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triploids</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">TR8, TR10</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> indigenous selections (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">S13,</ENAMEX>
        S34, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S146 and S1531</TIMEX>), the prominent indigenous variety
        Kanva-2 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">K2</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exotic varieties <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China White</ENAMEX> (CW) and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mandalay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MAN</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX> tree after bootstrap test of RAPD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a) clearly indicates the closeness of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">varieties TR8</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TR10</TIMEX>. Further, the varieties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MAN</ENAMEX> and CW
        were also closer to both the triploid varieties than to the
        other varieties while all the selection varieties grouped
        together (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a). On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX> tree after
        bootstrap test for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> data revealed that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">varieties S13</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S34 and TR8</TIMEX> were least distant to each other
        while the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> selection varieties were grouped differently
        relative to that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> analysis. These groupings of the
        varieties reflect the relative similarities of their
        genomic regions responsible for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> or DAMD profiles.
        Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, the latter (DAMD) profiles were obtained with
        higher stringency PCR conditions than the RAPD profiles and
        therefore, the closeness of the varieties to each other in
        DAMD profiles is attributable to the similarities of their
        minisatellite sequence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
        The RAPD profiles revealed that the varieties could be
        distinguished broadly into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of the selection
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">varieties</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">S13, S34, S146, S1531</ENAMEX>), the triploids (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">TR8,</ENAMEX>
        TR10), the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> exotic varieties (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MAN</ENAMEX>) and the
        indigenous variety <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">K2</TIMEX>. The DAMD profiles on the other hand
        resulted in a different clustering. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> techniques
        however, did not reveal any specific bias in the clustering
        of the varieties with reference to their geographical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origins</ENAMEX>. This shows that the geographical divergence of the
        varieties is not reflected in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> profiles.
        It has been shown <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> also on the basis of multivariate
        analysis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> different parameters that geographic
        diversity was not necessarily the direct cause of genetic
        diversity in mulberry [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
        RAPD profiles of the triploids were different from those
        of all the diploid varieties. Of these, however, the
        profiles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MAN</ENAMEX> and the triploid varieties <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TR8</ENAMEX> and TR10
        were relatively more similar. The distances of the two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triploid</ENAMEX> varieties to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MAN</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.27 and 0.31</NUMEX>, while amongst
        themselves, the distance was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only 0.24</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a).
        To the other diploid varieties the distances of the
        triploids were in the range <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.28 to 0.41</NUMEX>. The number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bands</ENAMEX> found in the triploids was not particularly large as
        compared to that in the diploids even though they had one
        additional set of chromosomes. On the contrary, in case of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OP-G5</ENAMEX> it was observed that the triploid variety DNAs
        specifically lacked a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> that was present in all other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diploid</ENAMEX> varieties (as indicated by a small arrowhead in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1b). In case of sugarcanes also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Botha</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
        ] did not observe any greater number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> bands in
        polyploids relative to the diploids. In the case of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> indigenous selections, the clustering of the varieties
        by both methods indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S34</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S13</ENAMEX> are most similar
        to each other (least distance <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.13</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> method). The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">varieties CW</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">K2</NUMEX> seemed to be more distant from the
        other varieties and were clustered differently relative to
        them by both the methods (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX>).
      
      
        Conclusions
        The overall extent of polymorphism was very high and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> data were useful in distinguishing between
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> varieties, despite including apparently diverse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> such as triploids and exotic varieties. As many as
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> primers and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">primer</ENAMEX> generated profiles
        that can together differentiate all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> varieties in
        terms of unique bands. These results are consistent with
        the fact that mulberry is known to have highly heterozygous
        varieties with large numbers of natural hybrids between
        unisexual mulberry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . Supporting this,
        genetic divergence amongst <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 58</NUMEX> varieties of
        mulberry was found to be high as determined by D
        2statistics of multivariate analyses [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . The greatest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distance</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.78</NUMEX>) and the smallest distance (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.13</NUMEX>) observed
        by the two methods in the present studies (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>)
        indicated that the varieties are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 22 and 87%</NUMEX>
        similar. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> methods individually revealed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91%</NUMEX> (DAMD) bands were polymorphic. For a plant
        with extensive natural hybridization amongst varieties and
        the reportedly high genetic divergence, these values are
        thus indicative of the wide range of diversity. An
        alternative interpretation is that mulberry has only
        recently split from its ancestral taxonomic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The
        present data on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only nine</NUMEX> varieties are, however,
        inadequate to really shed light on these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possibilities.
        Nonetheless, an important outcome of this study is the
        ability to distinguish between diverse varieties of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mulberry</ENAMEX> using only a small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> and DAMD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX>. Clearly, there is considerable scope for applying
        these techniques on a larger scale for the analysis of the
        entire mulberry germplasm.
      
      
        Material and methods
        
          Plant material
          Mulberry <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> different varieties, namely,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China White</ENAMEX> (CW), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kanwa2</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">K2</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandalay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MAN</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S1531</TIMEX>,
          S146, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S34</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S13</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Triploid-8</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TR8</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Triploid-10</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TR10</NUMEX>)
          were selected from amongst those being maintained at the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biomass Research Centre</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBRI</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banthra</ENAMEX>, on the
          outskirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucknow</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Isolation of DNA
          Total plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was isolated from fresh young leaves
          according to the method of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Kochko</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamon</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ]
          with some modifications [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least 3</NUMEX> independent
          DNA preparations were made from leaf tissues collected
          from each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. The quantity and quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA samples</ENAMEX>
          were estimated by comparing band intensities on agarose
          gel as well as by fluorometry (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DyNA Quant 200</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>)
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33258</NUMEX> as the fluorochrome.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Polymerase Chain Reaction</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> primers
          Decamers from kits B, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operon Technologies</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alameda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) were used as primers. DNA
          was amplified essentially following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> 
          et al. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . Initially a pilot
          experiment was carried out varying primer, template DNA
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mg</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ion concentrations. The final amplification
          reactions contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAPS</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.8</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> gelatin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> mM
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dNTP</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> pmoles primer, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> 
          Taq <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (Bangalore
          Genei, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangalore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ng mulberry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> template
          in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î</NUMEX>¼l reaction volume. The reaction was cycled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>
          times at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 min and 72Â°C</NUMEX> for
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 min</NUMEX> in a thermal cycler (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Robocycler 40</NUMEX>, Stratagene
          GmbH, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>). Additionally a final extension cycle
          allowed incubation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX>. Amplification
          products were separated by electrophoresis (at constant
          current of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mA</ENAMEX>) through <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0%</NUMEX> agarose gels in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.5X</TIMEX> TBE
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX>, visualized and imaged using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nighthawk</ENAMEX> â„¢gel
          documentation system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pdi Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) after staining with
          ethidium bromide.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Polymerase Chain Reaction</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minisatellite</ENAMEX> core
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence primers for Directed Amplification</ENAMEX> of
          Minisatellite DNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD-PCR</ENAMEX> was carried out essentially according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhou</ENAMEX>
          
          et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . This technique
          involves the use of minisatellite core sequence as a
          primer, singly, in the amplification reactions. Other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have also employed DAMD-PCR technique for
          determining both inter- as well as please intra-species
          variations [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23</NUMEX> ] . The optimum
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">annealing</ENAMEX> temperature was determined by carrying out
          DAMD-PCR at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different annealing temperatures, 50Â°C
          and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55Â°C</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> parameters were as follows: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> cycle
          of incubation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> min followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of
          incubation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 min</TIMEX>, at annealing temperature
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX> and at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> min. The final cycle
          allowed an additional incubation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min. The
          reactions contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> ng template <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> pmoles of
          primer, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mg</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ions, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î</NUMEX>¼M each dNTP, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> 
          Taq <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Ã—</NUMEX> assay
          buffer in a final volume of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î¼l</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were
          separated by electrophoresis through <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> agarose gels and
          the profiles were analyzed as described for the RAPD
          profiles.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Analysis</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> (fragment sizes of all amplification products,
          estimated from the gel by comparison with standard
          molecular weight marker, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Î» DNA</ENAMEX> double digested with 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hind III</ENAMEX> and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eco RI</ENAMEX>) were scored as discrete
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variables</ENAMEX>, using "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1</ENAMEX>" to indicate presence and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">0</ENAMEX>" to
          indicate absence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. A pair wise matrix of
          distances between genotypes was separately determined for
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPD</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23 primers</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAMD</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3 primers</NUMEX>) data using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaccard</ENAMEX>'s algorithm [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPDistance</ENAMEX> package [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> ] . From these matrices, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">NJ trees</ENAMEX> were generated
          according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saitou</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nei</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] , using the packages
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FreeTree</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TreeView</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DAMD - Directed Amplification of Minisatellite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, NJ -
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Neighbor Joining; RAPD - Random Amplified</ENAMEX> Polymorphic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
