
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Substance P</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>) is a peptide neurotransmitter that has
        been shown to play a role in nociception, smooth muscle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, allergic responses, inflammation and glandular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. The amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> sequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> was
        determined in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>] after being isolated from mammalian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gastrointestinal</ENAMEX> tract in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX> acts as an agonist
        at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SP receptor</ENAMEX> (SPR), known as the neurokinin-1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NK1</NUMEX>) in mammalian systems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> activation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coupled receptor</ENAMEX>, has a variety of effects
        in the nervous system including inhibition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +current (I 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> ) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. The mechanistic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">properties</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> have been extensively studied in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-expression systems. When transfected into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
        hamster ovary (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHO</ENAMEX>) cells, activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> results in
        an increase in intracellular Ca ++[ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>], accumulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inositol phosphates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cAMP</ENAMEX> formation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>].
        The recent development of intense, photostable and
        pH-insensitive fluorophores, along with improvements in
        optical detection systems, has led to fluorophore labeling
        of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pharmacological agents</ENAMEX>. Fluorescent probes can be
        used to directly label ligand-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> without the use
        of radioactivity or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Receptor</ENAMEX>-labeling with a
        fluorophore-conjugated agonist provides advantages over
        these conventional methods. The production of antibodies to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor protein</ENAMEX> is not required, as the labeled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agonist</ENAMEX> will bind directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. Fluorescence
        rather than radioactivity can detect the labeled ligand,
        which provides more information on the localization of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor upon SP activation</ENAMEX>. In addition, labeled agonists
        can be used in live cells. Therefore, the use of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fluorescently</ENAMEX> labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> may allow a more extensive
        investigation into various receptor functions.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Probes, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR) has recently
        synthesized <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five fluorophore-conjugated</NUMEX> analogs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> as
        potential tools for direct labeling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Alexa 488,</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY Fl</ENAMEX>, fluorescein, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green 488</ENAMEX> and
        tetramethylrhodamine have been conjugated to the third
        amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>. The amine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lys</ENAMEX> provides a
        convenient reactive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for labeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> without altering
        its original amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid sequence</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY Fl</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorescein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488</ENAMEX> are green fluorophores,
        while tetramethylrhodamine is a red fluorophore.
        We have compared the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor activation</ENAMEX> and labeling of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> newly synthesized fluorescent analogs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. Each of
        the probes has been tested for: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) ability to bind to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">receptor, 2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor activation</ENAMEX> in both a heterologous
        expression system and in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native neurons</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) fluorescence
        labeling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. This study provides an extensive
        characterization of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">derivatives</ENAMEX> that will
        provide a basis for future studies involving the
        fluorescent conjugates. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green 488</ENAMEX> was found to be
        the most useful fluorophore for labeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> without
        altering its biological activity, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> 488
        drastically altered the binding and activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectra</ENAMEX> properties of fluorescent analogs
          The fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">properties</ENAMEX> of a fluorophore can change
          when the fluorophore is attached to another molecule, in
          this case a peptide. Furthermore, the conditions under
          which fluorescence is measured, such as pH, ionic
          strength and buffer composition, can affect fluorescence.
          The absorption and emission spectra of the fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>
          analogs were assessed to determine their fluorescence
          under experimental conditions used here. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, the peak excitations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">490</NUMEX> nm, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">505</NUMEX> nm, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">495</NUMEX> nm, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">495</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nm</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">560</NUMEX> nm, respectively. The peaks of the emission
          curves were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">515</NUMEX> nm, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">510</NUMEX> nm, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">520</NUMEX> nm, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">520</NUMEX> nm and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">575</NUMEX> nm,
          respectively.
        
        
          Epifluorescence microscopy
          Direct-labeling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> with fluorescent ligands
          like those analyzed in this study would offer advantages
          over current methods of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor labeling</ENAMEX>. Some of these
          advantages include the ability to label live cells and
          the ability to conduct receptor labeling without
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> or radioactive ligands. Therefore, an
          important characteristic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluorescent SP analogs</ENAMEX> is
          their ability to bind to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> and to fluoresce under
          physiological conditions. In order to observe the
          direct-labeling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> conjugates to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHO</ENAMEX>
          cells expressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> SPR (rSPR), were incubated with
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> analogs (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100 nM</NUMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> hrs at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, to prevent
          internalization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, rinsed and fixed. Under
          these conditions, all of the labeled forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>, except
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX>, produced bright membrane staining (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Observation of transfected cells incubated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX> buffered saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>) in the absence of labeled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> conjugate showed that the transfected cells had some
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">intracellular</ENAMEX> auto-fluorescence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>). The
          fluorophore-treated cells also show some dull
          intracellular fluorescence, similar to the
          auto-fluorescence seen in the unstained control cells.
          The intensity of the staining produced by the green
          fluorophores was compared by quantitative analysis. The
          intensities of the fluorescence after staining with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> were
          significantly greater (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.0001</NUMEX>) than the intensity
          of the fluorescence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX> also produced intense membrane
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staining</ENAMEX>. The intensity of the staining with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX> could not be directly compared to
          the others due to its different excitation and emission
          wavelengths.
          The specificity of the fluorescence staining was
          revealed by the finding that unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX> effectively
          prevented the fluorescent staining of rSPR-transfected
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX>. The fluorescence of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> was similar to
          that of transfected cells incubated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> alone (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3,</ENAMEX>
          F) in that they possessed some intracellular
          auto-fluorescence but lacked membrane staining.
          Application of the labeled analogs to untransfected
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> did not produce membrane staining (data not
          shown). Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">intracellular auto</ENAMEX>-fluorescence, comparable
          to that observed with transfected cells incubated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> in the absence of labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>), was seen in
          cells lacking the rSPR.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SP</ENAMEX> receptor binding
          An important determinant of the usefulness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conjugates</ENAMEX> is their ability to bind to and activate the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>. Therefore, the ability of each of the fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analogs</ENAMEX> to compete with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>] SP binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> was
          assessed using a heterologous expression system,
          rSPR-expressing CHO cells. The results are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. The concentration of fluorescent analog required to
          inhibit the binding of radiolabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 %</NUMEX> (IC 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ) was calculated from the binding
          studies. The rank order of potency for the competing
          peptides was: unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.0 nM</NUMEX>) >
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.2 nM</NUMEX>) > <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.4 nM</NUMEX>) > <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BODIPY-SP</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18.0 nM</NUMEX>) > <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">44.5 nM</NUMEX>) >>> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488-SP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488-SP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, A) did not compete with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> for binding at the
          rSPR, therefore an IC 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> value could not be determined.
          Two-way analysis of variance followed by
          Student-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman-Keuls test</ENAMEX> showed that there was a
          dose-dependent effect (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>) on the binding of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">unlabeled SP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> analogs to the rSPR. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX>
          analysis also demonstrated that the competition binding
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">curves</ENAMEX> generated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">conjugates</ENAMEX> were significantly
          different than the unlabeled SP binding curve (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.001</NUMEX>). Further analysis showed that, with the exception
          of the binding curves produced by tetramethylrhodamine-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX>, a significant difference was
          seen between the binding curves of the different SP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conjugates</ENAMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Calcium measurements
          Activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> results
          in an elevation in intracellular Ca ++[ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. The
          biological activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">conjugates</ENAMEX> was tested by
          examining their ability to elicit <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ca ++elevations</ENAMEX>.
          Dose-response curves for the labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">analogs</ENAMEX> and for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">unlabeled SP</ENAMEX> to produce an increase in intracellular Ca
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">++</ENAMEX>in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells transfected</ENAMEX> with the rSPR are shown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
          None of the labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">analogs</ENAMEX> produced Ca
          ++elevations (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) when added to untransfected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHO</ENAMEX>
          cells at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 nM</NUMEX> (data not shown). When
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluorescent</ENAMEX> derivatives were added at a concentration
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM they produced an increase in the fluorescence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> due to the inherent fluorescence of the probes.
          This could also be seen in the absence of cells. Due to
          this interference, the activity of the fluorescent probes
          to produce Ca ++elevations could not be tested at
          concentrations higher than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488-SP</ENAMEX> produced the most prominent increase in
          non-specific fluorescence in the absence of cells. When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nM</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488-SP</ENAMEX> was added the fluorophore
          produced signals similar in intensity to those observed
          when this analog was added to transfected or
          untransfected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> (data not shown). To determine if
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488-SP</ENAMEX> could specifically produce a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-mediated Ca ++response, the average of the
          fluorescence signal produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> in the
          absence of cells was subtracted from the fluorescent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> obtained when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> was added to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SPR-expressing CHO cells</ENAMEX>. The results showed that Alexa
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> did not activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> to produce a Ca
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">++</ENAMEX>response. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">analogs</ENAMEX> were able
          to elicit Ca ++responses in rSPR-expressing CHO
          cells.
          Statistical analysis, two-way analysis of variance
          followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman-Keuls test</ENAMEX>, demonstrated that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">unlabeled SP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> analogs, except <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488-SP</ENAMEX>,
          elicited dose-dependent Ca ++elevations (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>).
          Analysis also showed that there was not a significant
          difference (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">> 0.05</NUMEX>) in Ca ++elevations generated by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">unlabeled SP</ENAMEX> or the various <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SP conjugates</ENAMEX>, with the
          exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> which did not elicit a calcium
          response.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Effects of SP</ENAMEX> analogs on single neurons
          The data thus far show that the labeled forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>,
          with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX>, can bind to and
          activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> in a heterologous expression
          system. It is also of importance to determine the
          activity of the labeled ligands in a cell that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endogenously</ENAMEX> expresses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> neurons of
          bullfrog sympathetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ganglia</ENAMEX> express a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> that has been
          well characterized with regard to its structure and
          function. The bullfrog sympathetic ganglia <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> (bfSPR)
          has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69%</NUMEX> homology to the rSPR at the amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> level.
          Perhaps most importantly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> that
          have been demonstrated to be important for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> binding to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mammalian receptors</ENAMEX> are conserved in the bullfrog
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. The effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> and other tachykinins at the
          bfSPR have been previously well characterized [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8, 9, 5</ENAMEX>].
          The primary biological response following activation of
          the ganglionic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> is inhibition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">+current</ENAMEX>, I 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> .
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX> produces a dose-dependent inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. The responses of a given
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neuron</ENAMEX> to a given form of labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> have been compared
          to the responses of those same neurons to unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> at
          a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100 nM</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). At this concentration
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> typically elicits a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 %</NUMEX> depression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon Green</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> produced an inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> similar to that of unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX> was variable in its ability to inhibit the
          current, being effective on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cells
          tested. At a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM, neither Alexa
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> nor tetramethylrhodamine-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SP</ENAMEX> inhibited I 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> ; thus they were further tested at a
          concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX>. At this concentration
          tetramethylrhodamine-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SP</ENAMEX> inhibited I 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 %</NUMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), however Alexa
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> did not inhibit I 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> . Dose-response curves for the
          analogs that inhibited I 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and for unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> are shown in
          the plots in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. A dose-dependency was observed for
          the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>
          Green <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        A number of previous studies have demonstrated that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fluorescently</ENAMEX> labeled ligands are useful probes for
        studying ligand-receptor interactions [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11, 12</TIMEX>].
        Improved fluorophores, better optics and the increased
        sensitivity of detection systems have led to an increased
        usage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fluorescently</ENAMEX> labeled ligands. It is of vital
        importance that additions of fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> do not
        alter the normal functioning of the ligand, for example, by
        changing the binding affinity or by altering the receptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> properties of the ligand. If the fluorescent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> does alter the properties of the ligand, it is
        important that these alterations be understood so that the
        results obtained with the labeled ligand can be correctly
        interpreted. In this study, we have examined the
        fundamental consequences of labeling the neuropeptide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>
        with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different fluorescent probes by comparing the
        effects of the labeled compounds with those of the parent
        compound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>.
        All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the fluorescent probes were modified at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3position</ENAMEX> with aromatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488</ENAMEX> and
        tetramethylrhodamine add negative and positive charges,
        respectively, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. The remaining fluorophores, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY Fl</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorescein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oregon Green 488</ENAMEX>, do not alter the charge.
        With regard to size, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY Fl</ENAMEX> is the smallest of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorophores</ENAMEX> added, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488</ENAMEX> and
        tetramethylrhodamine are the largest of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorophores</ENAMEX>.
        The most significant alteration of the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>
        was produced when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488</ENAMEX> was added to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. The
        experiments repeatedly showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> does not
        posses the same characteristics as unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. Alexa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> did not compete with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> in the competition
        binding assay. Consistent with the binding data, this SP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analog</ENAMEX> did not stain rSPR-transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX>.
        Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> did not exhibit functional
        activity in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different assays. It failed to elicit a Ca
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">++</ENAMEX>response in rSPR-expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> and failed to
        produce I 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> inhibition at the bfSPR, both of which
        are characteristic effects mediated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>.
        Like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alexa 488</ENAMEX>, tetramethylrhodamine also adds a charge
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>, but tetramethylrhodamine-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX> generated an IC 
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> that was the most similar to that of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">unlabeled SP</ENAMEX>. This SP analog also produced intense staining
        and typical Ca ++responses at the rSPR. However,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX> was ineffective at inhibiting I 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM concentration, but did so
        upon increasing the concentration to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX>. Therefore,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX> is capable of binding to the SPR
        and activating Ca ++responses, but has a decreased potency
        for inhibiting I 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3of SP</ENAMEX> has been shown to interact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -terminal extracellular tail (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-21</ENAMEX>) of the mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SPR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues 1</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse SPR</ENAMEX> are primarily conserved in the rSPR, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 5</NUMEX> of
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> are conserved in the bullfrog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>. Given
        the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3in</ENAMEX> the mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SPR</ENAMEX>, it is therefore
        conceivable that an alteration in the charge of the parent
        compound, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>, as is the case with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX>, may cause a change in the typical
        actions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. The addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">488</NUMEX> causes a greater
        change in the charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>, which might inhibit proper
        ligand-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor interaction</ENAMEX> and thus hinder binding of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> analog to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tetramethylrhodamine</ENAMEX> also alters the
        charge of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>, but unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488</ENAMEX>, the fluorophore is
        positively charged. Perhaps the addition a single positive
        charge to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> by tetramethylrhodamine does not disrupt
        proper <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ligand</ENAMEX>/receptor interactions as drastically as the
        multiple negative charges that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488</ENAMEX> adds to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>.
        Therefore, the less drastic charge alteration made by
        tetramethylrhodamine may allow the mechanistic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">characteristics of SP</ENAMEX> to be preserved, albeit with a
        decreased potency to inhibit I 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> .
        Although the structure of fluorescein is very similar to
        that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> 488 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>', <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>'-difluorofluorescein),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX> did not behave in the same manner as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>
        Green <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> or unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. Of the conjugates that
        competed with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>, fluorescein-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX> had the lowest
        binding affinity as compared to unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. The analog
        was also variable in its ability to inhibit I 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> at the bfSPR. However, it consistently
        produced Ca ++elevations and membrane staining at the rSPR
        expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> produced inhibition
        of I 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> and Ca ++elevations similar to that
        produced by unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. Thus, labeling with either of
        these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fluorophores</ENAMEX> did not alter the functional
        activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> in either a heterologous
        expression system or native cells. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SP analogs</ENAMEX> also
        brightly stained the membranes of rSPR transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHO</ENAMEX>
        cells. The IC 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> values of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>
        Green <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> in competition binding studies were greater
        than that of unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. When compared to unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP and BODIPY FL-SP</ENAMEX> had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-fold and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-fold increase in binding affinity, respectively.
        Interestingly, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY Fl</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oregon Green 488</ENAMEX> is
        charged.
        It is interesting to note that although there was a
        significant difference between the binding curves of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluorescent</ENAMEX> derivatives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP and unlabeled SP</ENAMEX>, there was
        not a statistically significant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptides</ENAMEX>' ability to
        produce dose-dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ca ++elevations</ENAMEX>. These might be
        explained by the differences in the mechanisms that
        underlie the measurements made in the different
        experiments. The binding experiments measure the actions of
        the peptides at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. Ca ++fluxes indicate
        additional mechanisms downstream of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, including
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger activation</ENAMEX>. The data may reflect the fact
        that receptor binding and signal activation are not
        strictly correlated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-protein coupled systems.
        The evidence presented here suggests that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the
        analogs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX>, are acting specifically at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>. Binding analysis showed that the above conjugates
        compete with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> at the rSPR. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> analogs
        only produced Ca ++responses in cells transfected with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>; they had no effect in non-transfected cells.
        Similarly, membrane staining was observed in transfected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX>, but not in untransfected cells.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX> introduced and investigated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> Alexa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dyes</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488</ENAMEX>, and reported that the dyes were
        more fluorescent and more photostable than their
        counterparts [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>]. In their study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488</ENAMEX> was compared
        to fluorescein. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> conjugated the Alexa
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorophores</ENAMEX> and other similar compounds, such as
        fluorescein, to different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> to compare brightness
        and stability. They showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488</ENAMEX> was brighter and
        more stable than fluorescein when conjugated to biotin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding proteins</ENAMEX>, goat anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgG</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ab</ENAMEX>')2
        fragments. However, they did not test for alterations in
        binding affinities or biological activity after the
        addition of the fluorophores.
        Another study has examined the effects of fluorescent
        conjugation on opioid peptide activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">BODIPY TR</ENAMEX> were used to label dermorphin, deltrophin, TIPP
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Try-Tic-Phe-Phe</ENAMEX>) and endomorphin by adding a cysteine to
        each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX>, followed by conjugation of
        the fluorophores to the cysteine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
        found that the dermorphin and deltorphin analogs had an
        increased binding affinity for the Î¼- and Î´-opioid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX>, respectively, and that the biological activities
        of parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">compounds</ENAMEX> were preserved. However, when Alexa 488
        was conjugated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIPP</ENAMEX> and endomorphin, the binding
        affinities of the parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">compounds</ENAMEX> were decreased.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buku et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>] synthesized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fluorescent probes for
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vasotocin</ENAMEX> receptor using fluorescein and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tetramethylrhodamine</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> had previously
        conjugated the fluorophores to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> position of
        vasotocin, a nonapeptide, and found that it had biological
        activity, but that the biological activity was reduced when
        compared to the native compound [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. Therefore, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> conjugated the fluorophores to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX>
        position and found that the analog was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-fold</NUMEX> more potent
        than the analog with the fluorophores at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>
        position. Thus, they concluded that by moving the bulky
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorophore</ENAMEX> to the end of vasotocin, and not altering an
        amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> involved in binding and activation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vasotocin</ENAMEX> receptor minimized the reduction in biological
        activity of the probes.
        In summary, our results along with those from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>
        show that, in some cases, conjugation of a specific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fluorescent</ENAMEX> label can be added to a peptide without
        altering the activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> compound. In other
        cases, however, the activity of the original compound may
        be drastically altered. Therefore, the biological activity
        of each novel fluorophore conjugate must be analyzed.
        Analysis of labeled compounds should include assessment of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> and biological activity as well as brightness and
        stability.
      
      
        Conclusions
        The results of our study show that there are dramatic
        differences in the function of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> labeled at the Lys
        3position with different fluorophores. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488</ENAMEX>, which was
        the largest and added the most charged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>, was
        unable to label the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> and altered the biological activity
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> in live and cultured cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green 488</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY Fl</ENAMEX>, which are smaller and uncharged, appear to be
        the most useful fluorophores for labeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> without
        altering the normal functions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> regardless
        of the expression system. These results suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>
        Green <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX> would be the most useful
        fluorescent ligands for future studies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Labeled peptides
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> labeled with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Alexa 488</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-13426</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> Fl
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-13425</ENAMEX>), fluorescein (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-13424</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> 488
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-13427</ENAMEX>) or tetramethylrhodamine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-13428</ENAMEX>) on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lys</ENAMEX> 3were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR), product
          numbers in parenthesis. The chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formulae</ENAMEX> for the
          labeled compounds are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectra</ENAMEX>
          Fluorophore spectral analysis was performed on a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">512 Spectrofluorometer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster City</ENAMEX>, CA).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Alexa 488-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon Green</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP and tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX> were analyzed at a
          concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM, using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>, as a
          solvent.
        
        
          Epifluorescence microscopy
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells stably</ENAMEX> transfected with the cDNA of the rSPR
          were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Krause</ENAMEX> and maintained as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. Transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> were
          cultured <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-well HTC super cured glass slides
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cel-Line Associates, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>). The following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, the slides were rinsed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the three
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wells</ENAMEX> from each slide were stained with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> conjugates. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> of each slide served as
          a negative control, in that the cells were incubated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> in the absence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> analog. Slides were incubated
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> hrs at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, to prevent internalization of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and thus provide membrane staining. The cells
          were then rinsed and fixed with paraformaldehyde (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 %</NUMEX>)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisher Scientific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> min.
          Slides were viewed under a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Eclipse</ENAMEX> E600FN
          fluorescent microscope (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fryer Company, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>). The green fluorophores were excited using a FITC
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fluorescein isothiocyanate</NUMEX>) filter set (excitation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">465-495</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nm</ENAMEX>, dichroic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">505LP</TIMEX>, emission <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">515-555</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">nm</ENAMEX>). The red
          fluorophore was excited using a TRITC
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tetramethylrhodamine isothiocyanate</NUMEX>) filter set
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">excitation 528-553 nm, dichroic 565LP, emission 600-660</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nm</ENAMEX>). Pictures were taken with a SPOT camera (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostic</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Instruments, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sterling Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>). All digital
          images of the green fluorophores were taken at a constant
          gain (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16</NUMEX>) and exposure time (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.7</NUMEX> s) to allow for direct
          comparison between cells and experiments. Pictures of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX>, the red fluorophore, were taken
          at a gain of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 and a 0.4</NUMEX> s exposure time.
          The specificity of the fluorescent staining to the
          rSPR was analyzed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. First, incubating
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">untransfected CHO</ENAMEX> cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM of each analog
          assessed non-specific staining. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>, staining of
          rSPR-transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> was performed in the presence
          of an excess of unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. Transfected cells were
          pretreated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼M unlabeled SP</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. Then,
          the cells were rinsed and incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼M unlabeled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nM</ENAMEX> labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> hr at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. The cells were
          rinsed, fixed and viewed as described above.
        
        
          Image <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX>
          Epifluorescence images from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> containing only
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">conjugated SP</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100 nM</NUMEX>) were analyzed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scion Image</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scion Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). For each fluorophore,
          except tetramethylrhodamine, a line was drawn around the
          outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> membrane of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>
          cells/experiment) to create a boundary; the area and
          pixel intensity were then measured within each boundary.
          Background, as determined by measuring the intensity and
          area of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> control cells incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> in the
          absence of a fluorophore, was subtracted. Cell area was
          used to normalize between cells, thus the ratio of
          intensity to area was calculated for the treated and
          untreated cells.
        
        
          Receptor binding
          Radioligand competition binding assays utilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHO</ENAMEX>
          cells stably expressing the rSPR were performed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bolton-Hunter</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) at a
          concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> pM. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BODIPY</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fl-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fluorescein-SP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Green</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">488-SP</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">tetramethylrhodamine-SP</ENAMEX> was added at increasing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentrations</ENAMEX>, from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 pM to 1 Î¼M</NUMEX>, to compete with the
          [ 125I] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. In order to reach equilibrium,
          rSPR-expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> cells/well) were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in a pre-wetted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Millipore Multiscreen 96</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX>
          BV filtration plate (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>) with both radiolabeled and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fluorescently</ENAMEX> labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> hrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peptides</ENAMEX> and
          cells were prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris Buffered Saline Binding</ENAMEX>
          Buffer: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml bacitracin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml leupeptin, 20 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> chymostatin, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1 %</NUMEX> bovine serum
          albumin, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>. Following incubation, cells were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">filtered</ENAMEX> and washed using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millipore</ENAMEX> vacuum manifold
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>). Filters were punched and analyzed using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packard Cobra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II series</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma</ENAMEX> counter (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meriden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CT</ENAMEX>)
          to determine counts per minute (cpm).
          Non-specific binding was specified as the counts
          obtained with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼M unlabeled SP</ENAMEX> in the presence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">radiolabeled SP</ENAMEX>. Statistical analysis showed that there
          was not a significant difference between the fluorescent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conjugates</ENAMEX> and unlabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼M of SP</ENAMEX> or its
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">derivatives</ENAMEX> was present with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pM</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. In each
          experiment, specific binding was determined by
          subtracting nonspecific binding from the original cpm
          measurements. The data were normalized by calculating B/B
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> for each fluorophore, where B is the
          cpm of [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX> specifically bound in the presence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">non-radioactive SP</ENAMEX> and B 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> is the cpm of [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">125I</TIMEX>] SP
          specifically bound in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> pM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fluorescently</ENAMEX> labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX>. The data were plotted as a
          function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> concentration vs. B/B 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigmoidal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> parameter)
          regression was then performed on the data to determine
          the IC 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> , the concentration of fluorescent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analog</ENAMEX> required to inhibit the binding of radiolabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>
          by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 %</NUMEX>, for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SP analog</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Calcium measurements
          Dose-response curves for the ability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> analogs
          to produce Ca ++elevations upon binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> were
          obtained as previously described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transfected CHO</ENAMEX> cells expressing the rSPR were cultured
          onto coverslips until âˆ¼ <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> confluent. The coverslips
          were incubated in a Ca ++-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fura-PE3</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pluronic acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Fluorescence Labs</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min., washed, then incubated in a Ca
          ++-containing solution for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min. A CAF-110
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intracellular Ion Analyzer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jasco Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>)
          was used to measure the fura- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PE3</NUMEX> fluorescence emission.
          Cytosolic Ca ++concentrations were measured by taking the
          ratio of fluorescence emission at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">510</NUMEX> nm by excitation at
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">340 and 380</NUMEX> nm. Dose-response curves were obtained by
          measuring the Ca ++responses produced by adding various
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentrations</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> pM, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> nM and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 nM</NUMEX>) of the
          labeled probes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ionomycin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) was
          added at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼M at the end of each
          experiment to obtain the maximal Ca ++elevation for that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coverslip</ENAMEX>. Ca ++responses were measured by subtracting
          the peak of each response from the baseline. Responses
          are expressed as a fraction of the ionomycin (maximum)
          response.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> experiments were carried out to serve as negative
          controls. In the first control experiment, untransfected
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> were utilized to determine if any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>
          conjugates were eliciting Ca ++responses through a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> independent of rSPR activation. Each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SP</ENAMEX>
          isoforms was added to untransfected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> at a
          concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM and the signals, if any, were
          recorded. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">conjugate</ENAMEX> caused an increase in Ca ++at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 nM</TIMEX>, then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> nM concentrations for that
          fluorophore were also tested.
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> control experiment measured fluorescence
          produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> analogs themselves, in the absence of
          cells. Each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fluorophores</ENAMEX> was added to the Ca
          ++solution in the absence of cells at a concentration of
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 nM</TIMEX> and increases in fluorescence, if any, were
          recorded. If a response was observed at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentration</ENAMEX>, then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> nM concentrations were also
          tested for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> analog. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SP analog</ENAMEX> produced a Ca
          ++elevation in either control assay, then the average (n
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) for the differences between the baseline and peak
          Ca ++signals for that concentration was calculated. The
          average was then subtracted from the Ca ++responses
          observed when that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SP</ENAMEX> analog was added to transfected and
          untransfected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CHO cells</ENAMEX> at that concentration.
        
        
          Electrophysiology
          Single neurons were dissociated from bullfrog
          sympathetic ganglia as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>].
          Briefly, ganglia were dissected, treated with enzymes and
          then stored in growth medium at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 to 3 days</TIMEX>. The
          ganglia were triturated to release single neurons for
          daily use.
          Whole cell recordings of isolated neurons were
          conducted at room temperature, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">âˆ¼ 21Â°C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> were applied
          by single cell superfusion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>] and the bath constantly
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perfused</ENAMEX> separately with extracellular solution. Whole
          cell recordings were made with electrodes with
          resistances of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MÎ©</ENAMEX> when filled with intracellular
          solution.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> for electrophysiology
          are shown in mM unless otherwise noted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intracellular</ENAMEX> (or
          recording electrode) solution: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">120</ENAMEX>, MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4 BAPTA 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.15</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">GTP 0.4</NUMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.8</NUMEX>
          (with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KOH</ENAMEX>). Extracellular solution: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">118</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">KCl 2.4</NUMEX>,
          CaCl 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 1.8</TIMEX>, MgCl 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 1.8</TIMEX>, sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pyruvate 5</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose 5</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TTX 0.0003</NUMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.4</NUMEX> (with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaOH</ENAMEX>). Growth medium:
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NaCl 118</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">KCl 2.4</NUMEX>, creatine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.7</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose 5</ENAMEX>, sodium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pyruvate 5</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100Ã— MEM vitamins 10 ml</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/L</ENAMEX>, penicillin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">U/ml, streptomycin 100 Î¼g/ml, 50Ã—</ENAMEX> MEM essential amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">acids 20</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ml</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/L</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100Ã—</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEM</ENAMEX> non-essential amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> 10
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ml/L</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.4</NUMEX> (with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaOH</ENAMEX>).
          I 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> was monitored by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 ms pulses</NUMEX> from
          a holding potential of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-30</NUMEX> mV to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-50</NUMEX> mV every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> s. The
          recordings were filtered at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> kHz and stored on magnetic
          tape. The I 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> relaxations were sampled on line at
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4</NUMEX> kHz. I 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> was measured as the amplitude of the
          current tail following a voltage step from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-50</NUMEX> mV to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mV</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>]. To quantify the inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> , the current before <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and at the
          maximum inhibition during each response were measured and
          the percentage of inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> was calculated.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          The percent of ionomycin data from the Ca ++elevation
          experiments and the B/B 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0</ENAMEX> data from the binding experiments
          were both subjected to two-way ANOVA analysis, with the
          independent variables being fluorescent conjugate and
          dose. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One-way ANOVA</ENAMEX> analysis was used to describe the
          intensity to area measurements from the fluorescent
          images, except tetramethylrhodamine. These data, like the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> obtained from the binding assay and Ca ++analysis,
          were analyzed for variance followed by the
          Student-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman-Keuls</ENAMEX> test.
        
      
    
  
