
  
    
      
        Background
        The advent of the polymerase chain reaction (PCR) played
        an important role in revolutionizing research in the field
        of molecular biology [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . A recent adaptation of this
        technology, known as polymerase <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>, or "polonies",
        holds tremendous promise as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polony</ENAMEX> technology is a
        form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> in which the reaction is immobilized in a thin
        polyacrylamide <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gel</ENAMEX> attached to a microscope slide [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] .
        As the PCR proceeds, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products diffuse radially
        within the gel from its immobilized template (e.g., genomic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>), giving rise to a circular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product, or polymerase
        colony. When the gel is stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">SybrGreen I and</ENAMEX>
        scanned with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">microarray scanner</ENAMEX>, the polymerase colony
        resembles a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> on an agar plate, hence its name.
        Herein, we describe the applications of polony technology
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> research with the goal of screening for: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
        mutations in key <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor and oncogenes; as well as
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) loss of heterozygosity.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the hallmarks of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> includes the accumulation
        of mutations in key genes, namely <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA repair genes</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] ,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor genes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] , and proto-oncogenes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX>
        ] , accompanied by the loss of the wildtype allele,
        resulting in loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heterozygosity</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOH</ENAMEX>, see reviews by [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9</NUMEX> ] ]. Pancreatic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, which results in the death of
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> and is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
        leading cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> mortalities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
        exhibits this hallmark [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . For example, in pancreatic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> there is a high incidence of mutations (><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>) in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor genes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p16</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53 and DPC4</TIMEX> and
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 90%</NUMEX> of cases coincide with a mutation in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oncogene K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> [see review by [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] ].
        Furthermore, a significant percentage of tumors harboring a
        mutated copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DPC4</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p53</NUMEX> also lose the corresponding
        wildtype allele, resulting in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOH</ENAMEX> [see reviews by [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ]
        ].
        Of particular importance to this study are the genes p53
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> since a significant proportion
        of the mutations are localized to a relatively small number
        of mutational hotspots [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14 15 16</NUMEX> ] . In this paper we
        introduce a screen to detect the presence of pancreatic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> by looking for somatic mutations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> using polony technology to
        microsequence mutational hotspots within these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>.
        In addition polonies are used to diagnose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOH</ENAMEX> in these same
        genes.
      
      
        Results
        Previous work has shown that a significant percentage of
        mutations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> are localized to mutational
        hotspots, namely codons <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">175, 245, 248, 249, 273</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">282</NUMEX> in
        p53 and codons <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 13</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> [reviewed in [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 17 18</NUMEX> ] ].
        Each of these mutational hotspots was sequenced in the
        genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> of various pancreatic cell lines using polony
        technology as follows. Initially, each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exon</ENAMEX> bearing a
        mutational hotspot was individually PCR amplified in a
        polyacrylamide gel giving rise to one polymerase <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>, or
        polony, per copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genomic p53</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        ras <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. The non-acrydited strand
        of the polony was then stripped away after formamide
        treatment and electrophoresis. A sequencing primer was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridized</ENAMEX> to the single-stranded copy of the PCR-amplified
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p53/K-</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> fragment and a single base
        extension with either a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cy-3</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cy-5</ENAMEX> labeled dNTP was
        performed prior to scanning on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">microarray scanner</ENAMEX>. The
        process of formamide denaturation, hybridization, and
        extension was repeated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> additional times in order to
        perform an extension with each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> dNTPs and
        completely sequence each position.
        When all the mutational hotspots were sequenced in the
        Panc-1 cell line (results of sequencing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>), it was
        determined that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> was heterozygous (i.e. one
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mutant</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one wild</TIMEX> type allele) at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> position of
        codon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> harbored a mutation at the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> position of codon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">273</NUMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). In addition to the
        cell line <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Panc-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> mutations in the second
        position of codon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> were also shown to be present in the
        cell lines AsPC-1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> â†’ A; data not shown) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAPAN-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> â†’
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>; data not shown). These results are in agreement with
        previously published data concerning the genotype of these
        cell lines [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21</NUMEX> ] .
        One hallmark of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> that can be readily observed
        using polonies is loss of heterozygosity (LOH). Polony
        technology provides this capability due to its "digital"
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>, where one DNA molecule gives rise to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> polony. As
        a result, polonies can be used to detect changes in gene
        copy number that arise due to either deletions or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multiplications</ENAMEX>. For example, previous studies have shown
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Panc-1</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX>, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> copy of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX>, due
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOH</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . When equivalent quantities of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panc</ENAMEX>-1
        genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> were polony amplified, there were approximately
        twice as many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> polonies as there were p53
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polonies</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). These results, taken in conjunction
        with the 
        in situ genotyping shown previously
        in Figures <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2and 3</ENAMEX>, clearly demonstrate the ability of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polonies</ENAMEX> to detect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOH</ENAMEX>. It should be noted that polony
        amplification of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genomic DNA</ENAMEX> from strains with equal p53
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        ras <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> copy numbers, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAPAN-1</ENAMEX>,
        yielded equivalent numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p53</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">polonies</ENAMEX> (data not shown). This
        eliminates the role of primer bias contributing to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">distinct</ENAMEX> number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p53</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> polonies amplified in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panc</ENAMEX>-1
        genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Discussion
        We have shown that polony technology is an improved
        method to study, and potentially diagnosis, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] .
        Specifically, polony technology was successfully applied to
        both detect intragenic mutations in well-defined mutational
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotspots</ENAMEX> in key cancer genes as well as determine if loss
        of heterozygosity of these same genes had occurred. For
        example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Panc-1</ENAMEX> was determined to possess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> copy of
        p53, which possessed an intragenic mutation in codon <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">273,</ENAMEX>
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> copies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> wildtype and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with an
        intragenic mutation in codon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>. These results are
        consistent with findings from previous work [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] .
        The approach described herein was applied to a clonal
        cell line. However, this approach could be used to detect
        rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">somatic mutations</ENAMEX> and to diagnosis <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> with genomic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DNA</ENAMEX> collected from patient samples or biopsies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24 25</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27</NUMEX> ] in a manner similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital PCR</ENAMEX> developed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogelstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinzler</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . In the case of analyzing
        pancreatic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ras 2</ENAMEX> mutations, it seems likely that
        only a small percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA harbors mutant DNA</ENAMEX>. However,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polonies</ENAMEX> seem well suited for this type of analysis since
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several million</NUMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] polonies for a
        particular gene can be analyzed on a single slide, thereby
        increasing the likelihood of detecting a rare event [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ]
        . Additionally, the frequency of mutations can be readily
        determined using this approach due to the "digital" nature
        of polonies.
        Finally, it should be noted that this approach is not
        without limitations. For example, sequencing each
        mutational hotspot is laborious and detecting mutations
        outside the hotspots is not feasible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adherence</ENAMEX> to
        mutational hotspots was directly responsible for the
        inability to detect the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p53</NUMEX> mutations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPAN</ENAMEX> and
        AsPc-1 cell lines [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 21</NUMEX> ] . The best approach for
        detecting mutations outside the hotspots will involve
        direct sequencing of the polony <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2 13 14</ENAMEX> ]
        .
      
      
        Conclusions
        We have shown that polony technology is an improved
        method to study, and potentially diagnosis, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] .
        Specifically, polony technology was successfully applied to
        both detect intragenic mutations in well-defined mutational
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotspots</ENAMEX> in key cancer genes as well as determine if loss
        of heterozygosity of these same genes had occurred. These
        results are consistent with findings from previous work [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] .
      
      
        Methods
        
          Preparation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pancreatic Cell Line</ENAMEX> Genomic
          DNA
          The pancreatic cell lines <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AsPc-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAPAN-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panc</ENAMEX>-1
          were purchased from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture Collection</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manassas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>) and were grown according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29 30</NUMEX> ] . Genomic DNA
          was harvested from these cells using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alameda</ENAMEX>,
          CA) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cell Culture DNA Midi Kit</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Polony gels
          Polony gels for genotyping mutational hotspots were
          cast on Teflon-printed microscope slides as described by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitra et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teflon</ENAMEX>-printed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24.4</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.7</NUMEX> mm
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oval</ENAMEX> slides (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Bio-Labs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bend</ENAMEX>, OR) were treated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bind Silane</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) in accordance with
          the manufacture's instructions. The slides were stored in
          a desiccator. To cast the polyacrylamide gels used for
          the immobilized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reaction, a master <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mix</ENAMEX> was first made
          for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12 polony gels</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">131.0 Î¼L</NUMEX> of filter-sterilized doubly
          deionized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25.5 Î¼L</NUMEX> of 10X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JumpStart Taq Polymerase</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reaction Buffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.55 Î¼L</NUMEX> of dNTP
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 mM</NUMEX> each), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 Î¼L</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.55 Î</NUMEX>¼L <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          Tween <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">56.16 Î¼L</NUMEX> of degassed, filter-sterilized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acrylamide</ENAMEX>). For each position within a mutational
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotspot</ENAMEX> to be genotyped, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼L</NUMEX> of master <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mix</ENAMEX> was combined
          with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼L</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genomic DNA</ENAMEX> as well as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.23 Î¼L</NUMEX> of each the
          forward and reverse primers (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼M each; see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>)
          designed to polony amplify the portion of the exon
          bearing the mutational hotspot(s). Depending on whether
          the sense or anti-sense strand was to be sequenced,
          either the forward or reverse primer was modified with a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' acrydite to covalently attach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acrylamide matrix</ENAMEX> (see below). Immediately prior to
          casting the polony gel, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.38 Î¼L</NUMEX> of JumpStart Taq
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polymerase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.34 Î¼L</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APS</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.34 Î¼L</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEMED</ENAMEX> was added to the master mix/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">primer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA solution</ENAMEX>.
          The gel was polymerized for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>, a hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> cover
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Bio</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>) was placed on top of the gel and light
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mineral</ENAMEX> was pipeted into the hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well chamber</ENAMEX>. The
          slide was placed in a placed in an 
          in situ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MJ Research</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>)
          and thermalcycled (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">94 C</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 min; 39</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">94 C</NUMEX> for
          15 s, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">m -3</ENAMEX>) C for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> s and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> s;
          final extension at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">72 C</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 min</TIMEX>). (Note: T 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> is the melting temperature of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> primer with the lower melting temperature in a given
          primer pairing.)
          Upon completion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reaction, the slide was
          immersed in clean hexane to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> prior to staining
          in 2X <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sybr Green</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. The slides was then washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBE</ENAMEX> and scanned
          with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ScanArray 5000</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">microarray scanner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellesley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> laser and filter set.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denaturation</ENAMEX> and electrophoresis of polony
          gels
          Prior to genotyping, the double stranded polonies were
          made single stranded by stripping away the non-acrydited
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strand</ENAMEX> in a two-step procedure [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . The polony <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was
          denatured by incubation in a formamide buffer (1x <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> formamide, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> doubly deionized-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>) at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70 C</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          min. Immediately following denaturation, the gels were
          subjected to electrophoresis (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 %</NUMEX> urea in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.5x</TIMEX> TBE) to
          remove the non-acrydited strand.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hybridization</ENAMEX> and single base extension
          After electrophoresis, the polony slides were washed
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4Ã—</NUMEX> in wash 1E (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M Tris-HCl</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>) to prepare for hybridization of the sequencing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primer</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î¼L</NUMEX> of annealing buffer (6x <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSPE</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>
          X-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> primer (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>) was then
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pipeted</ENAMEX> onto the gel and covered with a hybrid well
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX>. The slide was then incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX> C
          followed by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min at</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tm-3</ENAMEX>) C to facilitate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization</ENAMEX>.
          Genotyping of mutational hotspots was finally
          accomplished by performing single base extensions of the
          hybridized sequencing primer with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fluorescently</ENAMEX> labeled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deoxynucleotides</ENAMEX>. Following hybridization, the gels were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">washed 2Ã—</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wash1E</TIMEX> and then equilibrated in Klenow
          extension buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 minute</TIMEX>.
          For each sample, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼L <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing approximately
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> units of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klenow</ENAMEX> large fragment (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Biolabs</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 Î¼g</NUMEX> of single stranded binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
          Biochemicals, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cy3-</ENAMEX> or
          Cy5-labeled dATP, dCTP, dGTP or dUTP (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer</ENAMEX>) was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pipeted</ENAMEX> onto the gel. The single base extension was
          allowed to proceed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> min. The gels were then washed
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wash1E</TIMEX> to reduce background fluorescence and scanned
          on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ScanArray5000</TIMEX> with the appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lasers</ENAMEX> and
          filters. The process of formamide denaturation,
          hybridization, extension, and scanning was repeated 3
          additional times for each primer in order to do a single
          base extension with each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> labeled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nucleotides</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX>'s contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KD</ENAMEX> grew the cell lines used in experiments. JB designed
        and performed all of the experiments in this manuscript. JE
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EW</ENAMEX> conceived this project. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and
        approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
