
  
    
      
        Background
        Since the publication of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diabetes Control</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Complications Trial</ENAMEX> results demonstrating the efficacy of
        intense glycemic control using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> therapy and frequent
        self-monitoring of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood glucose</ENAMEX> (SMBG) in improving health
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>, [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> has become a principal component of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diabetes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. While the efficacy of self-monitoring
        independent of other self-management practices is still
        uncertain, the practice is recommended for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using
        either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> or oral drug therapy. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] As a result,
        managed care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> (MCOs) are under increasing
        pressure to cover the cost of self-monitoring equipment [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        ] and to improve rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> among their diabetes
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ]
        In addition to logistic barriers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] , some
        recent evidence suggests that adult <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who
        may be at greatest risk for poor outcomes (e.g.,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>, lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX>) may be least likely to
        self-monitor. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 6</NUMEX> ] In a study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 44,000</NUMEX>
        managed care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with type 1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2,818</NUMEX>) and type 2
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">41,363</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karter et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] identified older age,
        male gender, non-white race, lower socioeconomic status,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language difficulty, higher out of pocket test
        strip costs, intensity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> therapy, greater alcohol
        consumption, and smoking as independent predictors of less
        frequent self-monitoring in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. This study
        was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to move beyond simple reporting of
        descriptive statistics in order to assess predictors of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> in managed care settings. Unfortunately, the validity
        of the study findings is limited by the reliance on
        self-reports of self-monitoring, an unreliable measure of
        actual behavior. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ]
        The purpose of the current study was to examine the
        relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> characteristics and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> in a
        large health maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> (HMO) using objective
        measures of self-monitoring practice. Specifically, we
        tested the hypothesis that, controlling for type of drug
        therapy and severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at
        greatest risk for poor health outcomes (e.g., older age,
        multiple chronic conditions, non-white race, lower
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neighborhood SES</ENAMEX>) are less likely to practice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>. The
        study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 4,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> managed
        care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, oral, or a combination of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> drug therapies. Our use of objective measures of SMBG
        distinguishes this study from previous attempts to identify
        predictors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> in managed care. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> represents
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phase of a larger study to evaluate the effect of
        distributing free home glucose monitors to diabetes
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England HMO</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Setting and Data Sources</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Vanguard Medical Associates</ENAMEX> (HVMA) is a
          multi-specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group practice</ENAMEX> serving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 300,000</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in diverse ethnic and socioeconomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in
          and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. At the time of the
          study, nearly all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HVMA</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX>
          health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> were insured in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Pilgrim Health</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care</ENAMEX> (HPHC), one of the largest HMOs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>. Home
          glucose monitoring test strips were covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPHC</ENAMEX> and
          all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> had coverage for prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>.
          The automated medical records system (AMRS) at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HVMA/HPHC</ENAMEX>
          captured data from all ambulatory and inpatient
          encounters between plan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> in a
          combination of both coded and narrative fields. The AMRS
          has been previously used for research purposes. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ]
          In addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMRS</ENAMEX> data, we mapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' addresses
          to census tract information to control for the
          socioeconomic characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s
          neighborhood of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Study Cohort
          In order to be eligible for inclusion in the study,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 18 years old</TIMEX> and to have been
          diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> or to have received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX>
          prescription for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> or an oral sulfonylurea at some
          time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between December 1, 1991 and November 30, 1993</TIMEX>. This
          study represents the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> phase in an evaluation of the
          implementation of a policy to provide free home glucose
          monitors to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPHC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. All data for this study were
          collected from medical records covering the year
          preceding the policy change (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/1/92</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/30/93</NUMEX>). For
          continuity of the study cohort, we included only those
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with no more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45 days</TIMEX> disenrollment between
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01/01/92 and 09/30/95</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with gestational diabetes
          were excluded.
        
        
          Dependent Variables
          Our outcomes of interest were the likelihood of 
          any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> and 
          regularity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> once initiated.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> were classified as having ever self-monitored if
          they filled at least one prescription for self-monitoring
          test strips during the study period. Test <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> use has
          been employed in previous studies as a reliable indicator
          of actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11 12</NUMEX> ] As only
          a very small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were using urine test
          strips to monitor glycemic levels (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX>), we did not
          include urine testing as a measure of
          self-monitoring.
          Regular SMBG among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with any test <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> use
          was defined as filling prescriptions for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX> or more test
          strips per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> (i.e., testing an average of at least
          once per day) for those using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> or combination
          therapy, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> or more per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> (i.e., testing an
          average of at least once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX>) for those using
          oral sulfonylureas only. Cut points for regular use were
          based on dispensing patterns and recent guidelines
          recommending testing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times per day for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and less frequent testing for non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] We assumed that test strips were used evenly
          over the period between test strip dispensings. Test
          strips were prorated over a minimum of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> if the
          next dispensing occurred sooner than that, and over a
          maximum of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX> if there was no subsequent dispensing
          during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>. Multivariate analyses were limited to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> therapy and stratified by type of
          drug therapy (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> alone or with sulfonylureas,
          sulfonylureas only).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Independent Variables</ENAMEX>
          We identified variables in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMRS</ENAMEX> that represented
          factors that may influence preventive health behavior [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> ] as well as those identified in the literature as
          being predictive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 6</NUMEX> ] Available demographic
          information included gender, age, race, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> insurance status as recorded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> or
          health plan. Given the small numbers of other minority
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HVMA</ENAMEX>, we combined all racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> other than
          white or black into a single category labeled other. We
          then created <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dichotomous variables, black and other,
          with white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> as the reference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> tract level data were used to represent the
          socioeconomic status of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> and their
          neighborhood of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX>. We created an index composed
          of the sum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> weighted census tract measures (i.e.,
          percent with a college education, median household
          income, percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> was the
          primary language, and percent home ownership). The
          variables included in the index were standardized for
          summation by centering them around a mean of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. Their
          relative weightings in the index were determined using
          factor analysis. Among several measures created from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">census</ENAMEX> tract variables to measure neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX>, the
          index created using the factor analysis approach proved
          to be the strongest predictor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> in univariate
          analyses.
          Clinical assessments of health status as measures of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">susceptibility</ENAMEX> or potential for the threat of poor health
          outcomes included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dichotomous measures of body mass
          index [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] (i.e., overweight: <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2</ENAMEX>< <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMI <</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">kg/m 2</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">obese: BMI â‰¥ 30 kg/m 2</ENAMEX>) and an age- and
          gender-weighted chronic disease score (CDS) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] based
          on the presence or absence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> specific comorbidities
          determined from pharmacy dispensing data. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several</TIMEX> HMO
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">settings</ENAMEX>, the CDS has performed as well or better than
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambulatory Disease Groups</ENAMEX> as a measure of illness
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">severity</ENAMEX>, explaining <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50-60%</NUMEX> of variation in health care
          utilization, costs, and mortality. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] We included
          deciles of the CDS in multivariate regression analyses.
          We categorized the last recorded <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">HbA1c</NUMEX> test value for
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dichotomous measures
          representing poor and very poor glycemic control (i.e.,
          poor: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">HbA1c</NUMEX> > <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX>; very poor: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">HbA1c</NUMEX> > <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>), with
          HbA1c â‰<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¤ 8.0</NUMEX> as the reference <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
          Average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">standard monthly</TIMEX> dose of oral diabetes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> used was also included as an indicator of
          severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>. These standardized measures were
          constructed by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> calculating median <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> dose of
          each drug type received in the entire study cohort during
          the study period. The actual dose received in a month
          divided by this median dose yielded a standardized
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> amount for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. We then calculated the
          median of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>-level standardized measures for
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and included it as a covariate in the
          multivariate analyses.
          Dichotomous variables representing the number of HbA1c
          lab tests ( = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> if <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#</NUMEX> tests <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">â‰¥ 2</ENAMEX>) and the number of
          physician visits ( = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> if <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#</NUMEX> visits <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">â‰¥ 4</ENAMEX>) were included as
          measures of predisposition to use health services. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HVMA</ENAMEX> primary care site, defined as the health center
          where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 75%</NUMEX> of outpatient visits occurred (defined
          for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>), was included as a fixed effect to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> for variations in practice patterns. As the vast
          majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">96%</NUMEX>) paid a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 copayment</NUMEX> for
          test strips during the study period, cost to the patient
          was not included as a covariate of interest.
        
        
          Statistical analyses were carried out using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V8.04</ENAMEX>.
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] All analyses were stratified by type of drug
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">therapy</ENAMEX> (none, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> alone or in combination with oral
          sulfonylureas, and oral sulfonylureas only) in accordance
          with the literature which suggests greater rates of
          monitoring among those using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> therapy. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20</NUMEX>
          ] We used <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">chi-square</NUMEX> tests to compare baseline
          differences in demographic status and health care
          utilization by type of drug therapy, and in glycemic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> by level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> (e.g., none, any, regular use).
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using either form of drug therapy, we used
          logistic regression to estimate the factors associated
          with the likelihood of initiating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> and regularity of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> for those with some test <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> use. We first
          examined the univariate relationships between each
          candidate predictor and our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> SMBG outcomes. Age,
          gender, chronic disease score, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HbA1c</ENAMEX> tests,
          and primary care location were controlled for in all
          models. Other variables were included in the multivariate
          models if univariate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX>-values fell below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.20</NUMEX>. We used
          backward selection to remove variables not significant at
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.05</NUMEX> level. Overall model fit, including the necessity
          for interaction terms, was ascertained using likelihood
          ratio statistics. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tests</ENAMEX> of mixed (i.e.,
          hierarchical or random effects) models, [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] where
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">census</ENAMEX> tract was defined as a higher-level random effect,
          produced no evidence of clustering at the census tract
          level, indicating that the fixed effects approach was
          adequate.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Characteristics of the Sample
          The total study sample consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,565</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
          among whom <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> used no drug therapy, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX> used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
          therapy alone or in combination with oral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX>
          were taking only oral sulfonylureas. The study cohorts
          defined by type of therapy varied considerably with
          respect to several important demographic and clinical
          characteristics. Compared to those using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> therapy,
          the non-drug therapy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was more likely to be female
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47%</NUMEX>; p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>), white (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.001</NUMEX>), and to have no comorbidities (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.001</NUMEX>). As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-managed patients
          were more likely to be female (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.001</NUMEX>), of younger average age (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">51</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>; p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>),
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX>; p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>) compared to those
          using sulfonylureas. They were also less likely to be
          enrolled in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24%</NUMEX>; p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>), which
          was consistent with the differences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>. While
          sulfonylurea-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were more likely to be
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obese</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX>; p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had a
          higher number of comorbidities, on average, than either
          the sulfonylurea only or the no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.1</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.8</NUMEX>
          vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX>; respectively; p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX> in both group
          comparisons). There were no significant (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>)
          differences in neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> by type of drug
          therapy.
          As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had more
          health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> visits on average (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14.2 Â± 11.9</NUMEX>) than those
          using either oral (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10.7 Â± 8.5</NUMEX>) or no drug therapy (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10.1</NUMEX> Â±
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8.8</NUMEX>); this difference was statistically significant (p
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>). Compared to sulfonylurea-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-managed were more likely to have been
          hospitalized during the study <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">period</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.001</NUMEX>) and to have had an emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> visit (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> vs.
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX>; p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lab Testing</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glycemic Control</ENAMEX>
          SMBG frequency was well below recommended guidelines
          for both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> and sulfonylurea <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Insulin</ENAMEX>-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were more likely to self-monitor
          compared to those using oral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24%</NUMEX>; p
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>). However, regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> was far less prevalent
          among <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-managed and sulfonylurea-managed patients
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> respectively, p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 7%</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> managed without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> used any test strips
          during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately 77%</NUMEX> of drug therapy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had at
          least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> HbA1c <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> test per year. In contrast, fewer
          than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> managed without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> were tested
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48%</NUMEX>, p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>). Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> lab
          test, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had higher average HbA1c
          levels (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.9%</NUMEX> test value Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.7%</NUMEX>) compared to
          sulfonylurea-managed (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.3% Â± 1.7%</NUMEX>) and non-drug managed
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.1% Â± 1.3%</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX> for both
          comparisons). Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX>) of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> on drug
          therapy who were tested had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> HbA1c value
          greater than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.0%</NUMEX> during the study period and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX> of
          those not on drug therapy who were tested had similarly
          elevated glycemic levels (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>). There were no
          significant differences in glycemic level by level of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> for those without any drug therapy and for patients
          using sulfonylureas. However, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-managed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who monitored regularly were much less
          likely to be in very poor control (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">HbA1c</NUMEX> >
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>) compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with no test <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> use (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX>) or
          with irregular test <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> use (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32%</NUMEX>) (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX> for
          both comparisons).
        
        
          Predictors of SMBG
          Results of the multivariate analyses examining the
          likelihood of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> are presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. For
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> of the census tract
          was significantly associated with greater odds of SMBG
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Odds Ratio</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.41</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> Confidence Interval: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.18</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.70</NUMEX>) as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hypothesized</ENAMEX>. Further, older <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 0.80</TIMEX>; CI:
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.70</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.91</NUMEX>), male gender (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 0.69</TIMEX>; CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.52</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.90</NUMEX>), and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with lower odds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>. However, higher level
          of comorbidity was associated with greater odds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>,
          an effect that ran counter to our hypothesis (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 1.63</TIMEX>;
          CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.21</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.20</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> or more laboratory HbA1c tests (OR:
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.60</NUMEX>; CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.19</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.14</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX> visits
          (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 1.80</TIMEX>; CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.16</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.81</NUMEX>) were also significant
          correlates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>.
          As in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">census</ENAMEX> tract was significantly associated with greater
          odds of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using oral sulfonylureas
          (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 1.26</TIMEX>; CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.07</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.47</NUMEX>). Older <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 0.85</TIMEX>; CI:
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.76</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.96</NUMEX>) was associated with lower odds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> or
          more HbA1c tests (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 1.45</TIMEX>; CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.14</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.86</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or more
          physician visits (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 2.06</TIMEX>; CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.40</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.01</NUMEX>), and the
          standard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 1.13</TIMEX>;
          CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.04</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.23</NUMEX>) were associated with greater odds of SMBG
          in the oral managed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Predictors of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regularity</ENAMEX> of SMBG
          The only factors significantly associated with regular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> (OR:
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.46</NUMEX>; CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.26</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.81</NUMEX>) and very poor glycemic control (OR:
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.38</NUMEX>; CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.21</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.69</NUMEX>). The only covariate identified as a
          significant predictor of regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> in the
          sulfonylurea-managed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or more</NUMEX> HbA1c
          tests (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">OR: 1.89</TIMEX>; CI: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.18</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.04</NUMEX>). The lack of significant
          predictors of regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> managed with
          sulfonylureas may be due to the small proportion (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX>) of
          regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Our findings suggest that managed care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who may
        benefit the most from intensive diabetes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> may be
        least likely to self-monitor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood glucose</ENAMEX>. Among insulin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, older age and lower neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> were associated
        with lower odds of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>. Further, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> and lack
        of glycemic control were significantly associated with less
        frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>, suggesting that these characteristics may
        represent significant barriers to adherence. For patients
        using oral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>, older age and lower neighborhood
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> were also associated with lower odds of initiating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>.
        Our findings for lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX>, older age, and black race
        were consistent with those of other studies. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5 6</NUMEX> ] In
        contrast to our hypothesis, having multiple comorbidities
        was associated with higher odds of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>. However, this result may be consistent with sicker
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> being urged to monitor more frequently. There was
        no evidence to suggest that glycemic level was associated
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>. Among this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, lack of glycemic control (e.g., <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HbA1c ></TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10.0</NUMEX>) was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with less than half the odds of frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>.
        In a recent study using data from the third <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutritional Examination Survey</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988-1994</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
        ] found no association between glycemic levels and SMBG
        controlling for type of drug therapy.
        There are several limitations to this study which merit
        discussion. Most importantly, the cross sectional nature of
        the study design prevents us from drawing causal inferences
        about the relationship between the chosen covariates and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> behavior. For example, the association between
        glycemic control and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> could suggest either that sicker
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are less likely to practice SMBG or that patients
        who practice SMBG are more likely to be in glycemic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, as most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now mandate coverage
        of home monitoring equipment, the impact of variations in
        coverage of test strips, which may cost the patient more
        than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> in the long run, may be a more relevant
        topic for future studies. Also, more evidence of the
        efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Type 2 diabetes</ENAMEX> is
        needed, especially given the potential importance of belief
        in the efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> on patient behavior. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ]
        The policy to cover the cost of home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glucose monitors</ENAMEX> at
        this HMO was implemented in anticipation of the DCCT
        results. In further analyses of the policy, we found that
        the barriers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> identified in this study did not
        change over time. Further, the rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> changed very
        little pre- and post-release of the DCCT findings and the
        policy change at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPHC</ENAMEX>. Lastly, similarities between our
        results and those from more recent studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>
        self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> would lend additional support to our
        conclusions regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>.
        Test <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip dispensings</ENAMEX> are not a perfect measure of
        actual use, but are likely to be more objective than
        self-reports. Also, failure to control for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX>
        may have caused us to overestimate the effect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neighborhood SES</ENAMEX>. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25 26</NUMEX> ] Still, other studies have
        found a significant effect of neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> on
        individual health and mortality even when individual-level
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> was controlled for in the analyses. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 28 29 30 31 32</NUMEX>
        ] Using an index similar to our own, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diez Roux et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ]
        recently found that living in a relatively disadvantaged
        neighborhood was associated with greater incidence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">coronary heart disease</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, even after adjusting
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>-level <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazard Ratio</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CI:
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>).
        Missing data may have introduced bias into our results.
        In particular, we only included <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were
        continuously enrolled, thereby limiting the
        generalizability of our study to continuously enrolled
        managed care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. Further, approximately
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> of the study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> did not receive an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HbA1c</ENAMEX> test
        during the study period, and we anticipate that patients
        with lower average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HbA1c</TIMEX> levels were less likely to have
        had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> test. Race data were unavailable for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX> of the
        study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. However, in a comparison of race data
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMRS</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> self-reports, it was found that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> were only slightly more likely to be incorrectly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">categorized</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>) or counted as
        missing (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>) relative to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> (unpublished data, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choo P</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Platt R</ENAMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> on duration of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> and type of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karter et al</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] identified as predictors of SMBG
        adherence, were not consistently available in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMRS</ENAMEX>.
        Therefore, we controlled for severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> using type
        and intensity of drug therapy, the number of comorbidities,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glycemic</ENAMEX> level, and health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> use. Still, it is
        possible that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of younger age with higher
        likelihood of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> may in part reflect differences in type
        or duration of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>.
        The greatest strength of our study is the use of more
        objective measures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> on test strips are less
        vulnerable to response biases that may hinder the detection
        of important relationships. Furthermore, the structure of
        the pharmacy benefit at the time of our study makes it very
        likely that all test strip dispensings would occur in
        health plan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pharmacies</ENAMEX>. While our data were gathered from
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>, the large and diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient population</ENAMEX> at HPHC
        increases the generalizability of our results to other
        managed care settings.
      
      
        Conclusions
        While the efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> has yet to be demonstrated,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCOs</ENAMEX> are under increasing pressure to cover the cost of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> equipment for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and to improve rates of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX>. Our findings provide troubling evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCOs</ENAMEX> may
        face the greatest challenges in changing the
        self-monitoring behavior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at greatest risk
        for poor health outcomes. Concern over health disparities
        has drawn increased attention toward community-based
        interventions for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. Results of ongoing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX> may provide managed care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> with
        useful strategies for reaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> most at risk for
        poor diabetes outcomes. In addition, well-controlled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">longitudinal</ENAMEX> studies of the relationship between the
        factors identified in this study and patterns of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMBG</ENAMEX> and
        self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> more generally can inform future
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing Interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' Contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASA</ENAMEX> participated in the design and analysis of the study
        and drafted the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FZ</ENAMEX> participated in the
        design and coordination of the study and performed the
        statistical analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SBS</ENAMEX> conceived of the study and
        participated in its design. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MB</ENAMEX> lent clinical expertise to
        the project. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DRD</ENAMEX> conceived of the study and participated in
        its design.
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved of the final
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
