
  
    
      
        Background
        The geographical distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> as an
        indicator of the research productivity of individual
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, regions or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> has recently become a
        field of interest. It has been investigated for the members
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooperation Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] ,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] and for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> medical school [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] .
        The research output of individual [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] and selected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] for single specialties, as well as the
        contribution of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ] has also been reviewed. To the best of our knowledge
        such an investigation was not carried out in the field of
        medical education. But would it not be important to find
        out which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are the most influential concerning the
        future of medical education? Who are the opinion formers
        and who does not take part in this important discussion?
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to answer these questions is to investigate which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> contribute to the most prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> in
        this field. Therefore a study of the geographical
        distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leading medical
        education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> determined by their impact factor was
        carried out. The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that contributed to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine and Medical Education</ENAMEX> and the amount of
        their contribution was examined with the help of the
        Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PubMed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medline</ENAMEX>-database of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Library of Medicine</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] .
      
      
        Methods
        
          Medical education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> and their impact
          factor
          In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Citation Reports-Science Edition</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> ] <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> were listed in the subject category
          "education, scientific disciplines". <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX>
          had the highest impact factor with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.472</NUMEX>, followed by
          Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.958</NUMEX>. All the remaining journals
          - not only those ones dealing with medical education, but
          also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Biological Education</ENAMEX> -
          had an impact factor below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.65</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> of the remaining
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> had an impact factor below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.32</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> ranked
          medical education periodical was Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teacher</ENAMEX> with an
          IF of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.574</NUMEX>. Out of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic</ENAMEX>
          Medicine and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX> were listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PubMed</ENAMEX> in
          each of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years from 1995 to 2000</TIMEX>.
          Nineteen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> were listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PubMed</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeSH</ENAMEX>
          heading "education, medical" [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> of these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> of some of the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX>, e.g. the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Journal of Medical Education</ENAMEX>
          as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only four</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> were listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PubMed</ENAMEX> throughout the whole
          investigated period of time. These are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive Therapy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Policy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>. Out of this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> and
          Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> were also listed in the subject
          category "education, scientific disciplines" of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Citation Reports-Science Edition</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> selection
          Although science is a discipline that prides itself on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">precision</ENAMEX>, quantification, standards, and controls, there
          is no absolute gold standard for the quality of
          scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . Only the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leading
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> with the highest impact factor in the field of
          medical education (category: education, scientific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disciplines</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] were investigated in this study to
          introduce some quality assessment. No measure of quality
          is perfect (or even close to it), but the citation index
          does provide some indication of how reliable, important,
          and useful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> find the work that is published
          in a given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . The impact factor is not
          valid for the assessment of the quality of individual
          papers, but it is a valid tool for the quality assessment
          of scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Search methodology
          PubMed was used to search <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medline</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2001</TIMEX>.
          Preview/Index was selected from the features <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX> was entered into
          the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journal</ENAMEX>" field. The search included the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> from
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 to 2000</TIMEX>, which were entered into the "Publication
          Date" field, respectively. Finally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> article was
          selected as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Publication Type</ENAMEX>" to exclude letters,
          editorials, news, etc. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . The search results were
          displayed in the MEDLINE format and the affiliation for
          each entry was retrieved for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>.
          If the affiliation of an entry could not be obtained from
          PubMed, it was looked up in the paper version of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX>. If <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was listed in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affiliation</ENAMEX>, each of them was rewarded with a count.
        
      
      
        Results
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1995 to 2000 2207</TIMEX> journal articles were published
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine and 746</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> articles were
        published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX>. The number of published
        articles per year increased for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The
        affiliation could not be retrieved for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> entries (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.6%</NUMEX> of
        all articles) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> and for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> entries
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.1%</NUMEX> of all articles) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> published articles from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 2000</TIMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX>
        had contributions from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the same period of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> contributed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> article in each
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of the investigated period of time to the journal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> contributed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> article in each
        of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> were responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87.5%</NUMEX> and
        their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.2%</NUMEX> of all articles in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX> together contributed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 74%</NUMEX>
        of all articles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
      
      
        Discussion
        In this investigation the geographical distribution of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leading medical education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>
        and the contribution of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> were studied. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> from all over the world
        published articles in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX> and to a lesser
        extent in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX>, but both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> were
        dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> from a few English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
        with the exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>. Most of the articles
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> were written by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and to a lesser
        extent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> were the main contributors to
        Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>.
        Recently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremer et</ENAMEX> al. investigated the geographical
        distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in reproductive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
        ] . They compared the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in the two
        leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> of this field and found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> was
        the most productive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
        was the most productive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the other as well as in
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> together. This is in accordance with our
        results that show the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> as the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42.6%</NUMEX> of all articles), whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> were the most productive contributors to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87.5%</NUMEX>) and both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> together
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68%</NUMEX>).
        It was reported that the proportion of authorship by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> has declined for
        critical care research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61%</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . This is in contrast to our
        findings that the proportion of authorship by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> remained fairly constant in both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> with minor fluctuations.
        Our search method differed from the previously described
        method [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] of using the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affiliation field</ENAMEX>" to enter
        country names for good reason. First, it was noted that
        spelling mistakes occur in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medline</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] . These could
        have an influence if the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affiliation Field</ENAMEX>" would have
        been used to enter <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> names. When we look at the
        search strategy used in our study it seems unlikely that
        the results could have been affected by misspelling. The
        use of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affiliation field</ENAMEX>" is also limited by the fact,
        that the name of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can be dropped from the
        affiliation if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> is located in the same country
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . Further such a search strategy would be
        questionable because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> names can appear in street
        names of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . Therefore the use of the
        "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affiliation Field</ENAMEX>" was avoided right at the beginning and
        the affiliation for each single entry was retrieved from
        the MEDLINE format.
        This study is limited by the fact that the affiliation
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PubMed</ENAMEX> only includes the institutional affiliation and
        address of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . Therefore some
        articles may have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but
        only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> was detected with
        the applied search strategy. To our surprise a few entries
        had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> listed in their affiliation field. Hence
        some of the articles resulting from international
        cooperation were found. Besides it seems unlikely that this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">limitation</ENAMEX> had a significant influence on the results of
        this study when we consider the nature of most journal
        articles dealing with the topic of medical education.
        Further we have to remind us that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> about
        medical education are not only found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> dedicated
        to this field, but also in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">e.g. general</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. Also contributions about the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> in special fields can regularly be found in
        specialty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, for example articles about the teaching
        of anatomy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Anatomy</ENAMEX>. Moreover some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> of medical education in their own
        language, e.g. the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Medizinische Ausbildung</ENAMEX>", which
        are often not indexed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medline</ENAMEX> and are not evaluated for
        their impact factor by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Scientific</ENAMEX>
        Information. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are included in other
        international databases but not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medline</ENAMEX>. Furthermore it
        should be emphasized that many research papers originating
        from developing world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and from non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>
        speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are published in reputable peer-reviewed
        local or regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> that are not listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medline</ENAMEX>.
        What makes things worse is that the already low
        representation of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medline</ENAMEX> is further
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vanishing</ENAMEX>, e.g. it is known that there is a progressive
        disappearance of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medline</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ]
        . On the other hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> striving for the broadest
        possible exposure and recognition of their work generally
        prefer to publish their findings in highly cited,
        international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . For biomedical disciplines
        these "highly cited, international" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are probably
        those which are covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medline</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] .
        As emphasized by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX>
        is the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Federation</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> and has therefore an important international
        role. In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> is the official
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal of the Association of American Medical Colleges</ENAMEX>.
        Hence the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> represented by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> could
        explain the difference in the number of contributing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and the domination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, especially when remembering that journals
        which represent a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> tend to publish to a
        certain extent more papers coming from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of
        origin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> itself than from elsewhere [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ]
        .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> were the main contributors to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX>. This is in accordance with
        previous results from the field of gastroenterology and
        hepatology showing that a large proportion of papers
        originating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ]
        . The reasons for this observation remain to be elucidated.
        One could argue, that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> is more likely to accept
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscripts</ENAMEX> submitted from within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of its own
        origin. But as stated before [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] the 'equal opportunity'
        policy and the scientific rigor of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> can't be
        questioned. Further there is data from a major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>
        medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> showing that the acceptance rate for
        submitted manuscripts from the different parts of the world
        was approximately the same, while the number of submissions
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">around fifteen</NUMEX> times as high as the numbers
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> combined [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
        ] . Accordingly a lower number of submissions from the
        developing world could be a reason for the geographical
        distribution in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> investigated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. On the other
        hand, an investigation assessing if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>/non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>
        reviewers evaluated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">manuscripts</ENAMEX> differently, depending on
        whether the manuscripts were submitted from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
        or from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> and
        outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> evaluated non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> papers similarly and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evaluated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> more favorably,
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> having a significant preference for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
        papers [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . This would indicate that a selection bias
        must not be ruled out. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX> and
        Medical Education we can only speculate, because the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'native</ENAMEX>' versus 'foreign' manuscript submission/acceptance
        rates of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are not known to us. Further we
        do not know the quality of the submitted manuscripts. The
        only information available is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education</ENAMEX>
        published around <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX> of unsolicited papers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ]
        .
        In a recent survey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> in the less developed
        world were asked what complicated publication in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . They repeatedly referred
        to the same topics. <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a language barrier
        constitutes a huge problem [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . Further the capability
        of selecting the right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> has an influence. It was
        stated that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> were unfamiliar with the range
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> open to them [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . Therefore manuscripts
        that are not accepted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> in one of the
        internationally known general medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> like the BMJ
        or JAMA, are frequently send to local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX> while
        overlooking the speciality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . In the case of
        medical education this would suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are only
        send to general medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are not
        aware of the speciality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> in this field like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Medicine</ENAMEX>. But we have to be cautious with this
        argument, because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> deliberately publish
        their work in the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> to reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in
        their home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. If they would publish their paper in an
        international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, it could happen that their results
        never reach the majority of medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> in their
        home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for the same reasons like the language barrier
        and also scarce library resources. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> have
        supplied evidence against the perception of an editorial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX> against work submitted from the developing world. But
        there seems to be something true about the argument that to
        secure the maximum number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> who can afford to
        pay an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> subscription, as well as increasingly
        discriminating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> always have to work
        hard to appeal to the developed world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
        Therefore the filling of scarce pages with research from
        the developing world makes no commercial sense and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publishers</ENAMEX> are unlikely to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> who take their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX> in such a direction [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . This hindrance should
        be swept away by the appearance of e-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> like the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">BioMed</ENAMEX> Central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">periodicals</ENAMEX>, which theoretically have no
        page limitations.
        Providing free access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> for the poorer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the world [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] may help to solve some of the
        other problems. For example developing world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>,
        which are not aware of the variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> open to
        their research, have now a possibility to inform
        themselves. The opportunity of submitting a manuscript via
        the Internet excludes possible obstacles caused by poor
        postal services. Further <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> should try to remove
        remaining doubts about their manuscript selection process.
        This could be achieved by publishing the acceptance and
        submission rates for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> of the world. The
        inclusion of more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> from the developing world
        on the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> should also be considered [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
        Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> from the developing world should
        be encouraged to submit more of their research to the
        leading international medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        The geographical distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in the two
        leading medical education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> was investigated.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> from all over the world published articles in
        Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> and to a lesser extent in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic</ENAMEX>
        Medicine. But while there is a wide distribution of the
        contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are dominated by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> from a few English-speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with the
        exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>.
        This study is to the best of our knowledge the first
        that provides some facts for a discussion about the
        engagement of single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> on the topic of medical
        education measured by the amount of their contribution to
        these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        OT designed and carried out the study. He performed the
        analysis and interpretation of the data and wrote this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
