
  
    
      
        Background
        According to recent estimates from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heart</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, the number of cardiovascular operations and
        procedures performed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">384%</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1979 to 1998</TIMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] Specifically, the number of
        percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) procedures rose
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">248%</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987 to 1998</TIMEX>, and although not as spectacular,
        the growth rate for coronary artery bypass surgery (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX>),
        was also impressive, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 553,000</NUMEX> cases
        performed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. Whether these changes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX>
        apply to similar procedures performed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>) is a relevant question, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>
        provided health care services to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
        The comparison between the data <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cardiovascular</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and procedures and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> provision
        of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> is of interest because of the
        comparability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> health care system with national
        health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> such as those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. The
        similarity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> health care system to these national
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> (including global budgeting, regionalization of
        costly services, and essentially free provision of care to
        a defined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>) creates an important contrast with
        the remainder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> health care system. Most of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> health care system is driven by fee-for-service
        payment, particularly by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> in the population
        receiving cardiovascular procedures. The use of cardiac
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revascularization</ENAMEX> procedures, defined as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CABS</ENAMEX> or PCI,
        represents a distinct philosophy and organizational
        imperatives concerning the treatment of coronary artery
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. How these expensive procedures are used is an
        indication of how scarce health care dollars are
        allocated.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> objective of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is to compare over
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time CABS</ENAMEX> or PCI use separately for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHDS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIS</ENAMEX>;
        for example, within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991 through 1999</TIMEX> were
        there discernible trends in the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CABS</ENAMEX>? A second
        objective is to compare age adjusted use rates in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>
        with estimates from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> national databases.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Patient Treatment File</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Patient Treatment File</ENAMEX> includes records of all
          hospitalizations occurring in all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> from
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> to current; it has several components, which contain
          extensive demographic and service eligibility
          information, and procedures performed in the operating
          room as well as those performed in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
          locations, including the cardiac catheterization
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinical Modification</ENAMEX> (ICD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) codes; there is extensive
          coding of procedures with a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> codes per
          surgery performed in the operating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and a similar
          maximum per each procedure performed outside the
          operating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, with a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> separate entries per
          hospital stay. The database includes a record linkage
          number making it possible to link to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> data files
          as well as to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with multiple
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hospitalizations</ENAMEX>. For this study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> hospitalizations for
          the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 1991 through 1999</TIMEX> were used.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX> is an annual
          sample of hospital discharges from nonfederal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
          located in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ]
          The current study uses survey information for the years
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991 through 1999</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 2 million</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospitalizations</ENAMEX>). As in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> databases, coding of
          procedures is with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ICD-9</ENAMEX> procedure codes, although coding
          is not as extensive, with a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> procedures per
          hospitalization. There is also limited demographic
          information including age, gender, race, and geographic
          region of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> itself is
          not identified. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, there is no record linkage
          number to permit identification of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who are
          hospitalized more than once. Sampling weights are
          provided for calculating national estimates of the number
          of hospitalizations for specific cardiovascular
          procedures.
        
        
          Nationwide Inpatient Sample
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample of the Healthcare Cost</ENAMEX>
          and Utilization Project is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> random sample of all
          hospital discharges from selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> in
          participating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Hospitals</ENAMEX> and state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
          that agreed to release their discharge data for research
          purposes were randomly selected according to a sampling
          frame based on ownership control, bed size, teaching
          status, urban or rural location, and geographic region.
          Since its inception in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sampled</ENAMEX> and number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> participating have increased
          from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991, to 17</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, and to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, when
          there were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 7 million</NUMEX> discharges in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ] As in the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> data sources, procedures are
          identified with ICD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> procedures codes, with a maximum of
          15 codes per hospital stay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient</ENAMEX>
          Sample does not include a record linkage number for
          identifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who have been hospitalized more
          than once, but it does identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and
          generally has more information than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discharge Survey</ENAMEX>. It also provides case weights for
          generating national estimates of cardiovascular procedure
          use. For purposes of this report, hospital discharges for
          the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 1993 through 1997</TIMEX> were used, with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> being
          the most current year for which discharges were
          available.
        
        
          Study population
          For each data set, hospital discharges with evidence
          of coronary revascularization procedures were selected by
          employing specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ICD-9</ENAMEX> procedure codes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX> was
          defined as procedure code 36.1x; discharges with
          concomitant procedures involving the valves or septa of
          the heart (code 35.x) were excluded, so that only
          isolated procedures were selected. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
          discharges with procedure codes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36.01</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36.02</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36.05</NUMEX>, or
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36.06</NUMEX>, with the latter code indicating coronary artery
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stenting</ENAMEX>. Since the code for stenting was implemented in
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1995</TIMEX>, rates of stenting are reported for the
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 1996 through 1999</TIMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, where it was possible
          to detect for an individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, multiple procedures
          of the same type performed on the same hospital day, only
          the first procedure of that type for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> was
          counted. Procedures occurring on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other days</TIMEX> of the same
          hospitalization were also included.
          Since <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 90%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, this study does
          not include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and given that use of these procedures
          is rare in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> 20
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years and older</TIMEX> were included. For purposes of comparison
          among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX> data sources, age, race, and geographic
          region of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> were also collected. Race was
          categorized as white, black, other, or unknown.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geographic</ENAMEX> region was defined as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> region included hospitals
          located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>
          region had the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>. The largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> in terms
          of number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West region</ENAMEX> had the following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Denominator construction
          Denominators for calculating age specific rates for
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX> were obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> census for the
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 1991 through 1999</TIMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] The numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in age
          categories <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20-34</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35-49</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-64</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65-74</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">≥ 75</ENAMEX> were
          reported for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, the numbers of unique
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> healthcare services were obtained from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outpatient Care</ENAMEX> files. The numbers of eligible male
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> visit to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> healthcare
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> were reported for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1991 through 1999</TIMEX>
          using the same age categories as for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> national
          surveys.
        
        
          Statistical methods
          It is important to recognize that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> of the data
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in this study included samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>,
          whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> contained all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and procedures.
          For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX> and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>, we obtained national
          estimates of the number of revascularization procedures
          by employing case weights. Age specific rates of use for
          each procedure were determined by dividing the number of
          procedures by the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the specific age
          category for that particular year. Age specific use rates
          were standardized by the direct method to create age
          adjusted-rates for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>; the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> male population
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years and older</TIMEX> was used as the standard. Rates are
          expressed as the number of procedures per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chi</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-square</NUMEX> for trend statistic was used
          to determine if there was a statistically significant
          increase or decrease in use rates within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHDS</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Baseline characteristics
          There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58,807</NUMEX> isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CABS</ENAMEX> performed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>
          medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991 through 1999</TIMEX>; distributions of
          age, race, and geographic location of the medical center
          are shown in table <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge</ENAMEX>
          Survey, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,540</NUMEX> hospitalizations for isolated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX>, and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>, there were
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54,218</NUMEX> procedures done in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. These cases provided the
          basis for the national estimates presented in table
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
          In general, the mean ages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> undergoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> were
          similar in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> datasets, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> had a lower
          proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 75 years</TIMEX> and older
          category. However, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> 75
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years and older</TIMEX> increased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> in
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, as seen in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as a
          whole, the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 and older</TIMEX> was relatively
          constant over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 9 years</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.6%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.6%</NUMEX> in
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>).
          These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were predominantly white, although the
          significant proportions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unknowns</ENAMEX> in the National
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>
          hindered comparisons across the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> databases. There were
          significant differences with respect to geographic
          location of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> where these procedures were
          performed. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 40%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> were located
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, whereas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge</ENAMEX>
          Survey and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>, the distributions
          were more balanced, although the latter had a higher
          proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>
          region. Presumably, these differences were due to
          sampling strategies employed in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> surveys of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>.
          The results for PCI mirror those for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX>, as seen in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">table 1</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51,509</NUMEX> hospitalizations
          performed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. Rather than combine all
          5 years of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>, we report
          baseline characteristics for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the most recent year
          for which these data are available. Noteworthy findings
          have to do with the lower proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> in the
          oldest age category and the predominance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> medical
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> region.
        
        
          Numbers of procedures and utilization rates
          In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991 through 1999</TIMEX>, there was a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35.6%</NUMEX>
          decrease in utilization rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.3%</NUMEX>
          decrease in the total number of procedures performed
          (table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). This decline was highly statistically
          significant (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0001</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi-square</ENAMEX> for trend). The
          trends for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were quite different.
          In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX>, there was a
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.8%</NUMEX> increase in utilization rates, as well as a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23.6%</NUMEX>
          increase in the estimated number of procedures (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.0001</NUMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>, utilization
          rates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 to 1997</TIMEX> increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.6%</NUMEX> and the estimated
          number of procedures went up by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16.4%</NUMEX>. Utilization rates
          were lowest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, and were considerably higher in
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> national samples. It is also noteworthy that
          beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, utilization rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX> declined in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX>.
          Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> rates in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18.3%</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>
          to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, and the number of procedures increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75.6%</NUMEX>
          during the same period (table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). This increase was
          highly statistically significant (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.0001</NUMEX>). As with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX>, there was a decline in utilization rates starting
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. In comparison to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, in the National
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX>, there were dramatic increases
          in utilization rates (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66.9%</NUMEX>), and the rise in the number
          of procedures was also higher than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95.5%</NUMEX>) (p
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.0001</NUMEX>). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, there was a decline in both rates
          and numbers of procedures, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> this trend
          reversed with significant gains for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">both 1998 and 1999</TIMEX>.
          In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>, where there were only
          5 years of data, utilization rates increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26.8%</NUMEX> and
          the number of procedures went up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36.5%</NUMEX>. Significant gains
          in the use of stenting were evident in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX>. As was the case with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> rates were lower in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> than in the other
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> settings. The findings for revascularization defined as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX> and/or PCI mirror those for the individual
          procedures, as seen in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The results of this study demonstrate considerable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">variability</ENAMEX> in the use of coronary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">artery</ENAMEX> revascularization
        procedures in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, not only
        were overall rates lower, but also both the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX>
        performed and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> adjusted rates declined from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> to
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, whereas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>, both the estimated number
        of procedures and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> adjusted rates increased during the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for which data were available. The findings for men
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undergoing PCI</ENAMEX> were somewhat different in that in all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        settings there were increases in both the number of
        procedures as well as the age-adjusted rates. However, in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> there was a noticeable decline in
        the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-</TIMEX>adjusted rates of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX>; this decline
        was also evident in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge Survey</ENAMEX>
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX>.
        Age adjusted rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> were lower in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>
        than in the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> settings, but it is important to put
        these rates in perspective. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX>, the
        age adjusted rate of isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">120.6</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>, somewhat lower than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">166.0</NUMEX>
        per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] By contrast, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age</TIMEX> adjusted
        rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 67.4</NUMEX> per
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presumably</ENAMEX>, the rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> would be higher if only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were included. A similar
        pattern was apparent for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX>, the age
        adjusted PCI rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">127.8</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>,
        very similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">139.8</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> and higher
        than the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">57.2</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ]
        The comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> rates to those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX>
        and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> is relevant because
        of the similarity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> health care system in the key
        dimensions of global budgeting and regionalization of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Hospitals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX> are heavily regulated
        compared to most of the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. They are
        capped in the amount of budget growth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>, and
        provision of costly, highly complex services such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> is limited. Similar constraints are in place in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>, to an even greater degree than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York State</ENAMEX>.
        There are several explanations as to why <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> adjusted
        rates in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> were lower than those reported in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        national surveys. First, not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> healthcare services undergo coronary revascularization
        procedures in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] This may be
        particularly true for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who are eligible for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and receive treatment for acute coronary syndromes
        in non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that are closer to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX> and
        have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac catheterization</ENAMEX> and open heart surgery
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> undergoing elective procedures, it
        may be that they lived far away from one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that performed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> and/or PCI and elected to
        undergo procedures closer to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. In short,
        veterans undergoing revascularization procedures in non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX> were not included in the age-adjusted rates
        reported in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, and this in part could account for
        the lower rates. The extent to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> of all ages
        undergo revascularization procedures outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> is not
        known. It is also possible that older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> were not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> or PCI due to excessive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comorbidity</ENAMEX>; there is evidence that older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> may have
        poorer health than non-veterans or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who are
        hospitalized in non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10</ENAMEX> ] Finally,
        although there is no evidence to support this, decision
        making for revascularization procedures may be more
        conservative in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VA.</ENAMEX>
        An explanation for the decline in use rates may have to
        do with the rapidly aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran population</ENAMEX>. The number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran users</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 75 and older</TIMEX> increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">177%</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210,000</NUMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991 to 582, 000</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> male population
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 years</TIMEX> and older increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 27%</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.8</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.1</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. Veteran users <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 years</TIMEX> and older comprised almost
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> of the veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, yet in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, men
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75</TIMEX> and over accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 7%</NUMEX> of the male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years and older</TIMEX>. This higher proportion of older veteran
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, coupled with the fact that comparatively fewer older
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> underwent revascularization procedures in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, may
        in part explain the decline in use rates in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>.
        The results of this study must be considered in the
        light of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> limitations. First, it is important to
        recognize that the age adjusted rates from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> national
        surveys were estimates based on case weights. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        surveys produced somewhat different estimates of both the
        number of procedures performed and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> adjusted rates,
        because in part, the surveys probably selected different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>. While these surveys include hospitals
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, they do not
        necessarily contain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> that are indicative of those
        performing cardiac revascularization procedures. These
        differences may also be due to the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 15</TIMEX> procedure codes as
        opposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 4</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hospital Discharge</ENAMEX>
        Survey. The number of codes reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> was much
        larger, but this did not result in higher use rates for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VA.</ENAMEX>
        Due to both sampling and coding issues, the national
        surveys may incorrectly estimate the number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revascularization</ENAMEX> procedures. Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationwide</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inpatient Sample</ENAMEX>, which identifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, we
        estimated age-adjusted rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
        State for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> adjusted rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX> for both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">198</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>, which
        is higher than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tu et al.</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ] , who had counts of all surgeries performed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
        State. On the other hand, our counts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> were estimated
        by applying case weights to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> in the survey.
        The situation with respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> was different; the
        estimated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> adjusted rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> in the
        Nationwide Inpatient Sample was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">142</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>, similar to
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">128</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tu et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ]
        A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> limitation of this study has to do with the
        choice of denominators. For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> surveys, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years and older</TIMEX> was used, whereas
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, the number of eligible veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> was
        employed. As has been seen, the proportion of older
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> census was relatively constant,
        whereas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> the proportion of users <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 years</TIMEX> and
        older doubled during the study period. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> denominators
        include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of health care, whereas the denominators for
        the national survey include both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. Given
        potential over-estimation of the number of procedures in
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> national surveys, possible under-estimation of the
        number of procedures in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, and differences in the
        types of denominators, it is possible that age adjusted
        rates of procedure use were too high for the national
        surveys and too low for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VA.</ENAMEX>
      
      
        Conclusions
        In summary, national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> discharge databases
        reported dramatic growth in the use of cardiac
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revascularization</ENAMEX> procedures, although the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CABS</ENAMEX>
        declined slightly with the advent of stenting, which has
        reduced the need for emergent bypass surgery. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] In the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, there has been a decline in both the total
        number and rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CABS</ENAMEX> performed, and since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, a
        decline in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> adjusted rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX>. These declines are
        most likely a function of several factors, including
        increasing substitution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CABS</ENAMEX> and the aging of
        the veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, as well as its overall poorer
        health.
      
      
        List of Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CABS Coronary Artery Bypass Graft Surgery</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI Percutaneous Coronary Intervention</ENAMEX>
      
      
        Competing Interests
        None declared.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' Contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CM-Formulated hypothesis</ENAMEX>, study design, collected and
        analyzed data, interpreted results, drafted manuscript.
        AES-Drafted manuscript and provided critical
        comments.
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
