
  
    
      
        Background
        Most mammals in the temperate zones undergo seasonal
        changes in physiological state [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . There are two
        mechanisms mammals can use to regulate responses to
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> change. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is direct responsiveness to an
        environmental cue (or cues) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">time of year</TIMEX>, most commonly
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> changes in photoperiod. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is an
        endogenous circannual rhythm entrained by an environmental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cue</ENAMEX>(s). Endogenous circannual rhythms may serve to protect
        the timing of seasonal functions from noise in
        environmental cues [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] , and may improve seasonal timing
        by buffering variation in the detection or measurement of
        even the most reliable environmental cues, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photoperiod</ENAMEX>.
        Laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> have been considered the classical model
        of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">nonseasonal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breeder</ENAMEX>, responding almost
        entirely to immediate conditions to regulate reproduction
        and physiology. However, recent work shows that laboratory
        rat strains vary in their responsiveness to photoperiod [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5 6</NUMEX> ] . Laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> of some strains can be
        manipulated to unmask responses to photoperiod or
        melatonin, even though short photoperiod alone does not
        affect reproduction [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9</NUMEX> ] . Peripubertal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inbred Fischer</ENAMEX> 344 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">F344</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> (BN) strains are
        naturally sensitive to reproductive inhibition by short
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photoperiod</ENAMEX> alone [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5 6</NUMEX> ] . In several species of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rodents</ENAMEX>, peripubertal young have stronger reproductive
        responses to photoperiod than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11 12 13</NUMEX> ] , and
        this appears to be true for induced-photoresponsive
        laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> as well [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] .
        It is unknown if responsiveness to short photoperiod
        persists into adulthood in strains of laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> that
        are naturally sensitive to short photoperiod, and if so,
        whether these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> also have any endogenous rhythm of
        responses to short photoperiod. In this study, adult F344
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were first tested for responses to short photoperiod.
        If F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> are photoresponsive, we predicted that adult
        rats treated with a short photoperiod would exhibit a
        decrease in testis size, body weight, and food intake. In
        addition, adult F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were tested for evidence of an
        endogenous rhythm of photoperiodic responses, by assessing
        whether mature <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> that had become insensitive to short
        winter photoperiods would regain sensitivity in constant
        short photoperiod. If they have such an endogenous rhythm,
        we predicted that F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> treated from weaning with a
        constant short photoperiod or an intermediate photoperiod
        (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">L12:D12</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX>) would exhibit an initial decrease in testis
        size, body weight, or food intake, followed by a refractory
        period with no differences relative to a control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in
        long photoperiod, and then a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> period of sensitivity
        to shorter photoperiods, again relative to a control group
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long photoperiod</TIMEX>. Here we report that adult F344 rats
        retain both reproductive and nonreproductive responses to
        short photoperiod, and that there is weak evidence for an
        endogenous circannual rhythm of reproductive responses to
        short photoperiod in F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, but not such a rhythm for
        non-reproductive responses to short photoperiod.
      
      
        Results
        
          Experiment one
          Repeated measures ANOVA on estimated testis volume
          over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 2-16</TIMEX> of short photoperiod treatment (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">L8:D16</TIMEX>;
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>) revealed a significant interaction between
          measurement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> and photoperiod, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.001</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.09</NUMEX>),
          indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SD</ENAMEX> treatment produced differences between
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> over time (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>-tests for individual
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> indicated a significant difference after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8 weeks</TIMEX>,
          and this result persisted through the time of the last
          measurement after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 16</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> treatment
          resulted in a maximum difference in testis size of
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 15%</NUMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 weeks</TIMEX> of treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1b).
          Repeated measures ANOVA on body weight over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 2-16</TIMEX>
          of treatment revealed significantly lower body weights in
          significant interaction between measurement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">photoperiod</ENAMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.0001</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35.33</NUMEX>),
          indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SD</ENAMEX> treatment produced differences between
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> over time. Body weight responded very rapidly
          to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-tail t-tests for individual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> revealed
          a significant difference in body weight from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 2</TIMEX>
          through the time of the last measurement at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 16</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2a). Differences in body weight were created by slight
          reductions of body weight of rats in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in LD
          gained body weight steadily throughout the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 weeks</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2a).
          Repeated measures ANOVA on food intake over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 2-16</TIMEX>
          of treatment revealed significantly reduced food intake
          levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.0001</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53.07</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2b). There
          was a significant interaction between measurement week
          and photoperiod treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.0001</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13.26</NUMEX>),
          indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SD</ENAMEX> treatment produced differences between
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> over time. Differences in food intake between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were first significant during the week
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-6</ENAMEX> measurement period (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2b), and the lower level of
          food intake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> persisted through the time of the last
          measurements on food intake during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 12-16</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2b).
        
        
          Experiment two
          
            Testis volume
            Rats put into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> photoperiod treatment from the time
            of weaning exhibited an initial period of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photoresponsiveness</ENAMEX> during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> of the
            experiment (measurements in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 2-14</TIMEX>). There was a
            significant inhibition of testicular growth from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-14</ENAMEX> for SD relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.0001</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82.45</NUMEX>;
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3a& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3c</ENAMEX>). There were no differences in
            estimated testis volume over the middle <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the
            experiment (measurements from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 18 - 30</TIMEX>; P = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.38</NUMEX>,
            F = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.78</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 3b& 3d</ENAMEX>). In the final <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the
            experiment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SD</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had significantly
            smaller testis size than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in the test on
            transformed data (measurements from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 35 - 52</TIMEX>; P =
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.048</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.28</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 3b& 3d</ENAMEX>). This difference
            between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> was not significant in a test
            on untransformed data (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.06</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.96</NUMEX>). Analysis of
            the untransformed data identified a significant overall
            decrease in testis size of all of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> over the
            final <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.0001</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> =
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83.77</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1b). Pairwise comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> and SD
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> identified significant differences in testis
            size only in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> and last <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the
            experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
            Rats put into an intermediate photoperiod treatment
            from the time of weaning exhibited an initial period of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photoresponsiveness</ENAMEX> during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> of the
            experiment (measurements in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 2-14</TIMEX>). There was a
            significant inhibition of testicular growth from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-14</ENAMEX> for INT relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.0001</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39.68</NUMEX>;
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3a& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3c</ENAMEX>). There were no differences in
            estimated testis volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> over the
            middle <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment (measurements from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 - 30</NUMEX>; P = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.46</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.57</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 3b& 3d</ENAMEX>) or the
            final <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.56</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.38</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
            3b& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3d</ENAMEX>). Analysis of the untransformed data for the
            final <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment identified a significant
            decrease in testis size of all of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> <
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0001</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38.85</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3b). Pairwise comparisons of LD
            and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> identified significant differences in
            testis size only in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> of the study and in
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week 35</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
            Truly free-running rhythms generated by an
            endogenous timer should cause <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to lose
            synchrony with each other over time [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Thus, if
            changes in testis volume in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later weeks</TIMEX> of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Experiment 2</ENAMEX> were due to an endogenous timer, then we
            would predict less synchrony among rats undergoing a
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> period of testicular inhibition in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Experiment</ENAMEX> 2
            relative to the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Experiment</ENAMEX> 1 subjected to
            a sudden, synchronous change to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> photoperiod. To test
            this prediction, the degree to which testicular
            regression was synchronized among adult rats exposed to
            a sudden change to short photoperiod in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Experiment</ENAMEX> 1
            was compared to the synchrony of testicular regression
            in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half of Experiment 2</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). An <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-</ENAMEX>test for equality of variances was used to
            compare the variability in timing of minimum testis
            size for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The variance for the mean date
            of minimum SD testis volume was significantly greater
            in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> photoresponsive period of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Experiment</ENAMEX> 2
            than in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Experiment 1</ENAMEX> (variance ratio = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.105</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> =
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.105</NUMEX>, P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.0001</NUMEX>).
          
          
            Body weight
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> photoperiod treatment from the time of
            weaning exhibited an initial period of lower body
            weight relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> controls during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first third</TIMEX>
            of the experiment (measurements in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 2-14</TIMEX>; P <
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0001</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51.16</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). There were no differences
            in body weight over the middle <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.16</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.10</NUMEX>) or final <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.26</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.30</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> continued to
            gain weight throughout the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5b).
            Pairwise comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> identified
            significant differences in body weight only in the
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>).
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> photoperiod treatment from the time of
            weaning exhibited an initial period of lower body
            weight relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> controls during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first third</TIMEX>
            of the experiment (measurements in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 2-14</TIMEX>; P <
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0001</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20.28</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). There were no differences
            in body weight over the middle <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.14</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.28</NUMEX>) or final <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.33</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.97</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> groups
            continued to gain weight throughout the experiment
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5b). Pairwise comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> groups
            identified significant differences in body weight only
            in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>).
          
          
            Food intake
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> photoperiod treatment from the time of
            weaning exhibited an initial period of lower food
            intake relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> controls during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first third</TIMEX>
            of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.0001</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23.39</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
            There were no differences in food intake over the
            middle <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.82</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>) or
            final <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.93</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>).
            Pairwise comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> identified
            significant differences in food intake only in the
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> photoperiod treatment from the time of
            weaning exhibited an initial period of lower food
            intake relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> controls during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first third</TIMEX>
            of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.003</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.43</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). There
            were no differences in food intake over the middle
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.98</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>). However,
            during the last <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment (measurements
            in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 36-52</TIMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had lower food intake
            relative to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> controls (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.70</NUMEX>).
            Pairwise comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> identified
            significant differences in food intake in the first
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and last <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
          
          
            LH
            As a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> measure of reproductive status, plasma
            luteinizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LD</ENAMEX> treated rats
            were assessed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two time</TIMEX> points in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX>,
            middle <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, and final <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the experiment. There
            were no significant differences in LH levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> vs.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> during any of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> assessed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P > 0.10</ENAMEX> for
            all comparisons; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>).
          
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Previous work demonstrated that young F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> have a
        period of photoresponsiveness that delays reproductive
        maturation, reduces food intake, and slows somatic growth [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 15</NUMEX> ] , and that these responses are pineal and melatonin
        dependent [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5 16</ENAMEX> ] . This study demonstrates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F344</ENAMEX> rats
        are also photoresponsive as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Figs. 1& 2</NUMEX>), with
        SD inducing lower testis size, food intake, and body weight
        than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX>.
        Decreases in body weight occurred prior to significant
        decreases in food intake, suggesting that decreases in body
        weight might cause the decreases in food intake. In species
        of hamsters that show photoperiodic regulation of body
        weight, there is evidence that decreases in body weight in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> can be independent of changes in food intake [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] or
        caused at least in part by decreases in food intake [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ]
        . Effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> on body weight began almost immediately and
        persisted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 10 weeks</TIMEX>. However, between week
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 and 16</TIMEX>, body weight of SD <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> was increasing with the
        same slope as that of LD <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a), suggesting that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> had become refractory to the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> around week
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of treatment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Testicular</ENAMEX> responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> may have
        followed a similar period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 weeks</TIMEX> of sensitivity
        followed by refractoriness (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1b). The rapid decrease in
        body weight of rats in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>, followed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 weeks later</TIMEX> by a
        return to weight increases, might make this system useful
        in studies on the control of body weight in mammals.
        The magnitudes of differences in food intake and body
        weight in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 10-20%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>),
        similar to those in peripubertal young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> (e.g.,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>), indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and peripubertal young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>
        have similar non-reproductive responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>. In contrast,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> had a greater effect on testis size in peripubertal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">males</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55% smaller</NUMEX> testis volume in SD than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD; Fig 3</ENAMEX>) than
        in adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15% smaller</NUMEX> testis volume in SD than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The large difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> groups
        in peripubertal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> was caused by the rapid rate at which
        testes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were growing compared to a slow rate
        of growth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, in contrast,
        treatment effects were due to testicular regression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX>.
        The proportionately larger effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> on peripubertal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> are consistent with the hypothesis that young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>
        are more sensitive to seasonal reproductive inhibition than
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11 12 13</NUMEX> ] . The reductions in testis size of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">adult rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> were slight, and might, by itself, have
        negligible effects on fertility in adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. However, it
        is possible that the combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> with mild food
        restriction [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">e.g.</ENAMEX>, [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] ] or other treatments might
        interact to cause much more significant responses.
        It is possible that hormonal and behavioral effects of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> might suppress fertility of adult F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> even though
        testis size remained relatively large. In Siberian
        hamsters, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> can regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion and behavioral
        responses to a female independently of changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> or
        gross changes in testis size [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . However, the fact
        that no differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion were observed in
        response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) suggests that this is not the case
        in F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. It is also possible that the single point
        samples were not sufficient to detect differences in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pulsatile LH</ENAMEX> secretion between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, as has been
        suggested previously for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats induced</ENAMEX> to become
        photoperiodic by androgen treatment [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . It would be
        useful to repeat this comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> levels using
        multiple samples obtained from indwelling atrial cannulas.
        Repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX> using this technique was not feasible,
        however, due to the long-term nature of this study.
        Previous studies on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> have shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> of some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> can be made reproductively responsive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> by
        manipulations such as androgen treatment [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] ,
        olfactory bulbectomy [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22</NUMEX> ] (but see [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] ), or food
        restriction [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . An effect of short photoperiod on body
        weight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">unmanipulated adult rats</ENAMEX> has not been reported
        previously, but has been reported for unmanipulated young
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> of several strains (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zucker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] , F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wistar rats</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BN</ENAMEX> rats [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] ). To our
        knowledge, this study is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> report of reproductive
        and nonreproductive responses to short photoperiod in
        adult, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">unmanipulated rats</ENAMEX>.
        The single large and highly significant change observed
        after the early stages of experiment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> was a general
        decrease of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 10%</NUMEX> in testis size of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that occurred in the last <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the study (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The fact that the change occurred in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> controls as
        well as experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> implicates either a systematic
        change in measurement methodology of soft testes or a
        change in some uncontrolled variable. Possibilities for the
        latter include age effects, a change in the tap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or
        food, and various forms of stress. This finding highlights
        the importance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as an essential control in
        this study. Without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as a control, this kind of
        change attributable to an uncontrolled variable would have
        been impossible to distinguish from the effect of an
        endogenous timer controlling the response to photoperiod.
        The change across all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> is similar to many previous
        reports on 'annual' or 'seasonal' changes of various
        physiological measures in laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">e.g.</ENAMEX>, [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27 28</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> ] ]. These previous studies provide evidence for
        temporal differences among rats held in apparently
        identical conditions, but these previous studies generally
        lack the controls necessary to distinguish between
        endogenous timers, seasonal cues, and effects of
        uncontrolled variables.
        In constant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> in experiment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, estimated testis volume
        was slightly reduced, relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> controls, in the final
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the study (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), but there was no effect of SD
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> intake or body weight. The changes in testis size
        were desynchronized relative to those occurring in
        experiment 1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), consistent with the prediction that
        a sudden photoperiod change would result in greater
        synchrony than would changes due to an endogenous timer. A
        previous study on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siberian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hamsters</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] reported a
        similar dissociation between endogenous timing of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reproductive</ENAMEX> and nonreproductive responses to constant
        short photoperiod similar to the results in experiment 2.
        Siberian hamsters in constant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">short days</TIMEX>, but not long
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, underwent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of a seasonal rhythm in testis
        size, but reproductive changes in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> cycle were not
        accompanied by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a typical winter</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">molt</ENAMEX>, and there was
        inconclusive evidence for a body weight rhythm [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] .
        However, the results of experiment <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> were not consistent
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">INT</ENAMEX> treatments. During the final <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of
        the experiment, there was no effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> on testis size
        or body weight, though food intake was slightly reduced,
        relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> controls (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). Pairwise comparisons of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> or INT with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> identified significant differences in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few weeks</TIMEX> of the last <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of experiment 2 (Figs.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3, 5, & 6</ENAMEX>). Bonferroni adjustments to probability
        values on these multiple pairwise comparisons would have
        resulted in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX>-values that were nonsignificant for most
        comparisons during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the final third</TIMEX> of the experiment.
        Overall, these results can be interpreted as only weak
        evidence for endogenous timers regulating a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">type II</ENAMEX>"
        rhythm [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] of sensitivity to photoperiod in F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>.
        If endogenous timers that affect responses to constant
        photoperiod are present, they appear relatively unimportant
        in adult F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        This study provides strong evidence that transfer from
        longer to shorter photoperiod can have significant effects
        on body weight, food intake, and the reproductive system
        even in adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. However, the results provided only weak
        evidence for an endogenous circannual rhythm in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reproductive</ENAMEX> system. The effects of transfer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> on food intake and body weight were particularly
        dramatic, as they prevented the steady increase in body
        mass that is typical of ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lib</ENAMEX> fed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in this age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
        The mechanisms of this voluntary reduction in food intake
        and change in regulation of body mass may be relevant to
        the control of eating and weight gain in other mammals.
        These results have implications for studies on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">F344</TIMEX> and
        other photoperiodic strains of rats, particularly because
        the F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> is widely studied throughout the world, and
        has been the most commonly used inbred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> strain in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . The existence of both reproductive
        and nonreproductive responses of adult F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> to short
        photoperiod, and the possibility for weak endogenous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circannual</ENAMEX> responses to short photoperiods could complicate
        the design and interpretation of experimental results,
        especially in the case of long-term studies.
        Recent reports have documented variability in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photoresponsiveness</ENAMEX> in peripubertal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> among laboratory
        rat strains [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . The fact that photoresponsiveness
        extends to adulthood in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">F344</TIMEX> rats suggests that genetic
        variation in the presence and strength of adult
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photoresponsiveness</ENAMEX> is present among rat strains. If so,
        then these responses represent another genetically variable
        trait in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> of neuroendocrine inputs and regulatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> that regulates seasonality. There is increasing
        evidence for genetically based variation in seasonal
        strategies among natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of small mammals
        [reviewed by [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1 33</ENAMEX> ] ] and in laboratory strains of
        rodents [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 34 35</NUMEX> ] . Identifying and understanding the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neuroendocrine</ENAMEX> basis for this variability in rats and other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX> will be important for understanding the
        evolutionary physiology of reproductive strategies and for
        understanding genetic variation in brain function.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Experiment one
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-one</NUMEX> male F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were gestated and then
          raised in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long day</TIMEX> (LD) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16L:8D</TIMEX>; lights on at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0500</TIMEX>) to
          age <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22.3</NUMEX> Â± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.4 weeks</TIMEX> (mean Â± <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>) in our breeding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> were then placed in either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short day</TIMEX> (SD)
          (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8L:16D</TIMEX>;lights on at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0900</TIMEX>; n = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>), or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">LD</ENAMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> =
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>). The light intensity ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80-120 lux</NUMEX>.
          Treatments were balanced according to age, body weight,
          and testis volume. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> were individually housed in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polypropylene cages</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">36 Ã— 24 Ã— 19 cm</NUMEX>) and kept at a
          temperature of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23 Â±</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4Â°C</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> were provided with ad lib
          access to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rat-Mouse-Hamster</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern States</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooperative</ENAMEX>) and tap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Testis volume, body weight,
          and food intake were measured after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12</TIMEX>,
          and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 weeks</TIMEX> of treatment. Food intake was calculated by
          providing measured amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in the food hopper
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every two weeks</TIMEX> and measuring the difference between
          original food weight and the weight of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> remaining. In
          the rare cases in which unconsumed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was present
          within the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX>, the weight of unconsumed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was
          included in the food weight. Body weight and food intake
          were measured to the nearest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">g. Testis</ENAMEX> volume
          measurements, body weight measurements, and collection of
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">270 Î</TIMEX>¼L of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> were performed under light
          anesthesia with isoflurane. Testis measurements were
          taken externally on the left testis using dial calipers
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBS</ENAMEX>, blind with respect to treatment. In order to
          check for consistency of measurements, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> of the
          measurements were repeated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDH</ENAMEX>, blind both to
          treatment and to measurements by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBS</ENAMEX>, to determine
          measurement precision. Testis volume was estimated using
          the formula for a prolate spheroid (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Width</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2Ã— Length</ENAMEX> Ã—
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.523</NUMEX>). In previous studies in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, external testis
          measurements have been found to be highly correlated to
          measurements and weights later taken from the excised
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX> was collected in heparinized tubes
          from a small tail nick, refrigerated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> after
          collection, centrifuged within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>, and plasma frozen
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-50Â°C until</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">assay</ENAMEX> was performed.
        
        
          Experiment two
          Fifty F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 days</TIMEX> were gestated and raised
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> photoperiod in our breeding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> were
          weaned at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 days</TIMEX>, and placed into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> =
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>), or intermediate photoperiod (INT) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">L12:D12</TIMEX>; lights
          on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at 0700</TIMEX>; n = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>). Sibling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were divided among
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> treatments, and body weight was balanced across
          treatments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> in each group were housed in individual
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cages</ENAMEX> and maintained in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>-ventilated
          photoperiod-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>. In each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> rats
          were held in a single large photoperiod <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>, and the
          remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in each treatment were held
          in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> set to the same photoperiod.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was designed explicitly as a control for any
          changes in husbandry, allowing us to test for changes in
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> shorter photoperiod groups relative to the LD
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>. A number of studies have reported explicitly on
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> changes in animal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX>, including rat
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">e.g.</ENAMEX>, [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27 28</NUMEX> ] ], that could be caused by
          uncontrolled seasonal variation in husbandry. These
          potential differences have included such things as
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> changes in freshness of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, and changes in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, bedding, humidity, noise, or odors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> and SD
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chambers</ENAMEX> were in the same animal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, were identical in
          construction, and received air from intakes that were
          less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> cm apart. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">INT</ENAMEX> treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was in a
          similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> in a nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Feeding and watering
          were identical for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Thus, seasonal differences
          in husbandry should be controlled by comparing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Testis length and width
          measurements, body weight measurements, food intake
          measurements, and blood collection were performed at
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-week</TIMEX> +<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">/- 3-day</TIMEX> intervals for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 10 weeks</TIMEX> of
          treatment. Food intake continued to be measured at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-week</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intervals</ENAMEX>, except for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one 5-week</TIMEX> interval late in the
          study. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were inadvertently given an unmeasured
          amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 6 - 8-week</TIMEX> measurement period;
          food intake data in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX> for those <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were
          discarded. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 10 weeks</TIMEX>, testis volume
          measurements, body weight measurements, and blood
          collection were taken at approximate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-week</TIMEX> intervals,
          and then returned to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-week</TIMEX> intervals for the last
          portion of the study. More specifically, these data were
          taken at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 14, 18, 22, 26, 30, 35, 42, 46, 48</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49.5</NUMEX>,
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> collection was carried out as described in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Experiment 1</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> assay
          The plasma concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> was determined by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich immunoassay</ENAMEX> with the ORIGEN
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electrochemiluminescence</ENAMEX> (ECL) Immunoassay System. The
          protocol followed was developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DR Deaver</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://das38.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cas</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psu</ENAMEX>.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">edu/1</NUMEX>hecl.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm.</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monoclonal</ENAMEX> mouse
          anti-bovine LH <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (generously provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan</ENAMEX>
          Roser at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UC-Davis</ENAMEX>) was conjugated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORGIN TAG-NHS</ENAMEX> ester.
          A monoclonal rabbit anti-bovine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> was used as the
          capture <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (generously provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.J. Reeves</ENAMEX>
          at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Sheep anti-rabbit</ENAMEX> IgG
          Dyna-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">beads</NUMEX> M280 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynal</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>) were used to link
          the LH capture <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to magnetic beads for
          measurement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rat LH</ENAMEX> for a standard curve was provided by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. F. Parlow</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Hormone Pituitary Program</ENAMEX>.
          A linear regression model was matched to the standard
          curve and used to convert photon counts into LH
          concentrations in pg/ml. All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were run in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duplicate</ENAMEX>, and the mean value of each duplicate pair was
          used as a single data point in all statistical
          comparisons. All samples from a given blood collection
          period were assayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>, and control tubes that
          were run every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> tubes revealed no intra-assay drift.
          The sensitivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> assay was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> pg/ml for the
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-Î</NUMEX>¼l sample volumes. The mean of the intra-assay
          coefficients of variation for tubes containing pooled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">juvenile rat serum</ENAMEX>, containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LH</ENAMEX> at a low physiological
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentration</ENAMEX>, was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>, and the inter-assay coefficient
          of variation was also <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>.
          Only plasma samples for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 2, 4, 18, 22, 35</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Experiment 2</ENAMEX> were assayed. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These weeks</TIMEX> represented
          times at which minimum and maximum SD LH levels should
          have occurred based on examination of testis volume
          levels at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these weeks</TIMEX>, if an endogenous circannual LH
          rhythm existed. It was predicted that the minimum level
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> secretion would occur slightly earlier than the
          lowest measured level of testis volume due to the delayed
          effects of hormonal changes producing measurable
          differences in testis size.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX> data analysis
          
            Experiment one
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> on estimated testis volume were converted to
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-point running means before analysis. Measurements of
            soft testes through the scrotum are particularly
            subject to measurement error (especially small changes
            in measurement style over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods of weeks</TIMEX>). This class
            of error has little effect on differences between
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> within a single measurement period, but can
            cause apparent changes between measurement periods. In
            previous work on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, we have found that small
            differences in measurement style between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> can
            cause estimates of testis volume to fluctuate by
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 10%</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week to week</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] , and that
            use of running <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-point point means reduces this
            source of measurement error [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">e.g.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] ]. For testis
            volume, statistical analyses were also carried out on
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> tranformed by dividing individual data points in
            each measurement period by a constant, the mean for the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in that measurement period.
            Repeated measures <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>'s
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protected LSD</ENAMEX> post-hoc comparisons were used to test
            for changes in testis volume, body weight, and food
            intake using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SuperAnova</ENAMEX> (v. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abacus Concepts</ENAMEX>,
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, CA). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> testis
            volume, body weight, and food intake were performed for
            each measurement period using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-tailed t-tests, with
            the expectation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD < LD</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Statview v 4.5</ENAMEX>, Abacus
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concepts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, CA). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>-tailed t-tests were
            selected because only suppression of reproduction,
            reductions in body weight, and reductions in food
            intake have been observed in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> in prior
            experiments on F344 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5 15 16 19</ENAMEX> ] . For all
            tests, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.05</ENAMEX> were considered significant.
            Testis size was not adjusted for body weight. First,
            there was no correlation between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body mass</ENAMEX> and testis
            mass in adult rats at the beginning of the study (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>=
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX>; P = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.88</NUMEX>; n = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>). In addition, a
            previous study found that testis weight is not
            dependent upon body weight in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">F344</TIMEX> rats [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] .
            Therefore, adjustment of testis size for body weight
            using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANCOVA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> is not appropriate.
          
          
            Experiment two
            For all variables, statistical analyses were carried
            out in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. Analyses were carried out on both the
            raw data and on data tranformed by dividing individual
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> points in each measurement period by a constant,
            the mean for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in that measurement period.
            The latter approach allowed use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> for temporal changes over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that were
            independent of responses to photoperiod. In contrast,
            the former approach provided information on differences
            that might be due to uncontrolled variables over the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">year-long</ENAMEX> experiment. As in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Experiment 1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-point
            running means of estimated testis volume were used to
            reduce the effects of measurement error for testis
            size. As in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Experiment 1</ENAMEX>, testis size was not adjusted
            for body weight using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANCOVA</ENAMEX> models.
            Repeated measures ANOVA comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and LD
            with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> were carried out on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX>, middle
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last third of the 52 weeks</TIMEX>. These intervals
            were chosen because the initial effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> on young
            rats persist for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 14-16 weeks</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5 19</ENAMEX> ] ,
            and because species that have a type<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-II</ENAMEX> annual rhythm
            generally are photorefractory for a period of at least
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-20 weeks</TIMEX>, corresponding to the middle <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of our
            experiment, and then have a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> period of
            photoresponsiveness beginning at some time in the final
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year in photoperiod treatment [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">e.g.</ENAMEX>,
            see [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] ]. Additional analyses carried out on
            different time intervals produced similar results to
            those reported in the Results. Finally, pairwise
            comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INT</ENAMEX> were also
            carried out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> of measurement using
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-tailed t-tests. Bonferroni adjustment of
            probability values for multiple comparisons in these
            pairwise t-tests was not conducted. However, the
            likelihood of significant differences occurring by
            chance in this series of multiple comparisons is
            considered in the Results and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discussion</ENAMEX>.
          
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> contributed equally to the original ideas,
        experimental design, and data analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MBS</ENAMEX> carried out <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>
        percent of the data collection, performed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> assay, and
        wrote early drafts of the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDH</ENAMEX> carried out final
        revisions to the manuscript.
      
    
  
