
  
    
      
        Background
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dihydropyridine receptor</ENAMEX> (DHPR) of skeletal muscle
        consists of α 
        1S , α 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , β 
        1a and γ 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subunits</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . The α 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> subunit is a large <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-repeat
        transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~220</NUMEX> KDa that contains the basic
        functional elements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-type Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, including
        the Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+selective pore and S4 "voltage-sensing"
        transmembrane segments in each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> internal repeats
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . β subunits are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~65</NUMEX> kDa cytosolic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> essential
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">membrane</ENAMEX> trafficking, modulation of channel kinetics,
        and for excitation-contraction (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>) coupling [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] . The
        α 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> subunit is a highly glycosylated ~<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">175</NUMEX>
        kDa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> formed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two disulfide</NUMEX>-linked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">peptides</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] ,
        whereas the γ 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> subunit is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~32</NUMEX> kDa skeletal
        muscle-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> presumptive transmembrane
        domains with almost unknown function [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Skeletal</ENAMEX> muscle cells utilize the voltage sensors formed
        by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the S4</TIMEX> segments to trigger a rapid elevation of
        cytosolic Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+, thus coupling membrane excitation to
        muscle cell contraction. Subsequent to charge movements in
        the voltage sensors, a conformational change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> is
        transmitted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ryanodine receptor</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RyR1</NUMEX>), presumably,
        via <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-protein interactions</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . Ultimately, there
        is a brief opening of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">RyR1</NUMEX> channel resulting in the
        release of Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+from the sarcoplasmic reticulum (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SR</ENAMEX>).
        Numerous observations have lent support to this view, and
        especially significant are the functional expression
        studies in dysgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">myotubes</ENAMEX> lacking α 
        1S . The dysgenic myotube is devoid of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-type Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+current, charge movements and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling. All
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> are restored in the dysgenic myotube by expression of
        α 
        1S [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10 11</ENAMEX> ] . These results
        corroborated the essential role of α 
        1S in the mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skeletal</ENAMEX> muscle cells.
        The mechanism by which the DHPR signals <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the RyR1</TIMEX> is
        poorly understood [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domains</ENAMEX> in the cytoplasmic
        linker between repeats <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> have been clearly
        implicated [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15 16 17 18 19</NUMEX> ] , and some regions such as
        Thr671<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-Lue690</TIMEX> were suggested to trigger <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">RyR1</TIMEX> opening by
        binding to RyR1 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . However, extensive deletions
        within the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> linker that eliminate the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">RyR1</NUMEX> binding
        region, and other suggested signaling regions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX>
        loop [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , do not entirely eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX>
        ] . Hence additional domains of α 
        1S and/or other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subunits</ENAMEX> appear to
        be engaged by the voltage sensor and contribute to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
        coupling signal. In this respect, the contribution of the
        β1a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subunit</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling in skeletal muscle
        cells has been extensively documented [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 22 23 24</ENAMEX> ] .
        In the present report, we characterized a frame-shift
        mutant of α 
        1S that expresses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> complementary
        fragments of α 
        1S . Complementation between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> α 
        1S fragments produced recovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
        coupling in dysgenic muscle cells lacking α 
        1S . The results suggest the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling
        voltage sensor of skeletal muscle is modular in function
        and can be assembled from separate hemi-Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+channel
        fragments.
      
      
        Results and Discussion
        
          Expression of a frame-shift mutation of α 1Sin
          dysgenic myotubes
          Primers for the frame-shift mutant, fs-α 
          1S , were originally designed to
          delete the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20-mer</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thr671-Leu690</ENAMEX> in the cytosolic loop
          between repeats <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> of α 
          1S and to generate a full-length α 
          1S carrying this internal deletion. A
          proofreading error during a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reaction resulted in an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">amplified DNA</ENAMEX> with the desired deletion but also
          containing an additional thymidine following the TTG
          codon for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Leu670</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-base shift in reading
          frame introduced a serine at position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">671</TIMEX> followed
          immediately by a stop codon (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B). This frame-shift
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mutation</ENAMEX> was re-ligated into an otherwise full-length α 
          1S , subcloned into the mammalian
          expression vector <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pSG5</TIMEX>, and transfected into dysgenic (α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">null</ENAMEX>) myotubes. Fs-α 
          1S was abundantly expressed in primary
          dysgenic myotubes in culture (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C) and produced the
          expected truncated α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 1D</ENAMEX>). Western blots
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T7</ENAMEX>-tagged fs-α 
          1S and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T7</NUMEX>-tagged full-length α 
          1S showed that the expressed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">full-length α</ENAMEX> 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> migrated with an apparent
          molecular weight of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 185</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDa</ENAMEX> under reducing
          conditions. This result is consistent with the mobility
          of the native purified skeletal muscle α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subunit</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . The fs-α 
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90</TIMEX> KDa which is entirely consistent with
          the theoretical molecular weight of the expressed
          fragment which was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85.6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDa</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-fold
          overloading of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE gel failed to detect any
          fragment of a size comparable to full-length α 
          1S (not shown).
        
        
          Recovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling by the frame-shift a
          1ScDNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling was investigated in voltage-clamped
          myotubes with simultaneous monitoring of intracellular Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+using confocal fluorescence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluo-4</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . Controls
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2Aindicated that the overwhelming majority
          of non-transfected dysgenic muotubes (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> cells) did
          not produce detectable Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transients (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.1</NUMEX> ΔF/Fo) or
          Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+currents (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO"><20 pA/cell</ENAMEX>) in response to
          depolarization under voltage-clamp. This is shown in the
          line-scan images of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluo-4</ENAMEX> fluorescence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2Aand the
          corresponding traces of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICa</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+during a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-ms
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">depolarization</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+30</NUMEX> mV and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+90</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mV</ENAMEX> delivered at the
          start of the line scan in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. However, in two
          cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> cells) we observed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idys</ENAMEX>, the low-density
          endogenous Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+current previously described in dysgenic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">myotubes</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 28</NUMEX> ] . The reason for the low abundance of
          this current in these cultured myotubes is unknown. Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+currents and stimulated fluorescence for one of the
          cells expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idys</ENAMEX> is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B. We observed a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peak ICa</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+density of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 0.8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pA/pF</ENAMEX> and a
          barely detectable fluorescence signal which in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2Bis
          indicated by the arrow in the trace of integrated
          fluorescence at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+30</NUMEX> mV. This small fluorescence signal
          disappeared entirely at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+90</NUMEX> mV, suggesting it might be
          contributed directly by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idys</ENAMEX> or might be due to SR Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+release induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idys</ENAMEX>. The voltage dependence of the
          fluorescence signal and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICa</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+are compared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2Cfor
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cells expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idys</ENAMEX> and for the vast majority
          of cells which altogether did not express intracellular
          Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transients or ICa <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+. The maximum fluorescence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> contributed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idys</ENAMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idys</ENAMEX> was present, was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT"><0.2 ΔF/Fo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, the shape of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorescence</ENAMEX> vs. voltage relationship was bell-shaped and
          a mirror image of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICa</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+vs. voltage curve. These
          controls indicated that non-transfected dysgenic myotubes
          are low-background cells that do not express
          voltage-activated Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+signals of major consequence for
          the present studies.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3shows that fs-α 
          1S recovered a significant fraction of
          the voltage-activated Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient compared to that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> by full-length wt-α 
          1S . The magnitude of the fluorescence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> expressed by fs-α 
          1S was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 5</NUMEX>-fold larger
          than the largest Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient detected in
          non-transfected myotubes expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idys</ENAMEX>, ><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-fold
          larger than the average Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient detectable in
          non-transfected cells, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1/3</NUMEX> of the maximum SR Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+release expressed by the control wt-α 
          1S construct. Thus, we are confident
          that the voltage-evoked Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient in cells
          transfected by fs-α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> was a direct consequence of
          the expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. Also shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3is ICa
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+activated by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>-ms depolarization used to activate
          the Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient. fs-α 
          1S did not express L-type Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+current
          even though it was consistently able to activate the Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> cells. Absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICa</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+was
          further verified using longer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">500-ms</TIMEX> depolarizing pulses
          (not shown). The skeletal nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling
          expressed by fs-α 
          1S is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A. The peak Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+vs. voltage relationship expressed by fs-α 
          1S , like that of wt-α 
          1S , was sigmoidal in shape reaching a
          maximum at large positive potentials (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>50 mV</NUMEX>), a range
          in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICa</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+is progressively small. The line scans of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4Bfurther confirmed that a Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient of similar
          shape and magnitude was observed in a fs-α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">transfected</ENAMEX> myotube in the absence
          of external Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+. Hence the signaling mechanism, like
          that reported in normal myotubes and dysgenic myotubes
          expressing wt-α 
          1S , was Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+entry independent [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ]
          . We also expressed fs-α 
          1S in cultured myotubes from two
          available gene knock-out (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KO</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, lacking the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">β1a</ENAMEX> isoform of the skeletal muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ]
          and lacking RyR1 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B, we failed
          to detect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling in these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">KO cells transfected</ENAMEX> with
          fs-α 
          1S . In summary, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling
          expressed by fs-α 
          1S is strictly skeletal-type and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">requires RyR1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">β1a</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          fs-α 1Sexpresses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> complementary protein
          fragments
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling recovered by fs-α 
          1S could be due either to the activity
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of α 
          1S alone or to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-protein
          complementation between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and a
          fragment expressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of α 
          1S . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of α 
          1S could have been translated by the
          fs-α 
          1S expression vector if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATG</ENAMEX> codon
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Met701</NUMEX>), which is downstream from the TGA termination
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">codon</ENAMEX> and is in-frame with the wild-type message (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 1B</ENAMEX>)
          served as open reading frame for translation of the
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the wt message. Although this would be
          unusual, the fact that the codon for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Met701</TIMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 25</NUMEX>
          bases downstream from the termination codon could have
          substantially increased the possibility of a re-start of
          the translation of the second half of the message at
          Met701. This phenomenon has been described in eukaryotic
          cells and in viral-infected mammalian cells and is known
          as translation by leaky <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal scanning</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX> ] . To
          test this explanation, the presumptive restart condon,
          Met701, was mutated to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Ile701</NUMEX> in the fs-α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">template</ENAMEX>. If fs-α 
          1S recovered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling by virtue of
          expressing a single protein fragment, then fs-α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M701I</ENAMEX> should also recover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
          coupling since the mutation was introduced downstream
          from the stop codon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5shows that this was not the
          case. Fs-α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M701I</ENAMEX> did not recover Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transients in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> tested cells, consistent with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leaky ribosomal scanning</ENAMEX>. As a positive control, we
          coexpressed fs-α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M701I</ENAMEX> and the C-terminus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of α 
          1S , namely α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Δ1-700</ENAMEX>, cloned into a separate pSG5
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX>. The results in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5indicated that α 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1S Δ1-700</ENAMEX> alone was inactive. However,
          when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">myotubes</ENAMEX> were cotransfected with fs-α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M701I</ENAMEX> and α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Δ1-700</ENAMEX>, each in a separate pSG5
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX>, there was a robust recovery of Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transients in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6Ashows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fluorescence</ENAMEX> vs. voltage
          relationships for the fs-α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M701I mutant</ENAMEX> and for this mutant
          coexpressed with α 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1S Δ1-700</ENAMEX>. The combined expression of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> complementary fragments of α 
          1S resulted in a robust recovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
          coupling with sigmoidal Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+release vs. voltage
          characteristics. A summary of the maximum fluorescence
          during the Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient in response to a depolarization
          to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+90</NUMEX> mV is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6B. The magnitude of the Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient expressed by fs-α 
          1S <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M701I</NUMEX> + α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Δ1-700</ENAMEX> was indistinguishable from
          that of wt-α 
          1S (t-test significance p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.671</NUMEX>, see
          figure legend). To confirm expression of the C-terminus
          half of α 
          1S in cells transfected with fs-α 
          1S , we used the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> loop
          polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody SKI</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] directed against epitope
          Ala739-Ile752 which is downstream from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Met701</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          6Cshows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> loop antibody recognized the
          C-terminus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> when cells were transfected with fs-α 
          1S but not when myotubes were
          transfected with fs-α 
          1S <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M701I</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal protein
          which is consistent with the theoretical molecular weight
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">132</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDa</ENAMEX>. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6Dshows that fs-α 
          1S <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M701I</TIMEX> was abundantly expressed in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">myotubes</ENAMEX> in the absence or presence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal
          fragment. This indicated that the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling
          observed in myotubes expressing fs-α 
          1S <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M701I</TIMEX> was not due the production of
          a labile <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. In summary, the recovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling
          by coexpression of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> functionally inactive proteins
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) taken together with the immunoblots (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6C)
          favor the explanation that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) fs-α 
          1S recovers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> function by virtue of
          expressing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> complementary fragments of α 
          1S and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the expression of the
          C-terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of α 
          1S by fs-α 
          1S is likely to occur by leaky
          ribosomal scanning.
        
        
          Implications for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling in skeletal
          myotubes
          Except for the magnitude, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SR Ca 2</ENAMEX>+release signal
          expressed by fs-α 
          1S was entirely typical of skeletal
          myotubes with sigmoidal voltage-dependence, proceeding in
          the absence of external Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+and requiring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RyR1</TIMEX>. A
          comparison of the maximum fluorescence (Δ<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/Fo max</ENAMEX>) at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">+90</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mV</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6B) shows that the signal generated by fs-α 
          1S was significantly smaller than that
          generated by the control construct (wt-α 
          1S vs. fs-α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX>-test significance p = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.014</NUMEX>) and
          smaller than that generated by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> coexpressed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragments</ENAMEX> (fs-α 
          1S vs. fs-α 
          1S <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M701I</NUMEX> + α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Δ1-700 t-</ENAMEX>test significance p =
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.013</NUMEX>). These observation suggests that the magnitude of
          the Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+release appears to be limited by the low yield
          of expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal fragment achieved by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leaky ribosomal scanning</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half of the fs</TIMEX>-α 
          1S message. To test this explanation
          further, we coexpressed fs-α 
          1S and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of α 
          1S each in a separate pSG5 vector. We
          found that fs-α 
          1S and α 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 SΔ1-700</ENAMEX> together expressed Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transients with a ΔF/Fo max similar to wt-α 
          1S control (not shown). Thus we are
          certain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling expressed by fs-α 
          1S is mechanistically similar to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> skeletal-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling but limited in
          magnitude by a comparatively lower density of functional
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPRs</ENAMEX> that are assembled in cells expressing fs-α 
          1S . It is conceivable that the
          functional integrity of the fragmented α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is maintained in part by
          the β subunit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> which spans both <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">halves</NUMEX> of the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">α1</NUMEX> pore subunit by binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">I-II</ENAMEX> loop and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36</NUMEX> ] . Consistent with this explanation,
          we failed to detect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling recovery when fs-α 
          1S was expressed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">β1</NUMEX>-null
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">myotubes</ENAMEX>.
          Earlier studies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">voltage-gated Na</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> had
          shown that pore function was not compromised when the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II-III</ENAMEX> linker or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">III-IV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">linker</ENAMEX> was cut and the two
          fragments were coexpressed each in a separate vector [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>
          ] . We would thus conclude that in the case of the Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, an intact <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> loop is essential for this
          function since neither fs-α 
          1S nor the combined expression of the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> truncated fragments (not shown) was able to rescue Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+current. This result is entirely consistent with the
          identification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> loop as critical for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enhancement of L</ENAMEX>-type Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+current expression by the RyR1
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . However <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling, per se, can clearly proceed
          with a cut in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> loop. This was shown here by the
          behavior of the fs-α 
          1S construct and elsewhere by
          expressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> (α 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1S 1-670</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> (α 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1S 701-1873</ENAMEX>), each with entirely wt
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX> and each in a separate expression vector [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ]
          . The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thr671</ENAMEX>-Leu690 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> known as Peptide A [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> ] is missing in fs-α 
          1S suggests this <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20-mer</NUMEX> domain is not
          critical for the conformation change transmitted from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the RyR1</TIMEX>. To test this further, we generated an
          in-frame deletion of this region, as originally intended,
          that showed normal function [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . Another domain
          critical for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling is Csk35 downstream from Peptide
          A (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Leu720-Gln765</ENAMEX>). This region was identified using
          chimeras of α 
          1S and α 
          1C [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Csk53</TIMEX> is present in
          α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Δ1-700</ENAMEX> and was detected by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II-III</ENAMEX> loop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> which is directed against the center
          portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Csk53</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] , the participation of this
          domain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> cannot be ruled-out.
          In eukaryotic cells, translation starts at the AUG
          codon nearest to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' end of the mRNA, and this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">initiator</ENAMEX> site is found by sequential <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal</ENAMEX> scanning
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>' direction [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . However, translation
          initiation at internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUGs</ENAMEX> due to leaky ribosomal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scanning</ENAMEX> has been documented, especially for mRNAs
          consisting of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">a short</ENAMEX> leader <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> upstream from the main
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX>. In some cases, reassembly of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal</ENAMEX>
          initiation complex after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terminator codon</ENAMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leader ORF</ENAMEX> serves to re-initiate translation at the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">initiator AUG</ENAMEX> codon for the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX>, and thus two
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are generated [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . In other cases, leaky
          scanning by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal</ENAMEX> initiation complex bypasses the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-located leader <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> entirely, and only the "internal"
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> is translated [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . In the case of fs-α 
          1S , we are not entirely certain which
          mechanism best applies. A bypass of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' end
          of the α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> in favor of a presumed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> at
          Met701 is unlikely because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal fragment of the
          size expressed by α 
          1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Δ1-700</ENAMEX> has not been detected in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skeletal</ENAMEX> muscle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SKI antibody</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] or other
          antibodies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . Thus Met701 is not an internal
          initiation site under normal circumstances. Entry of a
          new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Met701</TIMEX> seems a more likely
          explanation. However, re-initiation after a stop has only
          been described for cases in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ORF</ENAMEX> is no
          longer <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">than 30 codons</TIMEX> because initiation factors fall off
          shortly after recognition of the initiator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUG</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] .
          In the case of fs-α 
          1S , what can be considered the
          "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> encodes for a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">671</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX>. Hence
          we are not certain if re-initiation of translation after
          would apply here. At the same time, it is important to
          point out that in the present studies, fs-α 
          1S expression is under the control of
          a viral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> and that in this hybrid viral-mammalian
          expression system, the rules pertaining to leaky
          ribosomal scanning may be different. The mechanism of
          translation of the fs-α 
          1S clearly deserves closer scrutiny in
          the future.
        
      
      
        Conclusions
        The present studies show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling recovery by a
        frame-shift mutant of α 
        1S due to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-protein
        complementation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">halves</NUMEX> of
        α 
        1S . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> houses repeats
        I and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">adjoining cytosolic</NUMEX> loop and the
        C-terminal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> loop, along with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repeats III</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> with the adjoining loop. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein-protein</ENAMEX>
        complementation between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal
        fragments produced a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DHPR</ENAMEX> capable of functioning as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
        coupling voltage sensor, thus suggesting the presence of at
        least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> functional modules within α 
        1S . Recent evidence suggests that the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> internal repeats of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">voltage-gated Na</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>,
        which is closely related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-type Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+channel encoded
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX>, have non-equivalent functional roles because
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">S4</NUMEX> segments of repeats <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">I and II</ENAMEX> move much faster than
        those of repeats III and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . By analogy, the
        "fast-moving" module of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> would be represented by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal fragment and the "slower-moving" module by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal fragment. Interactions between these two
        modules are likely to be critical for intramembrane charge
        movements in the assembled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> and for
        coupling the movement of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">S4</NUMEX> gating charges to the
        opening of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">RyR1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. Future studies of gating
        currents in each hemi-Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+channel fragment should provide
        valuable information on how the "fast" and "slow" gating
        modules interact during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> coupling in skeletal muscle.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal fragment was generated by an unusual
        restart of translation of the fs-α 
        1S message at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M701</TIMEX>, presumably by leaky
        ribosomal scanning, and was eliminated by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M701I</NUMEX> mutation.
        Hence, a premature stop codon in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> loop upstream
        of M701 may not necessarily cause a loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHPR</ENAMEX> function
        because in these cases, function would be recovered by
        complementation between protein fragments expressed by the
        same cDNA. From a methodological perspective, leaky
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scanning</ENAMEX> could be further used as a means to control
        protein expression to desired levels, since restart of
        translation after a premature stop codon is sensitive to
        the number of nucleotides separating the stop and restart
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">codons</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . By changing the position of the restart
        methionine relative to the premature stop codon, it might
        be possible to significantly change the level of expression
        of the distal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein fragment</ENAMEX> and hence functional protein
        as a whole. Thus, leaky scanning remains as an attractive
        possibility for boosting or depressing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels in a
        transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Primary cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> myotubes
          Primary cultures were prepared from hind limbs of day
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 embryos</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">E18</NUMEX>) as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . cDNAs
          of interest and a separate expression vector encoding the
          T-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">membrane antigen CD8</ENAMEX> were subcloned into the
          mammalian expression vector pSG5 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>, CA) and
          were mixed and cotransfected with the polyamine LT-1
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panvera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>). Whole-cell recordings and immunostaining
          were done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-5 days</TIMEX> after transfection. Cotransfected
          cells were recognized by incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD8 antibody</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beads</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>). The coincidence of expression of
          CD8 and a cDNA of interest was ><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">α</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1ScDNA</ENAMEX> constructs
          
            pSG5 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wt</ENAMEX>-α 1S
            A unique silent 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HindIII</ENAMEX> site was introduced by
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> at nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2228</TIMEX> in the full-length α 
            1S <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">template</ENAMEX> and cloned into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">T7</NUMEX>-α
            
            1S pSG5 vector using 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AgeI</ENAMEX> and 
            XhoI <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. The 
            HindIII-XhoI fragment (nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2228</TIMEX> to
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">nt 2878</ENAMEX>) encompasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> loop was subcloned into
            pCR <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TOPO TA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>, CA) and this plasmid was
            further used for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reactions.
          
          
            pSG5 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fs</ENAMEX>-α 1S
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reactions for deletion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">671-690</ENAMEX>,
            consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nanograms pCR <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TOPO</ENAMEX>/ 
            HindIII-XhoI insert, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> pmoles of
            each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primer</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM dNTPs, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1X</TIMEX> cloned 
            Pfu buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX>
            cloned 
            Pfu <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>).
            The antisense primer was complementary to nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2202</TIMEX> to nt
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2235</TIMEX> and the sense primer was nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2296</TIMEX> to nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2326</TIMEX>.
            Amplification was carried out for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95°C</TIMEX> for
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 seconds</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 minutes</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">72°C</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>/kb of plasmid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reaction was treated
            with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U of</ENAMEX> 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DpnI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>) and
            recircularized with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T4 DNA ligase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>). Once
            amplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>, the 
            HindIII-XhoI digest was ligated
            into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">T7</NUMEX>-α 
            1S pSG5 vector using the same
            restriction sites.
          
          
            pSG5 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fs</ENAMEX>-α 1SM701I
            The construct was produced by a two-step PCR
            reaction using fs α 
            1S as template. Using conditions as
            above, the sense primer (nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX> to nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>) was paired
            with antisense primer
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>'TCCAGCTTCTTGGCGATCACAGACTTCTCC3' carrying the point
            mutation. In a seperate reaction, sense primer
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>'GGAGAAGTCTGTGATCGCCAAGAAGCTGGA3' was paired with
            antisense primer (nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3100</TIMEX> to nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3081</TIMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> PCR
            products were diluted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500</ENAMEX> in ddH 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> and then hybridized to each
            other for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95°C</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 minute</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43°C</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
            minute at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 pmol</TIMEX> of nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX> to nt
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> primer and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> pmol of nt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3100 to 3081</TIMEX> primer were
            added and further cycled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95°C</TIMEX>, then
            30X of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95°C</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 minute</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60°C</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 minute</TIMEX> at
            72°C and finally <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72°C</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product
            was then cloned into the fs α 
            1S construct using 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HindIII</ENAMEX> and 
            XhoI <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            pSG5 a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1SΔ1</NUMEX>-700
            The construct was produced by cutting pSG5 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fs</ENAMEX> α 
            1S with 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AgeI</ENAMEX> and 
            HindIII enzymes and filling-in
            the overhangs with klenow fragments. The plasmid was
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religated</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA T4 ligase</ENAMEX>.
          
        
        
          Whole-cell voltage-clamp
          Whole-cell recordings were performed as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] using an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Axopatch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">200B</ENAMEX> amplifier (Axon
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Instruments, Foster City</ENAMEX>, CA). All experiments were
          performed at room temperature. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Patch</ENAMEX> pipettes had a
          resistance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-2 MΩ</ENAMEX> . The external solution was (in mM)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">130 TEA-Methanesulfonate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> CaCl 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 , 1 MgCl</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HEPES-TEA</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>), pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>. The
          pipette solution was (in mM) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cs-aspartate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX> (for Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transients) or
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX> (for Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+current), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MOPS-CsOH</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">voltage</ENAMEX> dependence of peak intracellular Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+(Δ<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/Fo</ENAMEX>) was
          fitted according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Boltzmann</ENAMEX> distribution (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eqn</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) A =
          A 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max /</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>+exp(-(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX>-V 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/2</NUMEX> )/k)). A 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max</ENAMEX> is ΔF/Fo 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">max</ENAMEX> ; V 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1/2</ENAMEX> is the potential at which A = A 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">max /2</ENAMEX>; and k is the slope factor.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ΔF/Fo</ENAMEX>=(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-Fo</ENAMEX>)/Fo where F is the fluorescence during a Ca
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+transient and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fo</ENAMEX> is the resting fluorescence of the
          cell immediately before the stimulation.
        
        
          Confocal fluorescence microscopy
          Line-scans were performed as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] in cells
          loaded with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> mM fluo-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> AM (fluo-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> acetoxymethyl ester,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>, OR) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">~30 minutes</TIMEX> at room
          temperature. Cells were viewed with an inverted Olympus
          microscope with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20X</NUMEX> objective (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.A.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.4</NUMEX>) and a Fluoview
          confocal attachment (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Olympus, NY</ENAMEX>). Excitation light was
          provided by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mW <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argon</ENAMEX> laser <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">attenuated</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> with
          neutral density filters. For immunofluorescence, confocal
          images had a dimension of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1024</TIMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1024</TIMEX> pixels (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.35</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">microns/pixel</ENAMEX>) and were obtained with a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">40X</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>-immersion
          objective (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N.A.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.3</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Immunostaining
          Cells were fixed and processed for immunofluorescence
          as described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 20</ENAMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal fragment expressed
          by fs-α 
          1S or wt-α 
          1S was identified with a mouse
          monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> against a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">T7</NUMEX> epitope fused to the
          N-terminus of α 
          1S . The anti-T7 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novagen</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>) was used at a dilution of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>. Secondary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were a fluorescein-conjugated goat anti mouse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehringer Mannheim</ENAMEX>, IN) used at a dilution of
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> and a fluorescein-conjugated donkey anti-rabbit
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemicon</ENAMEX>, CA) used at a dilution of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1000</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Western blots
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal fragment was identified with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKI</ENAMEX>, a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rabbit polyclonal antibody</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II-III</ENAMEX> loop of α 
          1S (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ala739-Ile752</ENAMEX>) previously
          characterized [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . Cells were scrapped from tissue
          cultures dishes with cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> plus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protease inhibitors</ENAMEX>
          and spun in a cold table-top centrifuge. Cells were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homogenized</ENAMEX> in a glass-teflon homogenizer in a minimal
          volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and diluted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:1</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">vol:vol</ENAMEX>) with SDS-gel
          loading buffer composed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris-Cl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.8</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> mM
          dithiothreitol, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> bromophenol blue and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glycerol</ENAMEX>. Samples were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> mg of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was applied to a
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> polyacrylamide gel and electrophoresed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Proteins</ENAMEX> were transferred to PVDF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">membranes</ENAMEX> and analyzed with either anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">T7</NUMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SKI</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> and the appropriate secondary antibodies. The
          subunits were visualized using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SuperSignal ECL</ENAMEX> reagent
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>). The images were captured on a
          Chemi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Imager</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpha Innotech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Leandro</ENAMEX>, CA) set to a
          level just below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">saturation</TIMEX>.
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX> (dimethyl sulfoxide); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGTA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene glycol bis</ENAMEX>-α
        minoethylether <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tetraacetic acid</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-hydroxylethyl
        piperazine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-ethane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfonic acid</ENAMEX>); MOPS
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3N</NUMEX>-Morpholino-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">propane sulfonic acid</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PVDF</ENAMEX> (polyvinylidene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">difluoride</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTX</ENAMEX> (tetrodotoxin); <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TEA</ENAMEX> (tetraethylamonium);
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORF</ENAMEX> (origin of replication).
      
    
  
