
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Fetal alcohol syndrome</ENAMEX> (FAS) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do not display the
        normal hemispheric dominance patterns observed in non-FAS
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Dominance has been disrupted or is, in
        some cases, completely absent, depending on the amount of
        tissue loss in the corpus callosum. Morphological
        abnormalities, one of which is corpus callosum hypoplasia,
        has been observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAS</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archibald et</ENAMEX>
        al. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , using structural magnetic imaging (sMRI), also
        noted that there were corpus callosum abnormalities in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who had experienced prenatal exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>.
        In a magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) study of adult FAS
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>, callosal morphological data, when compared with
        landmark data, differed significantly from that of control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
        Agenesis of the corpus callosum occurs as a consequence
        of early embryonic insult. The exact time of the insult
        usually determines the extent of commissural agenesis.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeeves et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] reported a timetable in which, if the
        insult occurs before the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> embryonic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>),
        all forebrain commissures will be absent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ]
        observed that in utero exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX>) disrupted
        the distribution of callosal projection neurons in the rat
        somatosensory cortex. The complete absence of a corpus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">callosum</ENAMEX> in rats exposed in utero to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> has been
        documented by several studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9</NUMEX> ] . Because in utero
        exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> affects both corpus callosum development
        and laterality, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have turned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> model to
        assess the impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> on both measures.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimmerberg et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] rats prenatally exposed to a
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> derived calories (EDC) liquid diet did not
        display a preferred side for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-hole nose-poke
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apparatus</ENAMEX>, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> were maintained on a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chow</ENAMEX> or liquid diet. Later, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimmerberg et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ]
        assessed laterality using a left/right lever choice on a
        continuous reinforcement schedule. Again the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> exposed
        in utero to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">EtOH</ENAMEX> displayed less side preference than the
        chow fed and liquid diet pairfed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ]
        tested paw preference in rats, he found that rats exposed
        to ethanol during gestation were more likely than control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> to preferentially use the left paw. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zimmerberg et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] tested preferred tail direction in
        neonates exposed in utero to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX>. When compared to the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0%</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and the chow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left-</ENAMEX>preferred tail
        direction was exhibited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
        Thus it appears that in utero exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, at least
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>, results in a disruption of laterality
        patterns.
        We have investigated the potential fetoprotective
        capacity of silymarin (SY) against the toxic effects of in
        utero exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silymarin</ENAMEX> has long been noted
        for its hepatoprotective properties [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . The mechanisms
        through which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> is thought to manifest its therapeutic
        effects include the following: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) enhanced protein
        synthesis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) scavenging free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
        prevention of glutathione (GSH) depletion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
        preservation of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> membrane integrity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . The
        theories formulated to explain the physiological events
        that culminate in fetal alcohol <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX> include decreased
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antioxidant</ENAMEX> levels, decreased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein synthesis</ENAMEX>, increased
        free radical activity, and disrupted membrane function. The
        observation that the protective effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> and the
        causal factors in FAS overlap, led us to investigate the
        possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> might have application as a
        fetoprotectant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>. In a series of studies conducted
        in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> we have demonstrated that the coadministration
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> prevents ethanol-induced decreases in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">neonate</ENAMEX> mortality rate, decreases in pup birth weight, and
        increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> and brain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma glutamyl</ENAMEX> transpeptidase
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGTP</ENAMEX>) activity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> also prevented the deficits
        in spatial memory and social memory observed in rats
        exposed in utero to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] .
        Given that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> has been successful in ameliorating some
        of the negative consequences of in utero exposure to EtOH
        (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> model), we examined the possibility that SY
        might prevent EtOH-induced callosal agenesis and the
        disruption of laterality (as measured by paw
        preference).
      
      
        Methods
        
          Subjects
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Subjects</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> female <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fisher/344</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rats</ENAMEX> weighing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">235-245 g.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> were housed with male rats until
          pregnancy was confirmed by vaginal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smear</ENAMEX>. Once pregnancy
          was confirmed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were placed in standard plastic
          laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">maternal tubs</ENAMEX> and assigned to one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
          gestational treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten</TIMEX> pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> were
          assigned to each treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group 1</ENAMEX> consisted of
          pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> that received the liquid diet regimen
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bioserve; Frenchtown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) containing an isocaloric
          amount of dextrin maltose that matched the caloric amount
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> diet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were provided with the
          liquid diet to which a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">400-mg/kg</ENAMEX> dose of silymarin (SY)
          was added. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX>, provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inverni della Beffa</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, contained <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29.8%</NUMEX> silybin complexed with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphatidylcholine</ENAMEX>. The dose administered to the rats
          was based on the percent active ingredient in the
          compound and was derived from data acquired in our
          previous studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group 3</ENAMEX> rats received the
          liquid diet, which contained both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol-</ENAMEX>derived calories (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.7%</NUMEX> EtOH <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX>). In
          previous studies we established blood alcohol
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentrations</ENAMEX> (BACs) for all experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and
          ascertained that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> does not have any appreciable affect
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> were maintained on
          the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDC</ENAMEX> liquid diet and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were provided
          with unlimited access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab chow</ENAMEX>. The amount of
          liquid diet provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Groups 1, 2</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          was determined by the amount of liquid diet consumed the
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">preceding day</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> 4. The liquid diet
          treatments were discontinued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX>
          gave birth at which time they were provided access to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab chow</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EtOH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is
          continued until birth, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pup survival rats</ENAMEX> are extremely
          low. Once pups reached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 18-21 days</TIMEX> they were weaned
          and placed in individual standard laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cages</ENAMEX>. On
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of weaning we randomly selected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> female pup
          from each litter and as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> in the laterality
          testing procedure. We used <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> in an effort to remedy
          the paucity of FAS-related data collected on female
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX>. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat pups</ENAMEX> were selected from
          each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> original treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Apparatus and procedures
          
            Testing apparatus for laterality
            All testing sessions took place in a reaching
            apparatus. The apparatus was made up of three
            contiguous plastic cubicles, each of which measured
            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24.13 cm × 7.62 cm × 16.41 cm</NUMEX>. The adjoining walls of
            the cubicle were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6.35 mm</NUMEX> thick and were painted white
            so that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> in adjacent cubicles could not see each
            other. An <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> mm tube was installed in the face of each
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cubicle</ENAMEX>. All test sessions were videotaped.
          
          
            Laterality testing procedure
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> began laterality testing at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 12 weeks</TIMEX>.
            They were food-deprived for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14-21</NUMEX> hr prior to the
            testing sessions and each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> participated in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
            testing sessions. They were placed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> at a time into
            the reaching apparatus, one in each cubicle. Rats
            remained in the reaching apparatus until they had
            either reached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> times for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruit Loops</ENAMEX>) or one
            hour had passed. A single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruit Loop</ENAMEX> was placed in the
            reaching tube for each trial. A successful reach was
            defined as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> obtaining the piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruit Loop</ENAMEX>.
            Each time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fruit Loop</ENAMEX> was retrieved another piece
            was immediately placed into the tube. Upon completion
            of a testing session rats were taken out of the
            reaching apparatus and placed back into their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            Perfusion
            After all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> had completed the reaching
            protocol they were anesthetized and intracardially
            injected <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ringers</ENAMEX> solution and then with a
            fixing solution. After sacrifice the brains were
            removed, preserved in formalin, and stored in a
            refrigerator for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> corpus callosum extraction.
          
          
            Corpus callosum extraction
            Because hemisphere weights were also dependent
            variables a cut was made through the longitudinal
            fissure that separated the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> hemispheres, which then
            exposed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two halves</NUMEX> of the corpus callosum. The
            hemispheres were weighed separately prior to corpus
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">callosum</ENAMEX> extraction. Using a surgical knife the corpus
            callosum was outlined and lifted away from the rest of
            the brain. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two halves</NUMEX> of the corpus callosum were
            weighed separately on an analytical balance. The total
            length of the corpus callosum was measured before and
            after extraction. The genu, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, and splenium were
            identified to confirm complete development of the
            corpus callosum.
          
        
        
          Statistics
          The criterion for assessing individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laterality</ENAMEX> was
          generated from binomial z scores. To identify a group of
          rats as demonstrating paw preference, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> had to
          be observed reaching in the same direction. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> raters,
          who were unaware of treatment groupings, observed and
          counted the reaches. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Package</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sciences</ENAMEX> (SPSS) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reliability Analysis</ENAMEX> was used for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inter</ENAMEX>-rater reliability. A priori contrasts were
          conducted to determine if differences existed between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> on all dependent measures (laterality, corpus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">callosum</ENAMEX> [development and weight], splenium development,
          total brain weight, and pup weight gain).
        
      
      
        Results
        Pup weights were recorded at birth and again when the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were weaned. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX> and subsequent post hoc Tukey
        comparisons revealed that there were no significant birth
        weight differences for any experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> as compared
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>; although, the overall ANOVA was
        significant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, 45</ENAMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.98</NUMEX>, 
        p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .05</NUMEX>). However, when the
        wean weights were analyzed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX> results were
        significant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, 45</ENAMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.77</NUMEX>, p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< .01</NUMEX> and, the posthoc
        tests specified that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43.12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>) differed
        significantly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50.08</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>), t(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">45</NUMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.476</NUMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.001</NUMEX>. This indicates that
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH pups</ENAMEX> gained comparatively less weight during the
        period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between postnatal day</TIMEX> (PND) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 and PND 20</NUMEX>, which is
        when the pups were weaned. A percent weight gain was
        calculated for each group (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> was
        calculated and indicated that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61%</NUMEX> of the variance in pup
        weight gain values was attributable to the treatment
        received during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gestation</TIMEX>.
        Total brain weight and corpus callosum weight were
        determined for each of the pups and a total weight to
        corpus callosum ratio calculated (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Eta square
        was again calculated for the variance in corpus callosum
        weight resulting in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX> of the variance attributable to the
        treatment condition. After perfusion the brains were
        visually inspected to determine whether or not the splenium
        was fully developed. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> tested, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> did not have
        a fully developed splenium. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All 8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were from the EtOH
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>). A priori contrasts were conducted to
        assess group differences. All of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> comparisons were
        made with the Liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diet</ENAMEX> (LD) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Significant
        differences are reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tables 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2, 3</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> had an adverse impact on birth weight as indicated
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. Further, the in utero exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> also
        prevented normal weight gain during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20-day</TIMEX> suckling
        period. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SY</ENAMEX> given in combination with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> appeared to
        prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EtOH</ENAMEX>-associated low birth weight and attenuated
        weight gain. Although the birth weight of the SY-only pups
        was normal, weight gain during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the suckling period</TIMEX> was
        significantly less than that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Weight gain
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> pups, however, was still more than that observed
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> pups. In a previous study [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> pup weight
        gain did not differ significantly from weight gained by LD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pups</ENAMEX>.
        Brain weights did not differ significantly, although the
        lowest weights were observed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX>. Corpus callosum
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX>) weights did vary significantly, for which the EtOH
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pups</ENAMEX> had the lowest weights. Inexplicably, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chow</ENAMEX> pup
        callosal data weight data did not differ from that of the
        EtOH pups. However, when the ratio of brain weight to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX>
        weight was calculated there were no significant group
        differences. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> brain to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> weight ratio
        indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> weight as compared to total brain
        weight was the lowest observed among all of the treatment
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. This lower <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> weight might be associated with the
        unusual left paw preference displayed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> pups. As
        an indication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> fetal effects the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> weight
        measure does not seem to provide much relevant information,
        whereas the measure of splenium development clearly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indicates EtOH</ENAMEX>-induced disruption. The in utero effect of
        EtOH on splenium development has also been observed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAS</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sowell et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] , using MRI analytic
        methods determined that EtOH-related callosal area
        reductions were most severe in the splenium.
        Consistent with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] investigation, the
        EtOH-exposed rats displayed a left paw preference. Further
        evidence of laterality disruption was manifested by
        incomplete splenium development in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">EtOH</ENAMEX>-exposed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. The paw preference scores in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chow</ENAMEX> groups
        indicated an even distribution between left and right paw
        preference. An unexpected finding was that of the strong
        right paw preference displayed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY/EtOH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Given the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50:50</TIMEX> left/right paw preference
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>; the expected outcome of SY
        influence would be the preservation of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50:50</TIMEX> ratio. The
        SY paw preference results are, however, consistent with a
        very recent study by Pence [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . Male and female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>
        were tested for paw preference using a food-reaching task.
        There was no significant sex difference. He did observe
        that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70.2%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were right pawed, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19.3%</NUMEX> were left
        pawed, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.9%</NUMEX> were ambidextrous. Our observations can be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summarized</ENAMEX> as follows: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>/344 rats when not subject
        to any form of prenatal insult and subsequently raised with
        adequate nutrition and housing do not, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, display
        any particular paw preference. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Rats when exposed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">utero</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EtOH</ENAMEX> experience tissue loss in the splenium and,
        as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, display a left paw preference. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rats</ENAMEX> that
        have been exposed in utero to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EtOH</ENAMEX> co-administered with SY
        have a fully intact corpus callosum, yet display a
        right-paw preference. Why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> would have any impact on
        laterality that is distinct from EtOH exposure is puzzling.
        There is a possible explanation in light of the
        gender-specific differences observed in callosal size [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
        ] coupled with the fact that prenatal exposure to EtOH
        causes feminization of male rats and defeminization of
        female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 25 26</NUMEX> ] . There is a hormonal influence on
        the developing commissural pathway that could be disrupted
        by a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EtOH</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aberrations</ENAMEX> in hormone
        activity, such as the diminished perinatal surge of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">testosterone</ENAMEX> observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EtOH</ENAMEX>-exposed male fetal rats [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
        ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EtOH</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attenuation</ENAMEX> of the testosterone surge
        eliminated the normal sex difference in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> callosal size.
        In a previous study we observed that the coadministration
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> to pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX> prevented the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EtOH</ENAMEX>-induced
        deficits in social recognition observed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EtOH</ENAMEX>-exposed
        offspring [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> memory in rats is a sexually
        dimorphic behavior that requires adequate levels of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perinatal</ENAMEX> and neonatal androgen activity. In utero exposure
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> reduces testosterone levels as well as maternal
        levels of estrogen; consequently there is a reduction in
        P450-aromatase activity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] . This then results in a
        reduction in estrogen and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">estrogen receptor activation</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Estrogen</ENAMEX> receptor activity is necessary for the expression
        of androgen-driven behavior in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 27</NUMEX> ] . In
        addition to behavior, estrogen also affects neurogenesis,
        synaptogenesis, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">synaptic</ENAMEX> modifications [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . Our
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> were the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offspring</ENAMEX> of the various treatment
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. As previously confirmed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>'s corpus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">callosum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX>) is a sexually dimorphic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> with the
        larger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> observed in male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fitch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
        ] also determined that the feminization (reduction in size
        as compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> of male rats) of the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> only
        occurs if the ovaries are intact and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> is exposed to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estrogen</ENAMEX>. Recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bimonte et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] established that
        neonatal exposure to estrogen is essential to
        feminine-specific brain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to the extent that the
        brain can respond appropriately to the organizing effects
        of subsequent estrogen exposure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Experimental rats</ENAMEX> were
        administered an estrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor blocker</ENAMEX>, and later at
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">postnatal day 70</TIMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> responded to estrogen
        administration with an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> size; an effect
        opposite of what would be expected. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dehmlow et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ]
        have established that silymarin can compete with estradiol
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">estradiol</ENAMEX> receptor binding sites [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . Therefore, it
        is possible that the ameliorative effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> observed in
        the present study can be attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">estrogen</ENAMEX> receptor
        activation at developmentally appropriate times.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Because callosal development was complete in rats
        exposed to the co-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX>, it
        appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> conferred some ameliorative effects upon
        the corpus callosum developmental process. Without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX>,
        EtOH-exposed pups clearly displayed EtOH-induced disruption
        to normal callosal development. Even though the mechanism
        for the protective action of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SY</ENAMEX> is not clearly understood,
        our consistent findings of fetoprotectivity in the presence
        of in utero EtOH exposure merit further exploration.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX>'s contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author 1 NM</ENAMEX> performed all of the neuroanatomical
        assessments in the study and participated in the design of
        the study.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Author 2 LL Participated</ENAMEX> in the design of the study, the
        statistical analysis, and drafted the manuscript.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Author 3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">RM</ENAMEX> maintained the experimental protocol
        throughout the experiment and performed a portion of the
        laterality assessments.
      
    
  
