
  
    
      
        Background
        The increasing research in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Complementary</ENAMEX> and Alternative
        Medicine (CAM) and the importance placed on practicing
        evidence-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX> require ready access to the CAM
        scientific literature. The optimal retrieval of a
        literature search in biomedicine depends on the appropriate
        use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Subject Headings</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeSH</ENAMEX>), descriptors and
        keywords among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] .
        It has been recognized that available online databases
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">covering CAM</ENAMEX> differed in their thesaurus construction and
        indexing procedures, making effective and efficient
        searching difficult [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] .
        The controlled vocabulary for biomedicine has been
        developed and continuously updated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Library</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine</ENAMEX> (NLM). It is referred to as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM Medical</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subject Headings</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeSH</ENAMEX>). The purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeSH</ENAMEX> is to provide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uniformity</ENAMEX> and consistency to the indexing of the
        biomedical literature [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . With the recent development
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PubMed</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MeSH</ENAMEX> descriptors for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX> have
        been expanded.
        As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2002</TIMEX>, there were a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21,973</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeSH</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">descriptors</ENAMEX> found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM Medical Subject</ENAMEX> headings -
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annotated Alphabetic</ENAMEX> list, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . While the National
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Complementary and Alternative Medicine</ENAMEX> (NCCAM)
        has identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 360</NUMEX> healing modalities, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeSH</ENAMEX> currently
        included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 83</NUMEX> descriptors for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX>, arranged
        hierarchically under the sets of terms in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Complementary Therapies</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . In
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 41</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MeSH</ENAMEX> descriptors for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX>, arranged
        under 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alternative Medicine</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX>-references have been available to assist searchers in
        finding the most appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MeSH Heading</ENAMEX>, for example, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alternative Medicine</ENAMEX> see 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Complementary Therapies</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therapeutic Cults</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeSH</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">descriptor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1963 and 1993</TIMEX>. It was only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> that
        the term 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alternative Medicine</ENAMEX> was implemented in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM MeSH</ENAMEX> thesaurus. 
        Medicine, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional</ENAMEX> was the
        only new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MeSH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">descriptor</ENAMEX> added under 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Complementary Therapies</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> NLM
        Medical Subject <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headings</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] .
        Other biomedical databases that include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX> literature,
        such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL - Cumulative</ENAMEX> Index to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing and Allied</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Literature</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MANTIS - Manual</ENAMEX>, Alternative
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Therapy Index System</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] , also use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MeSH</ENAMEX> as
        their standard thesaurus with a list of supplement terms in
        their subject areas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX> medical subject headings
        include also a broad range of terms for research
        methodology including, for example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject headings</ENAMEX> for
        validity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] .
        The main purpose of database indexing is to enhance the
        yield and accuracy of search results. Indexing is done
        either manually or generated by computer programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Indexers</ENAMEX>
        carry out indexing manually in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>, and MANTIS
        according to their own perceptions and understanding of the
        study contents. In comparison, computer programs generate
        indexing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> database. These programs
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> words or phrases and group them by frequency of use [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> ] . Computer generation of keywords is referred to as
        semantic indexing while assigning controlled vocabulary by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> is referred to as analytic indexing [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> provides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX> and Keywords
        Plus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author Keywords</ENAMEX> are taken from a list of keywords
        that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> provided in their papers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keywords Plus</ENAMEX>
        are taken from references cited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. Therefore,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keywords</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> often include important terms not listed in
        the study title, abstract, or list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> keywords [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
        ] .
        Several studies on indexing practices have focused on
        areas other than complementary and alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>. A
        recent study looked at the process of indexing and
        retrieving medical information for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of different
        ethnicity in several major health-related databases. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> found that information might not be obtained if
        the health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> were not familiar with the
        indexing policy. They noted that databases were not in
        agreement about the definition and use of most of their
        search terms [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        Another study compared <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> articles that happened to be
        indexed twice. Comparing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> found significant differences in depth of
        indexing (e.g., the prevalence of major and minor
        descriptors, check-tags, and subheadings) and choice of
        subject headings [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] . This study illustrated that
        indexing practices are often inconsistent and little is
        known about indexing and retrieving information from
        databases on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX>.
        Searching databases for a CAM topic can be confusing and
        ineffective if terms are not used correctly. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> are
        reporting studies without using standard controlled
        vocabulary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> might not assign the appropriate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">terminology</ENAMEX> to represent the studies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Indexers</ENAMEX> are
        constrained further by the specifications of the controlled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vocabulary</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . In particular, a relatively small
        number of descriptors pertaining to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX> are contained in
        the controlled vocabulary [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] , thus limiting indexers
        further in their choice of assigning specific subject
        terms.
        practices in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> selected databases in relation to key
        terms used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and search terms used by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> to locate studies on the validity of spinal
        palpation as a model for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX> searches. We posed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        questions.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. What are the key terms used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> in the fields
        of chiropractic, physical therapy, allopathic and
        osteopathic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> in defining the validity of spinal
        palpatory diagnostic tests in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with spinal
        neuromuscular dysfunction?
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. What MeSH terms and descriptors are available to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> in different databases on the subject of validity
        of spinal palpation?
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. How frequently do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> assign appropriate MeSH
        terms or descriptors to represent the terms used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        in titles and abstracts?
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. What are the key terms used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> to
        conduct a literature search on the validity of spinal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palpation</ENAMEX>?
        We investigated the frequency of use by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indexers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, of search terms for validity,
        spinal palpation and musculoskeletal dysfunction. We
        evaluated and compared analytic manual indexing to computer
        program generated semantic indexing.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Develop <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Key Concepts and Identify Search</ENAMEX>
          Terms
          This study was conducted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Susan Samueli Center</ENAMEX>
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Complementary and Alternative Medicine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irvine</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 2001 and 2002</TIMEX>. A
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multidisciplinary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> including
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, clinicians, and a health sciences librarian
          undertook this study. Our research question was: "What is
          the validity of spinal palpatory procedures for diagnosis
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with spinal neuromuscular dysfunction<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" The
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step for conducting a literature search was to
          break down the research question into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> key
          concepts:
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. validity/validity assessment,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. spine
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">palpation</ENAMEX> procedures
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. neuromusculoskeletal dysfunction.
          The multidisciplinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> identified MeSH terms,
          descriptors, and potentially related keywords for these
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> key concepts [see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>].
          We then verified the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeSH</ENAMEX> terms [mh] using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Library of Medicine Medical Subject</ENAMEX>
          Headings-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annotated Alphabetic List</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, which was the
          current thesaurus at the inception of the study. In
          addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MeSH</ENAMEX>, we used subject headings [sh] in the
          CINAHL online thesaurus and the descriptors [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">de</ENAMEX>] in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">online MANTIS</ENAMEX> thesaurus to prepare searches in other
          online databases.
        
        
          Searching and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selecting Studies</ENAMEX> for
          Comparison
          Using the identified search terms listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>,
          we conducted multiple search strategies. The search in
          general can be stated as follow:
        
        
          Search queries <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1</NUMEX>
          (accuracy OR accurate OR analysis of variance OR
          construct validity <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">…</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: column <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Validity</ENAMEX>
          terms) 
          AND (cervical vertebrae OR cervical
          OR lumbar vertebrae OR lumbar <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">…</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: column <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX>:
          Spinal terms) 
          AND (diagnosis OR manual OR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">manipulat* …</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: column <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#3</NUMEX>: Procedure terms) 
          AND (apophyseal OR asymmetry OR back
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">pain …</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: column <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#4</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuromuscular Dysfunction</ENAMEX>
          terms.)
        
        
          Search queries <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX>
          (galvanic skin response OR measure* OR pain
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">measurement …</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#5</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Validity</ENAMEX>
          assessment terms) 
          AND (cervical vertebrae OR cervical
          OR lumbar vertebrae OR lumbar <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">…</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: column <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#2</NUMEX>:
          Spinal terms) 
          AND (diagnosis OR manual OR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">manipulat* …</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: column <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#3</NUMEX>: Procedure terms) 
          AND (apophyseal OR asymmetry OR back
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">pain …</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: column <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#4</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuromuscular Dysfunction</ENAMEX>
          terms.)
        
        
          Search strategy
          Search queries 
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1 OR #2</NUMEX> 
          We began the search in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PubMed</ENAMEX> and continued in the
          other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> databases. We proceeded with hand searching
          and contacting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and arrived at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,945</NUMEX> citations
          including overlapping and non-relevant studies. Inclusion
          and exclusion criteria were used to identify relevant
          studies. Inclusion criteria consisted of a document
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pertaining</ENAMEX> to manual spinal palpation procedures,
          measurement of validity or accuracy, primary research
          study published in a peer reviewed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> in any
          language, and made available <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between January 1, 1966</TIMEX> and
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 30, 2002</TIMEX>. Exclusion criteria consisted of a
          document pertaining to non-manual procedures, lack of
          sufficient tests or data, and anecdotal, speculative or
          editorial reports.
          A thorough review of titles and abstracts resulted in
          the identification of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> unique studies that were indexed
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> selected databases (see
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appendix</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> [ Additional file: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>] for citations). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> of
          these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> studies were indexed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all four databases</TIMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24 25 26</NUMEX> ] .
          In order to compare the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX> terminology among
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>, we focused the study on the
          standard practice of using MeSH among various databases.
          Based on the subject area of the research question, and
          the availability of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions library</ENAMEX> database
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subscriptions</ENAMEX>, we were able to evaluate databases like
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PubMed MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX> in comparison to a
          semantic database, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>.
          Additional file 1
          
          
          Click here for file
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Databases Selection</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PubMed MEDLINE</ENAMEX> is the most widely used and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> scientific literature database in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biomedicine</ENAMEX> and it has a subset focusing on complementary
          medicine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX>, a specialized database, was selected
          because it covers subject areas of interest to the
          research question including osteopathic medicine,
          chiropractic, and manual medicine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX> was included
          because the database covers literature related to nursing
          and allied health, including physical therapy, radiologic
          technology, occupational therapy and social
          service/health care. The thesaurus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> and CINAHL
          are based on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">MeSH</ENAMEX> with supplements for certain subject
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>. For comparison, we added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> database, Web of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>, which relies on computer generated indexing
          terms (i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keywords</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>) in addition to key terms
          provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> (i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX>). Similar to
          the other selected databases, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> covers a
          wide area of life sciences.
        
        
          Compilation of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Key Terms</ENAMEX>
          We verified how many of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">databases</ENAMEX> actually
          indexed each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> studies. We downloaded and
          imported the citations with title, abstracts, and
          controlled vocabulary into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EndNote</ENAMEX>. This resulted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>
          titles with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> abstracts. PubMed indexed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> studies,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> studies, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> studies. Across databases, we eliminated overlapping
          abstracts but retained the controlled vocabulary. We then
          used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EndNote</ENAMEX> search field to identify the key
          terms/controlled vocabulary in titles, abstracts, and
          indexes. We calculated and tabulated the frequency of
          search terms that were used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>. The
          tabulation for validity and validity assessment terms is
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, for spinal terms in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>, for
          procedural terms in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>, and for neuromusculoskeletal
          dysfunction terms in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>. The controlled vocabulary
          of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> studies that were indexed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">databases</ENAMEX> is provided in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>.
          For the purposes of this study, we printed in "bold"
          the controlled vocabulary and capitalized the first
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of each term. The free key terms were set in
          quotation marks. A "wild card" search is represented by a
          truncation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX>, e.g., palpat* will include palpation,
          palpated, palpatory, etc.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Validity and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Validity Assessment Terms</ENAMEX>
          The frequency of use of validity and validity
          assessment terms is presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. The most
          frequent validity term used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> was "accuracy",
          "accurate" (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/38</NUMEX> titles, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/37</NUMEX> abstracts). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>
          generated "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostic</ENAMEX>-accuracy" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Keywords Plus</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/26</NUMEX>).
          "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Accuracy</ENAMEX>" was not a controlled vocabulary in the
          selected analytic databases. Even though 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Validation Studies</ENAMEX> is a publication
          type in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, we did not find any study from our
          initial search result classified in this category. CINAHL
          provided a cross-reference to see 
          Validity as a search term for subject
          heading. We found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/13</NUMEX> studies indexed either under 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Criterion-Related Validity</ENAMEX> or 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Validation Studies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Authors</ENAMEX>
          used various terms containing "valid" in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/38</NUMEX> titles and
          6/37 abstracts, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> did not have the
          actual terms like "valid", "validation", and "validity"
          as controlled vocabulary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> indexed 2/26
          studies for "validity", i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keywords</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Validation</ENAMEX>,
          Disorders" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keyword</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Predictive validity"</ENAMEX>.
          
          Reproducibility of Results was the
          most frequently assigned validity term in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13/28</NUMEX>
          studies) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/29</NUMEX> studies) even though 
          Reproducibility of Results is a
          reliability term. Among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>, we did
          not find a study indexed as a subject heading under 
          Reproducibility of Results . Instead,
          CINAHL indexed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/13</NUMEX> studies using various validity terms
          from the extensive list of validity indexing terms
          available in the CINAHL thesaurus.
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Predictive Value of Tests</ENAMEX> was the
          next most frequently assigned validity term by NLM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indexers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">6/29 MEDLINE</ENAMEX> studies). While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> and CINAHL
          also contain 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Predictive Value of Tests</ENAMEX> in their
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thesaurus</ENAMEX>, the term was indexed only once in these two
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">databases</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> listed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Predictive value"</ENAMEX> once
          as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> used 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensitivity and Specificity</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2/38</NUMEX>
          titles and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/37</NUMEX> abstracts, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/29</NUMEX> studies
          indexed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, none in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2/13</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINHAL</ENAMEX>, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2/26</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX> listed
          individually.
          Several of our validity search terms, such as 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Content Validity</ENAMEX> , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Convergent Validity</ENAMEX> , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Discriminant Validity</ENAMEX> , and 
          Face Validity were CINAHL but not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MANTIS Subject Headings</ENAMEX>. We did not find
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> using these terms. Similarly, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Likelihood Functions</ENAMEX> , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reference Standards</ENAMEX> , and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROC Curve</ENAMEX> were Medical Subject
          Headings for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX>, but none were used by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> in the analytic databases.
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reference Values</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Subject</ENAMEX>
          Heading for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> selected databases, was the only
          controlled vocabulary used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> that
          was not included as a search term. Instead, we used "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gold</ENAMEX>
          Standard" as keyword and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reference Standards</ENAMEX> as the Medical
          Subject <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headings</ENAMEX> in our search [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">See</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>]. "Gold
          Standard" was used once in an abstract; neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
          nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> ever used 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reference Standards</ENAMEX> .
          The most frequent validity assessment terms was used
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> were "measurement" or 
          Pain Measurement as well as 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radiography</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Indexers</ENAMEX> also assigned
          these terms in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all four databases</TIMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">See</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>].
        
        
          Spinal Terms
          The frequency of spinal terms is presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>.
          The spinal term most frequently used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indexers</ENAMEX> was 
          Spine or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spinal"</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>
          titles and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21/37</NUMEX> abstracts contained 
          Spine or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spinal"</ENAMEX>. MEDLINE indexed 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spine</ENAMEX> (or spinal as an adjective) in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15/29</NUMEX> studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/28</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4/13</NUMEX>
          studies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> generated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8/26</NUMEX> studies as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keywords</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keywords</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>. Of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> studies, two
          were found as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Keywords Plus</ENAMEX>, i.e. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spinal Manipulation</ENAMEX>"
          and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lumbar Spine"</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervical Vertebrae</ENAMEX> to
          Neck. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervical Vertebrae</ENAMEX> (or cervical as an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjective</ENAMEX>) was used in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10/38</NUMEX> titles and in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15/37</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abstracts</ENAMEX>, and indexed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8/29</NUMEX> studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/28</NUMEX>
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2/26</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX>.
          In comparison, 
          Neck was never used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> in
          titles and in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 5/37</NUMEX> abstracts. It was indexed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5/29</NUMEX>
          studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2/28</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2/13</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>, and
          none were generated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thoracic Vertebrae</ENAMEX> (or thoracic as an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjective</ENAMEX>) was used infrequently by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palpation Procedural Terms</ENAMEX>
          The frequency of palpation procedural terms is
          presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>. The most frequent palpation
          procedural terms used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> were
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palpation</ENAMEX> or "palpat*". These term
          were used frequently (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/38</NUMEX> titles, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19/37</NUMEX> abstracts, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/29</NUMEX>
          studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16/28</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6/13</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4/26</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> frequently used palpation procedural terms
          that were not in the controlled vocabulary, e.g., "manual
          exam*", "manual diagnosis", or "manual tests" (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/38</NUMEX>
          titles and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/37</NUMEX> abstracts), and "manipulat*" (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2/38</NUMEX>
          titles, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/37</NUMEX> abstracts). From the controlled vocabulary
          for manipulation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> often chose 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spinal Manipulation</ENAMEX> rather than 
          Chiropractic , 
          Orthopedic , or 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osteopathic Manipulation</ENAMEX> . While
          MEDLINE indexed 
          Manipulation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orthopedic</ENAMEX> as the only
          manipulation term, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> indexed 
          Chiropractic , 
          Orthopedic , and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spinal Manipulation</ENAMEX> . Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
          nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX> used 
          Manipulation, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osteopathic</ENAMEX> . This was
          also the only palpation procedural term used in the
          search strategies that was not used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Indexers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX> selected 
          Diagnosis most frequently as a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">palpation</ENAMEX> procedural term (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17/29</NUMEX> studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23/28</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/13</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>). 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diagnosis</ENAMEX> was usually indexed in
          combination with a neuromuscular dysfunction term as a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subheading</ENAMEX>.
          While 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physical Examination</ENAMEX> was not included
          in our search strategies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> occasionally used it in
          the abstracts. MANTIS indexed 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physical Examination</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15/28</NUMEX> studies
          compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/29</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/13</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/26</NUMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keywords</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neuromusculoskeletal Dysfunction Terms</ENAMEX>
          The frequency of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">neuromuscular</ENAMEX>/musculoskeletal
          dysfunction terms is presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
          dysfunction terms used in the search strategies, only 
          Low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Pain</ENAMEX> and 
          Back Pain were used relatively
          frequently by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> in titles (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/38</NUMEX>) and in abstracts
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8/37</NUMEX>). Also the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> selected databases indexed these
          terms with highest frequency (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6/29</NUMEX> studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12/28</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4/13</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4/26</NUMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keywords</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyword</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>.)
          While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> used "mobility" and "dysfunction"
          relatively frequently, these terms were not part of the
          controlled vocabulary in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion</ENAMEX> , a controlled vocabulary, was
          used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7/37</NUMEX> abstracts but was not indexed in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> studies in MANTIS indexed
          
          Motion as a descriptor. Web of
          Science indexed 
          Motion twice as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Keywords Plus</ENAMEX> and
          once as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX>. 
          Subluxation , a widely used term in
          chiropractic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and a controlled vocabulary in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>, was not used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> in titles and
          abstracts but frequently indexed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/28</NUMEX>
          studies).
          Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> neuromusculoskeletal dysfunction terms used
          in the search strategies, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> were never used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indexers</ENAMEX> (apophyseal, blockage, hypomobility, manipulable
          lesion, motion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, and quality of motion.) While
          "motion palpation" was not used as a combined search
          term, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MANTIS</ENAMEX> indexed 
          Palpation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/28</NUMEX> studies.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> used "motion palpation" in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/38</NUMEX> titles and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3/37</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abstracts</ENAMEX>. "Motion palpation" was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MeSH</ENAMEX> or subject
          heading, and therefore it was not indexed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five Studies</ENAMEX> Indexed in all Four
          Databases
          Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> studies, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> studies were indexed in all
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> databases as shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>. The comparison of
          validity terms showed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> studies
          included a validity term in the title [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 26</NUMEX> ] , and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
          studies had a validity term in the abstract [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 25</NUMEX> ] .
          The study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kristiansson et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] did not provide a
          validity term in either title or abstract, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PubMed</ENAMEX> and
          MANTIS indexed validity terms for this study. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PubMed</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CINAHL</ENAMEX> did not pick up the validity term that appeared in
          the abstract by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gracovetsky et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] MANTIS
          recognized and indexed the validity terms for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX>
          studies. CINAHL indexed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> studies with
          validity terms [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 25</NUMEX> ] . In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> studies included <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX> for validity [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 25 26</NUMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> studies, published after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">generated Keywords Plus</ENAMEX> from the references cited by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, but only one study included a validity term [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
          ] .
          All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> studies included a neuromuscular dysfunction
          term in the title. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> included 
          Back Pain in the title and abstract
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 24 25</NUMEX> ] and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neck Pain</ENAMEX> in the title and abstract
          in one study [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> used "thoracic end-play"
          in the title and no other neuromuscular dysfunction term
          in the abstract [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All four</NUMEX> databases indexed 
          Back <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pain, Low Back Pain</ENAMEX> , and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neck Pain</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> respective
          studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 24 25 26</NUMEX> ] . In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>, these terms
          were provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX> and not
          generated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keywords</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
          Current Status of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard Glossaries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manual</ENAMEX>
          Medicine
          In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> sponsored a
          multidisciplinary research conference on status of spinal
          manipulative therapy [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . The orthopedic,
          osteopathic, and chiropractic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> reported on
          the understanding and use of the terminology in each
          respective profession. There was no consensus within or
          amongst professions at that time.
          Searching the Internet for orthopedic terminology for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, we located many glossaries designed to
          facilitate patient comprehension of orthopedic terms. For
          example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of Orthopaedic</ENAMEX> Surgeons
          provides a glossary of orthopedic diagnostic tests online
          which seems to be designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . At this
          web site, we did not identify a glossary of standard
          terminology for orthopedics.
          The osteopathic profession developed a standardized
          Glossary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osteopathic Terminology</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> that has been
          updated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> ever since [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . The online version
          is available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOAnet Yearbook and Directory</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ]
          . The osteopathic literature database <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSTMED</ENAMEX> went online
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1, 2002</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . For standard indexing practice,
          the database uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM MeSH</ENAMEX> terms and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 70</NUMEX> terms
          that are uniquely osteopathic, called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osteopathic Subject</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headings</ENAMEX> (OSH). To further assist in accessing the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">osteopathic</ENAMEX> literature database, 
          Manipulation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osteopathic</ENAMEX> became a
          MeSH term in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] .
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiropractic Library Consortium</ENAMEX> (CLIBCON)
          published the first list of chiropractic thesaurus
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHIROSH</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> to improve access to the chiropractic
          literature. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> produced the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> version of
          the Index to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiropractic Literature</ENAMEX> in print in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> and
          added the online version in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. The standard indexing
          practice is based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM MeSH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHIROSH</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] .
          Chiropractic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians</ENAMEX> but not the chiropractic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> use this CHIROSH thesaurus. Presently there
          does not seem to be a universally accepted glossary of
          terms in the chiropractic profession [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] .
          In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PubMED MEDLINE</ENAMEX> articles that were
          submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> do not contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MeSH vocabulary</ENAMEX>.
          This increasingly common situation contributes to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> retrieval problems that we have presented here and
          furthers the argument for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> to use controlled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vocabulary</ENAMEX> or commonly understood terminology in the
          titles and abstracts of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> in order to
          facilitate retrieval of their studies by key terms.
          In the field of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX>, semantic indexing might be more
          useful than analytic indexing because keyword indexing is
          generated by computer programs that pool words or phrases
          used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> at least twice. For instance, if the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> mentioned subluxation at least twice in the title
          or abstract, the term will be indexed regardless of
          professional agreement about the definition of the
          term.
        
        
          Strengths and Limitations of the Controlled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vocabulary</ENAMEX> and Keywords
          In our study, the limitations of semantic indexing in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> produced the lowest yield of relevant
          studies. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX> indexed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26/38</NUMEX> studies, only
          a few of these had been retrieved by the search strategy.
          Instead, we arrived at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> studies by individually
          verifying the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> studies that we knew to exist by using
          author name and title words.
          Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> studies indexed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> had
          been generated with both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX> and Keywords
          Plus, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> studies with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX> only. Web of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> did not generate any keywords for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11/26</NUMEX> studies.
          If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> relied on searching by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keyword</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>, the
          search strategy might miss many potentially relevant
          studies. At the same time, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are not
          familiar with the terms used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, a search
          strategy might miss relevant studies as well.
          In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web of Science</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX> have only been
          available for search since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. This limits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>'
          ability to find relevant literature prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. A
          search of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier years</TIMEX> has to rely on title word
          searches. It is likely because of this limitation, we
          found relatively few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keywords</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Keywords Plus</ENAMEX> for
          our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> search concepts.
          For databases that utilize analytic indexing, like
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM Medical Subject Headings Section</ENAMEX> staff
          continually revises and updates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeSH</ENAMEX> vocabulary.
          While there were major changes in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM MeSH</ENAMEX>
          thesaurus for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX>, the current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> edition added only
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> CAM therapeutic modality. It would be helpful if
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> and CAM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> become more active in contributing to the
          selection process of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX> descriptors in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM MeSH</ENAMEX> and
          other database descriptors. Individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> and
          subscribing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> as well, have significant
          influence on the modifications and updating processes of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">databases</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM</ENAMEX> Web site has a page for suggesting MeSH
          changes with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX>-sentence statement, the reason
          for the change, and one or two authoritative citations [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> ] . Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NLM Medical Subject Headings</ENAMEX> are the
          standard controlled vocabulary for the allied health and
          biomedicine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> in the fields of
          osteopathic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, chiropractic and physical medicine
          should take the opportunity to establish consistent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">terminology</ENAMEX> in the field of validity of spinal palpation
          for neuromuscular dysfunction.
          We recognize the difficulties of adding new
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">descriptors</ENAMEX> and updating the existing controlled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vocabulary</ENAMEX> because searching for a new concept requires a
          dynamic thesaurus while searching retrospectively
          requires stability and continuity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . Fortunately,
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Library of Medicine</ENAMEX> implements changes to
          the MeSH thesaurus in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX> retrospectively.
        
      
      
        Conclusions
        Searching databases on CAM related topics is challenging
        due to the diversity in the use of controlled vocabulary
        and indexing procedures in different databases.
        Collaboration is needed among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indexers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> to develop
        standard terminology in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, database vendors
        should augment their control vocabulary in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX>,
        particularly in the fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">manual medicine</ENAMEX>. A standard
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">terminology</ENAMEX> then could be used and referred to by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> in conducting their search strategies, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> when writing titles, abstracts and submitting
        keywords for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAM</ENAMEX> literature grows,
        dissemination and knowledge of the controlled vocabulary
        will become even more important.
      
      
        Competing Interests
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of this study did not have competing
        interests with this study. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> received
        reimbursement fees, funding, or salary from an organization
        that may in any way gain or lose financially from the
        publication of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' Contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LM</ENAMEX> conceived of the study, designed and carried out the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">searches</ENAMEX>, analyzed the search outcomes and the controlled
        vocabulary, researched the context of this study, drafted
        and finalized the manuscript.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SR</ENAMEX> participated in the design of the study, filtered the
        search results, participated in researching the context of
        this study, and assisted in drafting and finalizing the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>.
        WN coordinated the study, provided search terms,
        reviewed and filtered search outcomes, and assisted in
        drafting the manuscript.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VD</ENAMEX> provided search terms, reviewed and filtered search
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>, provided essential comments and approved the
        final manuscript.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> was the content <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in osteopathic medicine. He
        provided search terms, reviewed and filtered search
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>, provided essential comments and approved the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>.
        AA was the content <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in chiropractic. He provided
        search terms, reviewed and filtered search outcomes, and
        approved the final manuscript.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SM</ENAMEX> provided search terms, reviewed and filtered search
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>, reviewed and approved the manuscript.
      
    
  
