
  
    
      
        Background
        Major histocompatibility complex class <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">II</ENAMEX> molecules
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX>) are heterodimeric transmembrane glycoproteins that
        bind antigenic peptides and present such peptides to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ T
        cells. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> are not expressed by the vast
        majority of studied <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and human tumors, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ T
        lymphocytes specific to MHCII-restricted tumor antigens
        have been found in various <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Those
        lymphocytes are believed to be generated 
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vivo</TIMEX> following the recognition of
        MHCII-tumor peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> expressed by host <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>
        presenting cells and can cause regression of MHCII-negative
        tumors indirectly, via secretion of cytokines such as IL-2
        or IFNg [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . The released cytokines can recruit and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">activate cytotoxic</ENAMEX> CD8<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+ T</ENAMEX> lymphocytes and/or accessory
        cells (eosinophills, macrophages) which further mediate
        tumor destruction.
        It has been recently appreciated that sufficient
        concentrations of secreted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> may also induce susceptible
        tumors to express the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MHCII</ENAMEX> molecules, potentially leading
        to increased direct contact with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ T cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . Even
        though some reports indicate that tumor sensitivity to IFNg
        is not required to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">elicit tumor regression</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , it is
        conceivable that the IFNg-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> expression on tumor
        cells may boost the effector phase of antitumor responses
        through additional cytokine release or direct tumor
        eradication by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ T cells. Indeed, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ T cells that
        directly destroy MHCII-positive tumors were identified [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
        ] . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>, the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> on colorectal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carcinomas</ENAMEX> is correlated with more favourable prognosis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
        ] . Adoptive transfer studies show that 
        ex vivo activated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX>+ T cells are
        able to recognize, and to eliminate, MHCII-positive tumors
        either by themselves [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] or in co-operation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>+ T
        cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . It has been also demonstrated that the
        increased MHCII expression on tumor cells and macrophages
        following treatment with IFNg 
        in vivo was associated with enhanced
        efficacy of adoptive T cell therapy in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> model of
        metastatic sarcoma [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        Unfortunately, the induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> on tumor cells by
        IFNg 
        in vivo is difficult [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . In
        fact, the reported inducible tumors seem to be limited to
        freshly transplanted tumor cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 11</ENAMEX> ] or malignant
        cells present in the ascitic fluid [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . Many tumors do
        not express <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> after treatment with recombinant IFNg 
        in vitro either [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] .
        Given the role that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> may play in tumor immunity,
        further attempts to restore inducibility in IFNg-resistant
        tumors appear to be warranted. In this regard, several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> have recently been tested using 
        in vitro models of noninducible tumor
        cell lines. It was reported that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, e.g. histone
        deacetylase <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA methylation inhibitors</ENAMEX>
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] , can rescue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> inducibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> in
        cultured tumor cells.
        In this study, we explored whether the effect can be
        achieved by yet another category of modulators, the PKC
        agonists, chosen because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> has been shown to function as
        an upstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] that is
        involved in both IFNg signal transduction [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] and
        regulation of gene expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        Specifically, the influence of a potent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activator,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, and clinically tested <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryostatin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1</ENAMEX>, on the
        IFNg-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> expression in several IFNg-resistant
        tumor cell lines was examined. Previously, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> was shown to
        augment IFNg-mediated MHCII expression in MHCII-inducible
        tumor cell lines [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> ] . Here, we report that the
        presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> in tissue culture restores IFNg-dependent
        MHCII expression in the poorly-responding LS1034 colon
        carcinoma cell line but fails to produce this effect in two
        other IFNg-resistant cell lines, MSTO-211H <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mesothelioma</ENAMEX> and
        HepG2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hepatocellular</ENAMEX> carcinoma. We also show that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>-dependent MHCII expression in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX> cell line can be
        rescued by clinically acceptable concentrations of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bryostatin 1</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        
          Induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MHCII</ENAMEX> molecules by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
          different tumor cell lines
          We first compared the induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MHCII</ENAMEX> molecules in
          SW480, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MSTO-211H</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HepG2</ENAMEX> tumor cells in
          response to different concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>. MHCII
          antigens were initially undetectable in all cell lines
          tested. Incubation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as little as 10</NUMEX> 2IU/ml IFNg
          induced a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-fold increase of MHCII-specific fluorescence
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SW480</TIMEX> colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carcinoma</ENAMEX> cell line. In contrast, LS1034
          demonstrated only weak (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4- to 1.6</NUMEX>-fold) increases in
          level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX>, and remained weakly inducible even when
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> was increased to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 4IU/ml (Figure
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MSTO-211H</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mesothelioma</ENAMEX>, cell line also showed a weak
          induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HepG2</ENAMEX>,
          hepatocellular carcinoma, was completely non-inducible
          (data not shown).
          It should be noted, however, that we observed a small
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LS1034 cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of all cells)
          that demonstrated a modest (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3- to 4</NUMEX>-fold) increase in
          MHCII-specific fluorescence after incubation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 2-10</NUMEX>
          4IU/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> (data not shown). This could suggest that a
          small subset of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LS1034 cells</ENAMEX> might acquire an inducible
          phenotype at a certain stage of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell differentiation</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          PMA rescues <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> inducibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> in low
          responding LS1034 colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carcinoma</ENAMEX> cell line
          We next attempted to restore IFNg inducibility of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> in poorly responding tumor cell lines by adding PKC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agonist PMA</ENAMEX> into culture medium containing variable
          concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> did not improve IFNg
          inducibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MSTO-211H</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HepG2</ENAMEX> cell lines
          (data not shown). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>, on the other hand,
          demonstrated a robust increase in MHCII expression.
          The magnitude of response of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> cells varied
          greatly from experiment to experiment depending not only
          on concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>, but also on concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and even on type of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> (DMSO or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>).
          Therefore, the experiments were arranged in a factorial
          design for accurate analysis of possible interactive
          effects. For each combination of treatments, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-letter
          alphanumeric code was assigned (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four</TIMEX> dose
          levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> combined with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> dose levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          dose levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> generated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and the design
          was replicated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> times.
          The results demonstrated a substantial increase in
          MHCII expression in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX> cell line following combined
          incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>-factor
          analysis of variance revealed that the magnitude of MHCII
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induction</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> cells was almost totally determined
          by concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> (F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29.3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 10 -6</ENAMEX>). Higher
          response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> tended to be associated with higher
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> in some experiments, but the overall
          effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> did not reach a commonly accepted level of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">significance</ENAMEX> (F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.9</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.14</NUMEX>). Interestingly,
          the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> did reach significance in cultures
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> (F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.043</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">09bâ†’12b</ENAMEX>,
          15bâ†’18b, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21bâ†’24b</TIMEX>). No interaction effect between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> was found (F 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.14</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.99</NUMEX>).
          Since there were no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-factor interactions, several
          single-factor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were added, and data were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-analysed by using one-way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX>. Different
          combinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> were compared to the highest
          dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNg</ENAMEX> used without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> 20a or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20b</NUMEX>).
          Multiple comparisons were made using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tukey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSD</ENAMEX> test and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheffe</ENAMEX>'s test (the latter test is more conservative).
          Results demonstrate that the expression level of MHCII
          reached a plateau at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 3IU/ml IFNg</ENAMEX> in the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-10 4ng/ml PMA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>. Further increases in
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> (to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 4IU/ml</ENAMEX>) did not result in
          statistically significant increases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> expression
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2B</NUMEX>).
          Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2also</NUMEX> demonstrates that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> was totally
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inactive</ENAMEX> alone (compare group 20a vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20b</NUMEX>) but it
          significantly improved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> induction in the
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>. Because of variation between
          experiments, the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> could not be seen clearly
          in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. For that reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>-wise comparisons were
          made between cell cultures incubated either with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> or
          with a combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX>. Specifically, group
          09a was compared to group <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">09b</TIMEX>, etc. Data shown in Figure
          3confirm that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EtOH</ENAMEX> significantly improved PMA-potentiated
          response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linear</ENAMEX> regression analysis also
          revealed that the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> was more pronounced
          at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 2IU/ml IFNg</ENAMEX>.
          Taken together, the above results showed a strong
          potentiating effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> on IFNg-induced HLA-DR
          expression in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX> cell line and no changes in two
          other poorly inducible cell lines.
        
        
          Expression levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNg receptors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
          different tumor cell lines do not change following
          incubation with PMA
          It has been previously shown that potentiating effect
          of phorbol esters on IFNg-dependent MHCII induction in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">THP-1</ENAMEX> monocytic cell line was associated with the
          increase in synthesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNg receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] . For that
          reason, we questioned whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> could produce similar
          changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX> colon carcinoma cells. We compared the
          expression of alpha and beta <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNg</ENAMEX> receptor
          (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IFNgR1 and IFNgR2</TIMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX> carcinoma and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other
          tumor cell lines before and after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> hr incubation with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 3ng/ml PMA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>. Results, plotted in
          Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, show that untreated and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PMA-</ENAMEX>treated tumor cells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> about the same levels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IFNgR1 and IFNgR2</TIMEX>.
          Moreover, the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNgR1</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">HepG2</NUMEX> cells actually
          drops after exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>. Therefore, we conclude that
          it is unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> action in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX> carcinoma is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mediated</ENAMEX> through increased synthesis of IFNg
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Expression of the retinoblastoma <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is not
          lost in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MSTO-211H</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HepG2</ENAMEX> cell lines
          A substantial percentage of human tumors lose the
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rb</ENAMEX>), important as a necessary condition for
          IFNg-mediated induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . Therefore, we
          wished to determine whether the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> inducibility of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MSTO-211H</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HepG2</ENAMEX> cell lines could be
          explained by the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rb</ENAMEX>. Immunofluorescent staining
          with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rb</ENAMEX>-specific mAb (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">clone G3-245</ENAMEX>) demonstrated that
          all cell lines tested expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rb</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>).
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">closer</ENAMEX> look at Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5reveals</TIMEX> that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> cell lines
          can be ranked according to their Rb contents in the
          following order: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SW480 > LS1034 > MSTO-211H</ENAMEX> >
          HepG2. This ranking would be valid only if fluorescence
          intensity correlates closely with the absolute contents
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rb protein</ENAMEX> per cell. However, this may not always be
          the case. For example, the number of epitopes recognized
          by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">G3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">245</NUMEX> mAb may be reduced if tumor cells express viral
          oncoproteins that bind and inactivate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rb</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] .
          It is important to note that certain mutations greatly
          reduce transport of newly synthesized <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Rb</ENAMEX> molecules into
          the nucleus where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rb</ENAMEX> performs its function [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . As
          the flow cytometry protocol does not allow us to
          discriminate between cytoplasmic and nuclear staining,
          the question about the presence of functional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rb</ENAMEX> protein
          in the examined cell lines remains open.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase inhibitors</ENAMEX> on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physiological</ENAMEX> and PMA-potentiated response to IFNg
          The discovery of novel "non-kinase" phorbol ester
          receptors challenges the use of phorbol esters as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">selective PKC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activators</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . Therefore, we were
          interested in whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> family mediated
          the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LS1034 cells</ENAMEX> or whether some other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> could also be involved. Specifically, we
          investigated whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, staurosporine and GF
          109203X, could abrogate PMA-potentiated response of
          LS1034 cells to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staurosporine</ENAMEX> is a wide-spectrum
          kinase inhibitor and its specificity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> isoforms is
          limited to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> nanomolar range. In the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-100</NUMEX> nM
          range, staurosporine inhibits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX> different
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> shown in Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6demonstrate</TIMEX> that staurosporine
          caused about a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> inhibition of PMA-potentiated response
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> cells at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM. Complete
          inhibition occurred at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM. A much higher
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">109203X</ENAMEX> was required to completely
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suppress PMA</ENAMEX>-potentiated response in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> cells.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physiological IFNg</ENAMEX> response in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SW480</TIMEX> colon carcinoma
          cells was resistant to inhibition with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX> GF 109203X
          and was suppressed only when staurosporine concentration
          was increased to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX>. We conclude that the PMA effect in
          LS1034 cell line is most likely mediated by a PKC
          isoenzyme but other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinases</ENAMEX> that are sensitive to
          inhibition with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼M GF 109203X</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bryostatin 1 rescues IFNg</ENAMEX> inducibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> in
          LS1034 colon carcinoma cells
          To evaluate potential clinical implications of our
          findings, we asked whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>-dependent MHCII
          expression in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> cells could be restored by
          clinically achievable concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> agonists.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bryostatin 1</ENAMEX> is a potent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activator that has undergone
          extensive clinical testing for the treatment of
          hematological malignancies and solid tumors [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
          Animal studies show that the concentration of Bryostatin
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in various tissues after a single intraveneous
          injection stays in a range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/g for a period of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 72</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hr</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] .
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>, plotted in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, demonstrate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryostatin</ENAMEX> added into the culture medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-10 3IU/ml IFNg</ENAMEX> induced a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5- to 6</NUMEX>-fold increase in
          levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> expression. The potentiating effect of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryostatin</ENAMEX> first becomes noticeable at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 ng/ml</ENAMEX> and then
          reaches a plateau at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml. At low concentration
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 2IU/ml</ENAMEX>), the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryostatin</ENAMEX> was
          comparable to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>. At a higher concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 3IU/ml</ENAMEX>), however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> was much more effective.
          This may suggest that either the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activators act
          through different isoforms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> also activates
          enzymes outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
          Whatever the mechanism, it appears possible to restore
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>-dependent MHCII expression in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LS1034</TIMEX> cell line
          by clinically acceptable concentrations of Bryostatin
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activators <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bryostatin 1</ENAMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> inducibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> resistant tumor cell
        lines of different histological origin has been examined.
        We found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activators rescued high levels of MHCII
        expression in colon carcinoma cells and failed to do so in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mesothelioma</ENAMEX> and hepatocellular carcinoma cells. A poor
        response of tumor cells to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> is in agreement with
        previous observations that many tumors acquire such
        resistance upon malignant transformation, possibly
        important as a mechanism of tumor escape from immune
        surveillance [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . The nature of this phenomenon is
        complex, and multiple defects that can prevent IFNg
        responses in tumor lines have been described.
        Most frequently, poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> inducibility in response to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> has been attributed to alterations in the IFNg
        signalling pathway and epigenetic silencing of gene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expression</ENAMEX> (reviewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ref</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] ). The cascade of IFNg
        signalling events leading to transcription activation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MHCII genes</ENAMEX> has been characterized in great detail
        (reviewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ref</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] ). Binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> to its receptor
        results in JAK-mediated phosphorylation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">STAT1</TIMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tyrosine 701</ENAMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> interaction with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> leads to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p38MAPK</NUMEX>-mediated phosphorylation of STAT1
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">727</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . The phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STAT1</ENAMEX> dimerizes
        and translocates into the nucleus where it activates
        transcription of several other factors including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIITA</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>
        ] . Although the results of this study do not allow us to
        describe the exact mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> involvement in IFNg
        signalling in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> non-mutually
        exclusive scenarios can be hypothesized:
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> could act through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">JAK-STAT</ENAMEX> signalling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX>. It has been established that, to achieve its
        maximal transcriptional activity, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">STAT1</ENAMEX> must be
        phosphorylated on both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tyr701</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ser727</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] .
        Phosphorylation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">STAT1</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ser727</TIMEX> occurs in response to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UV</ENAMEX> irradiation and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> that activate the
        p38MAPK <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . As phorbol esters can also
        stimulate the MAPK cascade through activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ]
        , it is tempting to speculate that combined treatment of
        cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> could increase the pool of STAT1
        molecules phosphorylated on both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tyr701 and Ser727</TIMEX>. This
        effect is most likely mediated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX>-delta isoenzyme as
        this particular PKC isoform appears to be critical for
        phosphorylation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">STAT1</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ser727</TIMEX> and activation of
        p38MAPK [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Alternatively, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">PMA</ENAMEX> treatment could initiate a cascade
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein phosphorylation</ENAMEX> leading to the increase in
        transcriptional activity of chromatin at the type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIITA</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MHCII genes</ENAMEX>.
        Expression of many genes can be modified by treatment with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents acting</ENAMEX> at the level of enzymes and nuclear receptors
        that modify transcriptional activity of chromatin. Thus,
        histone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">deacetylase inhibitors</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butyrate</ENAMEX> and Trichostatin
        A - can rescue MHCII-inducibility in bladder carcinoma
        cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] and restore constitutive MHCII expression in
        plasmacytoma cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . In addition to acetylation,
        transcriptional activity of chromatin is also regulated
        through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">phosphorylation</TIMEX> (reviewed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ref.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] ). It has
        been shown that treatment of cells with phorbol esters
        leads to accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphorylated H3 histones</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ]
        . Therefore, it seems possible that in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> cells PMA
        could enhance transcriptional activity of chromatin at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> and/or CIITA genes. This possibility
        appears particularly important since the specific lack of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIITA</ENAMEX> inducibility was cited as the most common basis for
        lack of IFNg-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> expression among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rb</ENAMEX>-positive
        human tumor lines [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 21</NUMEX> ] .
        Another reported mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> in tumor
        cells is associated with down-regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNg-receptors</ENAMEX>
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . The relevance of this mechanism to MHCII
        inducibility was recently supported by the evidence that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> is able to enhance IFNg-dependent MHCII expression in
        THP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leukemia cells</ENAMEX> through the up-regulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNg receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] . In our experiments, however, the
        incubation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> did not
        lead to any changes in IFNgR expression as determined by
        flow cytometry (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Therefore, it is unlikely that
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up</NUMEX>-regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNgR</ENAMEX> contributed to the phenomena reported
        here. It should be emphasized that we determined the
        expression of both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNgR1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNgR2 receptor</ENAMEX> subunits
        since it has been shown that, in certain experimental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>, an IFNg <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> was due to a lack of cellular
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNgR2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> alone [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] .
        We also found that the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> cells can
        be significantly augmented by co-incubation with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">172</NUMEX> mM
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>. In certain types of tissues, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> has been
        shown to induce membrane translocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> isoforms
        through activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">phospholipase A</ENAMEX> and release of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diacylglycerol</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . This mechanism, however, does not
        appear to be significant in our case as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> without PMA
        failed to potentiate IFNg-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> expression in
        LS1034 cells. Alternatively, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> can modulate the
        activity of mitogen- and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinase cascades</ENAMEX>.
        It has been shown that hepatocytes exposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hr</ENAMEX> have a higher activity of p38MAPK induced
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">EGF</ENAMEX> treatment [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] . If in our experiments <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> did act
        through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ser727</TIMEX> phosphorylation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">STAT1</TIMEX>, the potentiating
        effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> can possibly be explained by its ability
        to stimulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> kinase cascade.
        It remains to be determined whether the restoration of
        IFNg-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX> expression by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> is unique to LS1034
        cells. A potentiating effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> has been reported in
        thyroid carcinoma cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] but, in contrast to LS1034
        cells, normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> response in those cells was only
        partially lost as a result of malignant transformation.
        Whether or not this phenomenon may be reproduced with other
        IFNg-resistant colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carcinoma</ENAMEX> cell lines is of particular
        interest, since colonic epithelium is physiologically
        exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> activators that enhance cytokine signalling
        in enterocytes during inflammatory responses within the
        intestinal mucosa [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] .
        It is well established that, besides the MHCII
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">molecules</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> can induce susceptible tumors to upregulate
        the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> I antigens [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] , tumor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antigens</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] , costimulatory molecules [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ]
        , and heat shock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] . In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> may
        have antimetabolic and antiproliferative influence on
        certain types of tumor cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX> ] . It has also been
        suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> may cause responding tumor cells to
        secrete <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">angiogenesis inhibitors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> ] . As it is not known
        which of those IFNg effects are missing or restored by PMA
        in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> cells, a thorough evaluation of the possible
        clinical implications of our 
        in vitro findings is quite difficult.
        However, if clinically tested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PKC</ENAMEX> agonists such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bryostatin 1</ENAMEX> are able to rescue the IFNg-induced MHCII
        expression within the tumor bed, it might be appropriate to
        consider them for trials to improve the clinical efficacy
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> immunotherapy.
      
      
        Conclusions
        In this study we showed that IFNg-inducibility of MHCII
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antigens</ENAMEX> in weakly inducible <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LS1034</ENAMEX> colorectal carcinoma
        cell line can be rescued by concomitant incubation with PKC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agonists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bryostatin</ENAMEX> 1 may be considered for further
        investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>-dependent MHCII induction in
        resistant tumors 
        in vivo .
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Cell lines
          Human tumor cell lines - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">LS1034</NUMEX> colorectal carcinoma
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC Number</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CRL-2158</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SW480</ENAMEX> colorectal adenocarcinoma
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC Number</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCL-228</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MSTO-211H</ENAMEX> biphasic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mesothelioma</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC Number</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CRL-2081</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HepG2</ENAMEX> hepatocellular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carcinoma</ENAMEX> (ATCC Number: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">HB-8065</ENAMEX>) - were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collection</ENAMEX>. Cultures were routinely
          tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Mycoplasma</ENAMEX> contamination by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Specialty</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratories</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX>, CA) and were consistently
          negative.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chemicals</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recombinant human Interferon</ENAMEX> Î³ 
          1b , specific activity <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3Â·10 7IU/mg,</ENAMEX>
          was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">InterMune Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staurosporine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">109203X</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calbiochem</ENAMEX>. Other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> used were phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-myristate 13</NUMEX>-acetate,
          dimethyl sulfoxide, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, propidium iodide and saponin
          (all from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). Fetal calf serum and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RPMI-1640</ENAMEX> culture
          medium supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irvine</ENAMEX>
          Scientific. Tobramycin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-glutamine and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> porcine
          trypsin - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.53</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbott Laboratories</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioWittaker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco</ENAMEX> correspondingly.
        
        
          Antibodies
          Monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> used in the study were: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) mAb
          against human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HLA-DR</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DP</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DQ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> conjugate
          (anti-MHCII-FITC), clone <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TÃ¼39</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> IgG2a; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) mAb
          against human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNg</ENAMEX> receptor R1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, biotin conjugate,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMHGR-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> IgG1; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) mAb against human IFNg
          receptor R2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, biotin conjugate, clone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMHGR-2</ENAMEX>, mouse
          IgG1; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgG2a</ENAMEX> isotype control mAb, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> conjugate
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IgG2a</NUMEX>-FITC); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>) mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgG1</ENAMEX> isotype control mAb, biotin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conjugate</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) mAb against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> conjugate
          (Rb-FITC), clone <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G3-245</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> IgG1; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>) mouse IgG1
          isotype control mAb, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> conjugate (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IgG1</NUMEX>-FITC).
          Streptavidin, phycoerythrin conjugate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SA</ENAMEX>-PE) and
          Streptavidin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa Fluor</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Â®488</NUMEX> conjugate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Alf488</NUMEX>) were
          from eBioscience and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Cell culture
          Cells were propagated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T75</TIMEX> flasks in RPMI-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1640</NUMEX>
          medium supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal calf
          serum, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> mM L-glutamine and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml Tobramycin.</ENAMEX> When
          cells were in exponential growth phase, they were removed
          from plastic by trypsinization and seeded into the wells
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well trays (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9 cm 2/well</ENAMEX>) at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3Â·10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5to 5Â·10 5cells / 4 ml /</ENAMEX> well. When cell cultures reached
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40-60%</NUMEX> confluency (usually, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>), growth
          medium was replaced with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ml of fresh medium containing
          variable concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Ten minutes</TIMEX> later,
          another <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 ml</NUMEX> of medium containing variable concentrations
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> were added into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> and the incubation
          continued for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 48</TIMEX> hr. Experiments involving
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase inhibitors</ENAMEX> were performed in a similar
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, except that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staurosporine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">109203X</ENAMEX> were added
          first, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> (or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PMA</NUMEX> plus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>) were added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hr later</TIMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staurosporine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">109203X</ENAMEX> were not washed away, so the
          cells were incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> in the constant
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>. In a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> group of experiments,
          stock solution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> was prepared at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mg/ml</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>,
          and the final concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> in culture medium
          was adjusted to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼l/ml (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">172 mM</NUMEX>). In all subsequent
          experiments, stock solution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> was prepared at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/ml</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX> and the final concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX> in
          culture medium was adjusted to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼l/ml.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Immunofluorescent staining of cell surface
          antigens
          Cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monolayers</ENAMEX> were rinsed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> times with
          Ca/Mg-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 min at 37Â°C</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>'
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">balanced salt solution</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> trypsin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>. Detached cells were washed twice
          with staining buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> sodium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">azide</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>) and stained as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, cells were transferred into
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of round-bottom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates, the plates were
          centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>, the supernatant
          removed by shaking, and the cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets resuspended</ENAMEX> in
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼l</NUMEX> of staining buffer containing saturating
          concentration of anti-MHCII-FITC. After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>-min incubation
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, cells were washed twice, resuspended in staining
          buffer and kept on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> before analysis on a flow
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytometer</ENAMEX> (FACSCaliburâ„¢, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX> Immunocytometry
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX>). Immediately before analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/ml propidium</ENAMEX>
          iodide was added to exclude dead cells. Matching isotype
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> mAb (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IgG2a</NUMEX>-FITC) was used at the same (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Î¼g</ENAMEX>/well) or a higher (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.0</NUMEX> Î¼g/well) concentration as the
          specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. The lack of staining of controls
          demonstrated that non-specific binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IgG2a-FITC</ENAMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PI</ENAMEX>-negative cells was negligible in all experimental
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig</ENAMEX> 8B,8E<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,8</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>). Staining for cell surface IFNg
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX> was performed similarly, except that cells were
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> incubated with biotin-conjugated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX>'s (specific or
          isotype-matched) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> times and then
          stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Alf488</NUMEX>. Staining of fresh and
          trypsin-treated monocytes demonstrated that epitopes
          recognized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX>'s against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFNgR1</ENAMEX> and IFNgR2
          were resistant to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">min digestion</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trypsin</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Immunofluorescent staining of cytoplasmic
          antigens
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytoplasmic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFNgR1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNgR2 receptor subunits</ENAMEX> were
          detected by using a procedure described for intracellular
          cytokine staining [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, cells were fixed in
          ice-cold <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX>, washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> times,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">permeabilized</ENAMEX> in staining buffer containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> saponin
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, incubated with biotin-conjugated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX>'s
          (specific or isotype-matched) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> times,
          incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SA-PE</ENAMEX> and washed again (saponin was
          present in staining buffer at all times). After the final
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">wash</ENAMEX>, cells were resuspended in buffer without saponin
          and kept on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> until analysis. Monocytes expressing high
          levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNgR1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNgR2 receptor</ENAMEX> subunits served as a
          positive control. Expression levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Rb protein</ENAMEX> was
          measured using a procedure described elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> ]
          .
        
        
          Flow cytometry
          Fluorescent emission of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexa Fluor Â®488</ENAMEX> was
          collected on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the FL1</TIMEX> detector (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">530 Â± 30 nm</NUMEX>, log mode) and
          fluorescence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PI-stained DNA</ENAMEX> was collected on the FL3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detector</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>650 nm</NUMEX>, log mode). Incubation of tumor
          cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">staurosporine</ENAMEX> dramatically increased
          cell-to-cell adherence and number of cell clumps. To deal
          with this problem, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the FL2</TIMEX> detector (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">585 Â± 42 nm</NUMEX>, linear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mode</ENAMEX>) was used to measure area and width of electronic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pulses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMT</ENAMEX> voltage of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">FL2</NUMEX> detector was set high
          enough to minimize the number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">FL2</NUMEX>-width events
          appearing in channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Regions R1</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">R2 and R3</TIMEX> were drawn
          to exclude debris (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 8G</ENAMEX>), dead cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 8A,8B,8C</ENAMEX>) and
          cellular aggregates (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig</ENAMEX> 8D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,8</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E,8F</ENAMEX>). Acquisition was
          stopped when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 10,000</NUMEX> events had passed R1 &
          R2 & R3 logical gate (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8H</NUMEX>). List mode data
          files were transferred to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Windows</ENAMEX>-based computer for
          off-line analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were gated and the median values
          of fluorescence peaks were computed by using FCSExpress
          software written by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Novo</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">denovosoftware</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Analysis</ENAMEX>
          Total fluorescence of cells stained with MHCII-FITC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> can be divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) fluorescence
          caused by specific binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHCII-FITC</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
          fluorescence of MHCII-FITC bound to cells
          non-specifically and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) autofluorescence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">intracellular</ENAMEX> molecules such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAD</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. An</ENAMEX> experiment
          performed to assess contribution of each of the three
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> demonstrated that: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) non-specific binding of
          IgG2a-FITC was negligible in all experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fig</ENAMEX>
          8H); (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) tumor cells incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> alone did not
          bind anti-MHCII mAb above the level of isotype control
          and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) tumor cells incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (or with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX>)
          demonstrated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> fold increase in autofluorescence.
          In order to correct for non-specific increase in
          autofluorescence, "brightness" of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with PMA
          alone (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) was subtracted from
          "brightness" of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">columns 2-4</ENAMEX>), e.g., group 05a value was subtracted from
          values of group <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11a</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17a and 23a</TIMEX>, etc. All statistics
          were calculated using these corrected values that
          represent distances (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> shifts) between median of
          fluorescence peaks. The additional file
          "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xls</ENAMEX>"contains both raw and corrected fluorescence
          values used to perform the analysis.
          Additional File 1
          Induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MHCII</ENAMEX> molecules is measured as the
          distance between the median of the experiment histogram
          and the median of the negative control histogram. This
          file contains data and charts for the majority of the
          subjects used in the current experiment
          Click here for file
        
      
      
        Note added in proof
        While the manuscript was under review, results of a
        clinical trial had been published showing that a systemic
        combination treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM-CSF</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">as long as</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-weeks</TIMEX> failed to induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MHCII</ENAMEX> on tumor cells in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> out of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> hepatocellular carcinoma <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. However, those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with inducible MHCII on hepatoma cells had better
        median survival as compared to MHCII negative cases (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> <
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.0001</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] .
      
      
        List of abbreviations used
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">class II</ENAMEX> transactivator CIITA
        dimethyl sulfoxide DMSO
        fluorescein isotiocyanate FITC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">interferon-gamma IFNg</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma receptor</ENAMEX> IFNgR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma</ENAMEX> receptor alpha-chain IFNgR1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma</ENAMEX> receptor beta-chain IFNgR2
        GM-CSF
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janus</ENAMEX> kinase JAK
        major histocompatibility complex class <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> antigens
        MHCII
        mitogen-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> MAPK
        monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> mAb
        phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-myristate 13</NUMEX>-acetate PMA
        propidium iodide PI
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> c PKC
        STAT1
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retinoblastoma tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> Rb
      
    
  
