
  
    
      
        Background
        The results of cell culture and animal studies have
        selectively killed cancer cells 
        in vitro [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Furthermore, n-3
        PUFAs incorporated into animal diets have reduced tumor
        growth rates 
        in vivo [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4</NUMEX> ] . The prevailing
        hypothesis for the reduction in tumor cell growth, 
        in vitro or 
        in vivo , by supplementing the diet
        with high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX> has been that the
        incorporation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX> into cell membranes of the tumor
        cells increased the susceptibility of the cells for lipid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peroxidation</ENAMEX> and that the products of lipid peroxidation
        subsequently accumulated to cytostatic or cytotoxic levels
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . It has also been reported that supplementing
        the diet of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> xenograft bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3</ENAMEX> PUFAs
        could increase the efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">edelfosine</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] ,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doxorubicin</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] , mitomycin [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] , cyclophosphomide and
        5-fluorouracil [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] or irinotecan [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] against the
        tumor. Since causing oxidative damage is one of the
        mechanisms of action of many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] , the
        increased efficacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> has been attributed to
        increasing the susceptibility of tumor cell membranes to
        lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX>.
        However, the results of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our early studies
        indicated that some factor in addition to lipid
        peroxidation was involved in the reduction in xenograft
        growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish oil fed mice</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . A clue as to this
        factor(s) was found in the report by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vankatraman et</ENAMEX> al.
        that antioxidant enzyme activity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> was altered
        following long term consumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . We
        reasoned that alteration of antioxidant enzyme activity in
        the tumor by consumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX> prior to chemotherapy
        treatment could increase oxidative stress within the tumor,
        perhaps resulting an enhanced sensitivity to oxidative
        stress induced by doxorubicin (DOX).
        In this study, we wanted to test the hypothesis that
        there are changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> xenografts of FOC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that sensitize the tumor to oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDA-MB 231</ENAMEX> human breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> bearing athymic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fed</ENAMEX> fish <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil concentrate</ENAMEX> (FOC) or control diets, with and
        without supplemental vitamin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX> and were euthanized both
        before and after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment to test this hypothesis. DOX
        was used to induce oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>, supplemental vitamin E
        was used to quench oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>. An important aspect of
        the present study was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3</ENAMEX> PUFAs dietary supplement
        be fed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> at a level that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> could readily
        consume. This level was based on calculation of calories
        contributed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> as a fraction of the total caloric
        content of the diet. A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 65%</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">omega 3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ethyl esters</ENAMEX> was used to increase the amount of
        long chain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX> contained in a small quantity of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supplement</ENAMEX>. A high amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">α-tocopherol</NUMEX>,
        (vitamin E, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> IU/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kg</NUMEX> diet) was added to the diet of some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> to suppress lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> in tissues.
      
      
        Results
        
          Fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> composition
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acid compositions</ENAMEX> of the microsomal and
          mitochondrial membrane fractions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>, colon and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDA-MB 231</ENAMEX> human breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> were analyzed by gas
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chromatography</ENAMEX>. The individual percent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX> for
          α-linolenic, eicosapentaenoic and docosahexaenoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          were summed to estimate the fraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 fatty acids</ENAMEX>.
          The individual percent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX> for linoleic and
          arachidonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> were summed to estimate the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fraction of</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-6</ENAMEX> fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>. The ratios of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-6 fatty acids</ENAMEX>
          in each tissue and subcellular fraction were subjected to
          statistical analyses. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX> revealed that the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-3</ENAMEX> to n-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ratio (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>) was significantly higher in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that consumed FOC than in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that consumed corn
          oil (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>) indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 fatty acids</ENAMEX> were
          incorporated in cellular membranes when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> was provided
          in the diet of the diet. Supplemental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitamin E</ENAMEX> in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diet</ENAMEX> did not effect the ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-6</ENAMEX> fatty
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Antioxidant enzyme activity
          To determine the effect of consumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> on
          endogenous antioxidant enzyme activity, the activities of
          superoxide dismutase (SOD), catalase (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX>) and
          glutathione peroxidase (GPX) were determined in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liver</ENAMEX>, colon and tumor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that had consumed the diet
          for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>. As summarized in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> way ANOVA
          revealed that the activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPX</ENAMEX> were not
          significantly altered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> or colon due to the
          consumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> or of supplemental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitamin E</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. However, GPX activity was significantly less in
          the tumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that consumed FOC than in the tumors
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that consumed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> and supplemental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitamin E</ENAMEX> did
          not significantly alter GPX activity. Thus, the effect of
          consumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> on GPX activity was different in the
          tumor than in the normal host <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> or colon.
        
        
          Lipid peroxidation
          
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) liverand colon
            a) Lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> was slightly suppressed by the
            addition of vitamin E to either diet, b) <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment
            did not significantly increase lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) tumor
            a) <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental</ENAMEX> vitamin E prevented an FOC induced
            increase in basal lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX>, b) supplemental
            vitamin E prevented the DOX induced increase in lipid
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peroxidation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that consumed the corn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> diet
            but did NOT prevent a DOX induced increase in lipid
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peroxidation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that consumed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> diet.
          
        
        
          Tumor growth rates
          Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1illustrates</NUMEX> the mean growth rates of the
          tumors of each dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ANOVA</ENAMEX> revealed that the growth rates of the tumors of
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that consumed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> were significantly less
          than the mean growth rates of both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          that consumed either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> diet.
        
        
          Multiple regression analyses
          Values for the means of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX>, GPX activities and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBARS</ENAMEX> from the tumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> killed after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> on each diet with or without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment and the
          mean tumor growth rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> fed each diet and treated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks</TIMEX> were entered into a forward
          multiple regression analyses. Multiple regression
          analyses can address the question: What variable(s)
          present in the tumor prior to or after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment best
          correlates with the response of the tumor to DOX
          treatment? The results of the analyses (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>) revealed
          that GPX activity in the tumor prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment
          explained <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> of the variation in tumor growth rate (the
          correlation coefficient (r) between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPX</ENAMEX> activity in the
          tumor before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment and the tumor growth rate
          following <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.88</NUMEX>). Increased TBARS
          following <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment added <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an additional 19%</NUMEX>
          explanation for the variation in tumor growth rate. Thus,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97%</NUMEX> of the variation in tumor growth rate could be
          explained by the diet induced decrease in GPX activity
          and by increased lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> in the tumor
          following <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment.
        
        
          Body weight
          The mean body weight change of each group of tumor
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bearing mice</ENAMEX> following consumption of each diet for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> or following <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks</TIMEX> was
          determined. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> way ANOVA (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>) revealed that
          addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitamin E</ENAMEX> to the diet did not significantly
          effect body weight but that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that consumed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> prior
          to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment gained significantly more weight than
          did <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that consumed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO.</ENAMEX> Neither fat type nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vitamin E</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supplementation</ENAMEX> significantly altered the change in body
          weight during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
          Body weight and tumor growth rate
          It has been reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">omega 3 fatty acids</ENAMEX> can
          decrease tumor cachexia [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21</NUMEX> ] . It is important to
          note that tumor bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that received <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> in
          their diet gained more weight prior to initiation of DOX
          therapy than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that did not receive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX>. At the
          initiation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> therapy, the tumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> fed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          were slightly, (but not significantly) smaller than the
          tumors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> fed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and at the end of the study the
          tumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> fed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were significantly smaller than
          the tumors of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> fed <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, thus the higher weight gain
          has to be body weight, not tumor weight. The
          significantly higher body weight gain is likely due to
          reduced tumor related cachexia.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> fed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> did not lose different amounts
          of body weight during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment. This fact and the
          maintenance of antioxidant enzyme production in colon and
          liver are indications that the toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> to normal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> tissues was not increased by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> diet.
          The tumor growth curves (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) illustrate the
          significant enhancement of the efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> against
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDA-MB 231</ENAMEX> human breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> xenografts when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> was
          incorporated in the diet. The tumor growth rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          consuming either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> diet was significantly less than the
          tumor growth rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> consuming either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> diet. It is
          interesting that adding vitamin E to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> diet slightly
          increased the mean growth rate of the tumors. Since
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitamin E</ENAMEX> quenches oxidation and oxidative damage is one
          of the mechanisms of action of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] , it would be
          expected that addition of vitamin E to the diet of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          bearing tumors with adequate GPX activity, might reduce
          the efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Conclusions
        These results indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX> in the diet are
        incorporated in cell membranes, increasing the
        polyunsaturation of the membrane and increasing the
        susceptibility for lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX>. The inability of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cells to maintain the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPX</ENAMEX> in the
        presence of a diet containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX> was related to
        increased oxidative damage to membrane lipids and to
        significant enhancement of the efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> therapy.
        Tumor bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that consumed n-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUFAs</ENAMEX> gained more
        weight prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> therapy than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that did not receive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX> indicating that tumor induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cachexia</ENAMEX> was
        reduced. Clinical trials are needed to test the use of this
        non-toxic supplement as an adjuvant for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> undergoing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> chemotherapy.
      
      
        Methods and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Materials</ENAMEX>
        
          Preparation of cells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cultured</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDA-MB 231</ENAMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX>
          Collection, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) were harvested, rinsed then
          suspended in serum-free <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">M3D</NUMEX> base culture medium (INCELL
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LLC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>). Cells in suspension
          were counted using a hemocytometer and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count was
          adjusted to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 × 10 6/ml</NUMEX>. The suspension was kept well
          mixed during the time of injection. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDA-MB 231</ENAMEX> cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ×
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 6cells</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> ml of serum free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>) were injected
          sc between the scapulae of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acids</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Corn oil</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>) contains <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50%</NUMEX> linoleic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23%</NUMEX>
          oleic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> C16 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acids</ENAMEX> and < <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 PUFAs</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 ethyl ester concentrate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> oil (FOC)
          containing > <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 ethyl esters</ENAMEX>, (> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>, >
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">n-3 fatty acids</ENAMEX>), was obtained from
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipro AS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> and was supplied antioxidant-free.
          This <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> is made in accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Good Manufacturing</ENAMEX>
          Practice and is approved as a food <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> is saturated with nitrogen to prevent oxidation
          during shipping and storage.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> and diet
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Health Science Center</ENAMEX>. All animal use and handling
          was approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTHSCSA Institutional Animal Care</ENAMEX> and
          Use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX> female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">athymic nu/nu mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlan</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprague Dawley Inc.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 months old</TIMEX> received
          tumor cells. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were housed under aseptic
          conditions in a temperature (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24°C</NUMEX>) and light-controlled
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> h/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
          The tumor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were fed the AIN-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>
          semipurified diet from receipt until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> after
          injection of cells to allow the tumor to become
          established. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Nude mice</ENAMEX> bearing growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDA-MB-231</ENAMEX> human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast carcinoma xenografts</ENAMEX> were then divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
          dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>) such that the mean
          tumor size was not different between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> group
          received the standard AIN-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX> diet containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> (the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO diet</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> received the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> diet supplemented
          with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IU/kg Vitamin E</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>+E diet), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
          received the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AIN-76</ENAMEX> diet modified to contain <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> diet) and the final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> received the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> supplemented with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IU/kg Vitamin E</ENAMEX> (the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOC</ENAMEX>+E diet). Supplemental vitamin E was added to quench 
          in vivo lipid peroxidation due to
          the diet. The diet composition is given in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>. Diets
          were prepared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> portions were individually
          packaged and stored at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">-20°C</NUMEX> in sealed containers with
          nitrogen gas atmosphere to prevent lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> were fed fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each day</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> remaining in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> was discarded.
        
        
          Tumor and body weight measurements
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lengths</ENAMEX> and widths of tumors and body weights were
          measured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>. Tumor sizes were calculated
          using the formula for the volume of a prolate spheroid: V
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">= 4/3 * 3.14 * L/2 * W/2 * D/2</ENAMEX>. The width measurement was
          used as the depth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> weight change
          before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment was determined by subtracting the
          mouse body weight on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the diet change from the
          body weight on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> DOX treatment, thus
          this represents body weight change due to effects of the
          growing tumor and of the diet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> weight change
          after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment was determined by subtracting the
          mouse body weight on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DOX</ENAMEX> injection
          from the mouse body weight on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of killing and
          represents body weight change due to diet, to the growing
          tumor and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> therapy.
        
        
          Doxorubicin therapy
          After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of consumption of the diets, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
          tumor bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> from each dietary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were killed
          for assay of the effects of the diet on the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> and
          normal tissues of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. DOX therapy (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 mg/kg body</ENAMEX>
          weight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each 4 days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.</ENAMEX>v. in a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lateral tail vein</ENAMEX>) was
          initiated on the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> tumor
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bearing mice</ENAMEX> from each group were killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> h after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
          dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of the acute effects of DOX
          on the sensitized tumors and normal tissues. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were losing excess weight at
          the given schedule of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment so the spacing of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">injections</ENAMEX> was increased to each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> for the next
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> and mouse weight stabilized. The remainder of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10</NUMEX> per diet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>) received <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment for a
          total of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five weeks</TIMEX> to allow time to generate tumor
          growth curves and to determine the long term effects of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FOC</ENAMEX> consumption and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment. Thus if day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0</TIMEX> was
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> injection, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> received DOX
          injections on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 0, 4, 8, 12, 19, 26</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> and were
          sacrificed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 1</TIMEX> or on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 34</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Necropsy</ENAMEX> and tissue processing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> were deeply anesthetized using a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ketamine/rompun</ENAMEX>
          solution prepared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTHSCSA</ENAMEX> veterinarian. The tumor,
          liver and large intestines were removed at necropsy.
          Portions of each tissue were placed individually in a
          labeled vial and flash frozen in liquid nitrogen. At a
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later date</TIMEX>, frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">livers</ENAMEX>, colon or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> were thawed and
          homogenized individually at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4°C</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX> mM mannitol with
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 mM HEPES</TIMEX> buffer with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BHT</ENAMEX> using a Polytron
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homogenizer</ENAMEX>. The homogenate was divided into aliquots and
          frozen at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-70°C</TIMEX> until subsequent analyses.
        
        
          Products of lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> in tumor, liver, and
          colon
          The total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> content of an aliquot of each tissue
          homogenate was analyzed by the method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradford</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ]
          using the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bio-Rad protein assay</ENAMEX> (micro-method). The
          thiobarbituric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid reactive substances</ENAMEX> (TBARS) assay was
          used to estimate lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> in the homogenate.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malondialdehyde</ENAMEX> and other products of lipid peroxidation
          can be estimated spectrophotometrically at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">535 nm</TIMEX> after
          reaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thiobarbituric acid</ENAMEX> to obtain an index for
          lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . The absorbance values
          obtained were compared against a standard curve of known
          concentrations of malondialdehyde and normalized to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> content of the specimen. The results were
          reported as nmol of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TBARS</ENAMEX> per mg of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gas chromatography</ENAMEX> (GC)
          The incorporation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acids</ENAMEX> into the mitochondria
          and microsomes of colon, liver and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> was determined
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> which consumed each diet. An aliquot of each
          whole tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">homogenate</ENAMEX> was fractioned into mitochondrial
          and microsomal fractions by successive centrifugation
          [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX> × g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> (remove large debris), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> × g for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> (mitochondrial fraction), then <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100,000 ×</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">g</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h
          (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">microsomal fraction</TIMEX>)] for assay of lipid composition.
          Chloroform:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methanol</ENAMEX> was used for lipid extraction of each
          fraction; lipids were esterified in acetyl
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chloride-methanol</ENAMEX> as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gas</ENAMEX>
          chromatography was done using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard 5890</ENAMEX>
          Series <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gas Chromatograph</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, CA) and
          conditions of: oven @ 170°C initial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5°/min</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gradient</ENAMEX> to
          220°C final temperature, injector temperature @ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">225°C</TIMEX>,
          flame-ionization detector @ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">250°C</TIMEX>, helium <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> gas @
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">400 Kpa</ENAMEX>. Fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid methyl</ENAMEX> ester standards (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nu-Chek-Prep</ENAMEX>,
          Elysian, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>) were used for peak identification. The fatty
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid methyl esters</ENAMEX> were reported as the percent of the
          total methylated fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> (area under the curve).
        
        
          Enzyme assays
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catalase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX>) activity in the tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">homogenates</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assayed</ENAMEX> using a microplate adaptation of the method of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aebi</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . In this method, the decomposition of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> due to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> activity was assayed by
          the decrease in the absorbance of H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">240</NUMEX> nm.
          Superoxide dismutase (SOD) activity of tissue
          homogenates was determined using a microplate adaptation
          of the ferricytochrome C reduction assay of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flohé</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ötting</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . In this method, the reduction of
          cytochrome C by superoxide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> is monitored at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX>
          nm utilizing the xanthine-xanthine oxidase system as the
          source for superoxide.
          Glutathione peroxidase (GPX) activity of tissue
          homogenates was determined using a microplate adaptation
          of the glutathione peroxidase assay of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paglia</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . This method follows the decrease in
          absorbance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">340</NUMEX> nm as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> is converted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADP</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Statistical analyses
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX> computer software was used for statistical
          analyses. Tests for normality (basic statistics) were
          used on each data set. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Two-way</ENAMEX> and one-way analyses of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">variance</ENAMEX> (ANOVA) followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman-Keuls</ENAMEX> (SNK)
          multiple range tests, as appropriate, were used to
          determine statistically significant (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>)
          differences in measured parameters due to the diet or to
          the chemotherapy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PRISM™</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GraphPad Software</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>,
          CA) was used to generate an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX> to test for differences
          between linear regression curves of tumor growth.
          Multiple linear regression analysis with forward
          selection was used to test for correlations in the data
          between the independent variables: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> and GPX
          activity in the tumor prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> therapy, and TBARS
          prior to or after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOX</ENAMEX> therapy and the dependent variable,
          the tumor growth rate following <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">DOX</ENAMEX> treatment.
        
      
    
  
