
  
    
      
        Background
        One mechanism by which tumors evade immune destruction
        is through cytokine production or induction [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prostaglandin E-2</ENAMEX> (PGE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), constitutively produced by many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX> has been identified as one factor that has direct
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunosuppressive</ENAMEX> properties and is known to induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL10</ENAMEX> in
        mononuclear cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . IL10 is a dominant
        immunosuppressive cytokine found in the NSCLC environment
        known to directly affect T cell-mediated immunity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7 8 9 10 11 12</NUMEX> ] . Both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL10</ENAMEX> have been shown to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">suppress antigen</ENAMEX> presentation, to suppress cytotoxic T cell
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTL</ENAMEX>) responses, and to inhibit cytokine production by T
        cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen presenting cells</ENAMEX>, perhaps most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">importantly IL12</ENAMEX>, that plays a central role in initiation
        and potentiation of cellular immune responses [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5 6 7</NUMEX>
        ] , [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19</NUMEX> ] . We asked whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGE</ENAMEX>-2
        levels and/or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> levels were elevated in plasma of NSCLC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, whether monocytes from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">NSCLC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> produce
        more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL10</ENAMEX> than normals, and whether there was correlation
        within our findings. As an additional 
        in vitro correlate, we evaluated
        differences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> production by normal adherent
        peripheral blood mononuclear cells cultured in conditioned
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> from cell lines that produce variable amounts of
        PGE-2.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> produced by tumor cell lines correlated with
          IL10 production by normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> adherent PBMC
          To confirm observations from the literature,
          supernatants from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> different NSCLC cell lines producing
          variable amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> (ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 pg/ml/5 × 10</ENAMEX>
          5cells to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">>50,000 pg/ml/5 × 10 5cells</ENAMEX>) were compared
          directly for their ability to induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL10</ENAMEX> in adherent
          mononuclear cells. Each cell line induced <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IL10</NUMEX> in
          adherent mononuclear cells that was greater than control.
          This relative increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> correlated with PGE-2
          produced by each cell line (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>).(Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> levels in plasma of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with
          NSCLC
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> separate assays yielded similar elevations in
          plasma levels of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">PGE2</NUMEX> above normals. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assay</ENAMEX> used
          different sets of normals for comparison. Significant
          differences were seen when comparing measurements from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NSCLC samples</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9 normals</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">234</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/-40</ENAMEX> vs.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">519</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/-54</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> =
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.0167</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> NSCLC patient samples to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> normals
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">846</NUMEX>+<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/-62</ENAMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1838</NUMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/-213</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0011</NUMEX>) (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
          Absolute measures of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> differed between assays that
          prevented the pooling of results; relative values may
          reflect differences in sample handling or assay
          conditions, or differences in ELISA kits themselves.
          Plasma <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> levels measured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> patient samples were
          not significantly elevated above controls (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.6 ± 4.6</NUMEX> vs.
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.9 ± 3.6</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> > <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>; not shown). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> levels did not
          correlate with stage or histology (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> > 0.1 all
          comparisons).
        
        
          Cytokine profiles of adherent mononuclear cells
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX> patients
          Adherent cells, predominantly mononuclear phagocytes,
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were evaluated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> production.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> show adherent mononuclear cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX> patients
          produced baseline levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL10</ENAMEX> significantly greater
          than those of normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 ± 25</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">574</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">127</NUMEX>; p
          < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>; Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). IL10 production did not correlate
          with stage or histology (not shown).
        
        
          Correlation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> levels and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL10</ENAMEX> production
          from adherent mononuclear cells
          Paired comparisons of plasma <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> levels and
          mononuclear cell IL10 was possible in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> patient samples.
          Paired comparisons in patient sample did not reach
          statistical significance (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">> 0.1</NUMEX>), although in a
          subset of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, excluding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> samples with the
          highest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> levels, a positive correlation of PGE-2
          levels and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL10</ENAMEX> production was apparent (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>;
          Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). There was no simple explanation for these
          outliers, nor rationale for excluding these samples.
          There was a significant correlation between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> levels
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL10</ENAMEX> production in normal samples (p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>), but
          combining normals and patient data did not strengthen the
          statistical observations.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX-2</ENAMEX> is an inducible enzyme upregulated in inflammatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] . Notably, many NSCLC and what have been
        characterized as "premalignant" lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> have been
        shown to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constitutively</ENAMEX> express the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COX-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">enzyme</ENAMEX> and
        produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prostaglandin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-2</ENAMEX> (PGE-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), the primary product of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COX-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23 24 25 26</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, PGE-2
        production by tumor cells has been linked to tumor-induced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunosuppression</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> has been
        shown to directly suppress T cell mediated immunity, the
        primary effector against tumor cells, at a variety of
        levels [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . Further, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> has been shown to
        induce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the IL10</TIMEX> in mononuclear cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5</NUMEX> ] . IL10 is a
        prominent immunosuppressive cytokine that may have a
        dominant role in preventing innate antitumor responses in
        the NSCLC environment [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5</NUMEX> ] , [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17 18 19</NUMEX> ] . Among myriad suppressive effects on T cells
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen presenting cells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL10</ENAMEX> is known to inhibit IL12
        production [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15 16 17 18</NUMEX> ] . IL12 plays a key role in
        the initiation and potentiation of cellular immune
        responses and alteration of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IL12</NUMEX> producing function in
        circulating mononuclear phagocytes may be a critical factor
        in suppressed T cell immunity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 28</NUMEX> ] .
        We evaluated both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL10</ENAMEX> in plasma of NSCLC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> finding only <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> to be significantly elevated
        above controls. Elevations were independent of stage of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor histology</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> also show mononuclear
        phagocytes from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">NSCLC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> produce significantly more
        IL10 <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 24</NUMEX> hr in primary culture than controls,
        consistent with reports of altered cytokine profiles of
        adherent mononuclear cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>
        ] . Although 
        in vitro experiments suggest there
        could be a direct link between elevated plasma <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> levels
        and increased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL10</ENAMEX> production by adherent mononuclear cells
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX>, the measurements of patient samples do not
        support a simple causal relationship. The correlation seen
        in a subset of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9/11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> samples may reflect only the
        presence of underlying malignancy, however, it is tempting
        to speculate on the physiologic relationship between the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> can be induced by a number of inflammatory
        conditions, however no single factor, other than <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, is
        likely to account for the significant differences seen in
        this series. Absolute values of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX>, that may vary with
        different assays, are likely less important than the
        observed differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX> and normals. The lack of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> stage or histology, and the
        nonspecific production of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> by multiple cell types, may
        limit the usefulness of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> as a specific, independent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marker</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX>.
        Apart from standardized measurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> as a marker
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, a biologically relevant aspect of elevated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> would be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> with altered immune
        profile of mononuclear phagocytes, specifically IL10
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induction</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, serum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> levels were established
        as an independent marker for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and response to
        therapy by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Vita et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . The source of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IL10</NUMEX> in
        that series was thought to be from mononuclear cells. Based
        on the observations and conclusions of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>,
        and the measurable increases in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> production by
        mononuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phagocytes</ENAMEX> derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">NSCLC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> compared
        to controls, plasma levels of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">IL10</NUMEX> from these patients
        might be expected to also be elevated. In the current
        series, however, there was no difference between patient
        and control plasma <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> levels. The reasons for this
        discrepancy are unclear, and may be related to differences
        in handling/processing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> or differences in the
        sensitivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISAs</ENAMEX> used in the studies. Further,
        there was no significant correlation between IL10
        production by mononuclear cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> stage, as might
        be inferred from the previously mentioned studies. There
        was no correlation with histologic type of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Plasma PGE-2</ENAMEX> levels may be a nonspecific marker for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX> and warrants further investigation. In contrast,
        plasma <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> levels did not appear to be sensitive markers
        in our studies; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL10</ENAMEX> production by circulating mononuclear
        cells, however appears to be associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. The
        reasons for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> production by mononuclear cells in NSCLC
        are speculative and may be varied. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plasma PGE-2</ENAMEX> may
        contribute but cannot be simply and directly linked.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Cell lines
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> established NSCLC cell lines (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">UKY-104</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI-460</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI-820</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1155</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1355</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A549</ENAMEX>) were evaluated.
          Cell line <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">UKY-104</ENAMEX> is an adenocarcinoma established in
          primary culture from a malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pleural effusion</ENAMEX>. Cell
          lines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI-460 and NCI</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1155</TIMEX> are large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell carcinomas</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI-820</ENAMEX> is a bronchoalveolar type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NSCLC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1355</TIMEX> is an
          adenocarcinoma, all established at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Cancer</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> (gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Oie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of</ENAMEX>
          Health, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). A549 is an undifferentiated lung
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carcinoma</ENAMEX> and was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX>
          Collection (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). All cells were
          maintained in RPMI complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 %</NUMEX> fetal bovine
          serum, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> units/ml penicillin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">streptomycin; Gibco</ENAMEX> BRL <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX>, a human
          embryonic kidney cell line was used as a control.
        
        
          IL10 production by adherent PBMC from normal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">donors</ENAMEX>
          Adherent monocytes, derived from whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> of normal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> were purified from peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> by lysing red
          blood cells using <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Red Blood Cell Lysis Solution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ficoll Hypaque</ENAMEX> density separation
          technique. Adherent mononuclear cells were separated from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">granulocytes</ENAMEX> and nonadherent mononuclear cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells,
          B cells Natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Killer cells</ENAMEX>) by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hour</TIMEX> adherence step.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 6cells/ml</ENAMEX> were plated in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> well culture dish for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hr</ENAMEX> in tumor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> or control cell conditioned media then
          supernatants were assayed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Human subjects
          Following informed consent, peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> was
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">histologically</ENAMEX> confirmed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX>. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> had concomitant illness such
          as infection and none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> in this series were
          taking anti-inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Plasma cytokines in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with NSCLC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plasma</ENAMEX> was separated from cells by centrifugation and
          cryopreserved at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-80° until</TIMEX> use. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL10</TIMEX> levels
          were measured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> NSCLC <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and compared to that
          from healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> levels were measured in two separate assays:
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> compared <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> NSCLC patient samples to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> normals;
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> compared <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> samples to a different set
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> normals. Stage distribution included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> stage I or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IIIa/b</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> stage 4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> donated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood samples</ENAMEX> during follow-up
          appointments in between cycles of chemotherapy. One
          individual was seen for local recurrence of primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease</ENAMEX> (stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>), all other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were drawn at the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of initial diagnosis. Histologies included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
          squamous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> adenocarcinoma, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adeno</ENAMEX>/squamous
          cell, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> unspecified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSCLC</ENAMEX> (undifferentiated or
          poorly differentiated non-small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> carcinoma) because
          specific cell type was not discernable from available
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biopsies</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Cytokine profile of adherent PBMC from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
          with NSCLC
          peripheral blood mononuclear cells were available for
          processing (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">stage I-II n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>; stage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIa/b n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>; stage
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV n = 4</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adherent PBMC</ENAMEX> were purified from peripheral
          blood as above. <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 6adherent</NUMEX> mononuclear cells/ml were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> well culture plate in complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> and
          supernatant was evaluated at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hr for basal production
          of IL10 by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plasma</ENAMEX> and mononuclear cells
          were available for evaluation in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> plasma
          samples.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> production by established cell lines in vitro
          and generation of tumor cell conditioned media
          Tumor cell lines or control cell line <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> were plated
          in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> well culture dish (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 × 10 5/ml</ENAMEX>) in complete media
          × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hr. Supernatants were assayed for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGE-2</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D</ENAMEX>). Tumor cell conditioned media (CM) was
          supernatant of cells cultured <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">× 24 hr</NUMEX> in RPMI complete
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> at a density of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 × 10 5/ml</NUMEX>. All conditioned media
          was filtered through a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.22</NUMEX> um filter prior to use.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          Comparisons among individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> samples were made
          using paired t-test and all other comparisons were made
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ANOVA</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        List of abbreviations
        Non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> (NSCLC); <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prostaglandin E-2</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PGE-2</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interleukin</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IL10</NUMEX>); cytotoxic T cell (CTL)
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GH</ENAMEX> performed all experiments; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LZ</ENAMEX> performed data analysis
        and assisted in writing the manuscript; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DD</ENAMEX> participated
        with extensive discussion and direction in experimental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">design; EH</ENAMEX> directed all studies including gathering all
        clinical samples. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final
        manuscript
      
    
  
