
  
    
      
        Background
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX>)/vascular permeability factor (VPF)-responsive genes
        could potentially help elucidate the detail molecular
        mechanisms of endothelial cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>) activation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> is a program of gene-expression that could
        affect angiogenesis, permeability, and inflammation that
        are closely associated with a large number of vascular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>. Recent studies show that priming of quiescent ECs
        with appropriate cytokines could switch-on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">transcription</ENAMEX> machinery, the genes and protein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> of
        which could activate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX>. Mediators known to activate ECs
        include inflammatory cytokines, growth factors such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF/VPF</ENAMEX> and basic fibroblast growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (bFGF),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extracellular matrix</ENAMEX> (ECM) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> such as collagen and
        fibronectin, and proteases such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] . 
        In vitro and 
        in vivo assays indicate that VEGF
        signaling promotes increased permeability, cell migration,
        proliferation, and differentiation, functioning through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>-specific tyrosine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinase receptor</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinase</ENAMEX> domain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX> (KDR) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3</NUMEX> ] . In the majority of solid tumors,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> is upregulated in response to hypoxia, inducing the
        expression of pro-angiogenic genes that promote tumor
        angiogenesis, growth and eventual metastasis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5</NUMEX> ] .
        The expression of both positive and negative factors must
        be tightly and specifically regulated in a coordinated
        manner. Uncontrolled expressions of these factors could
        activate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> transcription machinery, which could
        promote pathological consequences including tumor growth
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metastasis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5 6</NUMEX> ] .
        Thus, the identification and dissection of the cellular
        and molecular pathways associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> may
        reveal novel clues which could provide further
        understanding of biological processes such as wound
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">healing</ENAMEX>, vascular permeability, and angiogenesis among
        others. A number of 
        in vitro <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model systems</ENAMEX> have thus been
        developed to study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> activation that employs either one or
        more combinations of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ECM</ENAMEX> molecules including fibrin,
        fibronectin, collagens, laminins, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrigel</ENAMEX> ®matrices
        together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FGF</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9</NUMEX> ] . When placed in a 3D
        type I collagen matrix and stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX>, or
        bFGF, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> undergo rapid morphological changes and
        differentiate into capillary-like tubular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>.
        Transcriptional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> block this 
        in vitro tube formation, suggesting
        that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">angiogenesis</ENAMEX> requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> activation and gene
        expression [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] . Indeed, a recent review describes
        approaches used to identify such angiogenesis-related genes
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . Although many angiogenesis-related soluble
        factors, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECM</ENAMEX> components, and intracellular signaling
        pathways have been identified and elucidated, their
        subsequent targets and their mode of action still remain to
        be determined.
        Despite extensive studies, for example, the molecular
        mechanisms underlying endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell activation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
        differentiations are not entirely understood. To better
        understand molecular mechanisms and pathways of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
        activation, we embedded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> in 3D type I collagen in
        presence or absence of human recombinant <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">VEGF 165</ENAMEX>. RNAs
        isolated from these cultures were then subjected to
        display (SSHDD). Through this method, we identified a set
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> new induced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> previously not reported to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the processes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> activation. We
        confirmed expressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> genes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> by northern
        and western blot analyses. There is a large number of
        literature showing microarray and gene-expression profiling
        analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> transcriptome. However, this preliminary
        study forms the basis for the future experiments involving
        analyses of signaling pathways associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
        activation that are crucial for many pathophysiological
        conditions including angiogenesis, cardiovascular diseases
        and growth of solid tumors.
      
      
        Results
        
          Identification of VEGF-responsive endothelial cell
          genes using SSHDD
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angioblasts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> are the precursor cells that can
          form functional blood vessels in response to specific
          angiogenic stimuli. To study the molecular mechanisms
          underlying capillary morphogenesis in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX>, we used a
          well-established 
          in vitro model of angiogenesis.
          Model system employed in our study closely resembles with
          those that have been described previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9</NUMEX> ] .
          Either human microvascular endothelial cells (HMECs) or
          seeded between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> thin layers of type I collagen gels,
          and overlayed with complete media supplemented with VEGF
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">165</NUMEX>, as described in methods. This typically induced
          cytoplasmic projections, spikes and extensions,
          elongations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 to 8</TIMEX> hr. These processes were
          considered to represent a precursor to cell elongation,
          interconnections of cells, and eventual tubule formation.
          A small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> that failed to elongate, did
          not form such interconnections. This model system closely
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">approximates ECM</ENAMEX> proteolysis, cell migration,
          proliferation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">capillary</ENAMEX> formation. Representative
          photomicrographs of VEGF-induced capillary morphogenesis
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> hr and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> hr are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1Aand 1B</ENAMEX>,
          respectively. Figure 1Cshows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> forming (at 200X
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magnification</ENAMEX>) elaborate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interconnections</ENAMEX> and vacuole
          formation at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">36 hr.</TIMEX> Although control (un-stimulated) ECs
          formed interconnections at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of 24 hr</TIMEX>, but fail to
          form any capillaries (data not shown). Eosin staining of
          these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> demonstrated that the capillaries were
          surrounded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three to five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1D). To
          identify genes associated with activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX>, we used
          the method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSHDD</ENAMEX>. By employing forward- and
          reverse-subtraction, we identified both common (indicated
          by arrows) and differentially expressed genes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1E& <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1F</ENAMEX>). The addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> embedded in
          the 3D type I collagen matrix (forward-subtraction)
          generated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 450</NUMEX> cDNA fragments. To eliminate the
          identification of artifactual clones, we analyzed only
          those cDNA fragments that were detected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 4</NUMEX> times.
          Based on this criterion, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 311</NUMEX> cDNA fragments (clones)
          out of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">450 sequences</NUMEX> (clones) were retained for further
          evaluation. From <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this 311</TIMEX>, a total number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> induced
          fragments were identified and sequenced (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I</ENAMEX>).
          Database search with these nucleotide sequences using the
          BLAST algorithm revealed many known positive or negative
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of angiogenesis, including proteases and cell
          surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, we identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
          VEGF-responsive candidate genes associated with the
          activation of endothelial cells.
        
        
          Confirmation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Differentially Expressed Genes</ENAMEX> by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Blot</ENAMEX>
          To confirm the differential expression of genes
          identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSHDD</ENAMEX>, we performed Northern blot analysis
          of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> grown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3D</TIMEX> collagen
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">matrices</ENAMEX>. The expression of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of
          angiogenesis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDR</ENAMEX> and α 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> integrin, VE-cadherin, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MMP1</TIMEX>, and
          MMP2, as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> genes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I</ENAMEX>)
          identified were analyzed. Consistent with previous
          reports, the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDR/VEGFR-2</ENAMEX> increased by ~<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>
          fold at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~2</NUMEX> fold at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~1.5</NUMEX> fold at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">165treatment</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A),
          whereas the expression of α 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> integrin subunit was increased by ~<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          fold at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX>, by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~2</NUMEX> fold at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs, and was barely
          detectable at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">36 hrs</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] . Expression of
          VE-cadherin was minimal at the earlier time points, but
          significantly increased at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of 36 hours</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C).
          MMP1 expression remained robustly active from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 to 36</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2D). While expression of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">MMP2</NUMEX> appeared to be
          biphasic, highest expressions were detected at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 and 36</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hrs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2E). Equal loading of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAs</ENAMEX> was confirmed by
          probing membrane with a β-actin cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> (data not
          shown). Northern analyses of clones <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7D</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3B</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17E</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22G</TIMEX>,
          33A, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37F</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48A</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54C</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77D</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94H</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">263F</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">309C</ENAMEX> were
          performed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> hrs following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">165treatment</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3A,3B<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">,3C,3</NUMEX>D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E,3F</ENAMEX>,3<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>,3H<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I,3J</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>). Northern blot
          analysis did not support the differential expression of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">54C</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3H). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7D</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3B</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">309C</ENAMEX> probes each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">detected 2</ENAMEX> transcripts, which could be either
          alternatively spliced products or related genes. Clone
          17E, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22G</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33A</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37F</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48A</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54C</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77D</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94H</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">263F</TIMEX> probes
          detected single transcripts (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3C,3D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E,3F</ENAMEX>,3<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>,3H<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I,3J</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>). Of particular note, probe 3B
          (corresponding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanniocalcin</ENAMEX>) detected primarily the
          lower isoform (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.9 kb</NUMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> 309C
          (corresponding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stabilin</ENAMEX>) is known to produce <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isoforms</ENAMEX>. Most likely, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> primarily express Stabilin-1
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-2</NUMEX> that are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.8</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.2</NUMEX> kbs isoforms respectively.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GAPDH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> was included as a control for the
          quantity and integrity of the loaded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>, detecting a
          single transcript of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~1.3 kb</NUMEX>. All data shown are
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of those obtained in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX>
          separate experiments, with similar results.
        
        
          Confirmation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Differentially Expressed Genes</ENAMEX> by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Blot</ENAMEX>
          To confirm that the genes identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSHDD</ENAMEX> encode
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX>, we performed Western blot analysis of total
          cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> grown in monolayers.
          The addition of bFGF, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX>, or PMA to the monolayers ECs
          induced cellular elongation over a period of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 to 24</NUMEX> hr.
          In contrast, unstimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> remained proliferative and
          retained a cobblestone appearance (data not shown).
          Western blot analysis revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, but not
          bFGF, induced the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Flt-1</ENAMEX>, and the α 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> integrin subunit at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">48 hr</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          4A<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B,4C</ENAMEX>). Likewise, only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> upregulated the
          expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VE-Cadherin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4D). As expected, all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          cytokines induced the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          4Eand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4F</ENAMEX>). These cytokines also induced expression of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinesin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4G), albeit less appreciably. Furthermore,
          we found dramatic increase in expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">VCIP/PAP2b</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> that were stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4H, lane
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 and 4</NUMEX>), in contrast, in bFGF stimulated cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lane 2</ENAMEX>) or in control (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, lane 1</ENAMEX>) its expression
          remained undetectable. Anti-Grb2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> was included as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> loading (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4I). These data suggest
          that the cDNA fragments detected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSHDD</ENAMEX> were indeed
          active genes that produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that could activate
          endothelial cells. Similar studies will be required to
          test whether remaining novel genes produce functional
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> or not and to establish their exact role in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> immunoblotting experiment,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monolayer ECs</ENAMEX> as opposed to cells grown in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3D</TIMEX> gel were
          used. Because, it was difficult to solubilize ECs
          embedded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3D</TIMEX> gel. Cold cell extraction buffer
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.25%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">X-100</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> did not
          effectively solubilize solidified 3D collagen, - warm
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37°C</NUMEX>) cell extraction buffer was incompatible because it
          activated endogenous proteases. It remains possible that
          different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> may be expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> cultured as
          monolayer as opposed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3D</TIMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
          Known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Regulators</ENAMEX> of Angiogenesis
          Of the known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> activation identified in
          our study, the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX> has been well established.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matrix</ENAMEX> digestion by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-9</ENAMEX>, is a pre-requisite for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> activation,
          differentiation, and tumor induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">angiogenesis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ]
          . The growth of mesenchymal cells in a 3D type I collagen
          matrix induces the processing and activation of pro-MMP-2
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>. Consistent with this, incubation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> with
          angiogenic cytokines induced the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-2</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Figs. 2& 4</NUMEX>).
          We also identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> indirect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> and angiogenesis, i.e., myeloblastin,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cathepsin</ENAMEX> B, calpastatin, and urokinase plasminogen
          activator surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">u-PAR</ENAMEX>). The myeloblastin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protein</ENAMEX> displays anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">proliferative</NUMEX> properties and is
          also a key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protease</ENAMEX> involved in factor-independent growth
          of hematopoietic cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Overexpression of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">myeloblastin</ENAMEX> has been linked to multifunctional cytokine
          transforming growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-β</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF-β</ENAMEX>) a known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angiogenesis</ENAMEX>. We postulate that myeloblastin in our model
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> may negatively regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> activation, thereby
          signaling to end <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> morphogenic differentiation.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathepsin B</ENAMEX> is a lysosomal cysteine protease, the
          expression of which is increased in different tumors,
          including human brain, lung, colon, and breast tumors [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calpastatin</ENAMEX> is a physiological protease inhibitor
          that acts specifically on calpain, a calcium-dependent
          cysteine protease. The cleavage of calpastatin by
          caspases initiates the apoptotic cascade in certain
          neurological disorders [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . It is possible that
          increased expression of calpastatin may control calpain
          activity thereby limiting extent of proteolysis during
          capillary sprouting. In contrast, uPAR has been shown to
          regulate plasminogen-mediated extracellular proteolysis
          during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">angiogenesis</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] .
          The identification of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VEGFR-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VEGFR-2</ENAMEX> (KDR) was
          consistent with the observation that the stimulation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> increases the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VEGFR-2</ENAMEX>,
          promoting myocardial revascularization [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . We also
          detected the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> adhesion molecules <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VCAM-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VE-Cadherin</ENAMEX>,
          and the α 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> integrin subunit, all known
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of angiogenesis. In the present study, we
          confirmed the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDR</ENAMEX>, α 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> integrin, VE-cadherin, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MMP1</TIMEX>, and
          MMP2 in activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ECs</ENAMEX> by northern and western blot
          analysis (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2and 4</ENAMEX>).
          Finally, we identified a known modulator of
          angiogenesis, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prostaglandin endoperoxidase</ENAMEX>-H
          synthase, also known as cyclooxygenase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX-1</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isoform</ENAMEX> is constitutively expressed in blood vessels,
          while expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COX-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">isoform</ENAMEX> is induced in new
          blood vessels. In many angiogenic tumors <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX-2</ENAMEX>
          colocalizes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-β, and increased expression
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COX-2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> has been correlated with increased
          tumor microvascular density [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Metabolic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and Miscellaneous genes
          Although metabolic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> such as ketohexokinase,
          adenosine deaminase, and spermidine synthase detected by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSHDD</ENAMEX> assay 
          per se do not directly activate of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>, it is likely that they could represent a component of
          the "angiogenic switch". Among the miscellaneous genes
          identified in our study were adenylyl cyclase and
          platelet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor 4</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PF4</NUMEX>). Intracellular signaling
          machinery of adenylyl cyclase is required for
          cytoskeletal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel maturation</ENAMEX>, and vessel
          integrity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . PF4 is a chemokine that binds to FGF
          and is a known inhibitor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> proliferation and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . Thus, the upregulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PF4</ENAMEX> might
          limit the degree of activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> and morphogenic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX>. It is noteworthy that Stanniocalcin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stc</ENAMEX>; accession <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"># U25997</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3A</ENAMEX>) was also identified
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GeneCalling</ENAMEX> (a mRNA profiling technique) and 
          in situ hybridization demonstrated
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stc</ENAMEX> is expressed in the vasculature of a subset of
          squamous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> carcinomas [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stc</ENAMEX> is a secreted
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> known to regulate calcium and phosphate
          homeostasis, potential role of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> and permeability is not clear [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . Since
          most ECM-degrading enzymes are metal ion dependent, Stc
          may act as a sensor to maintain a steady-state level of
          metal ions during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> activation.
        
        
          Candidate genes associated with the activation of
          ECs
          In addition to the genes discussed above that have
          previously been implicated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> activation and
          differentiation, we also identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> genes
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I</ENAMEX>).
          Kinesin heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KHC</ENAMEX>; accession<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"># X65873</NUMEX>; Figs.
          3Band <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4G</ENAMEX>), mediates organelle movement towards the plus
          ends of microtubules in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and functions
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell differentiation</ENAMEX> and axonal guidance [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . To
          our knowledge, increased expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KHC</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> has not been previously reported.
          Although the specific role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KHC</ENAMEX> in the differentiation
          process is unclear, this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> might be important for
          the maintenance of the plasticity and/or polarity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX>,
          which may be a prerequisite for the formation of
          capillary ends.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epiregulin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3C) is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of epidermal growth
          factor (EGF) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mitogens</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . Expression of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epiregulin</ENAMEX> has been reported to be highest in placenta
          and in a subset of carcinoma cells. Epiregulin activates
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX-2</ENAMEX>, therefore, epiregulin may serve as an upstream
          inflammatory component of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX-2</ENAMEX> signaling pathway. The
          function of epiregulin in the activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> has not
          been investigated.
          A general transcription factor BTF3 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3D, clone
          22G, accession <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#AA130020</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is thought to be
          involved in precise transcription by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA polymerase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>,
          but fails to interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. Disruption of gene
          encoding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BTF3 protein</ENAMEX> in the mouse caused
          postimplantation lethality around embryonic day 6.5 [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          ] . Detailed studies have not been reported in the
          literature. We believe, this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> report of
          identification of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BTF3</TIMEX> as one of the induced genes in the
          activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX>.
          As a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step towards elucidating the molecular
          mechanisms and pathways associated with activation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX>, we cloned the full-length cDNA corresponding to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">33A</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCIP</ENAMEX>, also known as phosphatidic acid
          phosphatase type 2b (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PAP2b</NUMEX>). PAP2b shares similarity with
          
          Drosophila polarity gene 
          Wunen-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31 32</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">PAP2b/VCIP</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">encodes 311</ENAMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid residues</ENAMEX>, contains a single
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-glycosylation</ENAMEX> site, a consensus lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphatase</ENAMEX> motif
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KPSXXXRPH</ENAMEX>), an RGD cell attachment motif,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-transmembrane channel-like structure, and displays Mg
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">++</ENAMEX>independent lipid phosphatase activity in transfected
          293T <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>- and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX> segments of
          PAP2b<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/VCIP</ENAMEX> are located inside the cytoplasm. Consistent
          with previously published report our data suggest that
          PAP2b<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/VCIP</ENAMEX> is cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and the expression of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VCIP</ENAMEX> is highly enriched in vascularized tissues. In
          addition to its known lipid phosphatase activity,
          PAP2b<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/VCIP</ENAMEX> also mediate cell-cell interactions [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ]
          .
          Synaptojanin-2 (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4F</NUMEX>) is also known as a
          polyphosphoinositide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphatase-2</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> is distant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homolog</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast protein SacI</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ]
          . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SacI</ENAMEX> homology domain is most notably found at the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amino</ENAMEX> terminal of the inositol <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-phosphatase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synaptojanin</ENAMEX>. Synaptojanin-2 (lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phosphatase</ENAMEX>)
          activities may be regulated by cell-cell and cell matrix
          interactions through RAFTs 'morphogenetic' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>
          ] .
          G <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coupled receptor</ENAMEX> (GPCR) kinase-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">interactor</NUMEX>-2
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3G) interacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coupled</ENAMEX> receptor
          kinases, and exhibits ADP-ribosylation factor (ARF)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GTPase-activating protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAP</ENAMEX>) activity. It is known
          have several isoforms, alternatively sliced products,
          however, we primarily detected a single transcript of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.2</NUMEX>
          kb size (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> specific isoform?). Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GIT-2</ENAMEX> localizes
          with a subset of paxillin, therefore, makes it a
          potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> signaling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that may
          collaborate with focal adhesion signaling machinery [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
          ] . Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GIT-2</ENAMEX> may play a role in cell adhesion,
          spreading, and motility.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMAP</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Smg GDS-associating protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3H, Clone
          54C, accession<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"># AI401257</NUMEX>), contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armadillo</ENAMEX>' repeats
          and interacts with the smg <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GDS protein</ENAMEX> through these
          repeats. This <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">v-Src</ENAMEX> substrate,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">phosporylation</ENAMEX> affects the affinity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">smg GDS</ENAMEX>. The small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> protein GDP dissociation stimulator
          (smg GDS) acts on a group of small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> including
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Rap1</NUMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ki-Ras</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smg</ENAMEX> GDS
          exhibits dual activity. One is to stimulate their GDP/GTP
          exchange reactions, and the other is to inhibit their
          interactions with membranes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] .
          Angiopoietin related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AngRP</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3I) is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chiefly</ENAMEX> expressed by the hepatic cells. AngRP contain the
          characteristic coiled-coil and fibrinogen-like domains
          that are conserved in angiopoietins, however, do not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">interact with Tie-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie-2</ENAMEX> receptor [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AngRP</ENAMEX> act
          as a survival factor for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX>, but its role in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angiogenesis</ENAMEX> is not clear. It will be interesting to
          examine if there is a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> for this molecule
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> or other vascular cells.
          Probe 94H (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3J) detected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.8</NUMEX> kb transcript, amino
          acid sequence analysis suggest that this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is
          likely to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal protein</ENAMEX> L19 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . In
          eukaryotes, ribosome consists of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">60S</NUMEX> large subunit and
          a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40S</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subunit</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . In mammalian cells,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal proteins</ENAMEX> accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 12%</NUMEX> of the total
          cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
          The alpha subunit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Translational</ENAMEX> elongation factor-1
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3K) mediates binding of aminoacyl-tRNAs to 80S
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ribosomes</ENAMEX>. This process is driven by hydrolysis of GTP
          into GDP. Translational elongation factor-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> interacts
          with guanine nucleotides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">80S</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ribosomes</ENAMEX>, and
          aminoacyl-tRNAs. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Translational</ENAMEX> elongation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-1</ENAMEX> binds with the β subunit of Translational
          elongation <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-1</ENAMEX> to exchange bound GDP for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ]
          .
          Finally, clone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">309C</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3L) DNA sequence was
          identical with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stabilin-1</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stabilin</ENAMEX> has been described as
          an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">endothelial-macrophage member</ENAMEX> of the fasciclin domain
          containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. Stabilin-1 and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-2</NUMEX> are homologous
          transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> showing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> fasciclin-like adhesion
          domains, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGF</ENAMEX> domains, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 X</NUMEX>-link domain and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-6
          B-<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7</ENAMEX>)-B hyaluronan-binding motifs [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . Stabilin-1
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stabilin-2</ENAMEX> are likely to play a role in cell-cell and
          cell-matrix interactions in vascular cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] .
          Several articles describe the identification of genes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX> and angiogenesis,
          as well as the repertoire of genes expressed in normal
          versus tumor-associated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">endothelium</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 43 44 45</NUMEX> ] .
          Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> activation is a complex process, accompanied
          by alterations in many aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> physiology, it was
          not surprising that the genes identified in these studies
          were in several functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>. However, the genes
          identified in the present study are significantly
          different from those reported by others, which may
          reflect differences in the approaches used and types of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tissues</ENAMEX> analyzed [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 43 44 45</NUMEX> ] . This preliminary study
          serves as groundwork for our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>, and we believe,
          it will be worthwhile to examine their role in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECs</ENAMEX>.
          Detail study of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> genes will entail
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of recombinant cDNA constructs, generation of
          cell lines, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>, fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, and perform
          in-situ hybridization among others. Detailed analysis of
          each of the differentially expressed genes identified in
          this report is ongoing and is beyond the scope of this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Methods
        
          Materials
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVECs</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clonetics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CA</ENAMEX>). Most cell
          culture reagents were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">InVitrogen Corp.</ENAMEX>
          Oligonucleotide primers were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma-Genosys</ENAMEX>; recombinant human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VEGF</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">VEGF 165</NUMEX>), bFGF,
          anti-VEGF (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MAB293</NUMEX>), and anti-MMP1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MAB900</NUMEX>) from R&D
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX>; adult human serum-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gemini Bioproducts</ENAMEX>;
          and bovine skin-derived type I collagen, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohesion</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc. Affinity</ENAMEX>-purified anti-α 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> β 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 integrin</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MAB1988</NUMEX>), anti-α 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">v</ENAMEX> β 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 integrin</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">LM609</NUMEX>), anti-MMP2
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MAB13405</NUMEX>), and anti-VE-cadherin (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">MAB1989</NUMEX>) monoclonal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX> (mAbs) were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemicon Intl</ENAMEX>;
          anti-Flt-1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sc-316</ENAMEX>), anti-KDR (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sc-6251</ENAMEX>), anti-Kinesin
          heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sc-13359</ENAMEX>), anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanniocalcin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sc-14352</ENAMEX>),
          and anti-Grb2 were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, and anti-β 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> integrin subunit mAbs <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">(4B4</ENAMEX>), from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coulter Inc.</ENAMEX> Rabbit anti-α 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> integrin subunit polyclonal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX> (pAbs) were a kind gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guido Tarone</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Torino Pavia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>). Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> II
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">W6/32</NUMEX>) was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">VCIP/PAP2b-RGD</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was generated by immunizing rabbit with a
          synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptide</ENAMEX> modeled after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid residues</ENAMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">VCIP/PAP2b</ENAMEX> (EGYIQNYRCRGDDSKVQEAR) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Cell Culture
          Monolayer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> culture was performed as previously
          described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 47</NUMEX> ] . To induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">capillary</ENAMEX> formation,
          unstarved proliferating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVECs</ENAMEX> (passage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) were gently
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuspended</ENAMEX> (at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6 × 10 5cells/ml</ENAMEX>) in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3D</NUMEX> collagen matrix
          that was prepared by mixing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml type I
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX> solution with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 ml of 10X</NUMEX> M199 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>,
          adjusting the pH to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydroxide</ENAMEX>,
          adding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> ml of 100X ITS, and the final volume to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ml
          with sterile distilled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The cells were then seeded
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well tissue culture dishes and the matrix was
          allowed to polymerize for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX>. The matrix
          was subsequently layered with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M199</NUMEX> medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>
          adult human serum-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> mM L-glutamine, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1X</TIMEX> ITS, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml VEGF 165</ENAMEX>. The growth medium was supplemented with
          fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VEGF</ENAMEX> 165every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hours</TIMEX>. The old growth medium was
          removed and fresh medium + <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> added every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Differential Display</ENAMEX> (SSHDD)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVECs</ENAMEX> were cultured in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3D</NUMEX> collagen matrix for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 24, 36, 48</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX>, with or without VEGF 165and
          total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIzol ®Reagent</ENAMEX> (Invitrogen
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp</ENAMEX>). Integrity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was determined by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.2%</NUMEX>
          agarose-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde gel electrophoresis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poly</ENAMEX>(A) +mRNA
          was isolated from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~800</NUMEX> μg of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> using the
          FastTrack <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">®2.0 mRNA</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Isolation Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen Corp</ENAMEX>) and
          cDNA was subsequently generated using random hexamers as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S UPERS CRIPTII™ RNase H</ENAMEX> -Reverse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transcriptase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen Corp</ENAMEX>). The PCR-Select cDNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subtraction</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PCR-Select Differential Screening Kits</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech Laboratories Inc.</ENAMEX>) were used to enrich for and
          identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">differentially</ENAMEX> expressed genes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> and
          tester cDNAs [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48 49</NUMEX> ] . Both forward- and
          reverse-subtraction were performed; untreated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> cDNA
          served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VEGF-</ENAMEX>treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> cDNA served as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tester</ENAMEX> in the former, whereas untreated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> cDNA served
          as tester and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">VEGF-</ENAMEX>treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> cDNA served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> in
          the latter [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48 49</NUMEX> ] . Target cDNA fragments were
          amplified using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marathon</ENAMEX> cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amplification Kit</ENAMEX>,
          subcloned into pCR <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">®2.1</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA Cloning ®Kit</ENAMEX> and
          transformed into TOP <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shot</ENAMEX> competent cells (all
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen Corp</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequencings</ENAMEX> were performed by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Biosystems</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model 373A</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lonestar Lab</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Blot Analysis</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVECs</ENAMEX> were cultured in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3D</NUMEX> collagen matrix for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 24</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">36 hours</TIMEX>, with or without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">165</ENAMEX>, as
          described above. Northern blot analysis was performed as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KDR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> was amplified
          from full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDR</ENAMEX> cDNA (available in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>).
          The other probes were amplified from untreated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> cDNA
          which was generated from total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>, as
          described above. Oligonucleotide primers used for probe
          amplification from cDNA are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Table</ENAMEX> II.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Immunoblot Analysis</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUVEC</ENAMEX> monolayers were either left untreated or were
          treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> or bFGF, or with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 hours</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX>. Monolayers were then
          washed with cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, and solubilized in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> ml
          of cell extraction buffer (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 mM HEPES</TIMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>
          X-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> deoxycholate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM sodium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chloride</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, and protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>. Equal
          quantities of clarified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were resolved by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE under reducing conditions and transferred to a
          nitrocellulose membrane. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Antigen-antibody</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> were
          detected as described previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 47</NUMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX>, endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">matrix metalloproteinases</ENAMEX>;
        3D, three-dimensional; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinase domain receptor</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSHDD</ENAMEX>,
        differential display; VE-cadherin, vascular
        endothelial-cadherin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMA</ENAMEX>, phorbol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-myristate 13</NUMEX>-acetate;
        fibroblast growth factor.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKW</ENAMEX> was responsible for preparation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSHDD</ENAMEX>, northern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blot</ENAMEX>, data analyses, and manuscript preparation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GDT</ENAMEX> was
        responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA subcloning</ENAMEX>, northern blot analysis, DNA
        sequencing, and BLAST algorithm analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">JOH</ENAMEX> performed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> and Western immunoblotting assays. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">JY</ENAMEX> performed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>, northern and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequencing analysis. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        read and approved the manuscript.
      
    
  
