
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhabdomyosarcoma</ENAMEX> is a malignant neoplasm of skeletal
        muscle, and is one of the most common soft tissue
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">malignancies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        Histopathologically rhabdomyosarcoma can be divided into
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major subtypes, embryonal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rhabdomyosarcoma</ENAMEX> representing
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 80%</NUMEX> of the clinical cases, and alveolar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rhabdomyosarcoma</ENAMEX> representing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20%</NUMEX> of the total cases
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] . Extensive cytogenetic studies showed that the
        embryonal rhabdomyosarcomas are generally associated with
        loss of heterozygosity (LOH) for multiple closely linked
        loci at chromosomal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">11p15.5</ENAMEX>, suggesting inactivation of one
        or more tumor-suppressor gene(s) in this region [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] .
        But the gene involved in this region has yet to be
        identified. Many other associated mutation or amplification
        of oncogenes, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor genes including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K-ras</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-ras and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-myc, etc. are frequently seen, but the roles of
        these gene mutations/amplifications in pathogenesis of the
        tumor remain largely unclear [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] ; [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . The alveolar
        subtype of rhabdomyosarcoma, however, is consistently
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> common chromosomal translocations. Most
        cases of alveolar rhabdomyosarcoma are associated with a
        chromosomal translocation t(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">q35</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">q14</ENAMEX>), and less
        commonly with t(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>)(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p36</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">q14</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7 8 9</NUMEX> ] . The t(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>)
        translocation results in fusion of a portion of the Pax3
        gene to a portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FKHR</ENAMEX> gene, leading to formation of
        fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> Pax3-FKHR. Pax3 gene encodes a
        transcriptional factor important in early development
        program, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FKHR</ENAMEX> gene encodes another generic
        transcriptional factor that is widely expressed in
        mammalian tissues. The t(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>) translocation results in
        formation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pax7-FKHR</ENAMEX>. Both Pax3-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FKHR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pax7-FKHR</ENAMEX> were
        shown to possess more potent transcriptional activity than
        its original forms Pax3 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pax7</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX> ] . How the
        chimeric fusion proteins contribute to pathogenesis of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rhabdomyosarcoma</ENAMEX> remains unclear.
        Ataxia <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">telangiectasia mutated gene</ENAMEX> (ATM) is a newly
        identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PI3</ENAMEX> kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that is mutated in
        human autosomal recessive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, ataxia telangiectasia
        (AT) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> gene is large, spanning <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 150</NUMEX> kbs
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genomic DNA</ENAMEX>, and is located on chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11q22</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>. In
        response to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA damage agents</ENAMEX> such as ionizing irradiation
        and chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cisplatin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> kinase is activated,
        leading to a cascade of kinase reactions regulating cell
        cycle, apoptosis, and DNA damage repair [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15</NUMEX> ] . Many
        downstream target molecules of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> kinase were so far
        identified. These target <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> include the c-Abl
        tyrosine kinase, the p53 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Chk1</TIMEX> and
        Chk2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">serine</ENAMEX>/threoine kinase, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p34</NUMEX> subunit of replication
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protein A</ENAMEX> (RPA), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chk1 serine</ENAMEX>/threoine kinase and NBS1
        kinase which is mutated in human autosomal recessive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease Nijmegan breakage syndrome</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17 18 19 20 21 22</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> ] . Clinical characteristics of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> include
        hypersensitivity to irradiation, thymic dysplasia, immune
        defects and higher tendency to develop malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX>,
        suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> function is critical in DNA damage
        repair and tumor suppression. However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to date</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are not known to develop rhabdomyosarcoma.
        In this study, we report an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of human
        rhabdomyosarcoma with deletion/mutation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> gene. This
        is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> report so far of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> gene associated with
        solid malignancy except for the mantle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lymphoma</ENAMEX>, a
        malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> in lymphoid origin. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of ATM
        gene mutation/deletion with rhabdomyosarcoma suggests a
        link of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> gene with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> kinase may
        contribute to pathogenesis of rhabdomyosarcoma.
      
      
        Results
        Totally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> specimen were retrieved from the
        archived tissue blocks. The clinical characteristics of
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were listed as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s
        clinical information was not available at the time of the
        study. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> all carried clinical
        histopathological diagnoses of rhabdomyosarcoma (embryonal
        or alveolar type), and showed immunostaining positivity for
        myogenin, a specific skeletal muscle marker.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunofluorescent</ENAMEX> or immunohistochemical staining with
        anti-ATM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was performed on the total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specimens</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> rhabdomyosarcomas were negative
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATM protein</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX>) (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Totally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
        were positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> kinase (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59%</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATM protein</ENAMEX> was
        predominantly located in cytoplasm in the tumor sections
        and interestingly, predominantly seen in the nuclei in the
        rhabdomyosarcoma cell line, as those seen with myoD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staining</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RD</ENAMEX> cells) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 1and 2</ENAMEX>). There is no difference in
        staining pattern in regard to the subtypes of the
        rhabdomyosarcomas, namely embryonal or alveolar
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subtypes</ENAMEX>.
        It is surprising to note that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the17</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX>)
        rhabdomyosarcoma specimens stained negatively for the
        presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATM protein</ENAMEX>. Under the normal condition, ATM
        expression is ubiquitous. To further confirm the
        immunostaining results, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different approaches were
        taken. One was to see if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> mRNA is properly
        transcribed, and another is to directly see the ATM protein
        itself by Western blotting analysis from the tumors and
        compare with the normal form. Due to the limited resource
        of the fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tumor samples</ENAMEX>, we turned to the cell culture
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> and used the well-established rhabdomyosarcoma cell
        lines. First, we designed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> pairs of oligonucleotide
        primers encompassing the almost entire coding sequence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> mRNA based on the published cDNA sequence (Genbank
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">accession</ENAMEX> number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">U33841</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). The primer
        designing strategy is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fig 3</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> mRNA is
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 9.4</NUMEX> kbs in length and contains multiple
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein binding domains</ENAMEX> for its kinase activity and
        interaction with other cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fig 3</ENAMEX>). We used
        reverse transcription-PCR method to analyze <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> different
        rhabdomyosarcoma cell lines, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RD</ENAMEX> cells (embryonal), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Rh28</TIMEX>,
        Rh30 (alveolar), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Rh3</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Rh4</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse normal myoblast</ENAMEX> C2C12
        cells. The human foreskin fibroblasts were used as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> cells. The mRNA was isolated from these cells and
        used for RT-PCR assays. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fig 4</ENAMEX>, in normal
        fibroblasts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RD</ENAMEX> cells, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Rh28</NUMEX> cells, the amplified DNA
        fragments were identical in regard to the lengths in
        comparing with the control fibroblasts, whereas in Rh30
        cells, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fragments in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1 and #7</NUMEX> lanes (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.94 kbs</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lane</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX> kbs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lane</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#7</NUMEX>) were absent, and in lane <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#6</NUMEX>,
        the fragment amplified was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 200</NUMEX> bps smaller
        than that seen in the fibroblasts and other
        rhabdomyosarcoma <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fig 4</ENAMEX>). The combined length of
        missing DNA sequence is estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.4 kb</NUMEX> (fragment <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1</NUMEX>, plus
        fragment <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#7</NUMEX>, and additional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> bps in lane <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#6</NUMEX>).
        The next question is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATM protein</ENAMEX> is normally
        translated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> mRNA and expressed in the
        rhabdomyosarcoma cells. We analyzed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in
        different cell lines. In human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Hela cells</ENAMEX> and human normal

        foreskin fibroblasts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> was estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">360</NUMEX> kD,
        consistent with the results previously described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ]
        . In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> rhabdomyosarcoma cell lines (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RD</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Rh28 and RH30</TIMEX>),
        there was one aberrant form of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATM protein</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~260 kD</NUMEX>) that
        was significantly smaller than that seen in the normal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hela</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fig 5</ENAMEX>). The levels of ATM
        expression in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> rhabdomyosarcoma cell lines are
        not identical, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Rh30</NUMEX> cells seemed to express less ATM
        than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rhabdomyosarcoma</ENAMEX> cells. The murine ATM
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C2C12</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10T 1/2</NUMEX> cells were significantly
        different in size and there appeared to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATM proteins</ENAMEX> in murine cells.
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> gene is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PI3</ENAMEX> kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> kinase is
        critical in DNA damage signaling pathway. In response to
        DNA damage induced by ionizing radiation or chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agents</ENAMEX>
        such as cisplatin, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> kinase is activated and
        phosphorylates a number of downstream regulatory proteins
        important for cell cycle arrest, growth control, apoptosis
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> repair [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26 27 28</NUMEX> ] . AT <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are known to
        be predisposed to a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, and the fibroblasts
        of AT <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are hypersensitive to ionizing radiation [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> ] . Although many reports showed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of ATM
        mutation with risk of a number of different human
        malignancies, including prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>,
        ovarian <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-cell</ENAMEX> chronic lymphocytic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX> and
        mantle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lymphoma</ENAMEX>, the underlying molecular mechanism by
        which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> gene causes these changes are not well understood
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31 32 33 34 35</NUMEX> ] . There is so far no study showing
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> gene with any solid tumor. There is
        enormous epidemiological interest in establishing the link
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> gene abnormality with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk, since the
        percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> heterozygotes is high, and estimated
        to represent <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX> of total <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        We studied the immunostaining characteristics of ATM
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in clinical rhabdomyosarcoma cases and found that a
        significantly high number of cases lacked the proper ATM
        gene product (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> cases). The clinical significance
        of this finding is unclear at this point. There is high
        percentage of clinical rhabdomyosarcoma cases associated
        with p53 gene mutation/deletion. The p53 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mutant mice</ENAMEX> tend
        to develop rhabdomyosarcoma [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . P53 is a tumor
        suppressor regulating cell cycle control and apoptosis, and
        p53 is one of the many downstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinase</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 27</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> phosphorylate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Serine 15</NUMEX> in response to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA damage agents</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . It is unknown how the mutated
        ATM contributes to pathogenesis of rhabdomyosarcoma in the
        presence of the mutated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX>. In fact, the rhabdomyosarcoma
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells Rh30</ENAMEX> is known to have p53 mutation, and is also
        positive for t(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>) chromosomal translocation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] .
        Further investigations are needed to address these
        important questions.
        The finding of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATM protein</ENAMEX> predominantly present in the
        cytoplasm, but not the nucleus of the tumor sections
        suggests a different role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> in the tumor cells. In the
        tumor cell lines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is present predominantly
        in the nucleus. The underlying significance of this finding
        is unclear. Presumably ATM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in the cytoplasm may
        function differently in the tumor cells in vivo from that
        in the nucleus seen in the cell culture.
        The murine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> was found significantly different in
        size, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ATM knockout mice</ENAMEX> recapitulate the
        phenotypic features of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A-T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . This species
        difference may be important in interpreting the data from
        human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> and from murine cells.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunohistochemical</ENAMEX> and immunofluorescent
          staining
          Human rhabdomyosarcoma tumor specimens were obtained
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Pathology</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Hospital</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. All human tissues were formalin fixed,
          paraffin embedded and were previously used for diagnostic
          purposes. Current study was approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Board</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRB</ENAMEX>). The specimens were sectioned at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> micron in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thickness</ENAMEX>, and used for immunohistochemical staining with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATM antibody</ENAMEX> as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, the sections
          were de-paraffinized in xylene solution, de-hydrated and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rehydrated</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90% and 70%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. The specimens
          were immersed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antigen Retrieval</ENAMEX> solution (commercially
          available from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dako Corp.</ENAMEX> CA) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> to
          unmask the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> followed by incubation with primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4°C overnight</TIMEX>. The
          primary anti-ATM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was kindly provided by Dr.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gately</ENAMEX> and as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was either immuno-peroxidase conjugated for
          immunochemical stains or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Cy3</NUMEX> conjugated anti-rabbit IgG
          for immunofluorescent stains (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Molecular Probes, OR</ENAMEX>). For
          immunofluorescent staining for the tumor cell lines, the
          tumor cells were cultured on the glass coverslips, fixed
          by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde and stained with primary antibody
          against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MyoD</ENAMEX> as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Cell culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolation, reverse transcription
          and PCR
          Rhabdomyosarcoma cell lines, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rh3</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Rh4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rh</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>,
          RH30 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RD</ENAMEX> cells were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Arden</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ludwig Institute of Cancer Research</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSD</ENAMEX>. The tumor
          cell lines were cultured and maintained as described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX>
          ] . The total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was isolated from the cultured cells
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Trizol RNA</ENAMEX> isolation kit (GBCOL-BRL, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Besthesda</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). The cDNA synthesis was performed using the cDNA
          synthesis kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supersccript</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GBCOL-BRL</ENAMEX>) using random
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hexamer and oligo-d</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>) primers following the instruction
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. The total cDNA was directly used
          as templates for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplification for ATM gene using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primer</ENAMEX> pairs in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. The primer sequences were based
          on the ATM sequence (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genbank</ENAMEX> accession number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">U33841</NUMEX>),
          and were described for mantle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> lymphoma with slight
          modification [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . The primers were synthesized by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigma-Genosys</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodlands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrophoresed</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> agarose gel and visualized using
          ethidium bromide staining.
        
        
          Western blotting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX> protein
          The rhabdomyosarcoma cells are cultured and maintained
          as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] . The cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were
          prepared, separated on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> polyacrylamide gel and
          transferred onto nitrocellulose membrane. The immobilized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were incubated with anti-ATM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> of interest were detected by enhanced
          immunochemiluminescence kit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Life Sciences</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX>'s contributions
        PZ designed and analyzed the data, and performed large
        portion of the experiments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KB</ENAMEX> helped in protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extractions</ENAMEX> and Western blot analyses. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JF</ENAMEX> and JW
        participated with extensive discussion of design and
        experiments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RON</ENAMEX> reviewed all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s tumor staining
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> cases for diagnoses. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read the
        final manuscripts.
      
    
  
