
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitochondria</ENAMEX> participate in numerous functions in the
        cell. In addition to producing energy, mitochondria are
        involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">intermediary metabolism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ion homeostasis</ENAMEX>,
        synthesis of lipids, amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>, and nucleotides, active
        transport processes, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell motility</ENAMEX>, and cell proliferation
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4</NUMEX> ] . Recent developments also demonstrate that
        mitochondria are key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of programmed cell death [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ] . Mitochondrial dysfunction is one of the most profound
        features of cancer cells. Several distinct differences
        between the mitochondria of normal cells and cancer cells
        have been observed at the microscopic, molecular,
        biochemical, metabolic and genetic levels [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] .
        Microscopic study of oncocytic tumors revealed
        mitochondrial hyperplasia [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] , and differential
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mitochondrial cytochrome oxidase II</ENAMEX> in benign
        and malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast tissues</ENAMEX> has also been reported [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] .
        Furthermore, mutations in mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (mtDNA) are
        commonly found in a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> including the
        ovarian, thyroid, salivary, kidney, liver, lung, colon,
        gastric, brain bladder, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and neck, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX> and breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] .
        Mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> encodes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rRNA, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> tRNA and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Each of the polypeptides form subunits of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> respiratory enzyme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> localized to the inner
        mitochondrial membrane [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . These subunits include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
        subunits of respiratory enzyme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> I, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> subunit of
        complex <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> subunits of complex <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> subunits
        of complex V [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . All other mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>,
        including those involved in the replication, transcription
        and translation of mtDNA, are encoded by nuclear genes and
        are targeted to the mitochondrion by a specific transport
        system [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Although the mitochondrial and nuclear
        genomes are physically distinct, there is constant
        communication between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> genomes to carry out many of
        the mitochondrial functions. For example, in the yeast 
        Saccharomyces cerevisiae, RTGproteins
        monitor the functional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of mitochondria and mediate
        the intergenomic communication between the mitochondria and
        the nucleus. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTG</ENAMEX> regulates transcription
        of numerous genes involved in several pathways that help
        cells adapt to mitochondrial dysfunction [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . In
        addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast cells</ENAMEX> shift their metabolic profile by
        altering expression of a number of genes that respond to
        depletion of the mitochondrial genome [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . As in the
        case of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX>, the depletion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mitochondrial DNA</ENAMEX> from
        human cell lines leading to the generation of cell lines
        devoid of mtDNA (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">denoted Rho 0</ENAMEX>) provides an opportunity to
        study nuclear responses to impairment of mitochondrial
        function. In the present study we isolated a Rho
        0derivative of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cell line. Our results
        demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0derivative</ENAMEX> experience increased
        oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> and has impaired mitochondrial function.
        Using cDNA microarray we compared differences in the
        nuclear gene expression profile between parental Rho
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">+breast cancer</ENAMEX> cell line and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho 0derivative</ENAMEX>. Our study
        suggests a variety of structural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> as well as genes
        involved in cellular signaling and transcriptional
        regulation are differentially regulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Rho</ENAMEX> 0breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cells.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Reagents
          The plasmid containing the mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">probe, pTZ19/K5</ENAMEX>, was a generous gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The probe has
          bases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2578-4122</TIMEX> of the human mitochondrial genome
          corresponding to a portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADH</ENAMEX> dehydrogenase I
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>, subcloned into the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">pTZ19</NUMEX> plasmid. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical</ENAMEX> reagents
          were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma-Aldrich, Corp.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>)
          unless otherwise indicated.
        
        
          Cell Culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDA-MB-435</ENAMEX> cells were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Culture Collection</ENAMEX>, and maintained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium/ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-12</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50:50</TIMEX> mix) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mediatech</ENAMEX>,
          Herndon, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIBCO/Invitrogen Life Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L-glutamine</ENAMEX>, penicillin, streptomycin, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Œ</NUMEX>ºg/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uridine</ENAMEX>. For measurement of cell growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> and
          galactose, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50:50</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mix glucose</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma-Aldrich</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ham</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-12</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biofluids, Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) was used. Either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>
          or galactose was added to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g/L</ENAMEX>, and the medium was
          supplemented as described above. Cells were cultured in a
          water-humidified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37¬∞C</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 %</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 /90%</NUMEX> air. Medium was replenished
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 2 days</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generation</ENAMEX> of œÅ 0Cell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Line</ENAMEX>
          Cells were cultured in the routine growth medium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">containing 50 ng/ml</ENAMEX> ethidium bromide (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.22</NUMEX> Œºm-filtered)
          with regular replenishment of medium. After a minimum of
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> culture, single cell clones were isolated by
          limiting dilution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96</TIMEX> well culture clusters, in the
          presence of ethidium bromide. The mtDNA status of clones
          was determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> blotting, after which Rho
          0clones were maintained in medium without ethidium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bromide</ENAMEX>. Cells were screened after a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population doublings</ENAMEX> in the absence of ethidium bromide
          to verify continued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Rho 0status</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MtDNA Southern</ENAMEX> blotting
          Total cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was isolated from washed
          exponentially growing cells extracted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris-Cl</ENAMEX>,
          pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">320</NUMEX> mM sucrose, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml proteinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.58%</NUMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dodecyl</ENAMEX> sulfate at
          37¬∞C for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h.</ENAMEX> An equal volume of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">phenol/chloroform/</ENAMEX>isoamyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25:24:</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisher</ENAMEX>
          Scientific, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>) was added to the extracts,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was isolated from the aqueous phases after phase
          separation by centrifugation. After a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">phenol/chloroform/</ENAMEX>isoamyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> extraction, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was
          cleaned with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chloroform</ENAMEX>/isoamyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>), twice
          with diethyl ether, and precipitated. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> Œºg of total
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> were digested with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PvuII</ENAMEX>, which cuts a single site in
          the mitochondrial genome. Linearized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was
          electrophoresed on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.8%</NUMEX> agarose gel in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TAE</ENAMEX> containing
          ethidium bromide, and photographed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was denatured
          and transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nytran SuPerCharge</ENAMEX> membrane
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schleicher & Schuell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX>) using TurboBlotter
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schleicher & Schuell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX>) rapid downward
          transfer with the alkaline transfer conditions
          recommended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was crosslinked by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UV</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> joules) and the membrane was prehybridized at
          65¬∞C for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> h in 3X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk powder</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>.
          Oligonucleotide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> was excised from pTZ19 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">K5</NUMEX>) by
          digestion with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HindIII</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EcoRI</ENAMEX> and isolated from low
          melting point agarose gel using <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Œ≤-agarase</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX>
          Biolabs, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>). Probe (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 ng</NUMEX>) was labeled with
          32P-deoxycytidine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Nuclear/ Perkin Elmer Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sciences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RadPrime</ENAMEX> random primer labeling
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) and unincorporated nucleotides were removed
          by Concert ‚Ñ¢ PCR purification kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">In Vitrogen</ENAMEX>). After
          hybridization with labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> for a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> h,
          the membrane was washed twice with 2X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> milk
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">powder</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, and twice for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> min with
          0.5X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk powder</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>. All washes were
          performed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65¬∞C</TIMEX>. Hybridization was visualized by
          autoradiography with X-ray film (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-80¬∞C</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Cytochrome oxidase immunoblotting
          Exponentially growing cells were washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and collected in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AG Buffer</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M PMSF</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,0</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.9%</NUMEX> NaCl<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,0</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X</ENAMEX>,1 mM EDTA<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,0</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.5%</NUMEX> NP40,50 mM Na 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HPO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Œºg/ml</ENAMEX>), leupeptin(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Œºg/ml</ENAMEX>), and aprotinin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 Œºg/ml</ENAMEX>). Extracts were
          homogenized for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> strokes on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and protein
          concentration was estimated using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX> protein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA). Equal amounts
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were separated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX>
          polyacrylamide gels under denaturing conditions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proteins</ENAMEX>
          were transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immobilon</ENAMEX>-P nylon membrane by
          electrophoresis, and protein transfer visualized by
          staining with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ponceau S</ENAMEX> and destaining with deionized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The membrane was blocked in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> in TBST
          overnight at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4¬∞C</TIMEX>, washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX> and hybridized with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">mouse anti-cytochrome</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oxidase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Probes Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>/TBST for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at room
          temperature. After washing, membranes were hybridized
          with horseradish peroxidase (HRP)-conjugated goat
          anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnology, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA) at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:5000</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>/TBST for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at room
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">temperature</ENAMEX>, washed, and incubated with ECL
          chemiluminescence solution. Antibody binding was
          visualized by exposure of membrane to X-ray film and
          subsequent processing. Membranes were stripped at 50¬∞C
          in, washed extensively with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBST</ENAMEX>, blocked and hybridized
          as described above using a mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-actin</ENAMEX> primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> and HRP-conjugated goat anti-mouse IgG
          secondary antiserum as described above.
        
        
          Cell growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> or galactose
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> +and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX> were plated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> well tissue
          culture clusters (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> cells/well) in growth medium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">containing 3.15 g/L</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> culture,
          cells were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, and growth medium
          containing either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> or galactose (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g/L</ENAMEX>) was
          added back to the cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> at a final concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Œºg/ml</ENAMEX> was added to triplicate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of both cell lines
          grown in both carbon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> immediately (t = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>) and at
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 48</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX> h following medium change. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> was also
          added to one well containing each medium only, as a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> h incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was
          aspirated, the converted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MTT-formazan</ENAMEX> extracted with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NaCl</ENAMEX>, glycine, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.5</NUMEX>, and the absorbance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">553</NUMEX>
          nm was measured by spectrophotometer.
        
        
          Measurement of lipid peroxidation
          Thiobarbituric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid reactivity</ENAMEX> was measured by a
          modification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohkawa et al.</ENAMEX>, [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] as described by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowie et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . Subconfluent cultures were
          collected by trypsinization, washed with ice cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and
          lysed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> freeze/thaw cycles in sterile deionized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Protein concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> was estimated
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad Protein Assay Reagent</ENAMEX> compared with BSA
          standards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1</ENAMEX>'<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,1</NUMEX>'<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX>'<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX>'-tetramethoxypropane (TMP) was
          diluted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris-Cl</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>, and serially
          diluted for standards. Equal volumes (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 Œºl</ENAMEX>) of lysate
          or TMP standards were mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">800 Œºl</NUMEX> of solution
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">containing 4 mg/ml 2-</ENAMEX>thiobarbituric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (TBA), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>,
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.4%</NUMEX> glacial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acetic acid</ENAMEX>, and heated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95¬∞C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h.</TIMEX>
          Samples were cooled to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> temperature, centrifuged for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> √ó <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>, and the absorbances of the
          supernatants were read at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">532</NUMEX> nm. Concentrations of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TBA-reactive substances</ENAMEX> were estimated by comparing
          values to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TMP</ENAMEX> standard curve.
        
        
          Microarray analysis
          Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted from exponentially growing
          cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trizol</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Precipitated RNA</ENAMEX> was resuspended in
          DEPC-treated deionized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and concentration was
          estimated by absorbance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX> nm. Labeled cDNA was
          prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX>-PCR according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Array-Advantage UA</ENAMEX>
          protocol from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambion</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambion Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Œºg experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNAs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Œºl</NUMEX> alignment control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          were denatured at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70¬∞C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> and allowed to anneal
          to oligodT by cooling to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> temperature for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M-MLV</ENAMEX> reverse transcriptase (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">units</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">[Œ±- 33P</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dATP</ENAMEX>,
          dCTP, dGTP, dTTP and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Œºl</NUMEX> 10X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> buffer were added to a
          final reaction volume of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Œºl</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> reaction proceeded
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42¬∞C</TIMEX>. Unincorporated nucleotides were removed
          by passing reaction through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NucAway‚Ñ¢ Spin Column</ENAMEX> and
          radiolabel incorporation of the reaction determined by
          liquid scintillation counting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human LifeGrid Array</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">membranes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incyte Genomics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, CA), which contain
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8000</TIMEX> cloned genes spotted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> positions on each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filter</ENAMEX>, were used for analysis. Membranes were blocked
          with heat denatured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">herring sperm DNA</ENAMEX> and prehybridized
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULTRArray</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hybridization Buffer</ENAMEX> at
          68¬∞C. Labeled cDNA from each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> reaction was heat
          denatured at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95¬∞C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX>, added to the
          prehybridization buffer, and hybridized to an array for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68¬∞C</TIMEX>. Membranes were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice 30</NUMEX> min each
          with 2X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, followed by 0.5X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, at
          60¬∞C. Membranes were exposed to phosphorimager screen for
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> hr, and imaged as .<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gel</ENAMEX> files using a phosphorimaging
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scanner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TyphoonScan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics</ENAMEX>, Amersham
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosciences</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) software. Spot intensities
          were measured using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ArrayVision</ENAMEX> software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imaging</ENAMEX>
          Research, Inc., <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Catharines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>), and the
          values. Genes corresponding to differentially expressed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAs</ENAMEX> were identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incyte Genomics</ENAMEX> clone
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">identification</ENAMEX> numbers. Membranes were stripped and
          reconstituted according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          instructions, and hybridizations repeated using freshly
          labeled cDNAs. In repeats, each cDNA was hybridized to
          the opposite membrane from that to which it had been
          previously hybridized. Only those genes that were
          consistently differentially expressed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> hybridizations
          were selected for analysis.
        
        
          RT-PCR analysis
          Trizol reagent (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">In Vitrogen</ENAMEX>) was used to isolate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 6cultured</NUMEX> cells according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instuction</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> micrograms of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was
          reverse transcribed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superscript II Rnase H</ENAMEX> -reverse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcriptase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">In Vitrogen</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> microlitres of the
          reverse transcribed products was used in the PCR
          reactions. Primers were made for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentially</ENAMEX> expressed genes and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G3PDH</TIMEX> a
          housekeeper gene. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty five</NUMEX> microlitres of the PCR
          reactions contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCL</ENAMEX>, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 ŒºM</NUMEX> dNTP and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> picomoles of
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primer</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Taq DNA</ENAMEX> polymerase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>). Each gene was amplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> using
          various cycle numbers ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 to 55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> to
          ascertain its linear amplification. In general the PCR
          profile consisted of an initial denaturation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94¬∞C</TIMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX> and a variable number of cycles of denaturation
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94¬∞C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sec</ENAMEX>, annealing at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">58¬∞C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min and</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">extension</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">72¬∞C</NUMEX> with a final extension at
          72¬∞C for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min. To aid comparison <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> microliters of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">differentially</ENAMEX> regulated genes
          were mixed with an equal amount of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX> gene
          products and electrophoresed on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> agarose gel and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visualized</ENAMEX> after staining with ethidium bromide (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Œºg/ml</ENAMEX>) under ultra <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">violet</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho</ENAMEX> 0breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cell line
          The rarity of recombination in the replication of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mtDNA</ENAMEX> is prohibitive to the possibility of selectively
          inactivating mtDNA encoded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> by homologous
          recombination [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . However, by culturing cells in the
          presence of low concentrations of ethidium bromide, it is
          possible to preferentially inhibit the replication of
          mtDNA, generating a cell line that are devoid of the
          mitochondrial genome [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . These cells, denoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho 0</ENAMEX>,
          have altered metabolic requirements due to the loss of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">components of the electron</ENAMEX> transport <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>, and require
          both uridine and pyruvate for growth [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . Cells with
          this engineered mitochondrial dysfunction require
          exogenous uridine because a functional electron transport
          chain is needed for pyrimidine biosynthesis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . We
          generated a mtDNA-depleted variant of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
          cell line <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDA-MB-435</ENAMEX> by culturing cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EtBr</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 90</TIMEX> cell generations, then
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isolating</ENAMEX> clones by limiting dilution. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from
          this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0clone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">clone 7</ENAMEX>) was digested with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PvuII</ENAMEX>, which
          cuts at a single site in mtDNA. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> blotting, and
          hybridization with a mtDNA-specific probe showed the
          presence of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.6</NUMEX> kb <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDA-MB-435 Rho</ENAMEX> +cell
          line. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.6</NUMEX> kb fragment was absent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho</ENAMEX> 0cell
          line (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1A,1</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B</ENAMEX>). To further verify loss of mtDNA
          encoded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, the expression of mtDNA-encoded
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">cytochrome oxidase II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX II</ENAMEX>) was assessed by western
          blotting. Expression is not observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cell</ENAMEX> lysates
          as compared to the parental cells (Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2Aand 2B</ENAMEX>). To
          assess the growth characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0clone</ENAMEX>, cell
          growth was measured in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> and galactose media. Cells
          with dysfunctional mitochondria are unable to efficiently
          utilize galactose as a primary carbon source for energy
          production (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14</NUMEX>). Following an initial growth lag,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">parental MDA-MB-435</ENAMEX> cells grown in galactose medium
          proliferated at a rate comparable to the rate observed in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">glucose</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3A</NUMEX>). However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX> were unable to
          grow in galactose media, indicating an impairment of
          mitochondrial function (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3B</NUMEX>). These results
          demonstrated that we had isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0breast</ENAMEX> cells that
          do not express <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> encoded by mtDNA, and which lack
          proper mitochondrial function.
        
        
          Increased lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Rho</ENAMEX> 0cells
          Mitochondria are the major site of reactive oxygen
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ROS</ENAMEX>) production [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] OS cause oxidative damage. It is
          conceivable that altered mitochondrial function in Rho
          0leads to increased oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>. We therefore
          measured lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> in parental and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho</ENAMEX> 0breast
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cells. Malondialdehyde, a product of the
          catabolism of peroxidized lipids, forms a pigmented
          reaction product with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thiobarbituric acid</ENAMEX> that can be
          measured spectrophotometrically [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX> ] . Levels of
          thiobarbituric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-reactive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> were measured in
          extracts of parental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> +and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX> to determine if
          altered mitochondrial function results in lipid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peroxidation</ENAMEX>. Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4shows</TIMEX> that thiobarbituric
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-reactive <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> were increased in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX> (solid
          bar) compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> +parental cells (open bar). We
          conclude that an increase in lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peroxidation</ENAMEX> is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the impairment of mitochondrial
          function.
        
        
          Microarray analysis
          Nuclear and mitochondrial genomes interact at least in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possible ways. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> they contribute essential
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein subunits</ENAMEX> to important mitochondrial function;
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> they collaborate in the synthesis of and assembly
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mitochondrial proteins</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . To identify genes that
          respond to lack of mtDNA encoded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, we compared the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> level between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cell</ENAMEX> line and parental Rho
          +cell line by cDNA microarray analysis. We analyzed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8000</TIMEX>
          genes present in the array. The microarray analysis
          revealed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> were significantly up regulated
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> were down regulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          classified into various classes including transcription
          factors and architectural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1and 2</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX>
          genes were selected randomly to confirm the microarray
          results by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>. The messages for each particular gene
          needed different cycle numbers to assess the exponential
          amplification accurately indicating the relative
          abundance of the individual messages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> results
          confirmed differential expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> indicated
          by the microarray results (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tables 1and 2</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> results show (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p19</TIMEX> (cyclin dependent
          kinase inhibitor) and v-maf were maximally up regulated
          followed by phospholipase C epsilon, a gene involved in
          signalling by increasing the intracellular levels of
          calcium ions. Among the down regulated genes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phospholipase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A2</ENAMEX> was maximally down regulated, followed
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX>-induced blocking factor 1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PIBF1</NUMEX>) a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that acts on the phospholipase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">enzyme</ENAMEX> and
          interferes with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arachidonic acid metabolism</ENAMEX>. These
          results suggest that impairment of mitochondrial function
          leads to altered expression of nuclear genes involved in
          communication between mitochondria and nucleus.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports on a comprehensive analysis of the
        nuclear gene expression in response to the absence of mtDNA
        in breast cancer cells. We demonstrate that expression of a
        number of nuclear genes is altered in response to the
        absence of mtDNA in breast cancer cells. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> ranged
        from transcription factors to genes that are involved in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">metabolism</ENAMEX>, cell architecture and signaling. Our results
        cells that reported altered pattern of nuclear gene
        expression due to elimination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mtDNA</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17</NUMEX> ] .
        We conducted comparative microarray analysis on Rho
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">+MDA-435</ENAMEX> cell line and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rho 0derivative</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX> have
        been used extensively to study the role of mitochondria in
        a variety of cellular processes that are affected by
        mitochondrial dysfunction (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 17, 18</TIMEX>). Our results showed
        that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> are up regulated (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">> 3</NUMEX> fold) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> are
        down regulated (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>3</NUMEX> fold) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0breast</ENAMEX> cancer cells. We
        chose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> randomly to confirm the results of
        microarray analysis with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). Among genes
        that are up regulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX> p19 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">INK4d</NUMEX>), a cyclin
        dependent kinase inhibitor, is focally expressed during
        fetal development and plays a role in terminal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INK</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are involved in arresting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> phase of the
        cell cycle. Conceivably, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p19</TIMEX> may be involved in the
        observed slow growth rate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rho 0</ENAMEX>. A number of genes
        that influence gene transcription are differentially
        expressed after mitochondrial impairment. The Maf
        oncoprotein, a basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leucine zipper</ENAMEX>-bearing transcriptional
        activator that recognizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maf</ENAMEX> recognition element
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MARE</ENAMEX>) DNA sequence (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX>) is noticeably up regulated in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cell</ENAMEX> line. c-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAF</ENAMEX> is highly expressed in developing
        skeletal tissues, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> where mitochondria play a central
        role in their functioning [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] . The transcription
        factors <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TFIIH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AML1</ENAMEX> were also up regulated in the Rho
        0cell lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TFIIH</ENAMEX> is associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA polymerase</ENAMEX> II
        transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, which is involved in transcription
        and transcription-mediated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> repair [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . The
        transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor AML1</ENAMEX> is frequently found translocated
        in leukemic cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . Conceivably, altered expression
        of these transcriptional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> in response to
        mitochondrial impairment could directly or indirectly lead
        to the changes in expression of other genes seen in Rho
        0cells.
        Phosphoinositide-specific phospholipase <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">C</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLC</ENAMEX>) Œµ was
        among the signaling molecules that were up regulated in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cell</ENAMEX> line. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLC</ENAMEX> is a critical signaling enzyme that
        hydrolyzes membrane phospholipids to generate inositol
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trisphosphate</ENAMEX> (IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ), which binds to IP 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and increases intracellular
        Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . The Œµ isoform of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLC</ENAMEX> is a novel effector of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ras</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] . Another signaling
        molecule of significance that is up regulated in the Rho
        0cells is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX>) homolog <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> vertebrate
        orthologs of the fly slit gene, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Slit1</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, have been
        isolated. Each displays overlapping, but distinct, patterns
        of expression in the developing vertebrate central nervous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, implying conservation of function [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . Slit3
        gene product is the least evolutionarily conserved of the
        vertebrate Slit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. The fact that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Slit3</TIMEX>, but not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Slit2</TIMEX>,
        is predominantly localized within the mitochondria makes
        its up regulation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX> an intriguing
        phenomenon [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] .
        One feature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cell</ENAMEX> line is the differential
        expression of certain genes that are involved directly or
        indirectly in metabolism of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acids</ENAMEX> or signaling
        (Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5and Table 1and 2</ENAMEX>). Among those that are up
        regulated are apolipoprotein <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ApoD</ENAMEX>) and arylacetamide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deacetylase</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ApoD</ENAMEX> may have a similar function as the
        other apoproteins, it does not share a similar protein
        structure to the other family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and does not bind
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> with high affinity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . Hence, it may have
        a unique effect via binding of different ligands. ApoD may
        be involved in the binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fatty acids</ENAMEX>, Apo
        D interacts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ob-Rb</ENAMEX>, but not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ob-Ra</ENAMEX>, in hypothalamic
        neurons 
        in vivo [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . In the central
        nervous system it was found that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Apo D</ENAMEX> may be activated
        through its interaction with a leptin-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ob-Rb</ENAMEX> and
        may bind a specific ligand in hypothalamic neurons, where
        it exerts signaling functions [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . Arylacetamide
        deacetylase may also function as a lipase during the
        process of lipoprotein secretion [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31 32</NUMEX> ] . Other genes
        involved in fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid signaling</ENAMEX> were down regulated in Rho
        0cells. These include phospholipase <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A2</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> closely
        involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arachidonic acid</ENAMEX> metabolism and also involved
        with cell signaling [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33 34 35</NUMEX> ] , that was found to be
        maximally down regulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX>. Phospholipase A2
        also plays a role in the translocation of PKC-mediated by
        fatty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>. Another gene with functions closely related to
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arachidonic acid metabolism</ENAMEX> that is down regulated in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX>-induced blocking factor
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">PIBF1</NUMEX>). PIBF1 is known to act on the phospholipase A2
        enzyme, and so interferes with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arachidonic acid metabolism</ENAMEX>,
        inducing a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th2</NUMEX> biased immune response [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . PIBF1 exerts
        an anti-abortive effect by controlling NK activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] .
        A gene related to lipid signaling that encodes
        agouti-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was also down regulated in the Rho
        0cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agouti</ENAMEX> is a paracrine-signaling factor that acts to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> melanocortin action [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38 39</NUMEX> ] . Disruption of
        melanocortin signaling with antagonist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> leads
        to an increase in feeding and eventually to obesity. Such
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blockage</ENAMEX> has been observed in both
        lipopolysaccharide-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and also during illness
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . The data exhibiting down regulation of the agouti
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX> is further strengthened by the down regulation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> reponse-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> synthase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5A1</ENAMEX> subunit gene that is directly
        involved in mitochondrial function was up regulated in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> synthase is a multimeric complex
        composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 16</NUMEX> different polypeptides, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
        which are mitochondrially encoded, and the remainder
        encoded by nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Certain leukemic cells
        show an increased production of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ATP5A1</NUMEX> subunit [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] .
        Interestingly, a down regulated gene CYP7B1 encoding an
        oxysterol <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7 alpha-hydroxylase</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytochrome</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P450</ENAMEX> subfamily
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VII</ENAMEX> BI) is involved in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">metabolic</ENAMEX> processes including
        bile <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid synthesis</ENAMEX> and neurosteroid metabolism [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ]
        .
        Mitochondria control Ca ++<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">homeostasis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Protein</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C Œ≥</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neurotensin</ENAMEX> receptor, and neuromodulin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAP-43</ENAMEX>)
        are among the genes that are involved in calmodulin
        regulation or related to calmodulin function [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44 45</NUMEX> ]
        which are down regulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0cells</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuromodulin</ENAMEX> is
        also a substrate for phosphorylation by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> kinase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> ] which may reflect an influence of mitochondrial
        function on multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a signal transduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX>. Another interesting feature in the expression
        profile of cells lacking mtDNA is the low expression of
        many genes that play a role in the development and
        maintenance of the nervous system [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47 48</NUMEX> ] . Of particular
        interest is the gene that encodes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neurotensin</ENAMEX> receptor I, a
        short peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> for neurotensin that exerts
        neuromodulatory functions in the central nervous system and
        endocrine/paracrine actions in the periphery [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuromodulin</ENAMEX> is also involved in the growth and
        regeneration of axons, and in the elongation of axons as an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">axonal</ENAMEX> transport membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synuclein</ENAMEX> is
        expressed in the nervous tissues and mutations in this gene
        are associated with rare <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">familial</ENAMEX> cases of early-onset
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's disease</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gamma synuclein</ENAMEX> is also
        involved in tumorigenesis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] . PKC-g mutation has been
        shown to lead to neurodegeneration [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> ] . Dachshund, a
        putative transcription factor, plays a role in retinal
        development [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] . Huntingtin-interacting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-2</ENAMEX> is
        involved in the neurodegenerative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Huntington disease</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX> ]
        .
        In summary, our data provides an overview of the genes
        that are involved in the nuclear and mitochondrial cross
        talk and respond to oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> manifested due to
        impaired mitochondrial function. The identification of a
        large number of genes whose expression is influenced by
        mitochondrial function provides a foundation for future
        investigation of the pathways affected by the impairment of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mitochondria</ENAMEX> in pathological conditions. An understanding
        about the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> in the maintenance of proper
        mitochondrial function and in oxidative stress response is
        critical for understanding the role of mitochondria in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carcinogenesis</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RD</ENAMEX> isolated and analyzed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rho</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0derivative</ENAMEX> of breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cell line. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AR</ENAMEX> performed microarray
        experiments in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EG</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">EG</ENAMEX> contributed to the
        analysis of microarray data and writing the manuscript. SK
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RD</ENAMEX>, wrote the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KKS</ENAMEX> conceived, coordinated,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">critiqued</ENAMEX> and designed the study.
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
