
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Promoter methylation</ENAMEX> has been well recognized as an
        important epigenetic change in the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ] . Normally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CpG</ENAMEX> islands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> regions of a
        number of genes are present in an unmethylated state [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ]
        . Aberrant methylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CpG</ENAMEX> islands in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> is
        characteristic of several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in cancer leading to loss
        of gene expression. A nonrandom pattern of promoter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypermethylation</ENAMEX> has been noted in specific genes in
        specific tumor types, although some genes are commonly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methylated</ENAMEX> in diverse tumors [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] . The extent of
        aberrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> and its association with
        loss of gene function in cancer suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CpG</ENAMEX> island
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methylation</ENAMEX> is an important mechanism in inactivating tumor
        suppressor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (TSGs).
        Germ cell tumors (GCTs) are the most common <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages 20-40</TIMEX> with an incidence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.2</NUMEX> cases
        per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> arise by transformation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">spermatogonial</ENAMEX> lineage cells and display pluripotentiality
        for embryonal and extra-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">embryonal</ENAMEX> lineage differentiation [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ] . Histologically, they may present as undifferentiated
        germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> (GC)-like seminomas (SGCTs) or highly
        differentiated nonseminomas (NSGCTs). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCTs</ENAMEX> display
        complex differentiation patterns that include embryonal,
        extra-embryonal, and somatic tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">types</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . Teratomas
        with somatic differentiation can undergo additional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">malignant</ENAMEX> transformation with characteristics of
        epithelial, mesenchymal, neurogenic, or hematologic tumors
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . While the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> exhibit exquisite
        sensitivity to cisplatin-based chemotherapy, a small
        proportion of metastatic tumors remain resistant.
        Therefore, male <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> comprise a unique model system to
        investigate the biology and genetics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> transformation,
        differentiation, and chemotherapy resistance/sensitivity [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ] .
        During the life span of a normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>, extensive
        methylation reprogramming occurs [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . However, the role
        of epigenetic changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX> etiology and biology are not
        well studied. To investigate such a role, we evaluated the
        status of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in GCT
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specimens</ENAMEX> and cell lines. We found an absence of promoter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypermethylation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGCT</ENAMEX> and acquisition of unique patterns
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCT</ENAMEX>. We also showed that
        the hypermethylation leads to loss of expression in most of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and reactivate upon treatment with demethylating
        drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-Aza-2</ENAMEX>' deoxycytidine.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> is common in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCT</ENAMEX> and
          rare in SGCT
          We assessed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT DNAs</ENAMEX> representing all histologic
          subsets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCT</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGCT</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> normal testes for
          methylation status of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CpG</ENAMEX> islands of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> by
          methylation-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> (MSP) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Of these, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          genes ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> , 
          RASSF1A , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> , 
          CDH1 , 
          MLH1 , 
          TIMP3 , 
          GSTP1 , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPK</ENAMEX> , 
          CDKN2A , 
          p14 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARF</ENAMEX> , 
          BRCA1 , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHIT</ENAMEX> , 
          TP73 , and 
          HIC1 ) had previously been shown to
          be commonly methylated in various solid tumor types [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ]
          . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> ( 
          RB1 , 
          NME1 , 
          NME2 , 
          BTG1 , 
          NEDD1 , and 
          APAF1 ) were studied because of
          their possible involvement in genetic alterations in GCT
          as indicated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOH</ENAMEX> studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 10</NUMEX> ] . The 
          RB1 gene at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13q14.2</NUMEX> showed frequent
          loss of heterozygosity (LOH) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . The 
          NME1 and 
          NME2 genes mapped to 17q21.3 also
          were affected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOH</ENAMEX> and exhibited loss of expression in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teratoma</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . The 
          BTG1 , 
          APAF1 , and 
          NEDD1 genes mapped to the 12q22
          common-deletion region, and thus considered as candidate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSGs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 10 11</ENAMEX> ] .
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> was not found in normal
          testes for any of the tested genes except 
          CDH1 . 
          CDH1 exhibited methylation in two
          of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">testes</ENAMEX> analyzed. However, promoter
          hypermethylation was detected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43 of the 92</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46.7%</NUMEX>)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> studied with an individual gene frequency of: 
          RASSF1A , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21.7%</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20.7%</NUMEX>; 
          BRCA1 , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19.8%</NUMEX>, 
          HIC1 , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19.6%</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.8%</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.6%</NUMEX>; 
          CDH1 , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.6%</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHIT</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.5%</NUMEX>, 
          MLH1 , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.3%</NUMEX>; 
          TIMP3 , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.3%</NUMEX>; 
          GSTP1 , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.1%</NUMEX>; and 
          NME2 , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.1%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The remaining
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> did not show methylation. Hypermethylation of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> was found only in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">29</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17.2%</NUMEX>) SGCTs
          but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38 of 63</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60.3%</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NSGCTs (Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGCTs</ENAMEX> that exhibited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> were
          methylated at a single locus and one tumor at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> loci,
          whereas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> NSGCTs exhibited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more
          methylated loci. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> was seen in
          all histologic subsets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCT</ENAMEX>, with yolk sac tumor
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YST</ENAMEX>) exhibiting a higher frequency of methylation
          compared to other histologies (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2& Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> and
          gene expression
          To examine the biological role of promoter
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypermethylation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX>, we assessed the levels of gene
          expression by semi-quantitative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> tumors (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCTs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> SGCTs) with known methylation status. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX>
          genes ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> , 
          RASSF1A , 
          BRCA1 , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> , 
          CDH1 , 
          MLH1 , and 
          TIMP3 ) that exhibited methylation
          in ><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> of the cases were examined (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
          Levels of expression of each gene were assessed by
          comparing with the respective control values, obtained
          from the averages calculated from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 to 4</TIMEX> normal testes,
          after normalization against 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACTB</ENAMEX> . All tumors with promoter
          hypermethylation of the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> and 
          MLH1 genes exhibited an absence or
          down-regulated expression of the respective gene, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> cases with 
          RASSF1A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">methylation</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          tumors with 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> methylation showed
          down-regulated expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> genes
          ( 
          BRCA1 , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> , 
          CDH1 , and 
          TIMP3 ) did not show a consistent
          pattern of correlation between methylation and loss of
          gene expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Of note, the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene exhibited down-regulated
          expression in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 of the 23</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95.7%</NUMEX>) tumors, including all
          the tumors that showed promoter methylation. No
          consistent down-regulation of expression of the other
          genes that lacked promoter methylation was detected in
          the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> of specimens. These data, thus, showed
          loss of 
          MGMT expression in majority of GCTs
          of all histologic subsets.
        
        
          Demethylation reactivates the gene
          expression
          To further examine the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter methylation</ENAMEX> in
          gene inactivation, we treated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> NSGCT cell lines
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2102E</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">833K-E</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tera-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tera-2</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">218A</ENAMEX>) with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-Aza-2</ENAMEX>'
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deoxycytidine</ENAMEX> and analyzed the expression of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> , 
          RASSF1A , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> , and 
          BRCA1 genes. The 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene exhibited promoter
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypermethylation</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the cell lines, which upon
          treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-Aza-2</ENAMEX>' deoxycytidine showed reactivation
          of expression in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2102E</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">833K-E</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tera-2</ENAMEX>). The
          cell line <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tera-1</ENAMEX> did not reactivate expression after
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">azacytidine</ENAMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). One cell line (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-218A</ENAMEX>)
          showed no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSP</ENAMEX> and no detectable
          levels of mRNA expression by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> but expression was
          reactivated after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aza-2</ENAMEX>' deoxycytidine treatment. Two
          of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> cell lines showed methylation in the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> gene, one of which (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tera-2</ENAMEX>)
          showed detectable levels of gene expression in untreated
          cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cell lines including the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2102E</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>) exhibited no
          detectable levels of 
          RARB expression. Azacytidine
          treatment activated gene expression in all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> cell
          lines, whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> had detectable methylation
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). The 
          RASSF1A gene was methylated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cell lines studied. While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the methylated
          cell lines showed expression in untreated cells, all
          other cell lines did not show detectable levels of mRNA.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Azacytidine</ENAMEX> treatment reactivated expression of 
          RASSF1A in one of each of the two
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methylated</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> unmethylated cell lines. The 
          BRCA1 gene showed promoter
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methylation</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cell lines. Irrespective of whether
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> is methylated or not, the 
          BRCA1 gene was expressed in all
          cell lines and the treatment of azacytidine had little or
          no effect on levels of gene expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Epigenetic mechanisms of gene silencing are increasingly
        being recognized to affect a number of molecular pathways
        in human cancer [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . The extent and the nature of such
        epigenetic modifications in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> are currently poorly
        understood. Here we show that hypermethylation is common in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCT</ENAMEX> and rare in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGCT</ENAMEX>. Several studies have shown that
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCTs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGCTs</ENAMEX> exhibit similar genetic alterations,
        including isochromosome for the short arm of chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>,
        i(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12p</NUMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . Thus epigenetic alterations such as those
        detected in the current study is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> distinct molecular
        change that distinguishes these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> histologic subsets. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rare CpG</ENAMEX> hypermethylation seen in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGCT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> may be
        due to the existence of a minor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCT</ENAMEX> component that might
        have escaped the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">histologic</ENAMEX> diagnosis. A unique feature of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> is their origin from germ cells at a stage in
        development where they undergo epigenetic reprogramming [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> ] . The absence of this epigenetic modification in SGCTs
        is consistent with their GC-like nature as previously noted
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 14</ENAMEX> ] . On the other hand, the extensive promoter
        hypermethylation seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCTs</ENAMEX> suggests a mechanistic role
        in their potential for embryonal and extra-embryonal
        lineage differentiation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 14</ENAMEX> ] . Establishment of DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methylation</ENAMEX> in the mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">genome</ENAMEX> is controlled by at
        least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA methyltransferases</ENAMEX> (DNMTs), 
        DNMT1 , 
        DNMT3a and 
        DNMT3b [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . The role of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNMTs</ENAMEX> in differential de novo methylation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGCT</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCT</ENAMEX>
        remains to be elucidated.
        The overall higher frequency of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> methylation
        seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCTs</ENAMEX> is noticeably evident in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> repair genes 
        RASSF1A, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BRCA1</TIMEX> , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> , and the hypermethylated in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> 1 ( 
        HIC1 ) gene, which encodes a
        transcription factor. These genes map to sites already
        known to be genetically altered in GCT specimens. The
        3p21.3 region to which 
        RASSF1A maps undergoes deletions in
        many solid tumor types, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . 
        RASSF1A encodes a splice variant of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human RAS</ENAMEX> effector homologue, which interacts with the XPA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and functions as a negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> of cell
        growth [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ] . 
        RASSF1A has been shown to be
        inactivated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter methylation</ENAMEX> in a variety of tumor
        types [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17 18 19</NUMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">17q21</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17p13</NUMEX> regions, to
        which 
        BRCA1 and 
        HIC1 map, respectively, also have
        been characterized by high frequency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOH</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        The 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRCA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> plays critical roles in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> repair and recombination, cell cycle checkpoint
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, and transcription and has been shown to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypermethylated</ENAMEX> in breast-ovarian <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . The 
        HIC1 gene is also often
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypermethylated</ENAMEX> in many human <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21 22</NUMEX> ] . The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> repair gene 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methyltransferase</ENAMEX> and this enzyme effectively removes DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adducts</ENAMEX> formed by alkylating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . Epigenetic
        inactivation of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene was reported in a wide
        variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25</NUMEX> ] . Also, a low frequency of
        methylation of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FHIT genes</ENAMEX> was detected in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCTs</ENAMEX>.
        Thus, the frequent hypermethylation in the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BRCA1</TIMEX> , and 
        RASSF1A , and 
        HIC1 define the methylation profile
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCT</ENAMEX>. These data suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> hypermethylation
        leading to gene silencing may affect key pathways in germ
        cell tumorigenesis.
        Aberrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> methylation changes that occur in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> are associated with transcriptional repression and
        loss of function of the gene by interrupting the binding of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> involved in transcription activator complex [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ]
        . Our gene expression analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> demonstrated that
        all tumors that showed methylation of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> and 
        MLH1 also showed down-regulated
        expression, while 
        RASSF1A and 
        RARB genes showed down-regulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> levels in most of the methylated tumors. Thus in these
        cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter hypermethylation</ENAMEX> is one mechanism whereby
        gene expression can be deregulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX>. On the other
        hand, methylation of 
        BRCA1 , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> , 
        CDH1 , and 
        TIMP3 genes did not correlate with
        expression levels. Interestingly, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene was also down regulated in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> tumors that did not exhibit methylation by MSP
        analysis. Therefore, these data indicate that other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epigenetic</ENAMEX> and/or genetic changes may be involved in
        regulating the expression of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX>. The MSP method detects
        only methylation of full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CpG</ENAMEX> islands and cannot
        identify partial methylation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX>. Thus, role
        of partial methylation in down-regulating 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MGMT</ENAMEX> cannot be ruled out. Other
        epigenetic mechanisms involving defects in chromatin
        modification factors such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl</ENAMEX>-CpG
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding proteins</ENAMEX>, acetylation and methylation of histone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are also becoming known [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . The role of these
        chromatin-mediated components in inactivating the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene remains to be examined in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX>. To determine whether the down-regulated expression of
        the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene is due to genetic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mutations</ENAMEX>, we examined the entire coding region in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> GCTs
        and found no inactivating mutations (unpublished
        observations).
        Epigenetic gene silencing of the 
        MGMT confers enhanced sensitivity to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alkylating</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in cancer [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25</NUMEX> ] . Lack of
        methylation, on the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> with high-risk
        of death [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] . It has been suggested that the
        high-levels of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGMT proteins</ENAMEX> contribute to a
        drug-resistant phenotype [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 90%</NUMEX> of newly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diagnosed GCTs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70-80%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who present
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">metastatic disease</ENAMEX> are cured with cisplatin-based
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemotherapy</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . However, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20-30%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        metastatic disease exhibit resistance to the cisplatin
        curative regimen leading to high mortality in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
        The molecular basis of this exquisite chemotherapy
        sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> is poorly understood. We
        have previously shown that subsets of resistant tumors
        exhibit 
        TP53 gene mutations and chromosomal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amplifications</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . However, the role of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> in GCT sensitivity or resistance
        to chemotherapy is not known. Our current observation that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undetectable</ENAMEX> levels of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene expression in ><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> appears to suggest that the lack of the
        cells to undergo apoptosis due to failure of repair of DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adducts</ENAMEX> formed by alkylating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. Lack of 
        MGMT expression in the majority of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> suggests a potential role for this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in lack of
        repair of cisplatin-induced DNA damage that may result in
        exquisite sensitivity in this tumor. It has been shown that
        engineered over-expression of wild-type p53 
        in vitro causes inhibition of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> transcription in human tumor
        cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . Abundant over-expression of wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p53</ENAMEX>,
        owing to their stage of origin, is a characteristic feature
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . A possibility also exists that the 
        MGMT expression may, in general, be
        down regulated in tumors arising from embryonic-type cells.
        To examine this, we analyzed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilms</ENAMEX>' tumor but
        found no decreased levels of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene expression (data not
        shown). These data, therefore, rule out the possibility
        that not all tumors arising from embryonic-type cells show
        down-regulated expression of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> .
        Transcriptional silencing of genes resulting from DNA
        hypermethylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CpG</ENAMEX> islands is reversed by treatment of
        the hypo-methylating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-aza-2</ENAMEX>'-deoxycytidine in a dose
        and duration-dependent manner. Since a number of gene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> were hypermethylated and showed down-regulated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX>, we wanted to test whether hypomethylation
        reactivates the gene expression in these tumors. We found
        that azacytidine treatment resulted in reactivation of gene
        expression in almost all cell lines that showed promoter
        methylation of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RASSF1A</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RARB genes</ENAMEX>, with the exception of the
        cell line <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tera-1</ENAMEX>. In addition, a number of genes that
        showed no evidence of full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CpG</ENAMEX> methylation was also
        reactivated upon azacytidine treatment. This was most
        evident for the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> gene, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> cell lines
        showed reactivation whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methylated</ENAMEX>. These data thus suggest that global
        demethylation may not only influence the expression of
        methylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> but also unmethylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. Such a
        phenomenon has previously been reported [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31 32</NUMEX> ] .
      
      
        Conclusions
        The data presented here show that promoter
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypermethylation</ENAMEX> is an important molecular signature
        differentiating seminomatous and nonseminomatous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Promoter methylation</ENAMEX> was frequently seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> repair
        genes 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> , 
        RASSF1A , and 
        BRCA1 , and a transcriptional
        repressor gene 
        HIC1 . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Promoter methylation</ENAMEX> of most
        genes resulted in transcriptional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repression</ENAMEX>. The data also
        suggest that multiple mechanisms, in addition to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter methylation</ENAMEX>, may play a role in silencing of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX> of all
        histologic subsets. Given the importance of the MGMT
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in treatment response to alkylating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, this
        molecular switch may play a critical role in sensitivity to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">cisplatin</ENAMEX>-based therapy in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCTs</ENAMEX>. Demethylation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> reactivated the gene expression in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> and 
        RASSF1A genes. Further
        characterization of the exact mechanisms involved in
        epigenetic gene silencing, especially in the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene, may provide important
        clues in understanding the pathways relevant to GCT
        biology.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Tumor tissues and cell lines
          A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX> GCT tumor tissues consisting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">83</NUMEX>
          primary tumors and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> lines were used in this
          study. The tumor biopsies were ascertained from patients
          evaluated at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSKCC</ENAMEX>) as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] after appropriate
          institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review board</ENAMEX> approval. Frozen tumor tissues
          or cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> were utilized for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          isolation by standard methods. Histologically, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> of
          these tumors were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SGCTs</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSGCTs</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> mixed or
          combined tumors. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> lines derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCT</ENAMEX> have
          been previously described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolated
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> normal testes were used as controls.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methylation Specific PCR</ENAMEX> (MSP)
          Genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was treated with sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bisulphite</ENAMEX> as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Placental DNA</ENAMEX> treated in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitro</ENAMEX> with 
          Sss I methyltransferase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England Biolabs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>) and similarly treated
          normal lymphocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> were used as controls for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methylated</ENAMEX> and unmethylated templates, respectively. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> used for methylated and unmethylated-specific PCR
          for genes 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB</ENAMEX> , 
          TIMP3 , 
          CDKN2A , 
          p14 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARF</ENAMEX> , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPK</ENAMEX> , 
          CDH1 , 
          GSTP1 , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1A</ENAMEX>, 
          RB1 , 
          MLH1 , 
          TP73 , 
          BRCA1 , 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHIT</ENAMEX> , and 
          HIC1 have been described previously
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://pathology2.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jhu</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">edu/pancreas/prim0425.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm#MSP</ENAMEX>; [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36 37</NUMEX> ] . For additional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, we designed the
          following gene-specific primers for methylated (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MF</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MR</ENAMEX>) and unmethylated (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UR</ENAMEX>) sequences according to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herman et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] :
          
          BTG1 -MF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GTCGTTCGTTTTTTACGTTTTT-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          BTG1 -MR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CGACCCGAATATAAAAAAAATAC-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          BTG1 -UF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GTTGTTTGTTTTTTATGTTTTTTTT-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          BTG1 -UR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAACCCAAATATAAAAAAAATACA-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NEDD1 -MF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGATATTTTTTAGTTTAGCGCG-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NEDD1 -MR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CGACCCCCTATTATATTACTACG-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NEDD1 -UF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TGGATATTTTTTAGTTTAGTGTG-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NEDD1 -UR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAACCCCCTATTATATTACTACA-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          APAF1 -MF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GCGCGTTCGTTTATGTAAATA-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          APAF1 -MR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CAAACCGACGAAACCCGAA-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          APAF1 -UF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGTGTGTGTTTGTTTATGTAAATA-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          APAF1 -UR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CACAAACCAACAAAACCCAAA-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NME1 -MF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GTTTCGTGCGTGTAAGTGTTG-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NME1 -MR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCACCGACAAAAACGAATCCA-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NME1 -UF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GTTTTGTGTGTGTAAGTGTTGT-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NME1 -UR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCACCAACAAAAACAAATCCAC-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NME2 -MF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTTTCGGTCGCGTCGGGTC-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NME2 -MR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GCGCGAAACCTACGAAAAATC-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NME2 -UF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GTTTTTTGGTTGTGTTGGGTTG-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          NME2 -UR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CACACAAAACCTACAAAAAATCA-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          RASSF1A -MF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ACGCGTTGCGTATCGCGCG-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          RASSF1A -MR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCGCGACGACTACGCTACC-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          RASSF1A -UF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ATGTGTTGTGTATTGTGTGGGG-3</ENAMEX>'
          
          RASSF1A -UR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCACAACAACTACACTACCCC-3</ENAMEX>'
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were run on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> agarose gels and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visualized</ENAMEX> after ethidium bromide staining. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purified</ENAMEX> MSP
          products were sequenced in representative specimens by
          direct sequencing to confirm the methylation scored on
          agarose gels.
        
        
          Semi-quantitative analysis of mRNA
          expression
          To assess gene expression, total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolated from
          normal testes, the cell lines, and tumor tissues, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polyA</ENAMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> of testis obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clontech</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>,
          CA) was reverse transcribed using random primers and the
          Pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STAR</ENAMEX> first strand RT-PCR kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stratagene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Jolla</ENAMEX>,
          CA). A semi-quantitative analysis of gene expression was
          performed using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 to 28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of multiplex RT-PCR with
          β-actin ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACTB</ENAMEX> ) as control and gene specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">primers</ENAMEX> spanning <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">at least 2 exons</NUMEX>, except in 
          RASSF1A . For the latter, we used
          single PCR with primers and conditions as previously
          described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . The gene primers used and their
          positions in respective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cDNAs</ENAMEX> were:
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MGMT -F 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GCACGAAATAAAGCTCCTGG-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">124-143 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT -R 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AGGGCTGCTAATTGCTGGTA-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">380-399 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MLH1 -F 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CTGGACGAGACAGTGGTGAA-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">52-71 bp</TIMEX>)
          
          MLH1 -<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CTCACCTCGAAAGCCATAGG-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">308-327 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APC -F 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AAGCCGGGAAGGATCTGTAT-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">329-348 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC -R 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TCCAATTGCCTTCTGGTCAT-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">588-607 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RARB -F 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AATTCAGTGAACTGGCCACC-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">770-789 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARB -R 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGCAAAGGTGAACACAAGGT-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1010-1029 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CDH1 -F 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CTCGACACCCGATTCAAAGT-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">335-354 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          CDH1 -<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TGGGCCTTTTTCATTTTCTG-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">615-634 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TIMP3 -F 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CTTCCGAGAGTCTCTGTGGC-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1440-1450 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          TIMP3 -<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGCGTAGTGTTTGGACTGGT-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1713-1732 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BRCA1 -F 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TCAGCTTGACACAGGTTTGG-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">676-695 bp</ENAMEX>)
          
          BRCA1 -<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R 5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGTTGTATCCGCTGCTTTGT-3</ENAMEX>'
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">896-915 bp</ENAMEX>)
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were run on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX> agarose gels,
          visualized by ethidium bromide staining and quantitated
          using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak Digital Image Analysis System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haven</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CT</ENAMEX>). A tumor was considered to have lost
          expression when the gene showed complete lack of
          expression or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 50%</NUMEX> reduction from the normalized
          values obtained from the average calculated utilizing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          to 4 normal testes. The effect of methylation on gene
          expression was similarly assessed on total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolated
          from cell lines treated with the demethylating agent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-Aza-2</ENAMEX>' deoxycytidine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> at a
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-5 μM.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Analysis of mutations
          Single strand conformational polymorphism (SSCP)
          analysis was performed on all coding exons using primers
          flanking intronic sequences of the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGMT</ENAMEX> gene by standard methods.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author 1</ENAMEX> (SK) carried out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSP</ENAMEX> and gene expression
        analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author 2</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">JH</ENAMEX>) coordinated the selection of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tumors</ENAMEX>, and isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genomic DNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author 3</ENAMEX> (MM)
        participated in the analysis of gene expression. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Authors 4</ENAMEX>
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JMM</ENAMEX>) have collected the clinical information.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author 6</ENAMEX> (VER) participated in histologic diagnosis. Author
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> (GJB) was responsible for referring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and
        clinical information. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Authors 8</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSKC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VVVSM</ENAMEX>) have
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conceived</ENAMEX> and coordinated the study. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and
        approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
