
  
    
      
        Background
        Lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> is the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> of all cancer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. It is generally classified as small cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carcinoma</ENAMEX> and non-small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell carcinoma</ENAMEX>. Treatment of lung
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> is less than optimal and the mean survival for
        advanced lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than one year</TIMEX>
        regardless what treatment regimen was used [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . A new
        approach other than conventional chemoradiation therapy is
        needed for prolonged survival of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Emerging new
        treatment modalities are generally targeted to specific
        tyrosine kinases of the tumor cells through basically two
        independent approaches [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . One is to use highly
        specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibody</ENAMEX> to target the membrane
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX> of growth factors important for tumor cell
        growth, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody/antigen</ENAMEX> complex evokes host immune
        system to kill the tumor cells. This approach is
        exemplified by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Her2</TIMEX>/neu <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herceptin</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> approach is to develop
        small organic molecules targeting the specific tyrosine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinases</ENAMEX> in the signaling pathway in the tumor cells that
        can easily gain access into the tumor cells. This approach
        is best exemplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> and BCR-ABL fusion kinase in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chronic myelogenous leukemia</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> (also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STI571</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imatinib</ENAMEX> from Novartis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmaceutical Inc.</ENAMEX>), a recently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> approved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">chronic myelogenous leukemia</ENAMEX>, is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> analogue, and it
        competitively binds to and inhibits BCR-ABL tyrosine
        kinase, resulted from the chromosomal translocation t(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>;
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> has been shown to induce clinical,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hematological</ENAMEX> and molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remissions</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
        ] . It cross-reacts with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other important growth factor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tyrosine</ENAMEX> kinase domains, c-kit and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF receptors</ENAMEX>, that play important roles in growth and
        proliferation of a variety of cell types [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . C-kit
        (also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD117</ENAMEX>) is frequently mutated in
        gastrointestinal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stromal tumor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIST</ENAMEX>), and the mutated
        c-kit shows higher tyrosine kinase activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> has
        been demonstrated to inhibit the growth and proliferation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIST</ENAMEX>, and induce complete or partial clinical remission
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GIST</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] . Recently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> was showed to
        inhibit the growth of dermatofibrosarcma protuberans (DFSP)
        through inhibiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF</ENAMEX> receptor [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] .
        As a part of effort to evaluate the newly emerging drugs
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX>, we studied the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> on
        non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. We previously showed that
        non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> express minimal (negligible)
        level of c-kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.</ENAMEX>, unpublished). Therefore it is
        unlikely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> exerts the effect, if any, through
        c-kit on non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. We reported here a
        study of inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> on lung cancer cells
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells) in vitro. We showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> alone can
        inhibit the growth and proliferation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells at the
        known therapeutic concentration for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML</ENAMEX>. Addition of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells with cisplatin induced cell death
        synergistically, suggesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> can potentiate the
        cisplatin effect on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells. We have demonstrated that
        A549 cells express PDGFR α, one of the known potential
        targets for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> effect. The inhibitory effect of
        Gleevec on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> is likely mediated through
        inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF receptor α phosphorylation</ENAMEX>. We further
        tested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' tumor specimens, and showed
        that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer tumor specimens</ENAMEX> expressed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR-α.</ENAMEX> These results provided important in vitro data to
        support the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> can inhibit the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cell
        growth and proliferation, and may potentially offer a
        treatment option for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX> either alone or in
        conjunction with chemotherapy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cisplatin</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gleevec</ENAMEX> inhibited the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cell growth in a
          dose-dependent manner
          We first test to see if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> can inhibit the growth
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">A549 cells</ENAMEX> under the culture conditions. We have
          chosen to perform the experiments under the normal
          culture condition since we reasoned that the effect of
          Gleevec on tumor cells, if any, should be under the
          normal, not serum free condition. Therefore, we chose to
          add the drug directly into the culture medium containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> fetal calf serum. A549 lung cancer cells were plated
          at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> densities into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">96</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well plates</ENAMEX>, and
          Gleevec was added to the culture medium. We used the MTT
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assays</ENAMEX> to assess the viability of the tumor cells treated
          with or without the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. It was evident that increasing
          concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> in the culture medium inhibited
          the growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">A549 cells</ENAMEX> in a dose dependent manner. The
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> to inhibit <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> cell growth
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IC50</NUMEX>) was estimated to be around <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-3 μM</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>),
          whereas the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IC50</NUMEX> of cisplatin on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">A549</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> was estimated
          to be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">64-70 μM</NUMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). We have also seen that Gleevec
          can inhibit the growth of human 293 kidney cells, but at
          slightly higher concentration (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 μM</ENAMEX>). The IC50
          concentration for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">A549 cells</ENAMEX> didn't appear to have
          inhibitory effects on human <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). These
          results showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> alone can indeed inhibit the
          growth of A549 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung</ENAMEX> carcinoma cells. The inhibitory
          effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> appeared to be in a
          therapeutic range of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> as demonstrated in chronic
          myelogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX> cells from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Gleevec potentiated the cell-killing effect of
          cisplatin
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the major reasons of testing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gleevec</ENAMEX> for
          treatment of non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carcinoma</ENAMEX> is to see if
          the specific tyrosine kinase inhibitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gleevec</ENAMEX>, and other
          potential small molecules currently on clinical trials,
          can be used as an adjuvant therapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in
          combination with conventional chemotherapy. We sought to
          see if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> can potentiate the cell killing effects of
          cisplatin, the leading chemotherapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> for almost
          all advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. We used the IC50
          concentrations for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> and cisplatin to treat
          A549 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in culture, and assessed the viability of the
          cells by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assays at the different time points (Figure
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 μM</ENAMEX>) and cisplatin (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">64 μM</NUMEX>) both inhibited
          the growth of the tumor cells individually after
          treatment of the cells for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hour</TIMEX>. Combination of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> and cisplatin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">synergistically</ENAMEX> inhibited the
          growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">A549 cells</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). This synergistic effect
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> and cisplatin on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A549</TIMEX> lung cancer cells were
          not seen for human 293 kidney cells (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>-α in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the A549</TIMEX> lung cancer
          cells
          Since the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> is mediated through
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibiting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BCR-ABL</ENAMEX> tyrosine kinase, c-kit, and PDGF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX>, we are interested in the potential target for
          Gleevec effect in the lung cancer cells. We have
          previously showed by immunohistochemical staining that in
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX> primary non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carcinoma specimens</ENAMEX>,
          expression of c-kit was weak and minimal, if any (Tang
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhang</ENAMEX>, unpublished observation). We sought to
          determine the expression levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF receptors α</ENAMEX> and β
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells and the primary non-small cell lung
          carcinoma by immunofluorescent and immunohistochemical
          staining methods. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells, expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>-α,
          not PDGFR-β, was detected with strong cytoplasmic and
          membrane staining patterns (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6and 7</NUMEX>). There was no
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">demonstrable</ENAMEX> nuclear staining signal. We further detected
          the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>-α in the whole cell lysates of A549
          cells by Western blotting analysis (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>). A549 cells
          were cultured under the condition described, and the
          cells were lysed and the whole cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were
          separated on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were transferred
          onto nitrocellulose membrane, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>-α was
          detected with anti-PDGFR-α <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnologies Inc.</ENAMEX>). Treatment of the cells with
          Gleevec at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> concentrations did not influence the
          expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>-α expression in the cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>-β
          was not detected in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells using both
          immunofluorescent staining and Western blot analyses
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> not shown).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microarrays</ENAMEX> and immunohistochemical staining
          Existing data suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> can exert its
          inhibitory effect on tumor cells through inhibiting PDGF
          receptor function, and we have shown that the primary
          non-small cells lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> expressed minimal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">c-Kit</ENAMEX>. We
          would like to see if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF</ENAMEX> receptor expression in lung
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> is frequent finding, and this could
          potentially provide a cellular mechanism by which Gleevec
          inhibits the lung cancer tumor growth. We used the tumor
          tissue micro-array technique using the high-density lung
          tissue arrays from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinomic Biosciences Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>. Lung
          tissue micro-array slides containing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> primary lung
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer tumor</ENAMEX> specimens with the corresponding normal lung
          tissues were used for immunohistochemical staining using
          anti-PDGFR-α and β <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> as described. The clinical
          diagnoses of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> were reviewed and confirmed.
          Using clinical diagnostic criteria, the immunostaining
          patterns and intensities were verified by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> independent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> certified surgical pathologists. Since
          immunohistochemical staining is a semi-quantitative
          method, we scored the staining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intensities</ENAMEX> arbitrarily as
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>+, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>+ (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>). There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> cases of squamous
          carcinomas of the lung within the tissue array slide, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> cases were positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR-α</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89%</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> cases were scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>+ (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cases <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
          cases <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>+ positivity (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> of the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> adenocarcinoma specimens that were positive for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PDGFR-α</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>) [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> cases <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>+ (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> cases <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          cases <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>+ (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX>) respectively]. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell carcinomas</ENAMEX> were
          also positive expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>-α [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> cases <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>)].
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> cases of malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mesotheliomas</ENAMEX> were negative for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR-α.</ENAMEX> The corresponding normal lung tissues were found
          to be negative for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR-α.</ENAMEX> Although there were some
          interstitial staining signals for PDGFR-β, the tumor
          tissues were negative for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR-β</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, micro-array
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> not shown). These results demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>-α
          expression is elevated in the tumor tissues compared to
          normal lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">parenchyma</ENAMEX>, and the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX>-α in
          tumor tissue may play important roles in tumor growth and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progression</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
          Gleevec effects vs drug toxicity
          We have shown in this study that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> alone can
          inhibit the growth of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells at the concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-3 μM</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IC50</NUMEX>). This is within the known therapeutic
          ranges for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML</ENAMEX>, since the plasma levels of
          Gleevec inducing hematologic and cytogenetic response in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML</ENAMEX> were reported to be in the range of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX> μg/ml (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.17</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.68</NUMEX> μM) after treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>-600
          mg /day [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . In our system, the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> at
          the tested concentration was in the low micromolar
          ranges, and the inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> on A549
          cells is likely to be genuine through binding to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, not due to the toxic effects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. This
          inhibitory effect can also be seen with the human kidney
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells with slight higher <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IC50</TIMEX>. At the concentration
          of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 μM</NUMEX> or higher, the inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> on
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">A549</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells were found to be identical
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2and 3</NUMEX>). Higher concentration than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 μM</NUMEX> in the
          cell culture condition is unlikely to be translated to
          clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, since the adverse effects of the drug
          will become intolerable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> in lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>
          Gleevec was designed to inhibit the BCR-ABL tyrosine
          kinase, and it cross-reacts with c-kit and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] .
          In non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, BCR-ABL expression has
          never been reported, and it is unlikely that BCR-ABL
          fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> plays any role in lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. There has
          been no report to link cellular ABL kinase mutation to
          any <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> except <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCR-ABL</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CML</ENAMEX>, although the
          detailed c-Abl function has not been extensively studied
          in lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAbl</ENAMEX> is a tyrosine kinase that
          plays important roles in cell growth, differentiation and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX>. Although c-Abl mutations have not been
          reported in human <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, c-Abl related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARG</ENAMEX> (or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Abl-2</ENAMEX>), was shown to be regulated in non-small cell lung
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> by hypermethylation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Reynolds</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institute of Occupational and Safety Health</ENAMEX>,
          Morgantown, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX>, personal communication). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARG</ENAMEX> shares
          significant homology with c-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abl</ENAMEX> throughout the amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> has been shown to inhibit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARG</ENAMEX> tyrosine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Wang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California San Diego</ENAMEX>, personal communication), although
          the functional significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARG</ENAMEX> kinase in lung cancer
          is yet to be elucidated.
          We have studied the expression of c-kit (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CD117</NUMEX>) in the
          non-small cell lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and we found that
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 13%</NUMEX> of the tumor specimens were weakly
          positive for c-kit. The level of expression is generally
          weak (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>+). These results lead us to find an alternative
          target for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX>, because of the low expression level
          and low frequency of expression of c-kit in the lung
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          PDGFR expression in lung cancer
          We have shown convincingly that lung cancer cell A549
          expressed PDGFR-α both by immunostaining the cells and by
          Western blot analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF receptors</ENAMEX> are widely
          expressed in a variety of tissues, and the levels of
          expression in normal tissues are minimal. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Over</NUMEX>-expression
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX> has been reported in a variety of human tumors
          including glioma and glioblastoma, pancreatic and colonic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX>, bone and ovarian tumors [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . In
          normal cells, expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX> can be seen in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> and the smooth muscle cells in the lung and
          airway [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . There is so far to our knowledge no
          report to link the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX> to lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
          Since it has been reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> can inhibit the
          function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR</ENAMEX> under the cell culture conditions, it
          is likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> exerts its inhibitory effects on
          A549 lung cancer cells through inhibiting the PDGFR
          function.
        
        
          Synergistic effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> and cisplatin on A549
          cells
          We have shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> can exert its effect
          synergistically with cisplatin. Cisplatin causes two
          types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> damage, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA adducts</ENAMEX> and inter-stranded
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-linking, resulting in activation of apoptosis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> in the target tumor cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] . Our results
          suggest that inhibition of tyrosine kinase activity of
          the potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gleevec</ENAMEX> appear to potentiate the
          effect of cisplatin in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-damage induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in
          A549 cells. Although the underlying mechanism of such
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synergism</ENAMEX> is unclear, it is of great interest to combine
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in clinical lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to see if
          the synergy of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> exists under the
          physiological conditions. It has been widely thought, but
          never been proven that the specific tyrosine kinase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> can be used as adjuvant
          therapy in combination with conventional chemotherapy,
          because the limited clinical trial data suggests only a
          marginal benefits using this kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> to treat the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> alone (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WVU Cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECOG</ENAMEX> trial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, personal communication). Current study results
          suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> can potentiate the cisplatin effect
          on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A549</TIMEX> lung cancer cells, and these findings provide
          important in vitro data for further testing the
          possibility of using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> as adjuvant therapy for
          clinical lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Methods
        
          Cell culture and drug testing
          Lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cell line <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells were cultured in DMEM
          with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> fetal calf serum as described. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> are
          seeded in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plate at the cell density of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-4 × 10</ENAMEX>
          4per well as indicated, and the tumor cells were cultured
          in the medium containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serum</ENAMEX>. Cisplatin was purchased
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemicals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>), and dissolved in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> at the concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> mM. The Gleevec
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novartis Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) was purchased from
          the outpatient pharmacy at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> and
          dissolved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> at the concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM. The
          experimental procedure for the cisplatin and Gleevec
          treatment was the following: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> and human 293
          cells were plated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">96</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> plates at the cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">density</ENAMEX> indicated and the cells were allowed to attach
          overnight. The attached cells in the plates were washed
          once with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and replaced with fresh medium containing
          various concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> indicated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assays
          were performed after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> of continuous incubation
          with medium containing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The values shown in the
          figures are mean readings from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> in each
          experiments and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> independent
          experiments.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assays
          We have performed a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assays to determine
          the effects of the anti-tumor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STI571</ENAMEX> on the number
          of A540 lung cancer cells and human 293 kidney cells. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> is based upon the cleavage of the yellow
          tetrazolium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> MTT
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bromide</ENAMEX>] to purple formazan crystals by metabolically
          active cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . The tested concentration of Gleevec
          ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 to 8 μM</NUMEX>. The tumor cells were seeded into
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well culture plate, and maintained for culture for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> before the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> compound was added to the medium.
          The cultured cells were incubated in a medium containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> serum and treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX>. After
          treatment, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 μl</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> labeling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reagent</ENAMEX> were added to
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> and plates were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 h.</TIMEX>
          Following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> incubation, the cultures were solublized
          and the spectrophotometric absorbance of the samples was
          detected by using a microtiter plate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wavelength</ENAMEX> to measure absorbance of formazan product is
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">570</NUMEX> nm, with a reference wavelength of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> nm.
        
        
          Immunofluorescent staining of the cultured
          cells
          The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells were cultured as described on the
          coverslips, and fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.7%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> at room temperature. The fixed cells were
          permeablized with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and directly
          used for immunofluorescent and immunocytochemical
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stainings</ENAMEX>. The primary anti-PDGFR-α <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnologies Inc</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA). The secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> for immunofluorescent
          labeling was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Probe Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>,
          OR).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lung tumor tissue microarrays</ENAMEX> and
          immunohistochemical staining
          The high-density lung cancer tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">microarray</ENAMEX> slides
          were made in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinomics Bisciences Inc. MA</ENAMEX>, and was used
          for immunohistochemical staining for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDGFR-a.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          the tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">microarray</ENAMEX> slides were sectioned at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> micron
          in thickness and heated to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">65°C</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de</ENAMEX>-parafinize the tissues. The slides were washed three
          times in xylene, then dehydrated and rehydrated in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95% and 70%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>. The tissue sections were finally
          washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> once before going through the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>
          retrieval process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen retrieval</ENAMEX> was performed
          using citrate buffer (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bench Mark II</ENAMEX> automated staining device following the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instruction (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ventana Medical Inc. Tucson</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AZ</ENAMEX>). The primary PDGFR-α <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnologies Inc</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA). The tumor section
          slides and the immunostaining patterns were reviewed by
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> independent practicing surgical pathologists, and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> intensities were scored at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>+, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+ and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>+. The
          staining characteristics of all tumors were summarized in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Western blotting
          The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells were maintained in the culture
          condition as described above. Western blotting analyses
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF receptors</ENAMEX> were performed using a previously
          described method [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . Briefly, the tumor cells were
          treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleevec</ENAMEX> at the various concentrations for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. The whole cell extracts were prepared and used for
          Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blot</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PDGF</ENAMEX> receptor α using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIPA</ENAMEX> buffer
          containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SDS</ENAMEX>. The whole cell extracts were separated on
          the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS PAGE</ENAMEX> and transferred onto nitrocellulose
          membrane by electroblotting. The primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> non-fat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> on the
          membrane <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of interest
          was visualized by the enhanced chemiluminescent method
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECL</ENAMEX>). The anti-PDGF <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor α antibody</ENAMEX> was used at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:500</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnologies Inc.</ENAMEX> CA).
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX>'s contributions
        PZ designed, organized the whole study and analyzed all
        the data. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WG</ENAMEX> performed a majority of the experiments in the
        study. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ST</ENAMEX> provided micro-array slides for lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, and
        discussed extensively regarding the design and execution of
        the study. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSD</ENAMEX> reviewed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s tumor specimens. All
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
