
  
    
      
        Background
        This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-paper series. It
        addresses whether there are statistically significant
        clusters of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ]
        examines whether the patterns in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> are spatially
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with patterns in the environment, specifically
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air toxics</ENAMEX>. This set of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> studies were prompted by
        ongoing concern over <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> patterns on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizens</ENAMEX> and public health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are concerned about two
        things - whether cancer clusters exist and, if so, what may
        explain the clusters. The possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
        clusters on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> has been in the news and the focus
        of recent research [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> had the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
        thhighest death rate from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-99</TIMEX>, though
        it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> thin colorectal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> thin lung cancer [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ] . While breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates are higher in the
        Northeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> than in other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kulldorff et al.</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] established that the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> metropolitan area has higher breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> mortality rates than the remainder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX>.
        The analysis performed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Department of</ENAMEX>
        Health (which used the average <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX>/population
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> as a whole as a reference) located significant
        elevations in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> in particular.
        Even when compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as a whole, the cancer
        rates on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> seem to be elevated. Given the concern
        and the apparent elevation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>,
        we focused our study on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, and Suffolk
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>, the easternmost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>
          published the cancer incidence data online as part of
          their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer Surveillance Improvement Initiative</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX>health.state.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ny.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">us/nysdoh/cancer/csii/nyscsii.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm.</ENAMEX>
          These data represent newly diagnosed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases in the
          period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-7</TIMEX> assigned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagnosis</ENAMEX>, and they are calculated as the number of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> for each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. When
          we began this study (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSDOH</ENAMEX> had
          released data on three <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX> (female only),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">colorectal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> and male), and lung (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> and male)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>. Since then, they released data on prostate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1994-8</TIMEX>, which we did not include in
          this study. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> has not yet been added for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> other
          than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-7</TIMEX> for the three <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> we analyzed.
          To protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> privacy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSDOH</ENAMEX> data provided
          case counts referenced to ZIP codes rather than
          individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>. ZIP codes are regions developed
          for mail delivery by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Postal Service</ENAMEX>. In the study
          area, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in ZIP codes ranges between
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">445</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105,723</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, with a mean of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 23,000</NUMEX>
          (using <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Census</ENAMEX> numbers,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://factfinder.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">census</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>). They are not uniform in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> nor ethnicity nor age. While ZIP codes are
          somewhat arbitrary spatial units of analysis with respect
          to potential health and environmental factors, they
          provided NYSDOH a convenient way to group the population
          to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> confidentiality. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> at a better
          spatial resolution were not made available to us. We
          combined the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosis data with ZIP code boundary
          files, reflecting the geography in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999</TIMEX>. We
          purchased the boundary files from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claritas Corporation</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">claritas</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSDOH</ENAMEX> provides
          information on the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, we focus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">214 ZIP</ENAMEX>
          codes within <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Suffolk County</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> move between ZIP codes and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> latency (the
          time between causative exposures and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> onset) is
          estimated to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 5-40 years</TIMEX> for these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, so
          the ZIP code where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was diagnosed may not be
          the location where the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> developed nor where
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">causative</ENAMEX> exposures occurred. We do not include any
          adjustments for migration or changes in any demographic
          patterns within the study area.
          While the observed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosis data did adjust
          for different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations-at-risk</ENAMEX> in the different ZIP
          codes, we also used <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX>'s adjustment for
          different age patterns as well. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> incidence
          is related to age, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSDOH</ENAMEX> calculated the expected cancer
          incidence for each ZIP code using the ZIP code's age
          structure and the average incidence by age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> for New
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. We calculated a standardized morbidity ratio
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX>) by dividing the observed value by the age-adjusted
          expected incidence. An SMR value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> indicates that
          the observed incidence is the same as expected, lower
          than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> indicates that fewer than expected cases of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> occurred, and greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> indicates that more
          than expected occurred.
        
        
          Local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cluster Analysis</ENAMEX>
          We identified significant clustering and spatial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outliers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anselin</ENAMEX>'s local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> test [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ClusterSeer™</ENAMEX> software
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">terraseer</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/clusterseer.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>. The local
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran test</ENAMEX> evaluates local clustering or spatial
          autocorrelation by evaluating the contribution of each
          location to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX>'s I statistic for the whole study
          area. Its null hypothesis is that there is no association
          between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> values in neighboring ZIP codes (no spatial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autocorrelation</ENAMEX>). The working (alternative) hypothesis is
          that spatial clustering exists. The statistic is:
          
          where I 
          i is the statistic for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ZIP code i</ENAMEX>, z 
          i is the difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> at
          i and the mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>, z 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">j</ENAMEX> is the difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">j</ENAMEX> and the mean for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ij</ENAMEX> is a weight so that the statistic
          only considers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> that share a common border (w 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ij</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/n</TIMEX> if the two ZIP codes are
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> using the rook contiguity relationship, where n
          is the number of rook <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, and w 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ij</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> otherwise). We evaluated
          the test statistic using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monte Carlo P</ENAMEX>-values [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] ,
          obtained from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">99,999</NUMEX> conditional randomizations of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dataset</ENAMEX>. Because it is possible for local clusters to
          overlap because of shared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, we therefore used an
          adjusted significance level (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonferroni</ENAMEX> adjustment) to
          evaluate P-values (α' = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01101</NUMEX>).
          The local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> test as we used it evaluates ratio
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, in this case the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX>. It does not, however,
          consider whether that ratio is based on many or few
          cases. A ratio based on few observed or expected cases
          (small ZIP code <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>) is more unstable than one
          based on more cases. To evaluate the stability of the SMR
          for significant clusters, we calculated its confidence
          interval [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . The confidence intervals increase as the
          observed number of cases decreases. Confidence intervals
          that overlap <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> indicate no statistically significant
          difference from the expected ratio.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorectal Cancer-Local Cluster Analysis</ENAMEX>
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Females</ENAMEX>
            The local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> test identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> local clusters
            with SMRs <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 45-50%</NUMEX> higher than the New York
            average, centered on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayport</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ZIP 11705</ENAMEX>) and
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11968</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Wainscott
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11937</ENAMEX>) is a significant spatial outlier with an SMR
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s average. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wainscott</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX>,
            however, has wide confidence intervals due to the small
            number of observed cases there. Thus, while
            statistically distinct from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, it does not
            have significantly reduced risk.
          
          
            Males
            For <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">colorectal cancer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>, the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> test
            identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> local clusters with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> values over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>
            higher than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> average (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
            These clusters share some ZIP codes in common; they
            form <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> large rather than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> small clusters. The
            western cluster is comprised of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> significant local
            clusters centered on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11967</ENAMEX>) and Mastic
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11950</ENAMEX>). The eastern cluster has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> significant
            local clusters centered on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11968</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11976</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sagaponak</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11963</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wading River</ENAMEX>
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11792</ENAMEX>) is a significant spatial outlier with an SMR
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 70%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state average. While Wading
            River is a significant outlier under the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX>
            test, its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> has a wide confidence interval due to the
            small number of observed cases there. Thus, while
            statistically distinct from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, it does not
            have significantly reduced risk.
          
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breast Cancer - Local Cluster Analysis</ENAMEX>
          We identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> local clusters with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70-83%</NUMEX> of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> average. These significant local clusters of
          low cancer overlap to form <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> larger cluster, centered
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Floral Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ZIP 11103</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodside</ENAMEX> in Flushing
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11137</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>, Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The local <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran test</ENAMEX> also
          detected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> local clusters with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30-50%</NUMEX> higher than
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> average. These significant local clusters
          also overlap and are centered on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southampton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11968</ENAMEX>) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wainscott</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11937</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelter Island</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11964</ENAMEX>) is a
          significant spatial outlier, though its confidence
          intervals are wide (and overlap <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) due to the small
          number of observed cases there. Thus, while statistically
          distinct from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, it does not have
          significantly reduced risk.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lung Cancer - Local Cluster Analysis</ENAMEX>
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Females</ENAMEX>
            The local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> test identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> clusters with
            SMR <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 70%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> average (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> local clusters are contiguous, share
            ZIP codes, and together comprise a single, large
            cluster extending through portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flushing</ENAMEX> in the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">north</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> in the south. This cluster is
            centered on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flushing</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ZIPs 11368 and 11367</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Albans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11412</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sayville</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11782</ENAMEX>) is a
            significant spatial outlier with low SMR (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72%</NUMEX> of the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> average), though its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> has a wide confidence
            interval resulting from the small number of observed
            cases there. Thus, while statistically distinct from
            its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, it does not have significantly reduced
            risk.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> local clusters of high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> values occurred in
            the more central portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>,
            Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). There is a cluster in north-mid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island,</ENAMEX>
            made up of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> significant local clusters centered on
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayville</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11709</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mill Neck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11765</ENAMEX>). This cluster
            has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 60-70%</NUMEX> higher SMR than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state
            average. A large cluster in south central <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>
            is composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> local clusters centered on
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ronkonkama</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11779</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Islip</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11722</ENAMEX>), Islip
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11752</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Islip</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11730</ENAMEX>). This cluster
            has an SMR <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40%</NUMEX> higher than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state
            average. Further east is a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> cluster of high female
            lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> incidence centered on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mastic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11950</ENAMEX>) and
            including several adjacent ZIP codes. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> is about
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> higher than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state average.
          
          
            Males
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> local clusters of low <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> values were
            identified, centering on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Neck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ZIP 11024</ENAMEX>), Roslyn
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11576</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntington</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11743</ENAMEX>), all in the northwest
            portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>). These
            clusters are typified by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX> SMR values that
            are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50-75%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State</ENAMEX> average. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
            clusters centered on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11024 and 11576</NUMEX> are adjacent to
            one another forming a single, large cluster of low lung
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> SMR for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far Rockaway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11694</ENAMEX>)
            and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moriches</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11955</ENAMEX>) are significant spatial outliers
            with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88% and 84%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> SMR respectively,
            though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> confidence intervals are wide because
            the number of observed cases is small in each location.
            Thus, while statistically distinct from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>,
            it does not have significantly reduced risk.
            A large cluster of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> SMR <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20-60%</NUMEX> higher
            than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> average was identified in central
            Long <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>. This larger cluster is composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
            significant local clusters, centered on Farmingville
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11738</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coram</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11727</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> Place (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11764</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11953</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mastic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11950</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mastic Beach</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11951</ENAMEX>),
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11967</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medford</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11763</ENAMEX>), and Sayville
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">11782</ENAMEX>).
          
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
          Comparison to Prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Studies</ENAMEX>
          
            Qualitative differences in clusters
            Some differences are immediately apparent when one
            compares, for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, the scan statistic
            clusters
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX>health.state.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ny.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">us/nysdoh/cancer/csii/nyscsii.</ENAMEX>htmto
            the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> clusters (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Under the scan
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">statistic</ENAMEX>, all of eastern and most of western Suffolk
            are declared a cluster, as are substantial portions of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nassau</ENAMEX>, and the western portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>. In
            contrast, the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> statistic finds significant
            clustering only in the southern fork towards <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Montauk</ENAMEX>,
            and identifies a significant clustering of low breast
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer morbidity</ENAMEX> on western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>. Boundaries in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer morbidity</ENAMEX> occur throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>,
            and identify adjacent ZIP codes that differ
            substantially in cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Hence the
            local <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> and boundary approaches identify clusters
            on a finer spatial scale, while the scan approach is
            identifying larger clusters.
            In addition, the scan statistic clusters include
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of ZIP codes that, in fact, have cancer
            morbidity 
            below the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State</ENAMEX> average.
            For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Fork</ENAMEX> is deemed part of a
            significant cluster of elevated incidence, even though
            the contiguous ZIP codes 11971 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.9058</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11944</NUMEX>
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMR</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.8602</NUMEX>) are below the expected value. Why might
            this be? First, the scan statistic evaluates geographic
            relationships using centroids and a circular scan
            window. Hence relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">geographies</ENAMEX>, such as Peconic
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bay</ENAMEX>, are not taken into account. In effect, the cancer
            morbidities on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Fork</ENAMEX> are lumped with the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> morbidities on the south fork. The local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX>
            approach, by evaluating geographic relationships using
            common borders, doesn't connect ZIP codes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
            Fork to ZIP codes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Fork</ENAMEX>. It is indeed a
            "local" statistic (hence its name) and is sensitive
            only to local clusters of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer morbidity</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the
            scale of the study is different for the scan statistic
            and for the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> and boundary analyses. The NYS
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX> applied the scan method to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> as a whole, while the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> and boundary
            analyses used only the ZIP codes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>. Each
            of these techniques employs randomization methods to
            evaluate statistical significance, and the results
            therefore may vary when one includes more areas in the
            analysis.
            To summarize, the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> clusters and the
            boundaries in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> incidence quantify spatial
            pattern on a finer spatial scale than scan statistic
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clusters</ENAMEX>. This arises because the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> and
            boundary analysis techniques use ZIP code zone
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjacency</ENAMEX> (sharing of a common border) rather than
            distance between centroids to evaluate geographic
            relationships, and because the scale of the study
            differs.
          
          
            The scale of the process
            This general result - the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> results and
            the boundary analysis results identify finer scale
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variation</ENAMEX>, while the scan approach picks up larger
            scale clusters - holds for all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> considered and
            is to be expected given the differences in the methods.
            An understanding of how results vary as a function of
            the scale of the study and as a function of the spatial
            sensitivity of the method is important for us to
            evaluate geographic variation in cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX>. We
            should expect potential exposures as well as cancer
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">correlates</ENAMEX> and covariates to have local- as well as
            large-scale components. At the local scale
            neighborhoods can change dramatically from one location
            to another, and many putative exposures involve point
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> that have local impacts (for example, fuel
            leaks from underground storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> are often limited
            to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few hundred cubic yards</NUMEX> of contaminated soil). But
            we also know that wind-borne <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> can impact much
            larger areas, as can agricultural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> and
            contaminants carried in ground <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Hence the
            techniques we employ should be sensitive to multi-scale
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographic</ENAMEX> heterogeneity, and thus able to identify the
            fine local scale variation that may be underlying
            exposures and/or genetic differences at the local
            level, as well as regional and sub-regional
            patterns.
          
          
            The scale of the study
            While both the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> and scan statistics
            assess statistical significance of a cluster relative
            to the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as a whole, we
            consider only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long Island ZIP</ENAMEX> codes in the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX>
            analysis, while the NYS scan analysis considers ZIP
            codes for all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Both statistics (local
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> and scan) use randomization techniques that
            "sprinkle" morbidity values over the study area in
            order to construct reference distributions under the
            null hypothesis. Thus the null hypothesis for the local
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> analysis is no spatial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>
            incidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX>, whereas the null hypothesis
            for the scan statistic is no spatial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> incidence in all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX>. Our
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">randomization</ENAMEX> approach "resampled" the data under the
            null hypothesis that a cancer incidence observed in a
            Long <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Island ZIP</ENAMEX> code is equally likely to occur in any
            other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> ZIP code. This means cancer risk on
            was assumed to be equal across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>. By
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">randomizing</ENAMEX> across all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX>, the NYSDOH
            study assumed cancer risk to be equal across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
            State and that, for example, risk on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> is the
            same as risk in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adirondacks</ENAMEX>. According to the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSDOH</ENAMEX> study, much of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> is included in
            clusters defined by higher incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>,
            male and female colorectal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and female lung
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
            This illustrates the spatial scale of the study is
            closely related to the question(s) being addressed. For
            the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moran</ENAMEX> analysis, we are asking questions
            specific to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>, against a null hypothesis that
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk is uniform across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>.
            In their analysis using the scan statistic, the NYSDOH
            is addressing questions regarding cancer incidence in
            all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX>, against the implicit assumption
            that risk is uniform across the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. However,
            the standardized morbidity ratio (SMR) is the ratio of
            the diagnoses in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> ZIP codes divided by the
            expected value calculated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State</ENAMEX> averages.
            Thus, it is still meaningful to compare our results to
            the state-level scan results. We identified clusters on
            Long <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX> that are exceptional compared to the state
            averages that went into the expected value
            calculation.
          
          
            The evaluation of geographic relationships
            The techniques employed by the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> and
            boundary techniques evaluate geographic relationships
            using the ZIP code and census geography of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>.
            In contrast, the scan technique, employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
            State, uses ZIP code centroids and circles drawn around
            those centroids to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX>'s geography.
            Because of its long and forked appearance, the
            geography of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> is poorly represented by
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centroids</ENAMEX> and circles. How geographic relationships are
            evaluated is intimately linked to the description of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographic</ENAMEX> variation patterns and to cluster
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">detection</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meaning of Geographic Variation</ENAMEX>
            The term "clustering" by and of itself is so generic
            as to be almost meaningless for describing spatial
            variation in cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX>. First, the differences
            between cluster detection methods already used to
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">analyze Long Island</ENAMEX> data illustrate the notion of a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cluster</ENAMEX> is meaningless without a precise description of
            the statistical test and its expectations. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>,
            an analysis approach that employs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> kind of
            cluster test is inappropriate. Obviously, a given
            technique will only detect the kinds of clusters it was
            designed to detect. In fact, experience has
            demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer morbidity</ENAMEX> evinces rich
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographic</ENAMEX> variation, and we therefore should employ a
            variety of techniques to more fully describe relevant
            aspects of spatial pattern.
          
          
            All Methods are Subjective
            Because they are founded on assumptions and are more
            or less sensitive to different aspects of spatial
            pattern, all techniques for statistical pattern
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> are subjective, because they are founded on
            assumptions and are more or less sensitive to different
            aspects of spatial pattern. The spatial scan is based
            on a likelihood statistic, it uses centroids of areas
            to define spatial relationships, employs circular scan
            <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, and is univariate. Clearly, "clusters" can be
            multivariate, and not just univariate; they can be
            other shapes than circular; there are techniques other
            than centroids for evaluating spatial relationships;
            and likelihood is just one of several statistical
            approaches for identifying departures from a background
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX>. The point is not that the scan statistic is
            somehow flawed - in fact, it is one of the most
            powerful statistical techniques for identifying
            univariate clusters with the above-defined
            characteristics. Rather, the point is that there are
            many different aspects to spatial pattern. In order to
            explore these different aspects, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> need to
            employ a variety of methods to more fully elucidate,
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">characterize</ENAMEX>, and quantify the geography of cancer
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX>. The scan statistic is but one tool we can
            bring to bear on the study of geographic variation in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer morbidity</ENAMEX>.
          
        
      
      
        Conclusion
        This is a methodological and comparative study to
        evaluate whether there is substantial benefit added by
        using a variety of techniques for geographic pattern
        detection at different spatial scales.
        This paper demonstrates that there is significant
        spatial pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, and Suffolk
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. The general pattern that
        there are clusters of higher than expected cancer incidence
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> is consistent with other studies of the same
        area, though the exact locations and shapes of the clusters
        vary with the methods used by different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>.
        Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> have observed that neither p-values nor
        confidence limits provide enough information to assess
        whether or not there is a true disease cluster caused by an
        environmental exposure. We <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> that the best approach
        would be to analyze the data using several cluster
        detection techniques, and if the area still sticks out like
        a sore thumb, there may be something there. As different
        tests identify different aspects of cluster morphology, the
        best characterization comes from an understanding of
        cluster shape, size, length, magnitude of excess,
        probability of occurrence, location of boundaries or
        gradients, relative locations of clusters and boundaries to
        each other, and finally correspondence of geographic
        patterns in health outcomes to potential exposures.
        The differences in our results and that of the NYSDOH
        underscore the need for an exploratory, integrative, and
        multi-scalar approach to assessing geographic patterns of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, as different methods identify different patterns.
        A concordance of the results from several different
        approaches increases the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>'s confidence that the
        suspected cluster indeed is unusual. By using several
        different methods - scan statistic, boundary analysis,
        local <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> is able to derive a more complete
        understanding of geographic variation in cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX>
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>. One benefit is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> can now
        focus etiologic investigations at the finer spatial scales
        where local excesses in cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> are found on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>. Specifically, using a battery of approaches allows
        us to quantify different aspects of clusters; to explore
        different scales of clustering, and to evaluate how
        sensitive the results are to different definitions of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clustering</ENAMEX>.
        We recommend that future studies of geographic patterns
        use a concordance of evidence from a multiscalar
        integrative geographic approach to assure that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) different
        aspects of spatial pattern are fully identified and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the
        results from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> of analyses are logically
        consistent.
        The obvious question after finding significant clusters
        of elevated and lower cancer incidence is - why? Could this
        pattern be explained by environmental exposures, by
        differences in social factors, such as socio-economic
        status or ethnicity, or another factor that varies over
        this study region? We cannot exclude any particular
        explanation, as this study did not consider any economic,
        ethnic, or environmental exposure data. We do, however,
        consider <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> possible factor in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> in this
        set, airborne carcinogens [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . But, as this is a study
        of encountered data, and data that are aggregated to a
        coarse spatial scale, it would be impossible to establish
        causation from these data on their own.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authors GMJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAG</ENAMEX> collaborated intensely on all
        aspects of the manuscript, from research design to data
        preparation to presentation. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> wrote and
        approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
