
  
    
      
        Background
        The majority of studies of indoor environmental quality
        and health outcomes focus primarily on the office
        environment and sick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> syndrome symptoms or rare
        illnesses such as hypersensitivity pneumonitis. Very few
        studies have attempted to determine the effects of
        ventilation on short-term sick leave absences caused by
        respiratory infections.
        Several studies have, however, made links between
        ventilation and respiratory illness [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4</NUMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of
        these studies were conducted in military settings. In a
        study at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brundage</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
        detected significantly higher rates of febrile respiratory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> occupants housed in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX>
        with low outdoor air ventilation rates as compared to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> housed in older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> with higher ventilation
        rates [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . In a study conducted during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richards</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> concluded that upper
        respiratory symptoms were more frequent in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> housed in
        air-conditioned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> when compared to those that were
        housed in non-air-conditioned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX>, open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> or
        tents [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . In a hospital-based study, an outbreak of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">varicella</ENAMEX> virus was explained by airflow studies, which
        demonstrated the spread of airborne virus from an infected
        patient housed in an isolation room to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ] . In a study conducted during a pneumococcal disease
        epidemic in a crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>, it was shown that attack rates
        were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> higher in cells with the lowest volume of air
        supply per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> studies have suggested a relationship between
        respiratory infections and office environments. In a study
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwaltney</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
        conducted an extensive study at a large insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
        Their results suggested that working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> were
        responsible for introducing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32%</NUMEX> of the colds their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
        contracted [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . More recently, a study of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX>
        office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who share <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are
        at increased risk of colds, although this study failed to
        conclude if the infections were transmitted as airborne
        infections or were transmitted by either large droplets or
        direct contact [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] .
        An underutilized method of evaluating building occupant
        health, which is particularly useful in office settings, is
        sick leave data. Sick leave data has been used for a
        variety of purposes such as to evaluate health promotion
        programs [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10</ENAMEX> ] , and to assess the efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">influenza</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vaccination</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . In general, a large fraction of sick
        leave is caused by respiratory illness [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12 13</NUMEX> ] . In a
        study conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nichol et al.</ENAMEX>, upper respiratory
        infections accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 65%</NUMEX> of sick leave
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working adults</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . In a study of military
        aircrews, respiratory infections accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> of the
        total number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> were grounded [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . In a
        study conducted on government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>, respiratory infections and gastroenteritis
        accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> of all absences [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milton et</ENAMEX>
        al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] used sick leave data to identify an association
        between outdoor air supply levels and sick leave among
        office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The results indicated that lower levels of
        outdoor air supply in office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were associated with
        increased sick leave. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> was seen in both
        crude analyses of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> total absence and in an analysis
        of short-term absences. This association between
        ventilation and absences occurred at ventilation levels
        that have not often been associated with non-specific
        symptoms or with building related complaints [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] .
        Because of this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> speculated that the observed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> between indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) levels and sick leave might have
        been due to the increased spread of respiratory illness
        from either airborne spread of infection or increased
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">susceptibility</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
        To determine whether a causal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> could be
        confirmed, we conducted an experimental intervention study
        of indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> levels, used as a surrogate for the
        concentration of viable airborne <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microorganisms</ENAMEX> capable of
        causing a respiratory infection and sick leave among <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX>
        office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid Corporation</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Study design
          We conducted a blinded experimental intervention study
          to determine the effect indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations on sick leave
          absences among <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> office workers in selected areas of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. To increase the range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations, the outdoor air
          supply dampers were adjusted to fixed positions that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alternately</ENAMEX> reduced or increased the outdoor air supply.
          We attempted to increase the outdoor air supply only
          would generally decrease the amount of outdoor air, such
          as during the heating and cooling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">winter</ENAMEX>. In general, we tried to obtain CO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations in the range of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100-250</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ppm</ENAMEX> above background levels during high
          ventilation intervention <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">350-500</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ppm</ENAMEX> above
          background in low ventilation intervention cycles. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>
          
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations were less than the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Society of Heating, Refrigerating</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air-Conditioning Engineers</ENAMEX> (ASHRAE) guidelines. Each
          intervention cycle lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately three months</TIMEX>. The
          study design was reviewed and approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
          School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health Human Subjects Committee</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and study population
          The office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> used for the study were owned and
          occupied by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid Corporation</ENAMEX>. All were located in
          suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, were open-plan offices
          with cubicles, and were mechanically ventilated without
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humidification</ENAMEX>. Building <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> was ventilated with a variable
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX> volume system, while <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 2</ENAMEX> had a constant air
          volume system. The variable air volume system in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> was overridden during the study, thereby effectively
          running the system as a constant air volume system. The
          study <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> had a high outside air ventilation
          capacity either by design or because they were remodeled
          from manufacturing spaces. Building <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> was studied from
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1999 to June 2001</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 2</ENAMEX> was studied
          from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000 to June 2001</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were
          studied but eventually proved unsuitable. Building <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> was
          withdrawn because few of the occupants were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and other means of acquiring accurate attendance
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> proved to be inadequate. Building was 4 dropped
          because outdoor air supply rates could not be adequately
          controlled. To determine the number of occupants in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, headcounts were taken either at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX> on randomly selected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> throughout the study.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1describes</ENAMEX> specific information regarding the study
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Ventilation and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 2measurements
          To alter the levels of fresh air entering the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, the dampers on the air intakes were locked
          into fixed positions at each cycle of the intervention.
          To determine the air changes <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per hour</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>,
          we conducted tracer gas tests periodically. Sulfur
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hexafluoride</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ) was used to generate a tracer gas
          decay curve. We injected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6</ENAMEX> into the fresh air plenum, followed
          by measurements in work areas and in the main return air
          duct with photoacoustic gas monitors (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruel & Kjaer</ENAMEX>,
          Naerum, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>) with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> filter (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model 1302</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> concentrations in the study areas were
          measured once every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vaisala</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> (model
          GMD20, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woburn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>) attached to data loggers
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HOBO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H08-004-02</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onset Computer Corp.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bourne, MA</ENAMEX>). We
          calibrated each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> known CO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations covering the range of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0-1000</ENAMEX> ppm at least once per intervention cycle. We
          placed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> centrally located monitors in each
          study area <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 1 1/2 m</NUMEX> above the floor. In
          addition, we located monitors out of doors on the roofs
          of study <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
          Our primary exposure measure was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration above background in
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. This CO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differential is used as a marker for
          the amount of air that has been previously breathed by
          building occupants. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rebreathed</ENAMEX> air potentially contains
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">respiratory</ENAMEX> pathogens from infectious occupants. To
          determine the differential, we first averaged the workday
          (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m. to 5 p.m.</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration and subtracted the
          average CO 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 concentration 1 a.m. - 3 a.m.</TIMEX>
          measured on the same date by the same monitor. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 a.m.</TIMEX>
          - <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m.</TIMEX> concentration measured by the same monitor was
          used rather than the outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> tend to exhibit baseline
          drift. The average CO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differential for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> was
          computed as the average across all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> in the study
          area. We then averaged the daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differentials to compute a weekly
          average CO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration differential.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bioaerosol</ENAMEX> and particulate sampling
          We sampled for airborne endotoxin and particulate in
          each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> during each intervention cycle. Samples
          were collected on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">37 mm diameter 0.4-μm</NUMEX> pore diameter
          polycarbonate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">membrane</ENAMEX> filters (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Whatman</ENAMEX> Nucleopore
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Filtration Products</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>) in closed face
          polystyrene cassettes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Millipore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>)
          at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 liters</NUMEX> per minute (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">l/min</ENAMEX>) using sampling pumps in
          acoustic foam insulated boxes. We extracted the filters
          in phosphate triethylamine buffer (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX>) and assayed
          the filter extracts for endotoxin levels using the
          kinetic limulus assay with resistant-parallel-line
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">estimation</ENAMEX> (KLARE) method [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endotoxin</ENAMEX> levels
          are reported as endotoxin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cubic meter</NUMEX> of air
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU/m 3</ENAMEX>). Particulate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were collected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impactors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">41 mm diameter 2.0-μm</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teflo</ENAMEX> filters
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pall Gelman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ann Arbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>) at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 l/min. Both</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endotoxin</ENAMEX> and PM 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were collected for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">consecutive days</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">working hours</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m. to 5 p.m.</TIMEX>)
          from the breathing zone of seated building occupants in
          the same location during each sampling period. Sampling
          took place over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>. In addition, we inspected each
          building for possible bioaerosol <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> prior to its
          entry into the study, and again periodically throughout
          the study. We conducted a thorough building walk-through,
          looking at the building exterior and surroundings, air
          intakes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HVAC</ENAMEX> system, mechanical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, occupied space,
          storage areas, and any other areas, which might contain
          bioaerosol <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reservoirs</ENAMEX>. Special attention was given to air
          handling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and any other areas where excessive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">moisture</ENAMEX> is likely to accumulate.
        
        
          Attendance data
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hourly</ENAMEX> attendance and demographic data for the study
          were collected using corporate databases. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
          Technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> provided attendance data from the
          payroll records for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Workers</ENAMEX> in the
          hourly payroll system completed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> time cards that
          contained information on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> worked and time claimed
          for various leave categories including sick time,
          vacation, and personal leave. Demographic data was
          provided from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources Department</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> database. Available demographic variables
          included employee ID number, seniority information
          (start, termination, retirement dates, etc.), race,
          gender, age, disability, and various job and departmental
          classifications. Final analytic data sets were produced
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> record per week per <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>, with
          demographic data appended to each record.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> analysis
          We analyzed the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> exposure in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX> and
          absence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the current week</TIMEX> using a generalized additive
          mixed model [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] with a logit link. A model employing
          continuous exposure was chosen a priori over a simple
          model categorizing intervention intervals as high and low
          outdoor air supply because a continuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> with
          appropriate lags does not require elimination of data
          from wash-out periods at the start of each interval, and
          allows for differences between successive high (or low)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interventions</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> used extends multiple logistic
          regression with an estimated "over-dispersion parameter"
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . First it allows the relationship
          between the covariates and input to the logit link to
          follow a smooth, not necessarily linear curve. The
          specific shape of the curve is modeled with a spline, a
          flexible model that essentially allows the data to
          determine the shape of the relationship. This feature of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is necessary in our study since there is a
          markedly nonlinear relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> exposure and the logit of absence
          probability. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> way this model extends multiple
          logistic regression is that it accounts for the
          correlation within the repeated measures on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
          using individual specific random effects [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . As
          discussed in Ruppert 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] we estimate the
          parameters in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> using the pseudo-likelihood
          method implemented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAS</ENAMEX> macro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GLIMMIX</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Results
        A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">294</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, whose characteristics are
        shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, worked in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and were
        included in the final analysis. Although each study area
        had both salaried and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only hourly</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were considered in the data analysis, because of
        the accuracy of records of their attendance data and
        because they spend the majority of their work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in
        their assigned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> was very
        transient which accounts for the large number of study
        subjects compared to the average number of occupants in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The majority of the study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> did not
        reside in the study <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> for the entire study period.
        The study included a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 49804</NUMEX> scheduled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">workdays</ENAMEX> and a total of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4405.6 hours</TIMEX> of sick leave.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> data over the course of the study is
        summarized in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outdoor CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> measurements confirmed that the indoor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations returned to outdoor
        background concentrations <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each evening</TIMEX>. The average weekly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outdoor CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 1</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">417</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ppm</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Range</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">324-497 ppm</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> ppm (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Range</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">327-549 ppm</ENAMEX>)
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 2</ENAMEX>. Figure 1displays <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration differential and the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> sick leave rates for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> included in
        the final analysis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> gaps in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1represent</NUMEX> time
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">periods</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2</ENAMEX> data was unavailable or HVAC dampers
        were being reset.
        The average CO 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differential, air exchange rate, and
        sick leave rates for each intervention cycle are displayed
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differential is well correlated with
        the outdoor ventilation rates, indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differential is an adequate surrogate
        of outdoor ventilation rates. We were unable to achieve the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">desired CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differentials of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">350-500</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ppm</ENAMEX> during
        low ventilation periods. Although we attempted to alter the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations by locking the outdoor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air dampers</ENAMEX> to fixed positions, in some cases the dampers
        did not remain in position. This resulted in less control
        over the air supply rates than we had hoped. Additionally,
        during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX> the chiller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 1</ENAMEX> was
        turned off, and as a result, the outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dampers</ENAMEX> were set
        to open automatically when the outdoor temperature was over
        0°C. The loss of control over the damper settings resulted
        in uncontrolled rates of outdoor air supply in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 1</ENAMEX>
        after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX>. The measured air exchange rates (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) support this conclusion. During the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> high
        ventilation cycles in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 1</ENAMEX> the air exchange rates
        were measured at above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 per hour</NUMEX>, while during the first
        low ventilation cycle, the outdoor air supply was measured
        at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 1</NUMEX> air change <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per hour</NUMEX> (ACH). After the dampers
        were adjusted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACH</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differentials were uncorrelated with
        the desired intervention throughout the remainder of the
        study. Although we were able to manipulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HVAC</ENAMEX> system
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 2</ENAMEX>, it appears that we were never able to alter
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.
        To determine if the number of occupants was driving the
        levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, random headcounts
        were taken throughout the study to approximate the total
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. The number of occupants was
        weakly correlated with the average CO 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differential from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same day</TIMEX> in each
        building (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 1</ENAMEX>: r = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.08</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 2</ENAMEX>: r = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>). Air
        sampling for endotoxin and PM 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> was conducted on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> occasions in
        Building <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and once in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 2</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>); the levels
        were well below those thought to be associated with
        symptoms. Samples were collected only once in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 2</ENAMEX>
        because we were unable to alter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations, and therefore we
        considered the entire time period that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 2</ENAMEX> was under
        study as one cycle.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Generalized additive</ENAMEX> mixed models with logit links were
        fit for the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. We modeled the
        probability of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupant</ENAMEX> having any absences during a
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> dependent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differential from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous week</TIMEX>
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-week</TIMEX> lag). Models with no lag and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-week</TIMEX> lags were
        also fit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differential was modeled as a
        continuous predictor because merely comparing the
        intervention periods would not have allowed for differences
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX> intervals assigned to the high ventilation
        condition and similarly each low ventilation interval.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Poisson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> were also constructed with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of absence
        during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> as the dependent variable. The Poisson
        models gave fits similar to those obtained from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">logistic</ENAMEX> models. Final models contained covariates for
        gender, race, age and individual random effects, which
        allow for correlation of absence rates within individuals
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>). A smooth term for time was included to control
        for unexplained trends in absence and the seasonality of
        absence. When the smooth term for time was not included,
        the shape of the curves did not change considerably,
        although the pointwise standard errors around the estimated
        curve increased substantially. Age, which was modeled as a
        continuous variable, was not significant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>,
        while gender was significant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 1</ENAMEX> model and
        race was significant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building 2</ENAMEX> model.
        We did not observe a consistent association between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> differential and absence at the levels
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> under study (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). In general,
        portions of the fitted smooth curves are significantly
        different from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> if the curve and the confidence
        interval curves are all above or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">below zero</NUMEX>. When data from
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> were combined, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> was
        observed between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations above background and
        sick leave.
      
      
        Discussion
        In this intervention study of sick leave absences among
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid Corporation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in
        suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, we did not find a
        consistent positive relationship between indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations and sick leave. This
        result is in contrast to the results of our earlier
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">observational</ENAMEX> study at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid</ENAMEX>, which found a significant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of outdoor air supply rates and sick leave [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
        ] . In the earlier study, we used a larger number of work
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">115</ENAMEX>) including areas with lower ventilation and
        higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations than were available for
        this intervention study. However, the previous study relied
        on a small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> measurements and primarily used expert
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX>, of an industrial hygienist blinded to absence
        rates, to assign outdoor air supply rates to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
        Thus, the intervention study was undertaken to confirm and
        extend the earlier findings.
        In the earlier study, estimated outdoor air supply rates
        ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-24 liters per second</NUMEX> (l/s) per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. In
        the current study, we can calculate the outdoor air supply
        rates if we assume a steady state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration in the study <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>,
        although this assumption is questionable. Using the steady
        state equation relating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX> levels and outdoor air supply rates,
        we calculate outdoor air supply rates that are nearly
        double that of the previous study, with the average daily
        outdoor supply rate of approximately <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> l/s per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for
        Building <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and approximately 40</NUMEX> l/s per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> as estimated from average CO 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations. We attempted to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control indoor CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations by adjusting the supply
        of outside air supply, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> available for the
        intervention study had an excess of ventilation capacity
        relative to the volume of office space and number of office
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. While these characteristics were advantageous for
        obtaining low CO 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations relative to background,
        it was difficult to increase the concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> substantially above background. ASHRAE
        standards allow for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 700</TIMEX> ppm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> above background in office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> ] , while the maximum <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentration above background in our
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">312 ppm</NUMEX>; the average was less than half
        that.
        This study showed that at high outdoor air supply rates
        sufficient to give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> average indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations in the range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> to
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 ppm</NUMEX> above background, sick leave is not associated with
        outdoor air supply rates. However, this study does not
        address the question of whether outdoor air supply rates
        resulting in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> concentrations <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 200 and 700</NUMEX> ppm
        above background can be experimentally shown to drive
        changes in sick leave rates as suggested by observational
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>. While this result is of interest to large, highly
        ventilated corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, it cannot be extrapolated to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> with lower rates of outdoor air supply.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACH Air</ENAMEX> changes per hour
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASHRAE American Society of Heating</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Refrigeration</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air-Conditioning Engineers</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLARE Kinetic</ENAMEX> limulus assay with resistant-parallel-line
        estimation
      
      
        Competing Interests
        None declared
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TM</ENAMEX> participated in the study coordination, data
        collection, carried out the molecular analysis and drafted
        the manuscript. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">JS</ENAMEX> performed statistical analysis. KA
        participated in data collection and statistical analysis.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MW</ENAMEX> participated in study design and facilitated site
        access. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SR</ENAMEX> participated in data collection and in the study
        design and coordination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DM</ENAMEX> conceived of the study, and
        participated in its design and coordination. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
        contributed to and approved the final version of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
