
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX>, normally expressed in high endothelial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">venules</ENAMEX> and in T cell zones of spleen and lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>,
        strongly attracts T cells and dendritic cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5 6 7 8</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> recruits both naÃ¯ve lymphocytes and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">antigen stimulated DC</ENAMEX> into T cell zones of secondary
        lymphoid organs, co-localizing these early immune response
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> that culminate in cognate T cell activation [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ] . The capacity to facilitate the co-localization of
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> and T cells forms a strong rationale for the use of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> in cancer therapy. In previous studies we have
        shown that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SLC/CCL21-</ENAMEX>mediated anti-tumor responses are
        accompanied by the enhanced elaboration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM-CSF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX>, but decreased
        PGE 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-Î² at the tumor
        site [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10</ENAMEX> ] . In addition, there was a marked increase in
        CD4 +and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +cells secreting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM-CSF</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
        expressing CD11c infiltrating the tumors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL 9</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">glutamine-leucine-arginine</ENAMEX> (ELR)-negative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokines that are potent chemoattractants for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activated T</ENAMEX> cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12 13</NUMEX> ] . These chemokines also have
        in common the ability to signal through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-coupled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR3</TIMEX>, expressed on activated T lymphocytes.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> are known to have potent
        anti-tumor activities 
        in vivo [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15 16 17</NUMEX> ] . Both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> are important for the anti-tumor
        activity mediated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> inducing cytokines such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 18 19</NUMEX> ] . Based on these findings we hypothesized that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">augmentation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> would
        play an important role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SLC/CCL21-</ENAMEX>mediated anti-tumor
        response. Here we show that the cytokines <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">effector</ENAMEX> molecules in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX>-mediated anti-tumor responses.
      
      
        Results and Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen presenting cells</ENAMEX> (APC) are critical for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-presentation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor antigens</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . However
        tumors have the capacity to limit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> maturation, function
        and infiltration of the tumor site [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22 23 24</NUMEX> ] . Thus
        molecules that attract host <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> and T cells could serve as
        potent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> immunotherapy. A potentially
        effective pathway to restore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag</ENAMEX> presentation is the
        establishment of a chemotactic gradient that favors
        localization of both activated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC and Type 1</ENAMEX> cytokine
        producing lymphocytes at the tumor site. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemokine</ENAMEX> expressed in high endothelial venules and in T
        cell zones of spleen and lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>, strongly attracts
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">naive T</ENAMEX> cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8</NUMEX> ] . Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DCs</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">potent APCs</ENAMEX> that function as principal activators of T
        cells, the capacity to facilitate the co-localization of
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> and T cells may reverse tumor-mediated immune
        suppression and orchestrate effective <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>-mediated immune
        responses [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 10 25 26 27</NUMEX> ] . In addition to its
        immunotherapeutic potential, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> has been found to
        have potent angiostatic effects [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] , thus adding
        further support for its use in cancer therapy. Based on
        these dual capacities, we as well as others have begun
        pre-clinical evaluation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> in several tumor
        models [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 10 25 26 27</NUMEX> ] .
        Utilizing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> transplantable murine <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX> models,
        we have previously shown that the anti-tumor efficacy of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> is T cell-dependent [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . In both models
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">recombinant SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> administered intratumorally led to
        complete <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor eradication</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 %</NUMEX> of the treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.
        Studies performed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD4</TIMEX> and CD8 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knockout mice</ENAMEX> also
        revealed a requirement for both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD4 and CD8</TIMEX> lymphocytes
        subsets for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> mediated <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor regression</ENAMEX>. Consistent
        with these findings we found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLC</ENAMEX> therapy did not alter
        tumor growth in SCID <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. In immune competent <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intratumoral</ENAMEX> injection of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> led to a significant
        increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD4</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD8 T</ENAMEX> lymphocytes as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
        infiltrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> and the draining lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>. The
        cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infiltrates</ENAMEX> were accompanied by an enhanced
        elaboration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> at
        the tumor site [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> is documented to have direct anti-angiogenic
        effects [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] ; the tumor reductions observed in this
        model could have been due to participation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secreting IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> leading to inhibition of angiogenesis via
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX>, as well as T cell-dependent
        immunity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> mediates a range of biological
        effects that facilitate anticancer immunity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> are potent angiostatic factors that are
        induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 16 17</NUMEX> ] . Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> are chemotactic for stimulated
        CXCR3-expressing activated T lymphocytes that could further
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amplify IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> at the tumor site [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . Hence we postulated
        that in addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> would
        also be important contributors to the tumor reduction in
        the context of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> therapy.
        To determine the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>, IP-10/CXCL10
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> mediated antitumor response,
        these cytokines were depleted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLC</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/CCL21</ENAMEX>-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.
        Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNÎ³ antibodies</ENAMEX> each
        partially but yet significantly inhibited the anti-tumor
        efficacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>* p <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX> compared to
        the control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>). Neutralization of IFNÎ³ caused
        a significant decrease in both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and IP-10/CXCL10
        indicating that these chemokines are largely IFNÎ³
        dependent. Thus, an increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> at the tumor site of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21-</ENAMEX>treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> could explain the relative increases
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>. The converse was also
        observed; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> production at the tumor site was found to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9- and IP-10/CXCL10-dependent</ENAMEX> as indicated by the
        fact that neutralization of these cytokines caused a
        significant decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>(Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Neutralization of
        any one of these cytokines caused a concomitant decrease in
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> cytokines, thus indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>, MIG/CXCL9
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> are interdependent in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX>-mediated anti-tumor responses. Based on these
        findings, we speculated that the decrease of IP-10/CXCL10
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> led to a decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> by limiting the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">influx of T</ENAMEX> cells producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> at the tumor site. Because
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> are chemotactic for stimulated
        CXCR3 expressing activated T lymphocytes, we determined if
        neutralizing these chemokines 
        in vivo in the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21-treated mice</ENAMEX>
        would decrease the frequency of CXCR3 expressing T cells at
        the tumor sites. Compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21-treated mice</ENAMEX>
        receiving control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, flow cytometric evaluation of
        single-cell suspensions of non-necrotic tumors from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21-</ENAMEX>treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neutralizing antibodies</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> showed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 12</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 %</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decreases</ENAMEX>, respectively, in the gated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD3 CXCR3</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veT</ENAMEX> cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). The fact that neutralization of IFNÎ³

        was the most efficient at decreasing the total number of
        CXCR3-activated T cells may be due to the decrease in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFNÎ³-dependent CXCR3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ligands</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Individually</ENAMEX>, neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and/or IP-10/CXCL10
        only led to a partial decrease in the total number of
        CXCR3-activated T cells. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and IP-10/CXCL10
        share the same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CXCR3</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> possible explanation
        of a partial decrease in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CXCR3</NUMEX>-activated T cells is that
        neutralization of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ligand</ENAMEX> may overexpose the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> to
        the other ligand. Furthermore, because <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">murine SLC</ENAMEX>/CCL21
        binds <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CXCR3 receptor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> may be recruiting CXCR3
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">+</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veT</ENAMEX> cells directly. An alternative explanation is that
        residual cytokines such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-inducible T</ENAMEX> cell Î±
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemoattractant</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ITAC/CXCL11</ENAMEX>) present after 
        in vivo neutralization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>, MIG,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> may have remaining activity and attract <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CXCR3</NUMEX> +veT
        cells. Our results imply that all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> cytokines, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>, MIG
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> play interrelated roles in the recruitment of
        CXCR3-activated T cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLC</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/CCL21-</ENAMEX>mediated anti-tumor
        responses. While the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD8 cells</ENAMEX> remained
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unaltered</ENAMEX>, compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21-</ENAMEX>treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> receiving
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> administered neutralizing antibodies
        to MIG/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCL9</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> showed respective
        decreases of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28 and 16%</NUMEX> in the number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11c</NUMEX> +DEC205
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">+DC</ENAMEX> infiltrating the tumor (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). At present it is not
        clear why there is a decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> following
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">neutralization of MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>. A
        plausible explanation is that these cytokines may be
        involved in complex interactions with other molecules that
        are chemotactic for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>. Further studies are required to
        delineate the mechanisms responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> mediated localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> at the
        tumor site.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Our results suggest that the anti-tumor properties of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> may be due to its chemotactic capacity in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> and T cells as well as in part to the
        induction of key cytokines such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Reagents
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abs</ENAMEX> to murine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX>, recombinant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> were obtained
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PharMingen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abs</ENAMEX> to murine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and recombinant cytokine standards was
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R&D</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>). Recombinant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PeproTech</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rocky Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>).
          Polyclonal goat anti-murine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX> and anti-murine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> specific <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-serum</ENAMEX> were produced and
          characterized as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . Anti-mouse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> monoclonal (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R4-462</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX>
          Collection, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>) neutralizing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was purified by affinity chromatography from
          SCID <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice ascites</ENAMEX>, which was generated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-4 weeks</TIMEX> after
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intraperitoneal</ENAMEX> injection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6R4-462</ENAMEX> hybridoma cells
          per mouse [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . For flow cytometry, labeled antibodies
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PerCP</ENAMEX>) against the T cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">markers</ENAMEX> to
          CD3, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD8</ENAMEX> and against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> markers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD11c</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEC</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">205</NUMEX> and the appropriate controls were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PharMingen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> labeled anti-rabbit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> was purchased
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PharMingen</ENAMEX>. Rabbit anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CXCR3 antibody</ENAMEX> was
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zymed Laboratories Inc.</ENAMEX> (So. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>, CA). Murine serum albumin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>) was utilized as control injections for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Cell culture and tumorigenesis model
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">weakly immunogenic lung cancer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> lung carcinoma
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3LL</ENAMEX>, H-2 b) obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CRL-1642</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LLC</ENAMEX>) was
          utilized for assessment of cytokines important for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> - mediated anti-tumor responses 
          in vivo . The cells were routinely
          cultured as monolayers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 cm 3tissue</TIMEX> culture flasks
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">containing RPMI 1640</ENAMEX> medium (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irvine Scientific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>, CA) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum (FBS)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gemini Bioproducts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calabasas</ENAMEX>, CA), penicillin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">U/ml</ENAMEX>), streptomycin (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM glutamine (JRH
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosciences, Lenexa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KS</ENAMEX>) and maintained at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in a
          humidified atmosphere containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in air. The cell lines were
          mycoplasma free and cells were utilized up to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX>
          passage before thawing frozen stock cells from liquid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> .
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tumorigenesis</ENAMEX> experiments, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 53LL tumor cells
          were inoculated by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">s.c.</ENAMEX> injection in the right supra
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">scapular</ENAMEX> area of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">C57Bl/6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and tumor volumes were
          monitored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five day</TIMEX> established
          tumors were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intratumoral</ENAMEX> injection of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 Î</NUMEX>¼g
          of recombinant murine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepro Tech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rocky Hill</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>) or murine serum albumin (utilized as an irrelevant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> for control injections) were administered three
          times per week for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> as previously described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
          ] . 24 h prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SLC/CCL21</ENAMEX> treatment, and then three
          times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were injected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">i.p.</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ml</ENAMEX>/dose of
          anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX>, or anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/</ENAMEX>dose of
          purified monoclonal anti-IFNÎ³ or appropriate control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX> (goat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgG</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat IgG</ENAMEX>) at equivalent doses for
          the duration of the experiment. In response to these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX>, there was a significant reduction of the
          respective cytokines 
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vivo</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Tumor volume
          was calculated as previously described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytokine ELISA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIG/CXCL9</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10/CXCL10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFNÎ³</ENAMEX> were quantified using
          a modification of a double ligand method as previously
          described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Flow Cytometry
          Flow cytometric analyses for T cell and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> markers
          were performed on a FACScan flow cytometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonsson Cancer Center Flow Cytometry Core</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Facility</ENAMEX>. Cells were identified as lymphocytes or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gating</ENAMEX> based on forward and side scatter profiles. CD11c
          +veDCs were defined as the bright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> within
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor nodules</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX>-gated events were collected and
          analyzed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Quest</ENAMEX> software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>).
          For staining, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three fluorochromes</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PerCP</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PharMingen</ENAMEX>) were used to gate on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CD3</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD4</ENAMEX> and
          CD8 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> lymphocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11c</NUMEX> +veDC in single cell
          suspensions from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor nodule</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR3</TIMEX> expression, T
          cells were doubly stained for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD3 and CXCR3</TIMEX> cell surface
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markers</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Groups</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were used. Statistical analyses of
          the data in figures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1, 2and</TIMEX> in table 1were performed
          using the paired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student t</ENAMEX> test.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Author</ENAMEX>'s contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Author 1 SS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Author 2</ENAMEX> SCY coordinated and carried out
        all the experiments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authors SH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LXZ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RKB</ENAMEX> and MDB
        contributed to the discussion of the article. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Author JFL</ENAMEX>
        together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> performed the statistical analyses.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authors RMS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMD</ENAMEX> together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> conceived of the
        study, participated in its design and drafted the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manuscript</ENAMEX>.
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final manuscript
      
    
  
