
  
    
      
        Background
        Normal spermatogenesis represents a precisely regulated
        balance between continuous cell proliferation and
        concomitant programmed cell death, apoptosis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4</NUMEX> ] .
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">More than 50%</NUMEX> of the germ cells die during their normal
        developmental process [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apoptosis</ENAMEX> in the testis of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rodents</ENAMEX> is detected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as the 14 thembryonic day</TIMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
        ] . After birth, an early apoptotic wave of germ cells
        during a critical pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pubertal period</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">around 3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>) [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> ] may be required for determining the subsequent normal
        pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spermatogenesis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] .
        Androgen binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (ABP) is produced by Sertoli
        cells of the testis, secreted into the lumen of
        seminiferous tubules, and transported with tubular fluid to
        the epididymis, where it is internalized and degraded by
        the epithelial cells of the initial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> and the caput;
        it binds testosterone (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>), dihydrotestosterone and
        estradiol with high affinity [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10 11</ENAMEX> ] . The functions of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> have been the subject of many reviews [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">e.g.</ENAMEX>, [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 12 13</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15</NUMEX> ] ]. It is thought to regulate spermatogenesis and
        sperm maturation by maintaining high androgen levels in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testis</ENAMEX> and epididymis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ] and has been proposed as a
        biochemical marker for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sertoli</ENAMEX> cell function and formation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>-testis barrier [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 18</NUMEX> ] . More recently, cell
        surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver-</ENAMEX>derived homolog sex
        hormone-binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">globulin</ENAMEX> (SHBG) were identified in several
        androgen target tissues, suggesting that these
        extracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid-binding proteins</ENAMEX> may have a much
        broader, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>-like function [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21</NUMEX> ] .
        In order to study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX>'s functions 
        in vivo , Reventos 
        et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] developed transgenic
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TG</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice overexpressing rat</ENAMEX> ABP. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">TG mice</ENAMEX> showed
        progressive structural and functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abnormalities</ENAMEX> in
        their testes, leading eventually to infertility [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24 25</NUMEX>
        ] . In our recent paper, we described an altered pattern of
        germ cell proliferation throughout postnatal life in the
        ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, resulting in a progressive reduction in total
        germ cell numbers with increasing age [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . However, it
        was not clear whether the reduction in germ cell numbers
        was the result of a reduced rate of proliferation, an
        increased rate of apoptosis, or a combination of the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
        The present study was performed to provide quantitative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> on germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell apoptosis</ENAMEX> in control and in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
        aged from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 to 360 days</TIMEX>. Apoptotic cells were identified by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">TdT</ENAMEX>-mediated dUTP-biotin nick end labeling (TUNEL)
        method and detected either by flow cytometry [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] or by
        light microscopy in histological sections [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . The
        results indicate that transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> alters the rate of
        testicular germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell apoptosis</ENAMEX> throughout life, but it is
        most likely to cause its germ-cell depleting effect by
        promoting germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell apoptosis</ENAMEX> during the critical
        pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pubertal period</TIMEX> ("puberty" in laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX> occurs
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at 50-60 days</TIMEX> of life and is defined as the first
        appearance of spermatozoa in the tail of the epididymis [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30</NUMEX> ] ).
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> were housed in an animal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> under
          controlled conditions and given food and water 
          ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libitum</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Care</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Use Committee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of North</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX> approved the protocols used in
          this study. Transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> over-expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> ABP in
          their testes were developed by Reventos 
          et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] and were propagated
          as described previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> (wild-type,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX>) and homozygous male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 14, 21, 30, 60</TIMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90, 120, 180, 240 and 360 days of age</TIMEX> were used in the
          present study. A minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were
          analyzed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> were sacrificed by overexposure to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ether</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chemicals</ENAMEX>
          TdT enzyme and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TdT</ENAMEX> buffer were purchased from Promega
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). All other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, unless stated
          otherwise, were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemical Company</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Preparation of germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> suspension
          The method described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Brien</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] , as modified
          by Jeyaraj 
          et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] , was used to isolate
          germ cells from the seminiferous tubules. Briefly, the
          decapsulated testes were incubated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/ml</ENAMEX> collagenase (type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">32Â°C</NUMEX> in a
          shaking water bath. After washing twice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">containing 1.0 Î¼g/ml DNase, 1.0 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> trypsin in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> was
          added and incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32Â°C</TIMEX>. Equal amount
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soybean trypsin inhibitor</ENAMEX> was added and the suspension
          was mixed by gentle pipetting with a plastic transfer
          pipette for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3-5 minutes</TIMEX> and was filtered through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 Î</TIMEX>¼m
          nylon mesh (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼m for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-30 days old</TIMEX>). The filtrate was
          washed twice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, and
          stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>.
        
        
          TUNEL labeling of germ cells for flow cytometry
          analysis
          The procedure followed in the present study for TUNEL
          labeling was described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krishnamurthy</ENAMEX> 
          et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-2</TIMEX>
          million/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>-fixed testicular germ cells were
          washed twice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, treated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> pepsin
          solution (dissolved in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.9%</NUMEX> saline, pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX>
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. After washing twice with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, the cells
          were resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TdT</ENAMEX> buffer containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
          potassium cacodylate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCL</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.6</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> mM
          CoCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml bovine serum albumin,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> nM biotinylated deoxyuridine triphosphate (b-UTP) and
          incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>. After washing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>,
          the cells were resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of a reagent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">containing 4x-</ENAMEX>concentrated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saline</ENAMEX>-sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">citrate</ENAMEX> buffer,
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml fluorosceinated avidin, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX>, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry milk</ENAMEX>, incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at room temperature
          in the dark, and washed twice in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. The cells
          were resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          propidium iodide and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNase</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> cells were
          processed as described but without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TdT</ENAMEX>. The intensity of
          the green fluorescence of avidin-FITC-stained cells and
          the red fluorescence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PI stained cells</ENAMEX> was measured in
          the FACScan flow cytometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton-Dickinson</ENAMEX>
          Immunocytometry, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). A marker was set in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> dot plot at the cut-off between background
          signals and positive staining, as determined from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> samples. Cells were considered TUNEL-positive if
          their fluorescence intensity exceeded that set level. The
          percentage of positive cells was quantified by using the
          "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summit</ENAMEX>" software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytomation Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Collins, CO</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          In situ end labeling and peroxidase staining on
          testicular tissue sections
          
          In situ apoptosis detection kit
          (Apoptag peroxidase kit) was purchased from Intergen
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> and their protocol was followed.
          Testicular tissue was fixed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bouin</ENAMEX>'s fixative,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dehydrated</ENAMEX> in graded concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> and
          embedded in paraffin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8 Î¼m</ENAMEX> sections were de-parafinized,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-hydrated and washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml proteinase-K
          was placed on the section and kept at room temperature
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>. After washing twice in distilled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>,
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were covered with equilibration buffer for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-15 seconds</TIMEX> followed by the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TdT</ENAMEX> enzyme for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-20 minutes</TIMEX>. The reaction was stopped by placing the
          sections in stop/wash buffer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were washed
          thrice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-digoxigenin</ENAMEX>-peroxidase conjugate
          was added on the section and incubated in a humidified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at room temperature. After washing
          the sections <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> times in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, diaminobenzidine
          tetra-hydrochloride (DAB) was used to develop the color
          (dark brown). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> slides were processed in an
          identical manner except that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TdT</ENAMEX> was omitted. The
          sections were counterstained with toluidine blue,
          dehydrated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> and xylene, coverslipped, and
          images viewed and recorded using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Eclipse 600</ENAMEX>
          microscope equipped with Spot digital camera (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnostic</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Instruments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sterling Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Induction of testicular germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> apoptosis
          To confirm the reliability of the above methods,
          apoptosis was induced by treatment with methoxy acetic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (MAA), which is known to cause apoptosis in
          testicular germ cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 32</NUMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult male</ENAMEX> control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 days old</TIMEX>) were given a single intraperitoneal
          injection of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">650</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kg</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAA</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          were decapitated, testes removed, isolated germ cells
          processed for flow cytometric estimation, and tissue
          sections for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> as described above.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          Changes were evaluated using unpaired "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">t</ENAMEX>" test and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">software GraphPad Instat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). P
          = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> or less was considered significant. Quantitative
          results throughout this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> will be stated as the mean
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Â±</ENAMEX> standard deviation.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Total number of germ cells undergoing apoptosis in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ABP-TG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          In control <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, the total number of germ cells
          undergoing apoptosis was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.47 Â± 0.07 million</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
          (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>& <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). It gradually increased to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24.77</NUMEX>
          Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.88 million</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 21</TIMEX> followed by a sharp increase on
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 30</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">141.74 Â± 30.13 million</NUMEX>) and a plateau thereafter
          until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 120</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From Day 180</TIMEX> onwards, a gradual increase
          was observed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 360</TIMEX>. The general pattern of germ
          cells undergoing apoptosis in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> was similar;
          however, the total number of germ cells undergoing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> was consistently higher than in
          controls on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 21, 30 and 60</TIMEX>, respectively (the
          increase was statistically significant on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 21</TIMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>). Starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from Day 90</TIMEX>, the number of germ cells
          undergoing apoptosis in TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> was consistently lower
          than in controls until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 360</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>& <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spermatogonia</ENAMEX> and secondary spermatocytes
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2C</NUMEX>)
          The total number of spermatogonial cells undergoing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in control and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ABP-TG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> remained unchanged
          until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 14</TIMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP-TG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between Days 21 and 60</TIMEX>, the
          number of spermatogonial cells undergoing apoptosis was
          significantly increased. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX>, even though a
          decrease was observed in the total number of
          spermatogonia undergoing apoptosis, the decrease was
          statistically significant only on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 90 and 240</TIMEX> (Figure
          5A& <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Spermatogonia synthesizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-phase</ENAMEX>)
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between Days 21 and 60</TIMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-phase</ENAMEX> cells
          undergoing apoptosis was significantly higher in ABP-TG
          than in control <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Starting from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 days</TIMEX>, a consistent
          reduction in the number of apoptotic S-phase <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> was
          seen in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>; the decrease was statistically
          significant on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 90, 240 and 360</TIMEX> (Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5B& Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Primary spermatocytes (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4C</NUMEX>)
          In the testes of ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, the total number of 4C
          cell population undergoing apoptosis was increased
          significantly (as compared to controls) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 21</TIMEX> and
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. The number of primary spermatocytes undergoing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> relative to controls was
          decreased after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days</TIMEX>; the decrease was statistically
          significant on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 90, 240 and 360</TIMEX> (Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5C& Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spermatids</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1C</NUMEX>)
          Although a greater number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spermatids</ENAMEX> underwent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> than in controls on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 21, 30</TIMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>, none of these changes were statistically
          significant. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 days of age</TIMEX>, the number of
          spermatids undergoing apoptosis was significantly lower
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP-TG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> than controls in all age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> studied
          (Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5D& Table 2</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Percentage of germ cells undergoing
          apoptosis
          On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 21, 30 and 60</TIMEX>, the percentage of germ cells
          undergoing apoptosis was higher in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> than
          controls (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> on testicular sections
          To further validate the results obtained in flow
          cytometric analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> assay was done on testicular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">paraffin</ENAMEX> sections from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> of different age groups
          (Figures <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6& 7</ENAMEX>). Microscopic observation of the
          sections revealed the presence of greater numbers TUNEL
          positive germ cells in the testicular sections of ABP-TG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages of 21</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 6F</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 6H</ENAMEX>) days
          compared to their age-matched controls than in any other
          age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Figures 7Eis the representative
          photomicrograph of a testicular section from an
          MAA-treated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">90 days</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">WT</ENAMEX> mouse processed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX>.
          Germ cells undergoing apoptosis are considerably more
          frequent in the testis of the MAA-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 7E</ENAMEX>)
          than the untreated control (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 7A</ENAMEX>). The increase seen in
          the frequency of TUNEL-positive germ cells in MAA-treated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> corroborates the results obtained from flow
          cytometry analysis. Figure 7Fis a negative control.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        It is well established that TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice overexpressing rat</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] develop a testicular impairment [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24 25</NUMEX> ]
        leading gradually to a reduced number of germ cells and
        infertility [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . Various theories were proposed to
        explain the possible mechanisms behind this testicular
        impairment seen in the ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice overexpressing rat</ENAMEX> ABP.
        The first theory invokes the indirect involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX>.
        The increased concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> present in the testes of
        TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] ) will chronically
        reduce the concentration of intra-testicular free T
        available for interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">androgen receptor</ENAMEX> (AR) and
        other molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. This is supported by the 
        in vitro study of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> and Zirkin
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] demonstrating that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> can actually inhibit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>'s
        action at the level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>. Our earlier findings
        including a reduced number of elongated spermatids in the
        ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] also support the notion that higher than
        physiological concentrations of ABP affect spermatogenesis
        indirectly, through sequestration of androgens; the
        transformation of round spermatids to elongated spermatids
        is known to be the main androgen-dependent step in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spermatogenesis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36 37</NUMEX> ] .
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> theory suggests the possible direct
        involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> in spermatogenesis. Specific cell
        surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> have been detected in several
        cell types including germ cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38 39 40 41</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerard</ENAMEX> 
        et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> was
        bound and internalized by germ cells and it also modified
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein synthesis</ENAMEX> in germ cells in a manner dependent on
        the presence or absence of sex <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX>. The presence of
        increased numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX>-containing germ cells in the
        testes of ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] and immunocytochemical
        observations of intense ABP immunoreactivity found in and
        around all types of germ cells in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ]
        support a possible direct involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> in the
        testicular impairment seen in the ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. The late
        stages of spermatogenesis (spermiogenesis) were extensively
        studied for the possible direct effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17 42</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44 45</NUMEX> ] . In these studies, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> (at least at
        physiological concentrations) appeared to be supportive,
        rather than detrimental, to spermatogenesis. Thus,
        available evidence does not seem to indicate a direct
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibitory</ENAMEX> or "damaging" role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spermatogenesis</ENAMEX>.
        Although optimal and highly regulated rates of
        "spontaneous" germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell apoptosis</ENAMEX> are essential for normal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spermatogenesis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 46 47 48</NUMEX> ] , there is evidence to
        link the increased or decreased apoptosis of germ cells
        with abnormal spermatogenesis and male infertility [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 49</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ] .
        In the ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, an overall reduction in the number
        of spermatids was reported [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] and suggested as one of
        the reasons for the reduced fertility seen in these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. Our finding of an increased rate of germ cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 and 30 days old</TIMEX> ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> as compared to
        controls is consistent with the possibility that the
        reduced fertility (reduced germ cell number) seen in the
        ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> during adulthood may be due to increased
        apoptosis of germ cells during the first wave of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spermatogenesis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the pubertal period</TIMEX>. In a recent paper,
        Selva 
        et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> ] described meiotic
        arrest and an "increased occurrence of apoptosis" of
        testicular germ cells (primarily pachytene spermatocytes
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in metaphase) in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3-, 6-</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-month old</TIMEX> ABP-TG
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and suggested that these events were the cause of the
        fertility impairment seen in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. However, in the
        study of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selva et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX> ] , apoptosis was not analyzed
        by flow cytometry but was detected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> reaction in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">histological</ENAMEX> sections only from a small number of
        homozygous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each of 3- and 6-month old</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-month old</TIMEX>) and no statistical analysis of the results
        was provided.
        The present study is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to describe the detailed
        quantitative pattern of testicular germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> apoptosis
        throughout life in normal as well as in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Flow
        cytometry detects TUNEL-positive cells in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>
        of germ cells in adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The greater numbers
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX>-positive cells detected in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of
        germ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (highest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4C</TIMEX>, primary spermatocytes) from
        MAA-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> than controls confirm the reliability of
        the methods we used in this study. Selective targeting of
        spermatocytes by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAA</ENAMEX> has been reported earlier [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52 53 54</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> ] .
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 days</TIMEX> old control mice <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.45</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.68%</NUMEX> and in ABP-TG
        mice <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.47</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.57%</NUMEX> of all germ cells are apoptotic.
        Analysis within each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> reveals that, in control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.47</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.65%</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2C</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.32</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.23%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-phase</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.26</NUMEX> Â±
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.76%</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4C</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.44</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.40%</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1C</NUMEX> cells were apoptotic.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP-TG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, the percentage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2C</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.45</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.70%</NUMEX>) and 4C
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5.82</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.27%</NUMEX>) cells undergoing apoptosis was significantly
        higher than in controls.
        Though the total number of germ cells undergoing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in control <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> increased gradually from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 7</TIMEX> to
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">360</NUMEX> (the total number of germ cells also increased in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, see Jeyaraj 
        et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] ), the percentage of
        germ cells undergoing apoptosis was at its peak on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 30</TIMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). These findings are consistent with the
        morphological analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russel</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] reporting higher
        incidence of degenerative <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the seminiferous tubules
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 and 32 days</TIMEX> old normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and lower levels found
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP-TG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, the total number of germ cells
        undergoing apoptosis also increased from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 7</TIMEX> and peaked
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 21 and 30</TIMEX>. After a decline by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 60</TIMEX>, the number of
        germ cells undergoing apoptosis leveled off in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From Day 90</TIMEX> onwards, in terms of total number of germ cells
        undergoing apoptosis, there is a clear and consistent
        reduction in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> compared to controls. However,
        since the total number of germ cells in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> of
        these age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 90 to day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">360</NUMEX>) is also reduced [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ]
        , the actual proportion (or percentage) of germ cells
        undergoing apoptosis remains similar in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
        The presence of increased numbers of apoptotic germ
        cells in ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> controls on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 21, 30</TIMEX>
        and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> suggests that this age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is more vulnerable than
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">adult animals</ENAMEX> to increased levels of intra-testicular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX>.
        This suggestion is supported by many of our observations:
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the percentage of germ cells undergoing apoptosis at
        these age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 21, 30 and 60</TIMEX>) was higher in ABP-TG
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> controls. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) The absolute numbers of germ
        cells undergoing apoptosis in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 and 30 days old</TIMEX> ABP-TG
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were significantly higher than in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> controls, albeit
        the total number of germ cells present in the testes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>
        and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> of ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> was similar to that in
        WT-controls [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 60</TIMEX>, even though the total
        number of germ cells present in the ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> was
        significantly lower than in age-matched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> controls [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ]
        , the number of germ cells undergoing apoptosis was
        nevertheless higher. Thus, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days 21, 30</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>, the
        changes observed must be directly related to the increased
        levels of testicular ABP present in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">TG animals</ENAMEX>.
        Our data indicate that the presence of greater than
        physiological concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> in the mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">testis</ENAMEX> has
        a biphasic effect on the frequency of apoptosis in germ
        cells. The initial increase seen in germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> apoptosis
        (especially at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 and 30 days</TIMEX>) is likely to result from a
        direct or indirect action of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> and may affect the
        subsequent life-death balance of germ cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> in
        TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. The subsequent reduction is most likely due to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maturation</ENAMEX> depletion (reduced germ cell numbers). Taken
        together, the presence of increased levels of
        intra-testicular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> in the TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days of age</TIMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] and a wave of germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> apoptosis seen in normal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 and 30 days of age</TIMEX> in this study and by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] suggest that the
        heightened apoptotic wave found in our TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> during the
        pre-pubertal period may be regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX>. However, at
        this point it is not clear whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> regulates this
        apoptotic wave by direct action on germ cells or
        indirectly, by reducing the intra-testicular concentrations
        of free (bioavailable) T. The known biochemical properties
        and actions of ABP make the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mechanism more likely
        (see Jeyaraj 
        et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] ). This would also
        indicate that the pre-pubertal wave of apoptosis is
        regulated, at least in part, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. Indeed</ENAMEX>, it has been
        reported that experimental reduction in the levels of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intra-testicular T</ENAMEX> leads to the activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">caspase-3</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> ] and thereby to an increase in germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> apoptosis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> ] . The roles of other apoptosis-regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>,
        such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fas/Fas</ENAMEX> ligand system [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47 59 60</NUMEX> ] , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bcl</ENAMEX>-2
        family of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61 62</NUMEX> ] , and several "inhibitor of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (IAP) are also likely to play a role in
        germ cell death and survival [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63 64 65</NUMEX> ] .
      
      
        In conclusion, our data suggest that the presence of
        high concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> in the mouse seminiferous
        tubules results in a dramatically increased wave of germ
        cell apoptosis during the pre-pubertal period. Since the
        most likely mechanism of this effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABP</ENAMEX> is androgen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequestration</ENAMEX>, androgens are likely to play an important
        role in regulating the wave of germ <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell apoptosis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.
        The altered rate of apoptosis at this time may in part be
        responsible for the subsequent progressive spermatogenetic
        defect seen in the ABP-TG <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. An analysis of androgen
        levels and ABP- and androgen-regulated gene expression
        within the seminiferous tubules may reveal the precise
        molecular mechanisms of these complex regulatory
        processes.
      
    
  
