
  
    
      
        Background
        Hotspots have been defined as the minimal functional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> interaction domains through which
        biological activity can be modulated [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3</NUMEX> ] . A novel
        strategy called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Phenogenix</ENAMEX> Â®has been developed as a means
        for studying these interactions. To enable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phenogenix Â®</ENAMEX>, we
        use large and diverse phage display libraries consisting of
        randomized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mer and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> mer amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> peptides with >
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 11independent clones. Because of their ability to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">modulate protein</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein interactions</ENAMEX>, the resulting
        peptides are called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hotspot Ligands</ENAMEX> (HSPLs). Using this
        approach, we have successfully identified peptide agonists
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> for a number of biologically important
        molecules including growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> receptor, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and the insulin-like growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor receptor</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX>
        ] .
        In this report, we describe the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phenogenix</ENAMEX> Â®to
        identify the critical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> interactions
        underlying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF/TNFR</ENAMEX> axis. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ²</ENAMEX> have been
        extensively studied and are involved in immune and
        pro-inflammatory responses, playing an important role in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> defenses against infection and other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> states [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . The biological effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ²</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mediated</ENAMEX> through the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> membrane associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>,
        TNFR1 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">p55</NUMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">p75</NUMEX>), that are expressed on the
        target cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] . The postulated pathogenic roles for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and other bacterial and viral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathologies</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11 12</NUMEX> ] , certain <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] ,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metastasis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] and chronic autoimmune disorders such as
        rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple sclerosis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ]
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Crohn's disease</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . It is worth noting that TNFÎ±
        mutants have been identified that selectively bind <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR1</TIMEX>.
        One such mutant induced less systemic toxicity yet showed
        no compromise in its anti-tumor activity in nude <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
        ] . These observations indicated that finding modulators
        specific for each of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> is indeed
        possible.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> binds equally well to both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, the
        majority of biologic responses attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> are
        mediated via TNFR1 although there is evidence that
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR2</ENAMEX> is responsible for some adverse effects
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21 22 23 24</NUMEX> ] . Thus, the differential
        regulation of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> may require <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that
        specifically target either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR1</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX> allowing
        therapeutic efficacy without the expected toxicity profile.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> obvious possibility then is to search for Surrogates
        that selectively bind and regulate the individual
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. To date several antagonistic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> reagents
        have been isolated for treating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> with an underlying
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> etiology. These include neutralizing monoclonal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> and soluble forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFR1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR2</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26 27</NUMEX>
        ] . However, both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> and extracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
        are large <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and not amenable to oral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.
        They also carry the unwanted risk of stimulating an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">auto-immune</ENAMEX> response during chronic use.
        By panning our peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the TNFR2</TIMEX>, we
        isolated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPL</ENAMEX> peptides binding specifically to human
        TNFR2 that allow the subdivision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> into a
        minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hotspots</ENAMEX> involved in
        its interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>. In a biological model for TNFÎ±
        activation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> peptides induced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytotoxic</ENAMEX> response in the target cell line suggesting that
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of these domains induced a unique
        TNFR2-specific biological response. Overall, these data
        show the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> of using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPL</ENAMEX> peptides for subdividing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein interacting domains</ENAMEX> and for defining unique
        novel biological activities not observed through the
        natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligand/receptor interaction</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Results
        Human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFR2</ENAMEX> was panned with random <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mer and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> mer
        phage display peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> of high diversity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 28</NUMEX>
        ] . After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> rounds of panning, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phage</ENAMEX> clones were
        isolated with specificity for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX>. The peptides were
        initially divided into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>: a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> mer designated
        KcF12 and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three 20</NUMEX> mers designated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcC7</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KcD11</ENAMEX> and KcF6
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). From the amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid sequences</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcC7</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KcD11</ENAMEX> and
        KcF12 were found to have a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cysteine residues</ENAMEX>
        suggesting the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">intra-chain</ENAMEX> disulfide
        bonding. In addition, a putative motif, 
        W x 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EY</ENAMEX> xx 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGG</ENAMEX> , was found for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">peptides KcF6</TIMEX> and
        KcD11 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). It was interesting that this motif was
        related to a sequence 
        W x 
        E xxxxx 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GG</ENAMEX> found at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX> (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">190-198</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-Î±.</ENAMEX> No appreciable sequence homology was
        seen between either of the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> or TNFÎ²,
        and KcF12 although the spacing of cysteine loop was close
        to that seen in the cysteine rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">domains</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR2</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] .
        At present, it is not known whether these structural
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> play a role in binding of the peptides to TNFR2
        and it may be that the peptides mimic rather than
        recapitulate the contact domains of the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligands</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> analysis showed that all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phage</ENAMEX> clones bound
        specifically to human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFR2</ENAMEX> and did not react with either
        human or murine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR1</ENAMEX> or murine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX> (data not shown).
        Competition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISAs</ENAMEX> were performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and TNFÎ²
        vs. the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phage</ENAMEX> clones at their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ED</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> values (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1a,1b,1c,1d</NUMEX>). More
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ²</ENAMEX> were required to compete KcF12 than the other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phage</ENAMEX> clones suggesting that certain intrinsic properties
        of KcF12 (such as its length and/or amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> content) may
        contribute to a higher relative affinity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). In
        addition, the synthetic forms of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcC7</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcD11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KcF6</ENAMEX> and the
        recombinant KcF12 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">rKcF12</NUMEX>) were able to compete the binding
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ²</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KcF6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KcF12</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">phage</ENAMEX> clones in
        the micromolar range (unpublished data). Interestingly, the
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three 20 mer HSPLs</TIMEX> but not KcF12 were competed by an
        anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TNFR2</NUMEX> monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mAb226</TIMEX>, (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
        suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KCF12</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">binds</ENAMEX> to a hotspot on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TNFR2</NUMEX> distinct
        from the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> peptides. A summary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phage</ENAMEX>/peptide
        competition data is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>.
        Binding of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">KcF12</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native TNFR2</ENAMEX> was measured in Jurkat
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiyoye</ENAMEX> cells using a radioreceptor assay. Jurkat cells
        have been reported to have approximately equal numbers of
        TNFR1 and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">TNFR2</NUMEX> per cell [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiyoye</ENAMEX> cells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> mainly TNFR2 (unpublished data). KcF12 inhibits
        TNFÎ± binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiyoye</ENAMEX> cells with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ki</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2</NUMEX> uM
        whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ki</ENAMEX> for the peptide in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jurkat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> was found to
        be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>30 uM</NUMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> binding to Jurkat
        probably involves both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR1 and TNFR2</TIMEX>, the data offers
        additional confirmation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcF12</TIMEX>'s selectivity for
        TNFR2.
        It has been previously reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> induced a
        TNFR2-specific proliferation of the neuroblastoma cell line
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK-N</ENAMEX>-BE [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . KcF12, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KcC7</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">KcF6</ENAMEX> inhibited the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proliferative</ENAMEX> response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± in this cell line
        indicating that they could act as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> (data not
        shown). In addition, the same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptides</ENAMEX> were found to
        be cytotoxic to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK-N</ENAMEX>-BE cells in the absence of TNFÎ±
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4a</NUMEX>). KcF12 possessed the strongest killing activity
        with an IC 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~700</NUMEX> nM whereas the IC 
        50 s for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcC7 and KcF6</TIMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> uM and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uM</ENAMEX>, respectively. None of the peptides induced a cytotoxic
        response in cell lines not expressing TNFR2 (data not
        shown). Interestingly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcD11</TIMEX>, which shares a motif with
        KcF6 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>), had no effect on SK-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-BE cells. The absence
        of activity by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcD11</TIMEX> did not appear to be due to breakdown
        of the peptide during culturing since mass spectral
        analyses on aliquots retrieved from culture media showed
        relatively no degradation of peptides between the initial
        and the final time points (data not shown). Therefore, the
        proliferation data suggests evidence of a hotspot on TNFR2
        recognized by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcF12</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcC7 and KcF6</TIMEX> that is linked to this
        unique biological effect. The inhibition of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the KcC7</TIMEX> and
        KcF6 cytotoxic effect with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mAb226</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4b</NUMEX>) confirms the
        relationship between the peptide-induced cytotoxic event
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR2</ENAMEX> because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>'s specificity for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX>.
        Overall, these data indicate that the surface topology of
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TNFR2</NUMEX> binding site is very complex and may be composed
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple hotspots</ENAMEX> capable of different regulatory
        functions.
      
      
        Discussion
        Peptide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> have been successfully used for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">identifying</ENAMEX> novel peptides mimicing natural molecules in
        terms of the critical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> interactions involved
        in biological activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanofsky et al.</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] described a
        peptide antagonist to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-1</ENAMEX> that was active in the nM range
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wrighton et al.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livnah et al.</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX> ] identified
        peptides binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">erythropoietin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EPO</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> with
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> agonist activity 
        in vivo . Neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EPO</ENAMEX> agonist nor
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> antagonist peptides show any significant sequence
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homology</ENAMEX> to the natural ligand suggesting that they act as
        mimics of the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligand</ENAMEX>. In the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EPO</ENAMEX>
        agonists, X-ray crystallographic analysis revealed that one
        of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptides</ENAMEX> spontaneously formed non-covalent
        homodimers that allowed the dimerization of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EPO</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of small peptides binding to the
        human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">thrombopoietin receptor</ENAMEX> (TPOR) were isolated that
        competed with the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligand TPO</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . The peptide
        with the highest affinity was subsequently dimerized and
        shown to function as a potent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TPO</ENAMEX> agonist 
        in vivo . Recently, a small,
        non-peptide organic molecule binding to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">EPO receptor</ENAMEX> was multimerized and shown to mimic the
        biological activities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EPO</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] .
        In this report we show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPLs</ENAMEX> can be isolated that
        bind to human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFR2</ENAMEX> at its ligand-binding site and
        subdivide it into multiple hotspots. All of the peptides
        were competed by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ²</ENAMEX> implying they
        recognized a hotspot that mapped either within or at least
        overlapping the ligand-binding domain of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX>. The HSPLs
        KcC7, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcD11</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcF6</TIMEX> but not KcF12 were also inhibited by the
        neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody mAb226</ENAMEX> suggesting the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mers but not
        KcF12 interact with a hotspot overlapping with the one
        recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. The fact that recombinant KcF12
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peptide</ENAMEX> competed all of the phage expressed peptides (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) indicated that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peptides</ENAMEX> also recognize a common
        hotspot which may be the one responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> ligand
        binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. In addition, the biological data
        suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KcD11</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">binds</ENAMEX> to a hotspot that can be further
        separated from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcF12</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcF6 and KcC7</TIMEX>. While we cannot rule
        out possible allosteric interactions between the peptides,
        the data suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPLs</ENAMEX> were able to dissect the
        ligand-binding region of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNFR2</ENAMEX> into several structural
        and/or functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hotspots</ENAMEX>. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPLs</ENAMEX> were
        specific for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX> unlike the native <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ligands</ENAMEX> TNF-Î± and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î² which bind to both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. These results
        demonstrate that the approach has the ability to dissect
        critical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> interaction domains in terms of
        both structural and functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>. Using a similar
        approach, we recently reported on the subdivision of the
        ligand binding domain on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin receptor</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        separate and non-overlapping hotspots with different
        biological activities [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] .
        It has been shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> induced proliferation of the
        undifferentiated neuroblastoma cell line, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK-N</ENAMEX>-BE, resulted
        from activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR2</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . Proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK-N</ENAMEX>-BE
        cells could be suppressed by the pre-incubation of cells
        with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TNFR2</NUMEX> blocking antibodies without concomitant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX> (data not shown). While all of the peptides
        blocked the agonist effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> indicating that they
        can act as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcC7</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KcF6 and KcF12</TIMEX> by themselves
        induced a cytotoxic response by killing SK-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-BE cells in
        the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>. This is surprising because these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptides</ENAMEX> share a hotspot with the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligand</ENAMEX> TNFÎ±
        (which is proliferative rather than-cytotoxic) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KcC7</ENAMEX> and
        KcF6 bind to a hotspot common to the neutralizing but
        non-cytotoxic, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody mAb226</ENAMEX>. Overall, these data suggest
        that activation (agonism or cytotoxicity) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR2</ENAMEX> is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mediated</ENAMEX> through unique hotspots on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> that can
        be defined by the peptides. Under the present experimental
        conditions, it is unclear whether the natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX>,
        touches the hotspot responsible for cytotoxicity although
        one can speculate that, if it does, the cytotoxic effect
        might be nullified by the sum of the natural
        ligand:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor interactions</ENAMEX>. Competition experiments
        showing that mAb <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">226</NUMEX> reversed the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">KcC7</ENAMEX> and KcF6
        confirm that these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> peptides induce their effects though
        their interaction with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX>. These findings suggest that
        TNFR2 has multiple biological functions. In addition to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transferring TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> to TNFR1 as proposed by the ligand
        passing model [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TNFR2</TIMEX> may have a role in modulating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proliferative</ENAMEX> responses in both positive and negative
        manner. Ongoing studies will attempt to elucidate the
        mechanism of action behind the phenomenon such as the
        effects on downstream signaling pathways including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFkB</ENAMEX>,
        and apoptosis. However, it is possible that peptide-induced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytotoxicity</ENAMEX> works through a mechanism similar to TNF
        mediated apoptosis in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] .
      
      
        Conclusions
        In summary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPLs</ENAMEX> were isolated with which we were able
        to dissect the ligand-binding domain of a natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>
        and generate information about novel and unexpected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bioactivities</ENAMEX>. This technology has also been successfully
        used for known protein <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNF-Î²</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] as well as non-protein
        targets such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNAs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . We have also
        shown that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> identify hotspots on novel
        genes of unknown function and identify functional
        interaction pathways (manuscript in preparation). Overall,
        the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPLs</ENAMEX> have the potential to become a general
        approach for scanning and understanding complex
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein interactions</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Materials
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> , strain TG1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genotype</ENAMEX> =
          K12Î” 
          (lac-pro), supE, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">hsdÎ”5/F</ENAMEX>' [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">traD36</TIMEX>,
          proAB , 
          lacI 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">q ,</ENAMEX> 
          lacZÎ”M15 ]) was obtained from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>). Recombinant human Tumor
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Necrosis Factor-Î±</ENAMEX> (rhTNFÎ±) was purchased from R&D
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PeproTech Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>). Monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against recombinant
          human soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF</ENAMEX> receptor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">mAb225</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RII</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">mAb226</NUMEX>)
          were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems, Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WST-1</ENAMEX> was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>).
          125I-TNFÎ± (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NEX 257</NUMEX>) with a specific activity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼Ci/Î¼g</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1698 Ci/mmol</ENAMEX>) was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEN Life Science</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Products, Inc</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beckman Ready Safeâ„</ENAMEX>¢
          scintillation fluid was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckman Coulter</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fullerton</ENAMEX>, CA). MultiSreenâ„¢ assay filter plate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">MultiScreen Â®MAFC filter plates</ENAMEX> were
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millipore</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> media, fetal
          bovine serum, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GlutaMAXâ„</ENAMEX>¢-I were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polyvinylpyrrolidone</ENAMEX> (PVP),
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tween-20Râ„¢</TIMEX>, phosphate-buffered saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>), and
          calcium or magnesium) were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Chemical</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). All other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> and reagents
          used were analytical grade.
        
        
          Cell Culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK-N</ENAMEX>-BE neuroblastoma cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jurkat</ENAMEX> (TIB-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">152</NUMEX>) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiyoye</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCL-87</ENAMEX>) cells were obtained from the ATCC
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manassas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK-N</ENAMEX>-BE and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat</ENAMEX> cells were maintained
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> media supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX> (FBS) and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">GlutaMAXâ„¢-I</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jiyoye</ENAMEX> cells were
          maintained in RPMI <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> media supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> FBS
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GlutaMAXâ„¢.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Design of the Primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peptide Libraries</ENAMEX>
          A description of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> design and production has
          been previously published [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3 28</ENAMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subtractive Panning and ELISA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panning</ENAMEX> was done as described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3 28</ENAMEX> ] , except that
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well microtiter plate were coated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">target</ENAMEX> at concentrations ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-100
          ng/well. The cross reactive phages from the eluted phage
          were then subtracted by panning sequentially against
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ²</ENAMEX> as a way to obtain peptides
          specific to the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> was done as
          previous described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3 28</ENAMEX> ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phage Competition ELISA Studies</ENAMEX>
          Target was coated on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MaxiSorp</ENAMEX> plates and blocked with
          NFM-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> as described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3 28</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HSPLs</ENAMEX> (phage clones or
          synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX>) are added in the presence of varying
          concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> ligand or soluble
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">receptor</ENAMEX>). IC 
          50 s are determined by probing for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phage</ENAMEX> or peptide binding to target in the presence of
          competitor.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Receptor Binding</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Competition</ENAMEX> Assay
          The binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFÎ±</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TNFR2</NUMEX> on intact cells was
          measured in a radioareceptor assay using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat</ENAMEX> and
          Jiyoye cells and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MultiSreenâ„</ENAMEX>¢ assay filter plate
          system as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> analysis was performed
          with an add-in for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Excel, Xlfitâ„¢</ENAMEX> (version <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.0</NUMEX>)
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ID Business Solutions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guildford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>), which allows
          curve fitting using nonlinear regression. To determine
          binding kinetic parameters, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>-Parameter logistic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">equation y = Bottom +</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top - Bottom</ENAMEX>)/(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> + (IC 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 /x</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> slope) was used to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">calculate IC</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> values and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> slopes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          i values were calculated according to
          the equation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          i = IC 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 /</ENAMEX>(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> + [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligand</ENAMEX>]/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          d ), as described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheng</ENAMEX> and Prusoff
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Proliferation cell assay
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK-N</ENAMEX>-BE cells were seeded loosely in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96</TIMEX> well plates in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK-N</ENAMEX>-BE medium and allowed to grow to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75-80%</NUMEX> confluency.
          Cells were starved overnight in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> serum
          before each cell experiment. Briefly, cells were first
          treated with a human TNFR1 blocking mAb, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mAb225</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ug/ml</ENAMEX>), for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> C prior to the addition
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> used in the cell experiment were
          serial diluted at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:2</TIMEX> and mixed in a separate plate
          before transferring into the actual cell plate. The
          starting highest final concentration of each peptide was
          at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 uM</TIMEX> or at its highest possible concentration. Cells
          were then returned into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40-45</NUMEX> hrs
          before the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/10</NUMEX> vol of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WST-1</ENAMEX>. The plates were
          further incubated and developed according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instruction.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' Contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KcH</ENAMEX> isolated and characterized the HSPLs binding to
        TNFR2. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RB</ENAMEX> prepared the primary and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">secondary</NUMEX> HSPL
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">libraries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PW</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ML</ENAMEX> produced and purified the recombinant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptides</ENAMEX> and performed the stability studies with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptides</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VR</ENAMEX> did the binding assays. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX> contributed
        helpful suggestions about the design of the studies. NG
        conceived the study and participated in the design and
        coordination of the experiments. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> have read and
        approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
