
  
    
      
        Background
        The adult mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ovary</ENAMEX> is a complex tissue composed
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> fundamental cell types: the oocytes, granulosa,
        interstitial, and corpora luteal cells. Within this basic
        quartet are many other cell types such as the ovary surface
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epithelium</ENAMEX> and blood vessels in addition to the classic
        subtypes of granulosa (membrana, periantral, cumulus, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corona</ENAMEX> radiata), theca (interna and externa), and luteal
        cells (granulosa and theca lutein). The coordinated control
        of proliferation, differentiation, and apoptosis in these
        cell types is the underlying basis for primate and
        non-primate menstrual and estrous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX>, respectively. The
        process by which each cell type obtains its state of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> is the subject of intense study. The role
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> in this process is clear; however, new results
        indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autocrine</ENAMEX>/paracrine or growth factor
        mechanisms also have important roles.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone morphogenetic protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> including
        ligands, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, and binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, has emerged as a
        central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in ovary physiology and female fertility [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
        ] . The BMPs represent a large subclass of the transforming
        growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-β</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF-β</ENAMEX>) surperfamily of ligands whose
        biological responses are mediated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser/Thr</ENAMEX> kinase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> via the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Smad</ENAMEX>-signaling molecules [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . The
        mRNAs encoding several BMP family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have been
        identified in the murine ovary, including the ligands,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] ,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7 8</NUMEX> ] , the BMP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] and the BMP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding protein</ENAMEX>, follistatin (FS) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . In the murine,
        BMP<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-4</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-7</NUMEX> mRNA have been identified in the theca
        interstitial cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-15</NUMEX> in oocytes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6 7</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX> in oocytes and granulosa
        cells (GCs) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> in granulosa and lutein cells [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 10</NUMEX> ] .
        The direct involvement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX> system in regulating
        ovary function has been established. 
        In vitro experiments with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> GCs
        have demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-7</NUMEX> inhibit and stimulate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FSH-induced progesterone</ENAMEX> and estradiol production,
        respectively [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . In related studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX>
        were found to block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> action through inhibiting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX>-dependent adenylate cyclase activity and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FSH</ENAMEX> receptor
        expression, respectively [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] . The importance of
        these findings is underscored by the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> action
        is obligatory for normal folliculogenesis and female
        fertility. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-15</NUMEX>, but not BMP<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-6</ENAMEX> have
        stimulatory effects on GC <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX>, indicating they
        may play a mitogenic role in follicle growth [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 12 13</ENAMEX> ] .
        The importance of this finding is underscored by the fact
        that the control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> proliferation is crucial for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">follicle</ENAMEX> dominance and atresia. Equally important, other
        studies have shown that loss-of-function and naturally
        occurring mutations in BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with dysregulation of folliculogenesis and
        ovulation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15 16 17 18 19</NUMEX> ] . Of particular interest is
        the finding that ewes having a mutation in the 
        bmp15 gene in both alleles are
        infertile whereas the heterozygotes are superfertile [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ]
        . Thus, the 
        bmp15 gene can control ovulation
        quota through a dosage-sensitive mechanism. Evidence that a
        mutation at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ser/Thr</ENAMEX> kinase domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> leads to
        high fecundity in ewes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18 19</NUMEX> ] provides further
        support that BMP signaling pathways play a key role in
        specifying ovary function.
        Although it is becoming clear that intrinsic BMPs are
        important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the ovary, the cellular localization
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX> in the ovary is poorly understood, and a proper
        understanding of how the cell-specific expression of the
        BMP system changes during the cycle is still lacking. As
        part of our ongoing investigations of the roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX> in
        ovary physiology, we have analyzed the spatiotemporal
        expression patterns of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX> system in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> ovary cell
        types during the normal estrous cycle.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>
          Adult female <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sprague</ENAMEX>-Dawley <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-3 months of age</TIMEX>)
          were housed (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> per cage) in isolation under
          controlled lighting conditions (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">14 h</NUMEX> of light, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> hr of
          darkness; lights on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 0500 to 1900</TIMEX> h) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23°C</TIMEX> and
          provided formulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat chow</ENAMEX> and water 
          ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libitum</ENAMEX> . Vaginal smears were
          taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, and rats exhibiting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or more</NUMEX> consecutive
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">estrous cycles</ENAMEX> were used. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> at each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of the cycle) were sacrificed on proestrus (P1000
          and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> h), estrus (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E0200</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E1000 h</ENAMEX>), diestrus I (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DI</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1100 h</ENAMEX>) and diestrus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DII</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1100</TIMEX> h). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rats</ENAMEX> were
          handled in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH Guide for the Care</ENAMEX> and
          Use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratory Animals</ENAMEX>, and the protocols were
          approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Subjects Committee</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Plasmid construction for synthesizing
          riboprobes
          Probes for 
          in situ hybridization studies were
          made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> from adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat ovaries</ENAMEX> was
          prepared and single-stranded cDNA was synthesized by
          reverse transcriptase and then subjected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] . To design primers for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>,
          DNA sequence information was first collected from GenBank
          and primers for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> were designed based on standard
          guidelines. All sequence information was derived from rat
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cDNA</ENAMEX> clones except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-7</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX>
          whose cDNA sequences in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> have not been deposited into
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX>. However, because cDNA sequences in human and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> are available from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX>, we designed the PCR
          primers by choosing the homologous DNA sequence regions
          between human and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse homologues</ENAMEX>. Specifically, these
          primers are derived from the cDNA clones at the following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">nucleotide</ENAMEX> numbers: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#511 - #528 and #1066 - #</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1083</TIMEX>
          (accession number of the cDNA clone is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M22489</TIMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX>-2
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] ; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#923 - #942 and #1341 - #1360</NUMEX> (accession number
          D63860) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kangawa</ENAMEX>, unpublished); <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#878 - #897</NUMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#1292 - #1311</NUMEX> (accession number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">D49494</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ]
          ; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#737 - #757 and #1181 - #1200</NUMEX> (accession number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Z22607</NUMEX>)
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] ; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#6 - #25 and #475 - #494</NUMEX> (accession
          number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">U66298</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knittel et al.</ENAMEX>, unpublished);
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#497 - 514 and #865 - #882</NUMEX> (accession number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">X56906</NUMEX>) for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] ; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#441 - #460 and #876 - #895</NUMEX> (accession
          number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">D38082</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] ; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#528 - #547 and #965</NUMEX>
          - <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#984</NUMEX> (accession number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">U89326</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astrom et</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al.</ENAMEX>, unpublished); <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#525 - #544 and #895 - #904</NUMEX> (accession
          number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">AF003942</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . These primers were
          selected from different exons of the corresponding genes
          to discriminate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products that might arise from
          possible chromosome <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA contaminants</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products
          were cloned into pBluescript <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK</ENAMEX>+ and their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequences
          confirmed. The plasmid containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FS</ENAMEX> was constructed by
          sub-cloning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XbaI-PstI</ENAMEX> fragment derived for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> FS
          cDNA clone [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pROF304</ENAMEX> into pBluescript <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SK</ENAMEX>+.
        
        
          In situ hybridization
          Ovaries were fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4°C</TIMEX>,
          washed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, dehydrated and embedded in paraffin. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX>
          consecutive sections (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">8 μm</ENAMEX>) were cut from each ovary and
          mounted onto poly-L-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">lysine</NUMEX>-coated glass slides. The
          sections were digested with proteinase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>, acetylated,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">washed</ENAMEX> and dehydrated as previously described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 26</NUMEX> ] .
          Anti-sense and sense cRNA probes were prepared by means
          of 
          in vitro transcription using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T3</ENAMEX> or
          T7 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA polymerase</ENAMEX>. Hybridization was carried out with the
          35S-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> probe (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-6 × 10 6cpm/ml</ENAMEX>) in a solution
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">vol/vol</ENAMEX>) deionized formamide, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M NaCl</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.2</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast tRNA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM
          dithiothreitol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> × <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denhardt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> dextran
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sulfate</ENAMEX>. Hybridization <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 μl</NUMEX>) was placed over
          each section and covered with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60 × 22</NUMEX> mm <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid washed</ENAMEX>,
          siliconized coverslip. Coverslips were sealed with liquid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DPX</ENAMEX>. Sections were hybridized for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> h at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58-60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> in a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humidified</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>. After hybridization, the sections
          were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ribonuclease A</ENAMEX> and washed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> mM
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">NaCl/1.5</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">citrate</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60-62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dehydrated</ENAMEX> slides were exposed to X-ray film for several
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. After adequate X-ray film images were obtained, the
          ovary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were treated with xylene, rinsed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ethanol</ENAMEX>, air dried, and then coated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> NTB-2
          liquid autoradiograph emulsion. Slides were exposed for
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 C</NUMEX> in a linedesiccated dark box. After
          exposure, the slides were developed (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">D19</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3.5 min</NUMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 C</NUMEX>), rinsed briefly in distilled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and fixed. After
          washing in distilled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX>, slides were lightly
          counterstained with hematoxylin and eosin.
          After an autoradiography and counterstaining, the
          sections were analyzed microscopically. The 
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">situ</ENAMEX> experiments were performed
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times for each BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. The intensity
          of the hybridization signals were determined as
          previously reported [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27 28</NUMEX> ] . A subjective
          comparison of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> sections from each ovary from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals hybridized</ENAMEX> with the same concentrations of sense
          and antisense cRNAs and exposed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same time</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>) was made. The hybridization signal was estimated
          on a scale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>+ to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>+ as originally described by Meunier
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] : +, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver grains sparse</ENAMEX>, but positive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization; ++</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver grains</ENAMEX> are numerous but do not
          cover the cell type in question; +++, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver grains</ENAMEX> are
          very numerous and begin to merge in some places; ++++,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver grains</ENAMEX> are very dense and form a near uniform mass
          above the cell type in question; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+/-</ENAMEX>, there was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterogeneity</ENAMEX> in the hybridization signal, e.g., some of
          the histological units contained a signal, others did
          not; -, no detectable hybridization signal. The slides
          were analyzed simultaneously by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and the
          results confirmed independently by another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>. In
          each experiment, tissues hybridized with the sense probe
          were used as the negative control. In all cases, the
          sense probes showed no specific hybridization to the
          adult ovaries above background (see for example <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1C).
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> mRNA
          In adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat ovaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> is highly expressed
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> of atretic follicles and at relatively high
          levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC of Graafian</ENAMEX> follicles (GF) and some
          corpora lutea (CL) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A,1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> is
          also expressed at lower levels in the secondary
          interstitial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (SIC) and theca interstitial cells
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIC</ENAMEX>) but undetectable in other ovary cell types (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was constitutively expressed
          at low to moderate levels over the cycle. A weak variable
          expression was sometimes seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
          In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> is expressed in a precise
          manner, indicating that gene activity is regulated during
          follicle development. A weak hybridization signal was
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> detected in some GC of early primary follicles,
          consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> gene activation during recruitment.
          As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">folliculogenesis</ENAMEX> progressed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> mRNA expression
          increased rapidly reaching maximal levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> of
          secondary follicles. The expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was
          heterogeneous. In preantral follicles, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> mRNA
          expression was confined mainly to the membrana GC with
          little or no expression in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corona radiata GC</ENAMEX> next to
          the oocyte (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,1</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX>). This indicates that the GC
          become functionally diverse very early in follicle
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, i.e. about the time the follicle has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
          layers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>. As the follicle undergoes its development
          to the preovulatory stage (i.e. from selection at E <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0200</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX> through ovulation at E <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0200</TIMEX> h the next cycle), the
          membrana, but not the cumulus and periantral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>, express
          high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1F,1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>). These findings
          indicate that the oocyte may regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> gene
          expression by a morphogen gradient mechanism. Finally the
          highest levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> in the ovary were seen in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> of atretic follicles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1H,1I).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> mRNA expression in the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follicle</ENAMEX> was
          rapidly down-regulated following ovulation. As such,
          there was no detectable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> in the new CL-I during
          luteinization i.e. E <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">2000 h to DI 1100 h</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1J,1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>).
          The message was re-expressed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DII</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1100</TIMEX> h (luteolysis)
          with strong hybridization for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> appearing in clusters
          of endothelial cells scattered throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CL-I</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1A<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,1</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B,1L,1M</ENAMEX>). This correlation suggests a possible
          function for endothelial-derived <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> in luteolysis
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1N).
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-3b</ENAMEX> mRNA
          The hybridization signal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3</ENAMEX> was relatively weak
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ovaries</TIMEX> examined (data not shown). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3</ENAMEX> mRNA
          expression was present in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIC</ENAMEX> of healthy Graafian
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">follicles</ENAMEX> and in the theca lutein cells (TLC) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CL-I</ENAMEX>
          at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DI 1100 h</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). This is consistent with a role
          for theca-derived <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3</ENAMEX> in regulating the dominant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">follicle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>.
          A strong expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was seen in some
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ovaries</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">folliculogenesis</TIMEX>, the theca
          cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>) of the theca interna (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>) and externa (TE) of
          dominant follicles strongly expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2A<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,2</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B,2C</ENAMEX>). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>, the expression appeared mainly in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIC</ENAMEX> located nearest the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2C). After ovulation
          the signal was reduced. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CL-I</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was
          expressed at low to moderate levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TLC</ENAMEX> and TE
          cells during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">luteinization</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,2</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX>). Little or no
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was evident in degenerating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2A,2<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). Interestingly, there was high expression in the
          ovary surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">epithelium</ENAMEX> (OSE) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2F), and in the
          epithelial cells of the sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cords</ENAMEX> (SC) located in the
          hilum of the ovary (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2G). In atretic follicles <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-</ENAMEX>3b
          mRNA expression was undetectable (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2H,2I).
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> mRNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was expressed in a variety of ovary cell
          types with the highest levels appearing in the theca, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> and endothelium of some blood vessels (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B,3C</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was constitutively expressed
          at high levels in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3C) and the
          endothelium lining the large sinusoids in the mesovarium
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3D). A weak hybridization signal was occasionally
          seen in some oocytes of primary follicles, but it was
          rare.
          In the theca, the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> mRNA change during
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">folliculogenesis</ENAMEX>. A weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> signal was first
          detectable in primary follicles, being localized to a few
          stroma fibroblasts near the basal lamina. This finding is
          consistent with the intriguing idea that the theca may
          begin to develop very early in preantral
          folliculogenesis, i.e. during the initial steps of
          primary follicle development. In secondary follicles,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was present at moderate levels in an outer
          layer of flattened cells (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX>) and in a subset of TIC
          adjacent to these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3E,3F<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was
          expressed at high levels in the theca of developing
          dominant follicles, again being localized to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adjacent TIC (Fig</ENAMEX>. 3H,3I<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>). Unlike healthy follicles,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was very low or undetectable in atretic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">follicles</ENAMEX>. High levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> continue to be
          expressed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">luteogenes</TIMEX>, i.e.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luteinization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E 0200</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">h</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DI 1100 h</ENAMEX>), and luteolysis
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DII</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1100</TIMEX> h to E <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0200</TIMEX> h the next cycle) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3K,3<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>). A
          potentially important finding is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSE</ENAMEX> covering
          the ovulated follicle and newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>-I expressed
          high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> while little or no <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> mRNA
          was detected in other areas of the surface epithelium
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3M,3<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,3</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>). This is consistent with a role for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX>-4
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSE</ENAMEX> regeneration following ovulation.
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> mRNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was present in the oocytes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>, blood
          vessels and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A,4<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). In the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vascular</ENAMEX> system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was continuously expressed at
          relatively high levels in the endothelial cells of some
          large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arteries</ENAMEX> and veins in the medulla (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4C). Thus
          BMP<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-6</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX>, could have a role in ovarian blood
          circulation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> mRNA showed relatively high expression
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSE</ENAMEX> throughout the cycle, suggesting a general,
          non-regulated role for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSE</ENAMEX> and/or adjacent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tissues</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A,4<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>).
          The expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> in oocytes was
          developmentally regulated. There was no detectable BMP-6
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> in primordial and primary follicles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>);
          however a weak hybridization signal was detected in
          oocytes of early secondary follicles when the second
          layer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCs</ENAMEX> was forming (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4D). Thereafter,
          expression increased sharply and was maximal in oocytes
          after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> layer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> had developed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4E<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>).
          High levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> were present in oocytes of all
          Graafian follicles, both healthy and atretic (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          4A,4B<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E,4F</ENAMEX>,4<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>,4H<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I,4J</ENAMEX>). The developmental changes in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oocyte</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> mRNA expression showed no obvious cyclic
          variation.
          Like oocytes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was first detected in the GC
          at the early <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">secondary</NUMEX> stage. Expression increased as the
          follicle grew and was maximal after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> layer of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> had formed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E,4F</ENAMEX>). In the preantral
          follicles, only the membrana <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX>,
          consistent with a role of the oocyte in regulating GC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4E<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was not
          detectable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> of dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">follicles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4G,4<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>).
          This loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> mRNA became evident soon after
          selection at E <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0200</TIMEX> h, and continued through dominant
          follicle development. This suggests the inhibition of GC
          BMP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> gene activity may be required for the formation of
          dominant follicles. The finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> is
          strongly expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">atresia</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4I<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>) is
          consistent with this idea. It is notable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> mRNA
          was expressed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CL-I</ENAMEX> from ovulation
          throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">luteolysis</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A,4B<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> mRNA
          As with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX>, relatively high expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX>-7
          mRNA was identified in the theca, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX> 1and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,5</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B,5C</ENAMEX>). A specific pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> expression
          was identified in the theca during folliculogenesis and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luteogenesis</ENAMEX>. The theca of developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">follicles</ENAMEX> first
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">exhibited BMP-7</ENAMEX> mRNA when the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> layer of GC
          appeared, i.e. at the primary/secondary follicle
          transition (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Subsequent follicle growth was
          accompanied by increased <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> mRNA expression which
          reached high levels in the theca of dominant follicles
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,5</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX>). An intriguing feature of theca <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> mRNA
          expression is that it restricted to the inner most layer,
          being present in a subset of fibroblast-like cells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">juxtaposed</ENAMEX> to the basal lamina and a sub-population of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adjacent TIC (Fig</ENAMEX>. 5D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,5</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E,5F</ENAMEX>). Notably, this pattern of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theca</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> mRNA expression is just the opposite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX>-4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> whose expression is limited to the outer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theca</ENAMEX>. These observations are consistent with the novel
          concept that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIC</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> represent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> classes
          based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX> mRNAs that they expressed. As atresia
          occurs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> is rapidly decreased to low or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undetectable</ENAMEX> levels, indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> is a marker
          for healthy follicles.
          Following ovulation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was expressed in
          moderate amounts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TLC</ENAMEX> of the newly formed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CL-I</ENAMEX> from E <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1000 h to DI 1100 h</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5A,5B<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,5</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>), however
          after the initiation of luteolysis at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DII</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1100</TIMEX> h, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX>-7
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mRNA</ENAMEX> becomes undetectable. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> transcripts are
          down-regulated in both the luteolytic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> and apoptotic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">follicles</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> mRNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> mRNA expression was strictly germ cell specific
          and was developmentally regulated during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">normal</TIMEX>
          folliculogenesis over the estrous cycle (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          6A,6<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> was absent in oocytes of primordial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">follicles</ENAMEX>. When the squamous GC start to become cuboidal
          a weak hybridization signal was detected in the oocyte
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6C), indicating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> gene activation is closely
          correlated with recruitment. Low levels of expression
          were seen throughout the growth of the primary follicle,
          but began to increase when a second layer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forming</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6D). As follicle development proceeded, the
          expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> mRNA increased dramatically and very
          high near maximal levels were seen after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> layer
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> had formed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6E). Expression was maintained at
          high levels from this stage through ovulation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6F).
          It is notable that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> mRNA levels appeared to
          decrease during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">atresia</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6G). The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> in
          the cycle did not appear to affect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX>
          expression.
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX> mRNA
          The BMPR-IA mRNA was ubiquitously expressed in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">adult rat ovary</ENAMEX>, indicating a broad function in a variety
          of ovary cell types during the cycle (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          7A,7<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). The highest expression was in the oocytes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>,
          theca, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>, with the greatest concentrations appearing
          in developing oocytes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Constitutively low to
          moderate expression was seen in the vascular system, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIC</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
          The potential importance of oocyte BMPR-IA mRNA is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illustrated</ENAMEX> by its continuous expression throughout the
          course of oogenesis as it occurs within the adult ovary.
          A weak hybridization signal could be identified in
          primordial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">follicles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7C). In the early stages of
          primary follicle development the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX> mRNA
          in the oocyte increased and were maximal in late
          preantral follicles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7D, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7F</TIMEX>). During the development
          of the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follicle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX> mRNA was abundantly
          expressed but the signal appeared weaker than in the
          secondary follicles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7G,7<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>). In atretic follicles,
          BMPR-IA mRNA was highly expressed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7I<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,7</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX>).
          In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7C,7D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,7</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>,7<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>) the pattern of BMPR-IA
          mRNA expression during folliculogenesis was similar to
          that found in developing oocytes. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>, moderate amounts
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX> mRNA were expressed as it underwent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luteinization</ENAMEX> and luteolysis. In the theca, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX> mRNA
          expression was not notable, except for a stage-specific
          increase among the early tertiary follicles at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> h
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7E<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,7</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> mRNA
          The expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> mRNA was strong in oocytes,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8A<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,8</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B,8C</ENAMEX>). There was also
          expression in the theca, vascular, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIC</ENAMEX> tissues, but
          at lower levels. In blood vessels, the BMPR-IB mRNA was
          moderately expressed in the tunica adventitia of the
          ovarian <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arteries</ENAMEX>, suggesting a role for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX> in the
          ovary arterial system (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8D). In the theca, some TIC
          and TE cells showed BMPR-IB expression with the highest
          levels appearing in dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">follicles</ENAMEX> at proestrus
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8A,8B<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,8</NUMEX>H<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,8</NUMEX>I).
          As with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX>, the message for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> was clearly
          visible in oocytes of primordial and primary follicles
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8E). At the primary/secondary follicle transition,
          a sharp increase in oocyte BMPR-IB mRNA expression
          occurred (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8G). High expression was observed in all
          dominant follicles. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> there were also clear
          follicle stage-specific shifts in BMPR-IB mRNA
          expression. BMPR-IB mRNA was first detected in some
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cuboidal GC</ENAMEX> of newly recruited primary follicles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          8E<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,8</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>). The formation of a second layer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> at the
          primary/secondary follicle transition was marked by a
          sharp increase in BMPR-IB mRNA expression in all the GC
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8G). The entire mass of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> in developing dominant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">follicles</ENAMEX> strongly expressed BMPR-IB mRNA (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          8A,8B<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,8</NUMEX>H<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,8</NUMEX>I). Cells in atretic follicles (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> and oocyte)
          continued to show high expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> mRNA (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          8J,8<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>).
          There was a marked decrease in BMPR-IB mRNA following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ovulation</ENAMEX>, whereby little or no expression was evident in
          the CL-I during the luteinization i.e. E <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0200</TIMEX> h to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DI</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1100</TIMEX> h (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). However, when luteolysis was initiated
          at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DII</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1100</TIMEX> h, the BMPR-IB mRNA is expressed in the TE
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8L,8<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>). Then at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> h, there was strong BMPR-IB
          expression in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of endothelial
          cells scattered throughout the luteolytic <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CL-I</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          8N,8<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX> mRNA
          Over the cycle, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> expressed the highest levels of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX> mRNA, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>, and the vascular
          endothelium showing low variable levels of expression
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9A,9<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). Although the oocytes of most
          follicles showed no hybridization signal above
          background, a weak expression was consistently seen in
          some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oocytes</ENAMEX> of primary and early secondary follicles
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9C). There was no detectable <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX> mRNA
          expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> of the primordial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">follicles</ENAMEX>; however, a
          low expression was detected in primary follicles after
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recruitment</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9C). During preantral follicle growth,
          expression increased reaching high maximal levels in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> of secondary follicles (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9A,9<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). High expression
          was seen in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> of the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follicle</ENAMEX>, except
          at ovulation when there appeared to be a decrease in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX> mRNA within the cumulus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,9</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovulation</ENAMEX> was accompanied by a rapid decrease in the
          levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX> mRNA. During the life of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>, low to
          moderate expression was seen in the lutein, but not the
          endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9H). <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">BMPR-II</ENAMEX> mRNA was strongly
          expressed in all GC during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">atresia</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 9F,9<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> mRNA
          The message for the BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antagonist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX>, was highly
          expressed during the estrous cycle, being present in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 10A,10<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). It is notable
          that a striking change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> mRNA expression occurred in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIC</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the preovulatory period</TIMEX>. In all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIC</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> mRNA was absent during most of the cycle, but at P
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> h, it was very strongly expressed (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          10C,10D<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,10</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX>). This observation suggests a burst of FS
          gene activity that may be associated with the
          preovulatory surge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">proestrus</TIMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folliculogenesis</ENAMEX> and luteogenesis were accompanied by
          striking changes in FS expression some of which were
          cycle dependent. During the preantral stages of
          folliculogenesis, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> mRNA was poorly expressed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>.
          By comparison FS mRNA was highly expressed in all the GC
          of the dominant follicles over the cycle (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          10A,10<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). Then, during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">atresia</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> mRNA was low or absent
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> gene activity and follicle
          dominance appear to be physiologically coupled. After
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ovulation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> showed high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> mRNA
          expression during luteinization at E <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0200</TIMEX> h and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E 1000</ENAMEX> h
          and moderate levels at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DI 1100 h</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          10F,10<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>,10H<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,10</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I,10J</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,10</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>). The high expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> mRNA
          correlates with a high expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX> by the
          new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CL-I. Interestingly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> mRNA fell to non-detectable
          levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CL-I</ENAMEX> when luteolysis occurred at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">DII 1100 h</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 10L,10<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> remained undetectable in the CL
          until P <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> h when high expression was induced in a
          subset of lutein cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 10N,10<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>). This high
          expression in the luteolytic CL-I persisted through
          estrous of the next cycle.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        To better understand the physiological role of the BMP
        family in ovarian function, the spatiotemporal expression
        patterns of a number of relevant BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>,
        and a binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were determined by in situ
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> ovaries over the estrous cycle. The
        general principle to emerge from our data is that the
        developmental programs of folliculogenesis (recruitment,
        selection, and atresia), ovulation and luteogenesis
        (luteinization and luteolysis) are accompanied by precise
        cell-specific changes in the expression of the genes
        encoding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Therefore, we hypothesize the
        regulated expression of BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> activity forms a part of
        the controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> that ensures the proper timing of
        the developmental events that generates a normal estrous
        cycle.
        The finding that the genes encoding the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> types of
        BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are expressed in primordial follicles
        indicates that these fundamental reproductive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> are
        targets for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX>. In this regard, we have shown
        recently that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> can promote primordial follicle growth
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . Thus, it is reasonable to propose that one
        function of the BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in the primordial follicle
        might be to mediate the activation of recruitment by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX>. As there is no evidence that primordial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">follicles</ENAMEX> express BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ligands</ENAMEX>, the mechanism by which this
        activation occurs would be paracrine, most likely involving
        BMP<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-7</ENAMEX> from adjacent tissues such as the theca, secondary
        interstitial, or sex cords.
        Unlike lower vertebrates, the developing mammalian
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">follicle</ENAMEX> is composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> layer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
        the most important concepts generated in the ovary BMP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oocyte</ENAMEX> derived <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GDF-9</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] plays a role in
        the mechanisms governing the development of the second
        layer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> i.e. the primary /secondary follicle
        transition. The question of how <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GDF-9</ENAMEX> controls this step
        has yet to be answered. Our data show that the
        primary/secondary transition stage is accompanied by some
        rather dramatic changes in BMP expression including
        increased expression of: i) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR IB</ENAMEX> in
        the oocyte; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ii) BMP-2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-IB and -II</ENAMEX> in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>; and iii) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> in the theca. Because
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">folliculogenesis</ENAMEX> in the murine proceeds to the preovulatory
        stage in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] , and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] , one can assume that the marked increases
        in these regulatory molecules are not essential for the
        development of a second layer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>. The question of
        whether the increased expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">BMPR -II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-4</NUMEX>,
        and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-7</NUMEX> contribute to this important developmental event
        remains to be answered. One interesting implication of our
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> data is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> have already attained different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of differentiation by the early stages of secondary
        follicle development Based on previous work [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX> ] , it
        is not unreasonable to propose that oocyte morphogens may
        have control over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> fate beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early</TIMEX> as the
        primary/secondary follicle transition. It will be
        interesting to investigate how this phenomenon fits into
        the mechanisms underlying the primary/secondary follicle
        transition.
        Our results demonstrate for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that the
        theca interna of healthy follicles is composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of theca interstitial cells (TIC). One
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>, which expresses <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX>, is present as an outer layer
        of cells juxtaposed to the theca externa (TE), and another,
        which expresses <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX>, is present at the proximal side of
        the theca interna near the basal lamina of the follicle.
        These differences can be found throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">folliculogenesis</TIMEX>,
        beginning during the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">secondary</NUMEX> stage. This, together with
        the failure to detect <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> in the theca of atretic
        follicles, supports the idea that the cellular sites and
        coordinate expression of these BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> may have important
        regulatory roles in maintaining folliculogenesis. In this
        regard, a recent study has demonstrated the ability of
        BMP<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-4</ENAMEX> to inhibit cyclic AMP-stimulated androgen production
        by the cultured human theca cell line, presumably by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activating</ENAMEX> BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> (BMPR-IA, -IB, and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-II</ENAMEX>) which are
        expressed in these cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . Because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">theca</ENAMEX> derived
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">androgen</ENAMEX> is required for follicle estrogen biosynthesis and
        has been implicated in ovary pathology [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] , it will be
        interesting to determine how the expression and functions
        of these TIC-specific BMPs are integrated into the overall
        processes of physiology and pathophysiology. Besides the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>, a high level of BMP expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) is found
        within the smooth muscle cells of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> during the process
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">follicle</ENAMEX> formation. Very little is known about the role
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> in folliculogenesis: however this new finding
        raises the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-4</NUMEX> could have
        autocrine actions on TE histogenesis and/or paracrine
        actions on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">theca</ENAMEX>/follicle morphogenesis.
        The rapid cessation of mitosis and the expression of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> is the sinequanone of follicle atresia.
        Our results suggest a possible role for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX> in follicle
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">atresia</ENAMEX>. The supporting data are as follow. First, a
        striking feature of atresia in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat ovary</ENAMEX> is the
        cessation of BMP expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-4</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-7</NUMEX>) within the
        theca compartment. This observation is particularly
        interesting with respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX>. In previous work, we
        demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> could stimulate DNA synthesis in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rat GC</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] , as it does in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">osteoblasts</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] .
        Equally relevant, several reports have demonstrated the
        role for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> in preventing apoptosis in other cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37 38</NUMEX> ] . Together, these data suggest that
        theca-derived <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-7</ENAMEX> might be a follicle survival factor
        through its ability to enhance GC proliferation and
        suppress apoptosis. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, atresia is accompanied by a
        relatively high level of expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX>, -IB, and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">-</ENAMEX>II. Significantly, this occurred in the
        absence of the BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antagonist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX>. Thus, it is possible
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor signaling pathways</ENAMEX> are under maximal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stimulation by BMP-2</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">atresia</TIMEX>. How this
        phenomenon contributes to atresia is unknown, but our
        finding [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> inhibits FSH signaling is
        relevant because there is compelling evidence that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">continuous FSH</ENAMEX> stimulation is essential for follicle
        survival.
        The expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX> (ligands, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
        and a binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>) in the fundamental cell types of the
        dominant follicles (DF) argues for a physiological role of
        an intrinsic BMP in directing growth and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell fates</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DF</ENAMEX>. This is supported by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main lines of evidence. First,
        we found that the genes encoding the BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-IB, -II</ENAMEX>) are highly expressed in the DF
        throughout its course of development. And <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, the BMP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligands</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-7</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-15</NUMEX>) act on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> to control
        the level of mitosis and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FSH</ENAMEX> receptor signaling [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . In
        this regard, one particularly interesting observation is
        the dramatic loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DF</ENAMEX> is
        selected at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E 0200 h. Because BMP-6</ENAMEX> can prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> action
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] , the rapid loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> expression may be required
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> to exert its crucial functions during
        DF-development. The secondary rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> on estrous
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> is obligatory for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DF</ENAMEX> selection, and we have
        preliminary data showing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> induces the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX>-6
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX>. Thus, the secondary rise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> may down
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">regulate BMP-6</ENAMEX> expression in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DF</ENAMEX>. It is notable that the
        absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> is a marker for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DF</ENAMEX>. Finally, with
        regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> action, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> has been shown to neutralize the
        bioactivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSH</ENAMEX> inhibitor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . It is
        possible, therefore, that the strong expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> by
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DF</ENAMEX> may serve to modulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-15</ENAMEX> action such that
        sufficient FSH <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are expressed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GC</ENAMEX> to permit
        the development of a preovulatory follicle.
        A role for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX> in regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">luteogenesis</ENAMEX> is
        strongly suggested our data. Some key findings are as
        follows. First, the classical view of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> development is
        that luteinization is inhibited by oocyte-derived
        luteinization <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 40 41</NUMEX> ] , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of which have
        been identified as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-15</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 12</ENAMEX> ] . Therefore, the
        loss of oocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-6</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-15</NUMEX> at ovulation undoubtedly plays
        an especially prominent role in activating luteinization.
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> expression is suppressed and
        activated during luteinization and luteolysis,
        respectively, suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-2</ENAMEX> might be a novel
        luteinization inhibitor. Further work is necessary to
        investigate this possibility. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> is strongly
        expressed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">luteinization</TIMEX>, but is undetectable at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luteolysis</ENAMEX>. Thus, it is conceivable that the cycle-specific
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> may control the level of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX> production through anti-BMP mechanisms. And
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, a role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> in luteogenesis was suggested by
        our finding that luteinization and luteolysis, respectively
        are characterized by the absence and presence of BMPR-IB
        expression in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX>. A functional link between the
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPR-IB</ENAMEX> and luteolysis comes from
        loss-of-function studies showing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> of the cycle
        continues to secrete <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX> in the absence of BMPR-IB
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . This work, together with our finding that BMPR-IB
        is selectively expressed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL</ENAMEX> at luteolysis,
        supports the novel hypothesis that the regulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inducible</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TE</ENAMEX> specific BMPR-IB gene expression may
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> luteolysis.
        The observation that the ovarian sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cords</ENAMEX> (SC) express
        an intrinsic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX> system replete with ligands (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-4</NUMEX>,
        -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> (BMPR-IA, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-IB, -II</ENAMEX>) is novel. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> are
        vestiges of the cranial portion of the mesonephric tubules
        and ducts, and in the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ovary</ENAMEX> appear as a cluster of
        blind tubules in the hilar region. Although little is known
        about the physiology and biology of ovarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>, they have
        been linked to the genesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ovary cancer</ENAMEX> through distinct
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGF</ENAMEX>-β signaling pathways [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 43</NUMEX> ] . Significantly, the
        importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> in the genesis of this <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> has been
        established [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] . Given the evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX> are
        potent growth factors and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FS</ENAMEX> can modulate their
        bioactivity, it will be interesting to investigate the
        possibility that this intrinsic BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> may be involved
        to pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> tumors. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> were occasionally
        found juxtaposed to developing follicles, blood vessels and
        secondary interstitial cells, one cannot exclude the
        possibility that the SC-derived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX> may have paracrine
        functions.
        A functional role for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMPs</ENAMEX> in the ovary surface
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epithelium</ENAMEX> (OSE) is suggested by the strong expression of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-4</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX>. Based on our data, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-3b</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-6</NUMEX> appear
        to be constitutively expressed throughout the epithelium
        over the cycle, a finding consistent with a
        maintenance-type role for these OSE BMPs. An interesting
        finding is the cell-specific induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> gene
        expression in a subset of epithelial cells covering the
        ovulated follicle and the newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CL-I.</ENAMEX> Although the
        function of this inducible and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>-specific gene
        expression is unclear, it is tightly correlated with the
        replenishment of the surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">epithelium</ENAMEX> that is exfoliated
        from the surface of ovulating follicle. Thus, the
        importance of this highly specific expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> may
        relate to the regeneration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSE</ENAMEX> during postovulatory
        repair. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> expression appears tightly regulated
        over the cycle, it remains to be determined how the
        regulation is controlled. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSE</ENAMEX> does not appear
        to express BMP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OSE-derived BMP-4</ENAMEX> probably
        acts as a paracrine growth factor in the underlying stroma.
        It is noteworthy that epidemiological studies have shown
        that the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">epithelial ovarian cancer</ENAMEX> is decreased by
        factors that suppress ovulation, i.e., pregnancy,
        breast-feeding, and oral contraceptive pill. [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45 46</NUMEX> ] .
        Given the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LH</ENAMEX>-dependent ovulation and
        the induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP-4</ENAMEX> expression, it will be important to
        explore a possible link between the risk of ovary cancer
        and the ovulation-inducible and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>-specific BMP-4
        gene expression.
        It is clear from this work that the regulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inducible</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>-specific expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BMP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is
        a general property of the mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ovary</ENAMEX>. Consequently,
        the potential for independent and coordinated contributions
        of different BMPs to control growth, differentiation, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> is widely distributed throughout all the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">histological</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> of the ovary. The current challenges are
        to understand how specific hormone/growth factor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interactions</ENAMEX> regulate BMP expression in the fundamental
        ovary cell types, and how these interactions are integrated
        into the morphological and histological events that
        generate the estrous cycle. The clinical relevance is
        emphasized by our previous finding that the expression of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GDF-9</ENAMEX> is dysregulated in oocytes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with Polycystic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ovary Syndrome</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX> ] .
      
    
  
