
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Steroid hormone receptors</ENAMEX> (SHRs) are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a family
        of ligand-activated transcription factors that regulate
        many biological processes, including metabolism,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reproduction</ENAMEX>, and development. In the absence of ligand
        such as androgen, glucocorticoid, progestin, and
        mineralocorticoid, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHR</ENAMEX> maintains a cytosolic inactive
        state by association with heat shock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> and/or other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> such as corepressors. Upon ligand binding, the SHR
        undergoes conformational changes that involve releas e from
        the repressor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, and translocation to the nucleus
        where it can bind to specific hormone responsive sequences
        in the DNA of genes regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid hormones</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] .
        The mechanism by which SHRs affect the rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">polymerase II</ENAMEX>-directed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">transcription</ENAMEX> likely involves the
        interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> with components of the
        transcription preinitialization <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. This interaction
        may be direct, or it may occur indirectly through the
        action of coactivators, which act as bridging factors. To
        date, numerous coactivator molecules have been isolated and
        characterized, encompassing several different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ] . Most of these cofactors are expressed in a wide
        variety of cell types and can interact with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
        type of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. The recent findings that members
        of the several different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coactivators</ENAMEX> possess
        intrinsic histone acetyltransferase activity suggests that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activated SHRs</ENAMEX>, and nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> in general, may also
        recruit these cofactors to remodel chromatin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> for
        better accessibility of the transcriptional machinery to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] .
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAK/STAT</ENAMEX> signaling pathway is involved in many
        cytokines, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>, and growth factors mediated signaling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX> to regulate a variety of biological responses,
        including development, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell differentiation</ENAMEX>, proliferation
        and survival [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] . Once <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">STAT proteins</ENAMEX> are activated by
        tyrosine-phosphorylation, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">form homo</ENAMEX> or heterodimers that
        are translocated to the nucleus, where they can bind to
        specific sequences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, thereby stimulating gene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX>. Similarly to nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and to other
        transcription factors, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">STAT proteins</ENAMEX> can interact with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coactivators</ENAMEX> to modulate their transcriptional activity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11 12</NUMEX> ] . Other reports have shown direct interactions
        between several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAK/STAT</ENAMEX> signaling pathway
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14 15 16</NUMEX> ] . Stat3 is one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that has been shown
        to modulate the expression of several genes related to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> cell cycle, proliferation and apoptosis, such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">D1</ENAMEX>, c-myc, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bcl</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">xL</ENAMEX>, respectively [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        Accordingly, alterations in the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">STAT3</ENAMEX> have been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with cell transformation and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> progression
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19 20</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Prostate cancer</ENAMEX> is the most commonly diagnosed <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>,
        and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> leading cause of death from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Prostate cells are dependant on androgen to
        keep their normal functions. Activation of androgen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor</ENAMEX> (AR) in prostate cells is a key step in developing
        and progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> respond
        initially to androgen deprivation or antiandrogen
        regiments, but eventually the tumor relapses in an
        androgen-independent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> with a poor outcome. Several
        possible mechanisms have been suggested to explain this
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>, including mutations in the gene encoding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> that alter the specificity for androgens, overexpression
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> itself, cross-talk to other signal
        transduction pathways, and altered levels or activity of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coactivators</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22 23</NUMEX> ] . Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> including ours
        have demonstrated a role of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stat3</ENAMEX> in the
        proliferation and survival of prostate cancer cells by a
        mechanism that involves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25 26 27 28</NUMEX> ] .
        In this study, we examined how <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Stat3</NUMEX> activates the SHRs
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>. We studied whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX>, a transcription
        factor itself, could act as a coactivator for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> and for
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX>. We report here that a constitutively active
        form of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX> stimulates transcriptional activity of SHRs
        in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>-dependent manner. We also report that active
        Stat3 can act synergistically with other coactivators to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stimulate SHRs</ENAMEX> transcriptional activity. Moreover, while
        Stat3 did not affect specificity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> to other steroid
        hormones rather than androgen, or binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> to other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HREs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stat3</ENAMEX> significantly increased the sensitivity of AR
        to androgen. These results can add more light to the
        mechanism by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> in particular, regulate
        gene expression.
      
      
        Results
        
          Effect of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX> on AR-mediated transcriptional
          activity
          Stat3 has been shown to enhance AR-mediated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX>
          expression and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> transcriptional activity in prostate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 25 28</NUMEX> ] . We used two
          well-characterized androgen-responsive luciferase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter plasmids</ENAMEX> to study the effect of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX> on
          AR-mediated transcriptional activity. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
          plasmids contain several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AREs</ENAMEX> that are required for
          androgen induction. As comparison, we used a saturating
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM, of a synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">androgen</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">R1881</TIMEX>. CV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells
          do not express endogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>, therefore, all experiments
          were performed in the presence of ectopic wild-type human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>. CV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells showed a strong response to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">R1881</TIMEX> compared
          to vehicle-treated cells with both androgen-responsive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> used (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Cotransfection of a plasmid
          expressing a constitutively active mutant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3C</TIMEX>,
          that forms homodimers and translocates to the nucleus
          without tyrosine phosphorylation, affected AR
          transcriptional activity in a dose-response manner (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1A) but only in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1Band <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">1C</ENAMEX>).
          Constitutively activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stat3</ENAMEX> also activates another
          androgen-responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> contained the fragment
          -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">286/</NUMEX>+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat Probasin</ENAMEX> (PB) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C).
          Wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stat3</ENAMEX>, that is in a latent cytosolic state
          without tyrosine phosphorylation nor dimerization, showed
          no additional stimulatory effect over the
          androgen-treated cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
        
        
          Effect of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">STAT3</TIMEX> on transcriptional activity of
          other SHRs
          Having demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX> enhance AR-mediated
          gene transcription, we next investigated the role of
          Stat3 on transcriptional activation with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX>. For
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>, we used the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmid as for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>,
          ARE-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TATA-luciferase</ENAMEX>, since it shows promiscuous response
          to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . For <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>, we used
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERE-TATA</ENAMEX>-luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> that is specific for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estrogen</ENAMEX>. CV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were also cotransfected with
          plasmids expressing ectopically <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>. Like the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX> enhances <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX> tested in the
          presence of the corresponding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dex</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>, R5020
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>, or E 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Taken together,
          Stat3 enhances <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> different SHRs transcriptional
          activity in the presence of their corresponding ligand,
          suggesting that active Stat3 acts as a coactivator for
          nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>.
          We next compared the coactivator activity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Stat3</NUMEX> to
          that of other known coactivators for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>. CV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were
          transfected with the same amount (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 Î¼g</ENAMEX>) of plasmid
          expressing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3C</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CBP/p300</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TIF-2</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P/CAF</ENAMEX>,
          respectively. Cells transfected with either coactivator
          or Stat3C showed comparable and higher luciferase
          activity in response to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">R1881</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> treated with
          hormone alone in the presence of empty vector (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
          None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coactivators</ENAMEX> tested showed any luciferase
          activity in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
          Stat3 is comparable to other coactivators on AR
          transcriptional activity: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SRC-1, CBP/p300, TIF2,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P/CAF</ENAMEX>.
          It has been reported that coactivators in combination
          can enhance transcriptional activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX> compared to
          when they are delivered to cells individually [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30</NUMEX> ] .
          Recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giraud et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] reported a direct
          interaction of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CBP/p300</ENAMEX>. We
          determined whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX> could act in a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">synergistic/additive</ENAMEX> way when administered to cells
          simultaneously to other coactivators. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3shows,
          coexpression of active Stat3C simultaneously to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-1</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CBP/p300</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TIF-2</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P/CAF</ENAMEX>, resulted in a more efficient
          enhancement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> transcription activity driven
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> as compared with any of the coactivators expressed
          separately. A similar enhancement in luciferase activity
          with simultaneous delivery of coactivators was observed
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
        
        
          Stat3 did not affect the specificity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> for
          non-androgen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid hormones</ENAMEX> or non-AREs
          Altered responses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> include activation by
          non-androgen ligands or recognition of other hormone
          responsive elements different from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AREs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] . We
          studied if active Stat3 could be responsible for this
          behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>. CV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were cotransfected with a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter plasmid</ENAMEX> responsive to androgen
          (ARE-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TATA-luciferase</ENAMEX>) in the presence or absence of AR
          and constitutively active Stat3C (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4top) and cells
          were treated with different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid hormones</ENAMEX>. Stat3C did
          not alter the specificity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> for other steroid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hormones</ENAMEX>, since it showed transcriptional activity only
          in response to androgen but not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dex</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">R5020</TIMEX> or E 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 4</ENAMEX>, top).
          To test whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX> could alter the specificity of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HREs</ENAMEX>, CV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were cotransfected with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter plasmids</ENAMEX> responsive to androgen
          (ARE-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TATA-luciferase</ENAMEX>) or to estrogen
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERE-TATA-luciferase</ENAMEX>), in the presence or absence of AR
          and constitutively active Stat3C (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4bottom). With
          ARE-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TATA</ENAMEX>-luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, luciferase activity was
          dependent on the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> and androgen, without any
          effect of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3C</TIMEX> on the basal levels of transcription
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 4</ENAMEX>, bottom left). Stat3C did not modify the
          sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> for other hormone responsive elements,
          since there was no response on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> transcriptional
          activity when we used an estrogen-specific responsive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter plasmid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERE-TATA-luciferase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 4</ENAMEX>, bottom
          right).
        
        
          Stat3 does not prevent inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> by the
          antiandrogen flutamide
          Another altered response of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> is manifested in the
          so-called "flutamide withdrawal syndrome" or more
          recently broadened to "antiandrogen withdrawal syndrome".
          In this condition, it is shown a decrease in serum levels
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSA</ENAMEX> after removal of flutamide or other antiandrogens
          from the treatment regiment [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . We studied if active
          Stat3 could be involved in this paradoxical effect of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiandrogens</ENAMEX>. CV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells cotransfected with an androgen
          responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmid (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARE-TATA-luciferase</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>, in
          the presence or absence of constitutively active <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3C</TIMEX>,
          were treated with androgen and flutamide (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). As
          expected, flutamide blocked substantially the induction
          of ARE-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TATA</ENAMEX>-luciferase activity by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">R1881</TIMEX> in the absence
          of active <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3C</TIMEX>. Similarly, the inhibitory effect of the
          antiandrogen on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> was not prevented by the presence of
          constitutively active <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3C</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Stat3 affects sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> for androgen
          Other mechanism by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> could show an altered
          response results from an increase in its sensitivity to
          very low levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">androgen</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] . We tested the
          role of active <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX> in this possibility cotransfecting
          CV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells with an androgen responsive reporter
          (ARE-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TATA-luciferase</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>, in the presence or in the
          absence of constitutively active <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3C</TIMEX>. Cells were then
          treated with different doses of androgen. Maximal
          transcriptional activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> was at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 nM R1881</TIMEX> both in
          the presence and absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3C</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). Stat3C
          enhanced luci ferase activity driven by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> even at the
          minimal dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R1881</ENAMEX> tested, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> pM, which showed no
          luciferase activity in the absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3C</TIMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Regulation of gene transcription mediated by
        hormone-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SHRs</ENAMEX> involves interaction with components
        of the transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. Coactivators are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
        the transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, which act as bridging factors to
        achieve optimal transcription activity. Coactivators are
        probably present in the nucleus in preassembled
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">multicomplex</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> ready to associate to activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SHRs</ENAMEX>.
        The role of the coactivators could be just as bridging
        factors, although some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p160</NUMEX> family
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CBP/p300</ENAMEX> present histone acetyltransferase activity [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX> ] . Stat3 is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAK/STAT</ENAMEX> signaling
        pathway, which is a transcription factor itself that after
        activation binds to specific sequences in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> to regulate
        expression of genes related to proliferation,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> and cell survival. Constitutive activation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stat3</ENAMEX> has been associated with cell transformation and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer progression</ENAMEX>. Previous data including from our group
        showed activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> in prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> mediated by
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25 26 27 28</NUMEX> ] .
        Here we show that constitutively active Stat3 enhances
        transcriptional activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>, in a
        comparable extent to the stimulation elicit by other
        coactivators, and even more, in a synergistic manner to
        these other coactivators. This stimulation is independent
        of the DNA binding activity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX>, since none of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">luciferase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> responsive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX> used throughout
        this report contain the DNA sequence responsive to Stat3 [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> ] . We cannot rule out, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX> is affecting
        an independent event that in turn activates SHR
        transcriptional activity. Nevertheless, direct
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-protein interaction</ENAMEX> has been documented by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coimmunoprecipitation</ENAMEX> experiments <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between Stat3</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] , and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] ,
        suggesting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX> might be involved directly in
        transcriptional activity elicit by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX>. Moreover, Stat3
        has also been directly associated with several
        coactivators, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CBP/p300</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 12</ENAMEX> ] .
        Recruitment of coactivators to nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> takes
        place via a common motif in the coactivators containing a
        core consensus sequence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LXXLL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>, leucine; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>, any
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aminoacid</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . Most of the coactivators contain more
        than one of these motifs, raising the question regarding
        specificity of these motifs to specific activating domains
        in the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. Stat3 also contains in its
        N-terminus one of this motifs ( <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">221LAGLL 225</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] .
        Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX> also presents a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ser</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-2</NUMEX> position of the
        LXXLL sequence, which in the case of the coactivator TRBP
        defines selectivity for nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] .
        Phosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stat3</ENAMEX> has been reported to occur only in
        705Tyr and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">727Ser</TIMEX>, allowing dimerization and full
        transactivating activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] . Whether this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">219Ser</ENAMEX> next
        to the LXXLL motif is involved in the coactivator activity
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX>, and the interaction of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX> with other
        coactivators only takes place in the context of Stat3
        transcription factor activity or also can be part of the
        general mechanism of the transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> formation
        requires further studies.
        Activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> is a driving force in development and
        progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>. Several mechanisms could be
        involved in this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AR activation</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22 23</NUMEX> ] . Changes in
        the specificity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> broadening the responsive spectrum to
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid hormones</ENAMEX> different to dihydrotestosterone,
        can be caused by genetic mutations affecting different
        regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>. We studied if active Stat3 could be
        sufficient to alter the specificity of a wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AR</ENAMEX> to
        non-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid hormones</ENAMEX>. Our results indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native AR</ENAMEX>,
        with no mutations, is responsible only to androgens, being
        Stat3 not sufficient to alter this feature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>. Activated
        Stat3 d oes not affect the specificity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> to bind to
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HREs</ENAMEX> different form ARE. Other altered response of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mutated AR</ENAMEX> is the paradoxical agonistic effect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antiandrogens</ENAMEX>. Also in this case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX> could not reverse
        the antagonistic activity of flutamide on a wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AR</ENAMEX>.
        These results point to mutations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> as a necessary step
        in some of the altered responses of AR seen in advanced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX>.
        Another possible mechanism by which a prostate cancer
        circumvents the low levels of androgens resulting from
        androgen ablation therapy is by increasing the sensitivity
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> to very low levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">androgens</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] . Stat3
        increased the sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> to a dose of androgen that
        showed no activity in the absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX>, in the absence
        of a mutated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>. The constitutive activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stat3</ENAMEX> found
        in prostate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27 43</NUMEX> ] could be an initial step in
        the clonal selection of malignant cells affecting not only
        Stat3-regulated genes but also AR, as part of the
        transcription <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> recruited in response to activated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>. Recently, overexpression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TIF-2</ENAMEX> has been
        found in prostate cancer recurrence after androgen
        deprivation therapy [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] , providing a molecular basis
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> activation that could be similar to the one
        displayed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX> in its role as coactivator.
        In conclusions, we report here that: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a constitutively
        active form of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3</ENAMEX> stimulates transcriptional activity of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>-dependent manner; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) active <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stat3</ENAMEX> can act
        synergistically with other c oactivators to stimulate SHRs
        transcriptional activity; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) Stat3 did not affect
        specificity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> to other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid hormones</ENAMEX> different than
        androgen, or binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HREs</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) Stat3
        increases the sensitivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> to androgen. These results
        can help to elucidate the mechanism by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHRs</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> in particular, regulate gene
        expression.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Plasmids
          Luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmids containing specific
          responsive elements for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GR</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRE-TATA-luciferase</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERE-TATA-luciferase</ENAMEX>) have
          been described elsewhere [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30</NUMEX> ] ; another
          androgen-responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> contained the fragment
          -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">286/</NUMEX>+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat Probasin</ENAMEX> (PB) promoter, and was
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. Matusik</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanderbilt University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> ] . An expression plasmid for wild-type hAR was kindly
          provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Chang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>.
          Expression plasmids for hGR, hPR Î± and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> have been also
          described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30</NUMEX> ] . Wild-type inactive form of Stat3
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pCAGGS-HA-Stat3</ENAMEX>) was from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. Hirano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Osaka</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . The plasmid expressing a
          constitutively active form of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Stat3</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stat3C-Flag</ENAMEX>) was
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Darnell</ENAMEX>, jr. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . This
          constitutively activated Stat3 (a mutant produced by
          substitution of the cysteine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> within the
          COOH-terminal loop of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SH2</NUMEX> domain of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Stat3</NUMEX>) induces
          cellular transformation and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> formation in nude <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . The plasmids to express other coactivators
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SRC-1, CBP/p300, TIF2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAF</ENAMEX>) have been described
          elsewhere [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30</NUMEX> ] .
        
        
          Cells and transfections
          CV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were maintained in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum
          (Bio-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whittaker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walkersville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 u/ml penicillin,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> streptomycin in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> before
          transfection, cells were plated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> well plates (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.2</NUMEX> Ã—
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> per well) in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> charcoal stripped serum (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyclone</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX>), antibiotics, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM L-glutamine in phenol
          red-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>. For transfections, we used (per well) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>
          Î¼g <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.2 Î</NUMEX>¼g <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼g</NUMEX> coactivator or
          empty vector. In experiments studying synergy of
          coactivators, the total amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was kept constant
          at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.4 Î¼g</NUMEX> per well. Transfections were performed with
          Superfect reagent according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protocol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valencia</ENAMEX>, CA). <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three hours</TIMEX> after
          transfection, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was removed and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> added in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenol</ENAMEX> red-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> charcoal stripped
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX> and antibiotics. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dihydrotestosterone</ENAMEX> (DHT),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dexamethasone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dex</ENAMEX>), estradiol (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ), and the synthetic anti-androgen
          flutamide were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). The
          synthetic analogs of androgen and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R1881</ENAMEX> and
          R5020, respectively, were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Nuclear</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Luciferase activity
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Thirty six hours</TIMEX> after incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>,
          luciferase activity was determined in cell extracts
          according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s suggestions (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>). Luciferase activity was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">normalized per Î</NUMEX>¼g
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradford</ENAMEX> assay (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coomasie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> are presented as a
          representative experiment, which was independently
          repeated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> times.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' Contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeMiguel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> carried out the entire experiments.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gao</ENAMEX> conceived of the study, and participated in
        its design and coordination.
      
    
  
