
  
    
      
        Background
        The nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (NR) family comprises <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>
        structurally related transcription factors, many of which
        require their cognate ligand for activity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3</NUMEX> ] . The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRs</ENAMEX> regulate transcription by binding to response elements
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of target genes and acting as scaffolds
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> of large coactivator and corepressor
        complexes [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> coactivators include the p160s
        (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GRIP1/TIF-2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">AIB1/ACTR/pCIP</ENAMEX>). The
        p160s enhance transcription by binding histone
        acetyl-transferases such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p300/CBP</ENAMEX> and pCAF [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl-transferases</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CARM1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRMT</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] which, in
        turn, enhance transcription by modification of chromatin.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> coactivators include TRAP220 [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , which is part
        of a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRAP/DRIP/SMCC</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX>) that contacts
        the basal transcription machinery and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PGC-1</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] , a cold
        inducible coactivator that binds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-1</ENAMEX> and proteins
        involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> processing [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> corepressors include
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> corepressor (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX>) and silencing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> of retinoid
        and thyroid responsive transcription (SMRT) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . Both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> repress transcription, at least in part, by
        binding to histone de-acetylases (HDACs) either directly or
        indirectly through other corepressor complex components.
        Other known NR corepressors include RIP140 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] ,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hairless</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] , short heterodimer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> (SHP) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ]
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAX</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] , and receptor specific corepressors such as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">estrogen receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>) interacting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins REA</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HET-SAFB</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15</NUMEX> ] .
        Generally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> transcriptional activity is dictated by
        the balance between coactivator and corepressor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recruitment</ENAMEX>, and one of the most important factors that
        influences this balance is the absence or presence of
        agonist ligands (reviewed in [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] ). Unliganded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NRs</ENAMEX> such
        as thyroid (TRs) and retinoid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> (RARs) bind
        corepressors, and ligand promotes release of corepressor
        and subsequent binding of coactivators. The mechanism of
        this coregulator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> is well understood. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRs</ENAMEX> consist
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> domains, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal domain (which contains a
        context-specific activation function <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AF-1</ENAMEX>), the central DNA
        binding domain (DBD) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal ligand binding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">domain</ENAMEX> (LBD), which contains a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>-dependent activation
        function, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AF-2</ENAMEX>. The unliganded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBD</ENAMEX> recognizes hydrophobic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motifs</ENAMEX>, termed interaction domains (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDs</ENAMEX>), which are
        reiterated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and twice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> and
        conform to the consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L/IXXIIXXXL</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] (see also [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ]
        ). By contrast, the liganded LBD binds shorter hydrophobic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motifs</ENAMEX> termed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> boxes that are reiterated several times
        within each coactivator and conform to the consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LXXLL</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBD</ENAMEX> utilizes a large hydrophobic cleft composed of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> along <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">H3</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H5</ENAMEX> to bind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] , and a smaller
        hydrophobic cleft that is composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> in the upper
        part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3 and H5 and H12</TIMEX> (and corresponds to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AF-2</ENAMEX>) to bind
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> boxes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Thus, agonists promote coregulator
        exchange by promoting the packing of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">H12</NUMEX> over the lower
        part of the ID binding region, an event that simultaneously
        completes the coactivator binding surface. In other cases,
        however, the balance of coactivator and corepressor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recruitment</ENAMEX> is regulated by direct competition for the AF-2
        surface, rather than ligand-dependent coregulator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>.
        RIP140, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hairless</ENAMEX> and DAX possess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> boxes that interact
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF-2</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 13 19</NUMEX> ] and these corepressors act as
        negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of the activity of the liganded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX>.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX>)
        that conform to the typical <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> domain NR structure and
        share extensive sequence homology in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBD</ENAMEX> region
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] . Analysis of the function of the individual ERs
        in mouse knockout models suggests that the major
        proliferative effects of estrogen are mediated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> and
        not by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX>, which seems to play an inhibitory role in
        proliferation in some studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] . The
        ligand-binding properties of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERs</ENAMEX> are different, with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> often exhibiting stronger binding to plant-derived
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phytoestrogens</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . More importantly, the ERs exhibit
        isoform-specific effects on gene expression. Both ERs
        enhance transcription from genes with classical estrogen
        response elements (EREs), but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> requires less ligand to
        obtain maximal activation than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] . Likewise,
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERs</ENAMEX> suppress the activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFα</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> in
        response to estrogens, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> is a more potent repressor
        than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . However, some of the most striking
        isoform-specific differences in gene regulation are
        observed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX>, such as that of cyclin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">D1</TIMEX>, which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contain AP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> or related cyclic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMP</ENAMEX> response elements
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CREs</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ERα</ENAMEX> enhances <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1 activity in response to
        estrogens, [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> inhibits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1 activity in
        response to estrogens [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30 31</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> also completely
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suppresses</ENAMEX> ERα activity at the cyclin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">D1 promoter</ENAMEX> and even
        suppresses the activity of an ERα mutant that is
        selectively superactive at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CREs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] .
        Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> shows a unique capacity to enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1
        activity in response to selective <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">estrogen</ENAMEX> receptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modulators</ENAMEX> (SERMs) such as raloxifene, tamoxifen and ICI
        observations suggest that there are fundamental differences
        in the way that the ERs bind unspecified cofactors that
        modulate gene expression, and that some of these cofactors
        must play a role in differential <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> activity at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1
        sites.
        Although the poorly conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTD</ENAMEX> region clearly plays
        an important role in isoform-specificity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX> ] , it is
        also likely that there are differences in the better
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conserved LBD</ENAMEX> region that contribute to differential ERα
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> activities. Phage display techniques have revealed
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> show different preferences in LXXLL
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> (reviewed in [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX> ] ). Moreover, some cofactors
        that contain LXXLL motifs show differential binding to LBDs
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> isoforms (reviewed in [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SHP</ENAMEX> binds ERα
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preferentially</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] , and represses ERα activity more
        strongly than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PGC-1</ENAMEX> related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> PERC
        also binds ERα preferentially, and potentiates ERα activity
        more strongly than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . We recently
        observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> binds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-terminal NR</ENAMEX> interacting
        regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERMs</ENAMEX> but not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estrogens</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . In this study, we report that ERβ
        interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> are promoted by agonists
        and inhibited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERMs</ENAMEX>. Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERs</ENAMEX> show completely
        opposite ligand preferences of interaction with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corepressors</ENAMEX>. We discuss the potential significance of
        these different modes of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in terms
        of known isoform-specific behaviors.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Agonist Dependent ERβ Interactions</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and
          SMRT
          To investigate ERβ interactions with corepressors, we
          examined the interactions of full length <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-530</ENAMEX>) with bacterially expressed C-terminal NR
          interacting domain of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944-2453</TIMEX>) 
          in vitro (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1Breveals,
          surprisingly, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in the absence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> and in the presence of agonist ligands (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DES</ENAMEX>)
          and phytoestrogens (genistein, coumestrol). Moreover,
          these interactions were suppressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERMs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICI</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">raloxifene</ENAMEX> and tamoxifen). ERβ bound to the coactivator
          GRIP1 more strongly than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX>, but did so with an
          identical ligand preference. Similar agonist-dependent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interactions</ENAMEX> could be observed between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alternate NR</ENAMEX> corepressor SMRT 
          in vitro (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> binding
          experiments performed in parallel confirmed that ERα
          bound to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERMs</ENAMEX>, and not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estradiol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1D) and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRβ</ENAMEX> bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in the
          absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>, and was released in the presence of
          T3, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRβ</ENAMEX> only bound GRIP1 in the presence of T3
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1E).
          To examine interactions between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in
          mammalian cells we performed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">assays</ENAMEX> using a
          GAL4 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBD/N-CoR C-terminus</ENAMEX> fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> as bait and a
          VP16-ERβ LBD fusion as the prey. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2shows that the
          ERβ-LBD bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in the presence of agonists and
          phytoestrogens, but not SERMs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid assays
          confirmed that a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">VP16</NUMEX>-TRβ LBD fusion protein bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-CoR
          in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>, but not in the presence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T3</TIMEX>.
          E2 dependent binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> was dose dependent
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B) with an EC50 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.3 nM</NUMEX>) that resembled that of
          ERβ binding to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GRIP1</NUMEX> NR box <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">610-770</ENAMEX>). Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> binds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal NR
          interacting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> in the presence of agonists, but not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERMs</ENAMEX>, and does so 
          in vitro and in mammalian cells.
          Moreover, results from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">assay</ENAMEX> indicate that
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ LBD</ENAMEX> is sufficient to obtain estrogen-dependent
          interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ Interactions</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> are Dependent on AF-2
          and require H12
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unliganded NRs</ENAMEX> usually bind ID motifs (consensus
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L/IXXIIXXXL</ENAMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR C-terminus</ENAMEX>. To ask whether ERβ
          might bind these motifs in the presence of estradiol, we
          examined the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX> containing known NR
          interacting motifs to compete for the interaction (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3A). A peptide overlapping to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ID1</ENAMEX> motif (amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">acids 2265-2291</ENAMEX>) that competes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> binding to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unliganded TR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] failed to compete for
          agonist-dependent ERβ interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX>. By
          contrast, a peptide corresponding to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">GRIP1 NR box 2</ENAMEX> did
          compete for this interaction [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 41</NUMEX> ] . This finding
          suggests that agonist-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> does not recognize ID
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motifs</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> more closely
          resemble those with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GRIP1</TIMEX>.
          NR interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> are usually mediated by a
          hydrophobic cleft that spans <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3 and H5</TIMEX> and
          includes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> that lie under <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">H12</NUMEX> in the liganded
          configuration [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 17</ENAMEX> ] . These interactions are either
          independent of, or inhibited by, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H12</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 39 42</NUMEX> ] . By
          contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> interactions with coactivators are mediated
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> from the upper part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H3-H5</ENAMEX> and also require
          H12 itself [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3Bshows that a mutation in a
          conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H12</TIMEX> that is required for coactivator
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">E493K</NUMEX>) abolished the interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> with
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GRIP1</TIMEX>. Moreover, other mutations in the
          upper part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H3-H5</ENAMEX> region that comprises the AF-2
          surface (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">D303Y</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">I310R and K314A</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">V328R and L331R</TIMEX> on
          H5) abolished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> interaction with both cofactors.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> mutations in other regions of the ERβ surface
          left its interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GRIP1</TIMEX> either
          slightly reduced or intact (these are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">L301R</TIMEX> at the base
          of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">V361R</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-bends</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M379R</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H8</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">L426R</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T434R</TIMEX> in
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the H10 and Y488S</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the H11-H12</TIMEX> loop). Thus, ERβ
          interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> are dependent on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF-2</ENAMEX> surface
          (including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H12</ENAMEX>) and, in this regard, resemble those of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GRIP1</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ Binds</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">NR Box-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Like Motif</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-CoR
          C-terminus
          To map the region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> that interacted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX>,
          we examined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> binding to a series of rationally
          designed smaller fragments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR C-terminus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> did not bind <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these smaller fragments of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944-2033</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2230-2322</TIMEX>) that contain known ID motifs
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDs</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 and 1</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] ). ERβ bound weakly to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> regions of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2033-2123</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2123-2230</TIMEX>), one of which (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2033-2123</TIMEX>)
          contains an ID motif (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ID2</NUMEX>), but did so in a
          ligand-independent fashion. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> did bind to a
          fragment that spanned the extreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C-terminus</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2322-2453</TIMEX>)
          and did so in a manner that was promoted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">E2</TIMEX> and
          suppressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICI</ENAMEX>, much like the interactions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> with
          the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">N-CoR</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> interacting region.
          The interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> with the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragment</ENAMEX> (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2322-2453</TIMEX>) was stronger than that
          observed with the intact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C-terminus</ENAMEX> (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944-2453</TIMEX>). This apparently improved binding is likely to
          be a consequence of our methodology (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . Unpublished data). In
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>, expression of large fragments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-CoR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E. Coli</ENAMEX> yields a mix of full length protein
          along with truncated products. To create the expression
          vectors for the smaller fragments, truncated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-CoR
          polypeptides that were obtained in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. Coli extracts</ENAMEX> were
          subjected to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> sequence analysis and cDNA fragments
          that coded for the major truncated products were
          prepared. Each of the resulting polypeptides was
          expressed very efficiently in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. Coli</ENAMEX>. The end product
          that was obtained after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> purification essentially
          consisted of a single short polypeptide as judged by
          Coomassie stain. Binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2322-2453</TIMEX>) is
          probably very efficient for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. First, equal
          amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were used as baits for the
          translated ERβ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in this series of experiments (3μg
          per assay). Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2322-2453</TIMEX>) is present in molar
          excess over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944-2453</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, as developed
          above, preparations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944-2453</TIMEX>) generally
          contain truncated products, so sequences corresponding to
          the extreme <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR C-terminus</ENAMEX> (which binds ERβ) is
          markedly under-represented. In any case, the fact that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> binds weakly or not at all to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR ID</ENAMEX>
          motifs that mediate interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARs</ENAMEX> and,
          instead, binds in an agonist-dependent fashion to a
          region in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus of N-CoR</ENAMEX> that has not previously
          been implicated in NR interactions indicates that ERβ
          recognizes a novel protein sequence motif within
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR C-terminus</ENAMEX> contains the sequence PLTIRMLS
          (β-box, amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2399-2406</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). This sequence
          does not exactly conform to the LXXLL consensus, but
          contains features (underlined) that resemble the ERβ H12
          region (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L LE</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ML</ENAMEX> ), and artificial ERβ
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interacting LXXLL</ENAMEX> peptides (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">293,</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P NLIS</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LLS</ENAMEX> ; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">D47</TIMEX>, 
          PL LLS 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LLS</ENAMEX> ), both of which bind to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF-2</ENAMEX> surface [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44 45 46 47</NUMEX> ] . Moreover, the
          presence of a proline residue amino-terminal to the
          hydrophobic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> is typical of so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">class II</ENAMEX> LXXLL
          motifs which are found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> interacting cofactors such
          as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TRAP220</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RIP140</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . Finally, the unusual
          C-terminal hydrophobic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> (ML) has been observed in ERα
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H12</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44 48</NUMEX> ] , and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RIP140</TIMEX> NR boxes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ]
          .
          We investigated the significance of the β-box in ERβ
          interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6Ashows, a synthetic
          β-box peptide competed for binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX>, albeit
          somewhat less efficiently than native GRIP1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> box 2.
          Similar results were obtained in competition experiments
          that used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-GRIP1</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST-N-CoR</ENAMEX> (data not
          shown). The isolated β-box also acted as bait for a
          VP16-ERβ fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in mammalian cells, and did so
          with similar efficiency to other known ERβ interacting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptides</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6B). Finally, mutations within the β-box
          (especially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">M2405A</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">L2406A</TIMEX>) disrupted ERβ interactions
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in mammalian <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">assays</ENAMEX>, but did not
          affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRβ</ENAMEX> interactions (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6C). Thus, the β-box is
          sufficient to bind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> and is essential for
          agonist-dependent ERβ interactions with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-CoR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus</ENAMEX>.
          Next, we examined whether the β-box would bind other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gal</ENAMEX>-β-box fusion failed to recruit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX>, TRβ
          or RARβ LBDs in mammalian <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">assays</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7A).
          Moreover, while the β-box and GRIP1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> box <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> peptides
          both competed for ERβ interactions with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">GRIP1</TIMEX>, only the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">NR box 2</ENAMEX> peptide competed for ERα interactions with GRIP1
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7B). Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> β-box is, at least to some
          degree, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> specific. Mutation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> to obtain a β-box
          sequence that more closely resembled a conventional LXXLL
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motif</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">T2402L</NUMEX>) led to enhanced hormone-dependent
          interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> and permitted novel
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone-dependent interactions</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7C). Thus,
          some of the observed ERβ specificity is probably a
          consequence of an unexpected ability to tolerate the
          absence of a leucine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus</ENAMEX> of the
          LXXLL motif. Together, our results indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> has
          the potential to utilize its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF-2</ENAMEX> surface to bind NR
          boxes within coactivators or an NR box-like sequence in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-terminus of N-CoR</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDAC Repressor Enhances ERβ</ENAMEX> Activity
          Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> in the presence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corepressors</ENAMEX> in the actions of agonist-bound ERβ 
          in vivo . To perform this
          experiment, we examined the effect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDAC</ENAMEX> inhibitor
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">trichostatin A</ENAMEX> (TSA) on ERβ activity in transiently
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transfected HeLa</ENAMEX> cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8Aconfirms that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> shows
          stronger transcriptional activity than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> at a simple
          ERE responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene. TSA enhanced the basal
          activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERE-TK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene by about
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX>-fold in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> (see inset). However,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSA</ENAMEX> also equalized the relative transcriptional activity
          of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8Bshows that the isolated ERα LBD
          exhibited more potent transcriptional activity than the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ERβ LBD</ENAMEX>. However, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBDs</ENAMEX> showed similar
          transcriptional activity in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSA</ENAMEX>. Thus,
          corepressor complex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDACs</ENAMEX> must play an unspecified role
          in restricting the transcriptional activity of both ERβ
          and, in particular, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ-LBD</ENAMEX>. This is consistent with
          the notion that corepressors restrict the activity of
          agonist-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ-LBD</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Conclusions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRs</ENAMEX> generally interact with the corepressors <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> either in the absence of ligand, or in the presence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">receptor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX>, and agonists promote corepressor
        release [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . In this study, we demonstrated that ERβ
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">binds</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> agonists such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estradiol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DES</ENAMEX> and the phytoestrogens genistein and
        coumestrol, but not in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERMs</ENAMEX>. Moreover,
        this interaction is dependent upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF-2</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H12</ENAMEX>,
        and is competed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box peptides</ENAMEX> but not ID peptides. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hormone-dependent</ENAMEX> component of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ /N-CoR</ENAMEX> interaction
        maps to the extreme <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C-terminus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX>, which has not been
        previously implicated in NR interactions, and requires a
        sequence that resembles an ERβ-specific NR box (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLTIRMLS</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">β-box</ENAMEX>). In this regard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ERβ</ENAMEX> differs from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX>, which
        probably binds ID motifs in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERM</ENAMEX>-dependent fashion [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ] and shows reduced binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in the presence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estradiol</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> also differs from many other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRs</ENAMEX>,
        which either bind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in the absence of ligand and are
        released in the presence of ligand or interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-CoR
        in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> but not agonists [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
        The fact that the mode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-CoR
        resembles that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRs</ENAMEX> with coactivators [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , or with
        corepressors that modulate the activity of liganded NR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complexes</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RIP140</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] , raises the possibility
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> may be able to recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> to
        estrogen-regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> in response to agonists and
        that the balance of overall ERβ activity in the presence of
        estrogens may be regulated by competition between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p160s</TIMEX> and
        corepressors for the same ERβ AF-2 surface. We recognize
        that our studies do not directly address this issue. Our
        attempts to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> mutants that differentiate between
        GRIP1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> binding to analyze the role of
        agonist-dependent corepressor binding have not yet been
        successful (probably because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> utilizes the same surface
        to bind both cofactors). Moreover, transfection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> or
        various mutated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> derivatives did not significantly
        affect ERβ activity at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EREs</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
        We do not understand why, but in our hands, transfected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> also fails to affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> or ERα activity (data not
        shown), despite the fact that it clearly interacts with
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRs</ENAMEX>. Nevertheless, we suspect that estrogen-dependent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> binding may represent an important component of the
        regulation of ERβ activity. As described in the
        Introduction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> must interact differentially with
        factors that modulate <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> activity in the presence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">estrogens</ENAMEX>. The finding that estrogens suppress <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-CoR
        binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] , but promote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> binding to ERβ
        represents the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> demonstration of a corepressor that
        shows completely distinct modes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>-dependent
        interaction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> isoforms. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> and
        their associated HDACs are excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to explain
        some of the differential behaviors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> isoforms.
        Consistent with this notion, the apparent weak
        transcriptional activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ LBD</ENAMEX> is a consequence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corepressor</ENAMEX> HDAC activity at some level (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX>
        verification of the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> interaction with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> will await demonstration that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> recruits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> to estrogen-regulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> 
        in vivo , and that this event is
        related to modulation of estrogen response.
        While the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isoforms</ENAMEX> have contrasting effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1
        activity in the presence of estrogens, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> truncations that
        lack the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> both enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1 activity in the
        presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERMs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31</NUMEX> ] . Mutational analysis of ERα
        action at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1 sites suggests these effects may be related
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> binding [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] , and we have proposed that SERM
        action at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> may therefore involve contacts with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corepressors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31 51</NUMEX> ] . The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> show
        completely different ligand preferences of interaction with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> suggests that the target for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERM</ENAMEX> activation at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1
        sites may not be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in both cases. Thus, this finding
        complicates our attempts to explain this unusual
        phenomenon. Perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> isoforms enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1 activity
        by superficially similar mechanisms that involve different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cofactors</ENAMEX>. Alternatively, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> action at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1 sites
        could, in fact, be mediated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SERM-dependent</ENAMEX> contacts with
        a common cofactor that is, as yet, unidentified. This
        common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> may yet prove to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> if ERβ interactions
        with the β-box were somehow masked 
        in vivo .
        What features of the β-<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">box</ENAMEX> contribute to ERβ
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specificity</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intriguingly</ENAMEX>, the β-box contains <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proline</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal serine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> that extend the
        homology of this region to an artificial ERβ-specific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> ] . However, the β-box also lacks the first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leu</ENAMEX> of the consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LXXLL</ENAMEX>. A mutation (PL 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T IRML</ENAMEX>>PL 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L IRML</ENAMEX>) that restores the LXXLL
        consensus increases ERβ binding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and permits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα</ENAMEX> to
        bind to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> in the presence of estrogens in mammalian
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-hybrid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">assays</ENAMEX>. Thus, the unusual sequence of the β-box
        contributes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> specificity and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> can tolerate the
        absence of a conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal leucine in LXXLL motifs.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> might bind to yet more cofactors that contain variant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> boxes that resemble the β-box. Other aspects of ERβ
        interactions with corepressors warrant further study. It
        will be interesting to understand whether the weaker ERβ
        interactions with other regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> (which are
        insensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICI</ENAMEX>) play a role in ERβ binding (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>).
        Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> also binds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX> in the presence of estrogens,
        but we have not explored the structural features that
        promote this interaction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intriguingly</ENAMEX>, human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SMRT</ENAMEX> contains
        a sequence insertion at the position of the hydrophobic
        pair in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> β-box, which apparently leads to deletion
        of both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR/RMLS>SMRT/RLqagvmaS</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX> ] .
        Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SMRT</ENAMEX> contains a different NR interacting motif or
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR NR</ENAMEX> box sequence may be more complex than we have
        initially reported here.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Materials
          Estradiol, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diethylstilbestrol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DES</ENAMEX>), tamoxifen,
          genistein, coumestrol, thyroid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">retinoic acid</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">trichostatin A</ENAMEX> (TSA) were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). ICI <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">182,780</NUMEX> was a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wakeling</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astra/Zeneca Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macclesfield</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>).
          Raloxifene was a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stefan Nilsson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KaroBio AB</ENAMEX>,
          Huddinge, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>). Peptides were synthesized at the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biomolecular Resource Center</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSF</ENAMEX>.
          The following plasmids (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pSG5-ERα</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pSG5</NUMEX>-ERβ (amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">acids 1-530</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] , pGEX-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and pGEX-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMRT</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] ,
          VP16-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRβ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gal-N-CoR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST-N-CoR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fusions</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ]
          , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERE-LUC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">GK1/Gal4</ENAMEX> responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gal-ERα LBD</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> ] , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pM-D2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pM-D47</TIMEX>, pM-F6 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] ) have been previously
          described. VP16-ERβ LBD and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gal</ENAMEX>-ERβ LBD contain human ERβ
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> and were gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Leitmann</ENAMEX>
          was a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.
          Gal-GRIP1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> box (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,2,3</NUMEX>) fusion (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">610-770</ENAMEX>) was
          prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplification of the appropriate region
          of GRIP1 (primers obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biomolecular Resource</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSF</ENAMEX>) containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">EcoRI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SalI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, the PCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragment</ENAMEX> was digested with these enzymes and subcloned
          into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the pM GAL4</TIMEX> expression vector (Clontech
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratories, Inc.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, CA). VP16-ERβ mutations and
          Gal-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> mutations were prepared using standard
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PCR</ENAMEX>-based site directed mutagenesis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quickchange Kit</ENAMEX>,
          Stratagene, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA) and confirmed by sequencing.
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">GAL4</NUMEX>-β box fusion was prepared by synthesizing
          oligonucleotides corresponding to the β-box sequence with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineered EcoRI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SalI</ENAMEX> restriction sites. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annealed</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylated</ENAMEX> double stranded oligonucleotide was
          subcloned into the appropriate sites in the PM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacterial Protein Expression</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> Pulldown
          Assays
          GST-fusions were expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. Coli BL21</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] .
          Cultures were grown to OD600 1.5 at room temperatures
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately 22°C</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> production was initiated
          by addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPTG</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX>, bacterial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pellets</ENAMEX> were obtained, resuspended in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 mM HEPES</TIMEX> pH 7.9/
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">80 mM KCl/6</TIMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 /1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dithiothreitol/1</ENAMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/0.2</ENAMEX> mM
          phenylmethylsulfonyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX> and protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sonicated</ENAMEX>. Debris was pelleted by centrifugation in an
          ss34 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rotor</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> rpm. The supernatant was
          incubated with glutathione sepharose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4B</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beads</ENAMEX> (Amersham
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia Biotech AB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uppsala</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>) and washed as
          previously described. Protein preparations were stored at
          -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20°C</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> glycerol.
          Labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERs</ENAMEX> were produced using coupled 
          in vitro transcription-translation
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX> kit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>). Assays were
          carried out in a volume of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">150μl</TIMEX> that contained 137.5μl
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>-cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> binding buffer (PBB) along with 10μl
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX>-bead slurry corresponding to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3μg</NUMEX> of fusion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1μl</NUMEX> of 
          in vitro translated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and
          1.5μl of ligand or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> and/or peptides or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBB</ENAMEX> was freshly prepared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ml aliquots composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ml</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A-150</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hepes</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 mM</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MgCl2</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glycerol</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ml each of phosphate buffered saline
          supplemented, respectively, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">X-100</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> and protease inhibitor cocktail
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novagen</ENAMEX>) were added to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mM, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2μg/ml</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/1000</NUMEX>
          dilution respectively. The mix was incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in the cold <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with gentle agitation, the beads
          were pelleted by spinning briefly on a bench top
          Eppendorf centrifuge, washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times with PBB
          containing no BSA, and the pellet was dried under vacuum
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX>. Labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was subjected to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoradiography</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Transfections
          HeLa cells were grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DME</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/F-12 Ham's 1</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mix,</ENAMEX>
          without phenol red (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> iron
          supplemented calf serum (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and pen-strep. Cells were
          transfected by electroporation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . Transfections
          contained 2μg of luciferase and actin-β-galactosidase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and, where indicated, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1μg</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">VP16</NUMEX>-fusion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">GAL4</NUMEX>-fusion protein expression vectors or
          empty vector controls. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luciferase</ENAMEX> and β-galactosidase
          activities were measured using luciferase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Galacto-Light</ENAMEX> assay systems (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tropix</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        List of Abbreviations
        AIB1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amplified</ENAMEX> in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> 1.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF-1 Activation</ENAMEX> function 1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF-2 Activation</ENAMEX> function 2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Activator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> 1
        CARM1 Coactivator associated arginine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl</ENAMEX>-transferase
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
        CBP CREB binding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRE Cyclic Amp</ENAMEX> response element
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAX Dosage</ENAMEX> sensitive sex reversal adrenal hyperplasia
        congenital critical region on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">X-chromosome</ENAMEX>, region
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DES Diethylstilbestrol</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA Deoxyribonucleic acid</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DBD DNA</ENAMEX> binding domain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFα Tumor</ENAMEX> necrosis factor alpha 1
        E2 Estradiol
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERα Estrogen</ENAMEX> receptor alpha
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ Estrogen</ENAMEX> receptor beta
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estrogen</ENAMEX> response element
        GRIP1 Glucocorticoid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor interacting protein 1</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST Glutathione S</ENAMEX>-transferase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H Helix</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAT Histone</ENAMEX> acetyl-transferase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HET-SAFB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hsp27-ERE-TATA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding protein</ENAMEX>/scaffold
        attachment factor B.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HDAC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Histone de-</ENAMEX>acetylase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ID Interaction</ENAMEX> domain.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBD Ligand</ENAMEX> binding domain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR Nuclear</ENAMEX> receptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTD Amino</ENAMEX> terminal domain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR Nuclear</ENAMEX> receptor corepressor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS Phosphate</ENAMEX> buffered saline
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PCR Polymerase</ENAMEX> chain reaction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PERC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PGC-1</ENAMEX> related estrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> coactivator
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">coactivator 1</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Retinoic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> receptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REA Repressor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">estrogen</ENAMEX> receptor activity
        RIP140 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Receptor interacting protein</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX> Kd
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sodium</ENAMEX> dodecyl sulfate polyacrylamide gel
        electrophoresis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SMRT Silencing Mediator of Retinoid and Thyroid</ENAMEX>
        Responsive transcription.
        SHP Short <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heterodimer</ENAMEX> partner
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-1 Steroid receptor</ENAMEX> coactivator <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR Thyroid</ENAMEX> receptor
        TRAP220 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kd</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing Interests
        
        PW None declared.
        
        CV None declared
        
        PN None declared
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RHP Jr.</ENAMEX> None declared.
        
        AM Since the studies were performed,
        has moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plexxikon</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with interests in protein
        structure.
        
        BLW Since the studies were performed,
        has moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plexxikon</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with interests in protein
        structure.
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JDB</ENAMEX> has proprietary interests in, and
        serves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy director</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karo Bio AB</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swedish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that develops <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX> that target
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRs</ENAMEX>.
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PJK</ENAMEX> has significant financial interests
        in, and is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karo</ENAMEX> Bio
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AB</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Authors Contributions</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PW Conceived</ENAMEX> and directed the studies, wrote the paper,
        performed plasmid constructions and transfection
        studies.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CV Performed</ENAMEX> transfection, mutagenesis and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> pulldown
        experiments under guidance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PW</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PN Performed</ENAMEX> transfection, mutagenesis and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST</ENAMEX> pulldown
        experiments under guidance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PW</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RHP Jr.</ENAMEX> Provided intellectual input in the study
        design.
        AM. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expressed GST N-CoR</ENAMEX> fragments for pulldown studies
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERβ</ENAMEX>.
        BW Designed bacterial expression vectors for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-CoR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragments</ENAMEX>, cloned cDNA fragments for GST-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> expression
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vectors</ENAMEX> and provided intellectual input into the study
        design.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JDB</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directed</ENAMEX> studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NR</ENAMEX> interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-CoR</ENAMEX> and
        provided intellectual input into study design.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PJK</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-directed studies along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PW</ENAMEX> and provided
        intellectual input into study design.
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
