
  
    
      
        Background
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one third</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
        nuclear hormone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> superfamily function as
        heterodimers with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Retinoid X Receptors</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXRs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NR2B1-3</ENAMEX>)
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Some, but not all of these heterodimers can be
        directly activated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> agonists, called rexinoids, which
        include the endogenous ligand <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9-cis-retinoic</NUMEX> acid
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cis</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) and a number of synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compounds</ENAMEX>. The
        rexinoid responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> are referred to as permissive
        and include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peroxisome Proliferator Activated Receptor</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPAR</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Farnesoid X Receptor</ENAMEX> (FXR) heterodimers; the
        Retinoic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Acid Receptor</ENAMEX> (RAR), and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thyroid Hormone Receptor</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX>) heterodimers are non-permissive [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] .
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">xenobiotic</ENAMEX> receptor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">NR1I3</NUMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] is one of
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimers that has not been assigned to
        either category. Initial results showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR</ENAMEX> is an
        apparently constitutive transactivator able to activate
        gene expression in the absence of exogenously added ligands
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] . The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR ligands</ENAMEX> identified, androstanol and
        androstenol, are inverse agonists that block this
        constitutive transactivation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . More recently, it has
        been found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR</ENAMEX> mediates the characteristic response of
        a subset of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> metabolizing enzymes to a variety of
        structurally unrelated foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">compounds</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] . These
        xenobiotic activators are referred to as "phenobarbital
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PB</ENAMEX>) - like," based on the prototypic effects of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anti-epileptic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> on drug metabolism [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13 14</NUMEX> ] . The
        most potent activator of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">murine CAR</ENAMEX> is the high affinity
        agonist ligand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,4</NUMEX>-bis
        [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,5</NUMEX>-dichloropyridyloxy)]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">benzene</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] .
        The effects of specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligands on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX>
        heterodimer have not been characterized, although high
        concentrations of both <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cis</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and all-trans retinoic acid
        have been reported to block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PB</ENAMEX> induction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR targets</ENAMEX>
        CYP2B1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CYP2B2</ENAMEX> in primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat hepatocytes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . In
        addition, a recent report suggests that both compounds
        decrease <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">TCPOBOP-dependent CAR transactivation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . In
        both cases, these effects were primarily attributed to
        sequestration of limiting amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> into
        ligand-dependent homodimers or heterodimers with other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>.
        We have used several approaches to specifically examine
        the responsiveness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimer to rexinoids.
        Unexpectedly, different responses were observed using
        different methods. Direct biochemical measurements
        demonstrate that rexinoids can induce coactivator binding,
        but can also inhibit the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR agonist</ENAMEX> and inverse
        agonist ligands. In transient transfections, the presence
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligands can also inhibit the effects of these CAR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligands</ENAMEX>. However, different <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimer binding
        sites show distinct responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> activation. Overall,
        these results significantly increase the potential
        complexity of the response of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimers to RXR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligands</ENAMEX> and suggest a potential modulatory effect of
        rexinoids on xenobiotic responses.
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligands block effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR agonist</ENAMEX> and
          inverse agonist ligands on coactivator binding in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vitro</ENAMEX>
          Initial functional results suggested that
          transactivation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimers is not affected
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligands, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cis</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> or synthetic
          rexinoids, indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR</ENAMEX> is a non-permissive RXR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. However, gel shift studies indicated that the
          mobility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> complex bound to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DR-5</ENAMEX> element
          is increased by the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-cis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, suggesting that
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligand can bind to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimer. An
          increase in the mobility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was also
          observed in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> or androstanol, alone
          or in combination with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-cis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
          To test the effects of rexinoids on coactivator
          binding in a defined biochemical system, surface plasmon
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resonance</ENAMEX> was used to characterize the effects of the
          various ligands on binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterodimers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-3</ENAMEX> (also known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACTR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p/CIP</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RAC3</TIMEX>,
          AIB1, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TRAM-1</ENAMEX>), an effective coactivator for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR</ENAMEX> and many
          other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor superfamily</ENAMEX>. As
          expected, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cis</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> stimulated coactivator binding to RXR
          alone, and the basal interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR with SRC-3</ENAMEX> was
          enhanced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> and decreased by androstanol (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1A,1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>). The interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-3</ENAMEX> with the preformed and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">characterized CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was increased
          by either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cis</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1C). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Strikingly,</ENAMEX>
          however, coactivator binding to the heterodimer complex
          was decreased below the basal level in the presence of
          both ligands. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-3</ENAMEX> binding to the
          heterodimer was decreased by androstanol and this effect
          was largely blocked by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cis</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. These effects of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cis</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> on coactivator binding to the preformed
          heterodimer contrast with the strong stimulatory effect
          observed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> alone, confirming the characterization
          of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. These results demonstrate that the
          presence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligand can significantly alter the
          response of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR ligands</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Effects of rexinoids on CAR responses to agonist
          and inverse agonist ligands in cells
          To examine the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligands on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transactivation</ENAMEX> in a more functional context, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rexinoid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LG1069</ENAMEX> was combined with the CAR inverse agonist
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">androstanol</ENAMEX> and the agonist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> in a series of
          transient transfection studies using different response
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>. Initial studies were based on a well
          characterized binding site for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimers, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DR-5</ENAMEX> element from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of the retinoic acid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor β2 isoform</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9 16</NUMEX> ] . In agreement with the
          biochemical results, the rexinoid blocked both the
          stimulatory effect of the agonist and the inhibitory
          effect of the inverse agonist on this element (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A).
          In more detailed dose response studies, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 nM</NUMEX> LG1069
          decreased the inhibitory effect of androstanol by as much
          as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> and had an even stronger effect on TCPOBOP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B). Consistent with previous results [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> ] , deletion of the helix <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF-2</ENAMEX> motif of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR</ENAMEX>
          eliminated both constitutive and ligand dependent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transactivation</ENAMEX>. Deletion of the same motif in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> also
          strongly decreased transactivation, but did not
          completely eliminate ligand responses (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A).
          To test whether the apparent allosteric effects of
          LG1069 on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR transactivation</ENAMEX> vary with different
          response elements, the effect of the rexinoid on
          transactivation directed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">cytochrome P450</TIMEX> response
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> was examined. In contrast to the results with
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DR-5</ENAMEX> site, but in agreement with the biochemical
          results, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LG1069</TIMEX> alone had a stimulatory effect on the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ER-6 CAR</ENAMEX> response element from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of the CYP3A4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). This effect was not due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> homodimer
          function, since no transactivation was observed with RXR
          alone. In contrast to both the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DR-5</ENAMEX> and biochemical
          results, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LG1069</TIMEX> did not block the stimulatory effect of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX>. Instead, the stimulatory effect of the two
          agonists was retained when they were combined. Combining
          LG1069 with the inverse agonist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">androstanol</ENAMEX> resulted in a
          partial block in its inhibitory effect and an
          intermediate level of activity. Similar results were
          observed with the tandem DR-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> from the CYP2B10
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>, except that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LG1069</ENAMEX> did not have a significant
          stimulatory effect on its own, but did augment the effect
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX>. It is interesting that these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> CYP elements
          respond somewhat differently to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> cotransfection, which
          increases responses directed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CYP3A4</TIMEX> element but
          modestly decreases responses of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CYP2B10</NUMEX> element (data
          not shown). On both elements, similar results were
          observed when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-cis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> was substituted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LG1069</TIMEX> (data
          not shown). These results show that the negative effects
          of rexinoids on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> and androstanol signaling
          observed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DR-5</ENAMEX> site from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RARβ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> are
          not observed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DR-4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> from the CYP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX>. Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heterodimer</ENAMEX> responds
          differently to retinoids on different elements.
        
        
          Rexinoid inhibition of agonist activation of an
          endogenous CAR target gene
          A previously described HepG2 derivative stably
          expressing mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] was used to determine the
          effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> agonists on CAR function in the context of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native chromatin</ENAMEX>. Expression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CYP2B6</TIMEX>, a human relative
          of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CYP2B10</TIMEX>, is constitutively induced in this cell line.
          In contrast to the results with the transient
          transfections with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CYP</ENAMEX> response elements, CYP2B6
          expression was decreased to a comparable extent by
          androstanol, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LG1069</TIMEX>, and the combination of both ligands.
          CYP2B6 expression was increased by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX>, as expected,
          and this response was blocked by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LG1069</TIMEX> treatment.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> have been
        categorized as either permissive or non-permissive based on
        their responses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ligands</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Although there are
        some reported discrepancies, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPAR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FXR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NGF-IB/</ENAMEX>NURR1
        complexes are generally considered permissive, while the
        non-permissive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VDR</ENAMEX> complexes
        (see [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5 6 7</NUMEX> ] ). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">permissive complexes</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coactivators</ENAMEX> can presumably bind to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AF-2</ENAMEX> surface of
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> is stimulated
        by rexinoid agonists. This can result in distinct responses
        depending on which of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> is activated. In the
        case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPARγ/RXR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, for example, activation with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPAR</ENAMEX> or RXR specific ligands results in recruitment of
        quite different coactivators [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] .
        Among the non-permissive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR/RXR</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterodimer</ENAMEX> is the best studied. Recent results suggest
        that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal helix <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> exerts allosteric
        effects on RAR function [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . However, additional studies
        suggest that corepressor binding to the apo-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAR</ENAMEX> component
        of the heterodimer blocks rexinoid induced binding of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coactivators</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . These results suggest that the
        mechanisms that account for the lack of responsiveness of
        the non-permissive <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> are complex.
        As summarized in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, the results described here
        demonstrate that the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> agonists on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterodimer</ENAMEX> can be quite different in different contexts. 
        In vitro studies in the absence of
        DNA demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">heterodimers</ENAMEX> can be activated
        by an agonist ligand for either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. This positive
        response to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cis</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> contrasts with the inhibition that
        would result from the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> to ligand-dependent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homodimers</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , confirming that these studies reflect
        the activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimers and demonstrating that
        such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> can be permissive for RXR signaling.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remarkably</ENAMEX>, however, coactivator binding is decreased in
        the presence of both of the activating ligands. Similarly,
        the inhibitory effect of the inverse agonist ligand
        androstanol on coactivator recruitment is blocked by
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cis</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        In transient transfections, the rexinoid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">LG1069</TIMEX> shows
        different effects on the ability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">xenobiotic</ENAMEX> receptor
        to transactivate various response elements. The rexinoid
        alone has no effect on transactivation of the βRARE, but
        strongly inhibits responses to both the agonist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> and
        the inverse agonist androstanol. In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LG1069</ENAMEX> can
        stimulate transactivation of the response element from the
        CYP3A4 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>. On that element it does not block the
        stimulatory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX>, but decreases the inhibitory
        effect of the androstanol somewhat. On the tandem CYP2B10
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LG1069</ENAMEX> does not have a stimulatory effect on its
        own and does not decrease the inhibitory effect of
        androstanol, but it does increase response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX>.
        Finally, expression of the endogenous CYP2B6 gene in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR</ENAMEX>
        expressing HepG2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> is modestly inhibited by LG1069
        alone, androstanol alone and the combination of both. In
        this context, the rexinoid blocks activation by the agonist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX>.
        These rexinoid responses share the general theme of
        inhibition of some of the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR ligands</ENAMEX> by RXR
        ligands, but are clearly quite disparate. The differences
        may be based on variations in experimental approach or on
        more fundamental functional differences. For example, it is
        possible that the inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LG1069</ENAMEX> in the stable
        CAR expressing cell line is based on the sequestration of
        limiting amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> into ligand-dependent homodimers,
        as has been suggested in previous studies using primary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hepatocytes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] . However, similar effects were observed
        with the relatively large amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RXR</ENAMEX> used for the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biochemical</ENAMEX> studies or with the transient transfections,
        which relied on cotransfected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX>. It is also possible that
        differences in the chromatin context could contribute to
        the differences between the effects observed with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endogenous</ENAMEX> and transiently transfected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX>. However,
        such differences cannot account for the results with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter plasmids</ENAMEX> that differ only in the identity of the
        response element. Overall, we conclude that binding of both
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligands can result in allosteric
        effects on the function of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimer.
        The disparities in these responses preclude a single,
        simple explanation for the effects of rexinoids on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterodimers</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless, one attractive possibility is
        that binding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> agonist exerts direct inhibitory
        effects on either the binding or functional effects of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR ligands</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">precedence</ENAMEX> for a significant allosteric
        effect of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> heterodimer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> on another is provided by
        the inability of the insect <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ecdysone</ENAMEX> receptor to bind its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid ligand</ENAMEX> in the absence of its heterodimer partner
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] .
        The outcome of this inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR ligand</ENAMEX> binding
        would be somewhat different depending on whether or not the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> agonist was able to activate the basal transactivation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimer bound to a particular element. On
        the βRARE, for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> agonist might bind, but not
        increase transactivation beyond that observed in the
        absence of ligands. In this case, blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> binding
        would strongly inhibit TCPOBOP-dependent transactivation.
        In the case of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CYP3A4</NUMEX> response element, however,
        activation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> agonist is comparable to that
        observed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> alone. Thus, blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX> binding
        would not result in the net inhibitory effect observed with
        the βRARE, but could account for the lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">additive</ENAMEX>
        effect of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ligands.
        A variety of factors complicate this relatively simple
        model, including the specific cytoplasmic to nuclear
        translocation that is required for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR transactivation</ENAMEX> in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 23</NUMEX> ] . Rexinoids by themselves are
        apparently unable to induce this translocation process in
        rat [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] or mouse (data not shown) hepatocytes and thus
        cannot directly activate CAR <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>. More complex
        combinatorial effects of other coactivators or corepressors
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">e.g.</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] ) could also contribute to the observed
        responses. Recent results suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR</ENAMEX> can interact
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCoR</ENAMEX> or SMRT in the presence of inverse agonists [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
        ] , although such interactions appear much weaker than
        those of other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. Further characterization of
        potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR cofactors</ENAMEX>, as well as the development of
        sensitive and direct ligand binding assays will be required
        to define the molecular mechanisms that account for the
        diverse effects of rexinoids on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">CAR transactivation</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Overall, we conclude that the disparate effects of
        rexinoids on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> heterodimers in different contexts add
        significantly to the potential complexity of the effects of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligands on such nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor heterodimers</ENAMEX>, and
        demonstrate that classifying a particular complex as
        permissive or non-permissive can be an oversimplification.
        The results described here also suggest that rexinoids may
        have modulatory effects on xenobiotic responses, and that
        such effects may differ for different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX> target genes.
        A systematic examination of the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> ligands and
        retinoid status on a number of the growing set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR</ENAMEX>
        target genes will be required to explore this
        possibility.
      
      
        Materials and Methods
        
          Surface plasmon resonance
          The effect of ligands on coactivator binding was
          evaluated using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BIAcore</ENAMEX> instrument as described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> ] . For interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX>
          heterodimer with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SRC-3</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-SRC-3</ENAMEX> fusion protein
          containing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> interaction domain of the
          coactivator was expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> and purified. This
          fusion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was immobilized in flow cells using
          anti-GST <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. Lack of binding of free GST
          demonstrated that the surface was saturated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GST-SRC3</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Purified CAR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RXR proteins</ENAMEX> were produced in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> and preincubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4°C</NUMEX> alone or in
          combination, and in the presence or absence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -5M
          androstanol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -6M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCPOBOP</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 -6M</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> cis-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, as
          appropriate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR</ENAMEX> alone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> alone, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR/RXR</ENAMEX>
          heterodimers bound to various ligands were injected
          individually into flow cells and binding was measured as
          described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] .
        
        
          Plasmids
          The βRARE-TK-Luc <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmid with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> copies of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DR-5</ENAMEX> motif from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of the mouse RARβ2 gene
          has been described previously, as has the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CYP2B10</NUMEX>-TK-Luc
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> copies of the DR-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> from
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of the mouse CYP2B10 gene and the
          CYP3A4-TK-luc <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>-6
          element from the human CYP3A4 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
          Expression vectors for full length mCAR and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RXR</ENAMEX> proteins
          were as described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cdm8-mCARΔ8</ENAMEX> deletion
          construct containing a deletion of the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          and the mutant with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 helix 3 mutations</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">F171L, I174A</ENAMEX>)
          that block ligand binding and response have been
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , as has the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">cdm8</NUMEX>-RXRΔ19
          construct with a deletion of the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
          ] .
        
        
          Cell culture and transfections
          HepG2 cells were maintained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> medium (DMEM) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyclone</ENAMEX>). For transfections, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 5HepG2</NUMEX> cells were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plated</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> well dishes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          charcoal stripped serum and transfected using the calcium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX> precipitation method as described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . The
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, cells were washed with phosphate buffered
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">saline</ENAMEX> and ligands were added. Typically, transfections
          included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> ng of luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmids, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
          ng of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">β-galactosidase (β-gal</NUMEX>) internal control plasmid
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMV</ENAMEX> β-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gal</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> ng of cdm8 expression vectors. A
          total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> ng of plasmids was used per well. Cells were
          assayed for luciferase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>) activities <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>
          after addition of ligands and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> expression was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">normalized</ENAMEX> to β-galactosidase activity (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tropix</ENAMEX>) according
          to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s directions. Similar results were
          obtained from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> independent experiments.
          Error <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> are included for experiments where variations
          were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 10%</NUMEX>. A previously described derivative of
          HepG2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells stably expressing mCAR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] was used for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> analysis. Cells were subcultured and incubated in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> charcoal stripped bovine serum
          overnight. Various ligands were added and total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was
          prepared <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 hours later</TIMEX> and used for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> blotting
          using standard procedures [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX>' contributions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. T. and S. S. C.</ENAMEX> carried out the studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAR</ENAMEX>
        function in transiently transfected cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. S. C.</ENAMEX> carried
        out the studies of gene expression in stable CAR expressing
        cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. C.</ENAMEX> carried out the surface plasmon resonance
        studies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. D. M.</ENAMEX> directed these studies. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> read
        and approved the final manuscript.
      
    
  
