
  
    
      
        Synopsis
        
          Introduction
          In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> large numbers of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells infiltrate
          the inflamed synovium [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 3</ENAMEX>]. The accumulated CD4
          +memory T cells in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium appear to be
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activated</ENAMEX>, because they express cytokines and activation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markers</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 5, 6, 7, 8</ENAMEX>]. Expressed cytokines and
          activation markers should play important roles in the
          pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. However, the frequency of cytokine
          expression by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells has not been
          analyzed accurately. Recently, the roles of chemokine and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor interactions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">T-cell</ENAMEX> migration have
          been intensively examined. Interactions of chemokine and
          chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> might therefore be important in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium.
          Accordingly, correlation of cytokine and chemokine
          receptor expression might be important in delineating the
          function and potential means of accumulation of
          individual CD4 +memory T cells in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium.
          In the present study we analyzed cytokine (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-2, IL-4,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-13</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT-Î±</ENAMEX> ),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">activation marker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD154</ENAMEX> [CD40 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ligand</ENAMEX>] and TRANCE - also
          [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX>] or osteoclast differentiation factor [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ODF</ENAMEX>]), and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expression by individual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T
          cells isolated from rheumatoid synovium and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. To
          achieve this we employed a single-cell reverse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> (RT) polymerase chain reaction (PCR)
          technique. This technique made it possible to correlate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNAs</ENAMEX> expressed by individual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovium</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Materials and method
          Synovial tissues from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and peripheral
          blood mononuclear cells from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and a normal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> were analyzed.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytokine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-2</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-13</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT-Î±</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">activation marker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD154</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX>) expression by individual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> were analyzed using a
          single-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>. In brief, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">single CD4</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells
          was sorted into each well of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well PCR plate using a
          flow cytometer. cDNA from individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> was prepared,
          and then the cDNA was nonspecifically amplified. The
          product was then amplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> using gene-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> to analyze cytokine and activation marker
          expression.
        
        
          Results
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytokine</ENAMEX> and activation marker expression by
          individual CD4 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissues
          was analyzed using a single-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> method.
          Expression of mRNAs was analyzed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">152</NUMEX> individual
          synovial tissue CD4 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells sorted from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in which T-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR</ENAMEX>) CÎ² mRNA was
          detected. Frequencies of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells expressing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">activation marker mRNA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium are
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. IL-2, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> were not expressed
          by the synovial tissue CD4 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells, whereas
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> of cells expressed the other cytokine mRNAs.
          Few correlations between cytokine and activation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marker</ENAMEX> mRNAs were observed. Notably, no cells contained
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNAs, cytokines that are thought to
          define the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-helper</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Th</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phenotype</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. However, the
          frequency of TRANCE-positive cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-positive
          cells was significantly higher than that in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-negative cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Moreover, the frequency
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX>-positive cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±-positive cells was also
          significantly higher than that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±-negative
          cells.
          Varying percentages of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells expressed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. The frequency of
          CCR5-positive cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-positive cells was
          significantly higher than that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-negative cells,
          whereas the frequency of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CCR6</NUMEX>-positive cells in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î±-positive cells was significantly higher than that in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î±-negative cells, and the frequency of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CCR7</NUMEX>-positive
          cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-positive cells was significantly higher
          than that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-negative cells. Furthermore, the
          frequency of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CXCR4</NUMEX>-positive cells in TRANCE-positive
          cells was significantly higher than that in
          TRANCE-negative cells.
          Expression of cytokine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">activation marker mRNAs</ENAMEX> was
          also analyzed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> individual peripheral blood CD4
          +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. IL-2, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-4, IL-6,</ENAMEX>
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± were not expressed by the peripheral <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +CD45RO
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+T</ENAMEX> cells, whereas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX> of cells expressed the other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markers</ENAMEX>. The most striking difference between synovial
          tissue and peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells was the
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± expression in the former, but not in the
          latter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± were not expressed by normal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peripheral blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells, although they were
          expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells.
        
        
          Discussion
          The present study employed a single-cell PCR
          technology to analyze cytokine expression by unstimulated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue CD4 +memory T cells immediately after
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">isolation</ENAMEX>, without 
          in vitro manipulation. The results
          confirm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Th1</TIMEX> nature of rheumatoid inflammation. It is
          noteworthy that no individual synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T
          cells expressed both IFN-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNAs, even though
          these are the prototypic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Th1 cytokines</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. These
          results imply that, in the synovium, regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± must vary in individual cells, even though both
          Th1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytokines</ENAMEX> can be produced.
          The present data showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> expression
          correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ but not with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± expression by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovial</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells. It has been reported that
          CCR5 expression is upregulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial fluid and
          synovial tissue T cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11, 12</TIMEX>] and that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5 Î” 32</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deletion</ENAMEX> may have an influence on clinical manifestations
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>], suggesting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX> might play an important
          role in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Recently, it has been claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preferentially</ENAMEX> expressed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Th1</TIMEX> cell lines [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 15</TIMEX>].
          However, in the present study CCR5 was not expressed by
          all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-expressing cells. Moreover, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX> expression did
          not correlate with expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial CD4
          +memory T cells. Therefore, it is unclear whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> is
          a marker of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Th1 cells</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> expression correlated with CCR7 expression by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovial</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells. Recently, it was reported [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>] that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CCR7</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells express
          lymph-node homing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and lack immediate effector
          function, but efficiently stimulate dendritic cells.
          These cells may play a unique role in the synovium as
          opposed to in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. By producing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, they might
          have an immunoregulatory function. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          expression also correlated with expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX>.
          Although it is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> produced by these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> inhibited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T-cell</ENAMEX> activation in the synovium, TRANCE
          expressed by these same cells might function to activate
          dendritic cells and indirectly stimulate T cells,
          mediating inflammation in the synovium. These results
          imply that individual T cells in the synovium might have
          different, and sometimes opposite functional
          activities.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± expression correlated with CCR6 expression by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovial</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells. It has been reported that
          CCR6 is expressed by resting peripheral memory T cells [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>], whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± expression is associated with the
          presence of lymphocytic aggregates in synovial tissue [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>]. The correlation between the expression of these two
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markers</ENAMEX> therefore suggests the possibility that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR6</TIMEX> may
          play a role in the development of aggregates of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T
          cells that are characteristically found in rheumatoid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovium</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX> is known to be expressed by activated T cells,
          and can stimulate dendritic cells and osteoclasts [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>].
          Of note, TRANCE-mediated activation of osteoclasts has
          recently been shown [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>] to play an important role in
          the damage to bone that is found in experimental models
          of inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. It is therefore of interest
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX> was expressed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial CD4
          +memory T cells. Of note, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±-positive cells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expressed TRANCE</ENAMEX>. In concert, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX> expressed
          by this subset of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells might make them
          particularly important in mediating the bony erosions
          that are characteristic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
          Interestingly, there was a correlation between
          expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral blood CD4
          +memory T cells. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD154</TIMEX> expression
          correlated with that of CXCR3 by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells. It
          has been claimed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>] that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CXCR3</ENAMEX> is preferentially
          expressed by 
          in vitro generated Th1 cells.
          However, in the present study CXCR3 did not correlate
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ expression. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNAs
          were expressed 
          in vivo by peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T
          cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA was not detected,
          whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± were not detected in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healthy donors</ENAMEX>. These findings indicate that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells are stimulated 
          in vivo , although they do not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA. The present studies indicate that the
          frequencies of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells that expressed IFN-Î³
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and in the synovium are comparable. These
          results imply that activated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells migrate
          between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and synovium, although the direction of the
          trafficking is unknown. The presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA in
          synovium, but not in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, indicates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory
          cells are further activated in the synovium, and that
          these activated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells are retained in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovium</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA decreases.
          In conclusion, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells are biased toward
          Th1 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium and peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. In the
          synovium, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± were produced by individual
          cells, whereas in the rheumatoid blood no LT-Î±-producing
          cells were detected. Furthermore, there were modest
          correlations between individual cells that expressed
          particular cytokines, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, and certain
          chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor mRNAs</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Introduction
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> large numbers of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells infiltrate
        the inflamed synovium [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 3</ENAMEX>]. The accumulated CD4
        +memory T cells in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium appear to be activated,
        because they express cytokines and activation markers [ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4,</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5, 6, 7, 8</ENAMEX>]. Expressed cytokines and activation markers
        should play important roles in the pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        However, the frequency of cytokine expression by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD4 +T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> has not been analyzed accurately.
        Recently, the roles of chemokine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor
        interactions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">T-cell</ENAMEX> migration have been intensively
        examined. Interactions of chemokine and chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
        might therefore be important for the accumulation of the T
        cells in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium. Accordingly, correlation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expression might be
        important in delineating the function and potential means
        of accumulation of individual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovium</ENAMEX>.
        In order to analyze cytokine, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">activation marker</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expression by individual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T
        cells, we used a single-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> technique. The method
        made it possible to analyze cytokine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor
        expression by individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells
        without 
        in vitro stimulation, and to
        correlate cytokine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expression.
        Using this technique, we analyzed cytokine (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-2, IL-4,</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-13</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT-Î±</ENAMEX>), activation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marker</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD154</ENAMEX> [CD40 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ligand</ENAMEX>] and TRANCE - also called
        osteoclast differentiation factor [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ODF</ENAMEX>]), and chemokine
        receptor expression by individual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells
        isolated from rheumatoid synovium and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. The results
        indicate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells are biased toward Th1
        cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium, although individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> produced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ or LT-Î±, but not both. A similar pattern of cytokine
        production was observed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, with the exception that no cells expressing LT-Î±
        were detected. There were modest correlations between
        individual cells that expressed particular cytokine and
        chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor mRNAs</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and method
        
          Specimens
          Synovial tissues were obtained at surgery from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. The synovial tissue was minced and incubated
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml collagenase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) for
          1h at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in RPMI <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> medium (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Partially digested pieces of the
          tissue were pressed through a metal screen to obtain
          single-cell suspensions. Mononuclear cells were then
          isolated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ficoll-hypaque</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia Biotech</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) gradient centrifugation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> was
          diagnosed according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College of</ENAMEX>
          Rheumatology criteria [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>].
          Also, peripheral blood mononuclear cells were
          separated by ficoll-hypaque gradient centrifugation from
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and a normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Single cell sorting and reverse transcription
          polymerase chain reaction
          The method for construction of cDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> from
          single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> was similar to previously reported
          techniques [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21, 22</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue T cells were
          analyzed without 
          in vitro culture or stimulation by
          staining synovium mononuclear cells with FITC-conjugated
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> mono-clonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Q4120</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and
          PE-conjugated anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (UCHL-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>),
          after which individual <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells were sorted
          in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well PCR plate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robbins Scientific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvale</ENAMEX>,
          CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACStar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Peripheral CD4 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">single</NUMEX> cells were
          also sorted into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well PCR plates using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACStar Plusflow</ENAMEX> cytometer.
          Each well contained <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 Î¼l</NUMEX> lysis buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 mmol/l</ENAMEX>
          Tris-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCl</ENAMEX> [pH8<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>], <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">75 mmol</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/l KCl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 mmol/l MgCl</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 , 1 mmol/l DTT,10 Î¼mol/l dNTP</ENAMEX>
          [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>], <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml PRIME RNase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Inhibitor</ENAMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX> ?? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incorporated</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">300 U/ml RNAguard</ENAMEX>
          [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia Biotech</ENAMEX>], <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml oligo [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dT</ENAMEX>] 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated DNA Technologies</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incorporated, Coralville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>], and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP-40</ENAMEX>). The
          samples were heated to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">65Â°C</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>, cooled to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20Â°C</NUMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 min</TIMEX>, and maintained on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> units of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMV</ENAMEX> Reverse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transcriptase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M-MLV</ENAMEX> Reverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Transcriptase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies</ENAMEX>) was
          added, and the samples were incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> min
          before heat inactivation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min. For
          polyadenylate tailing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' end of the cDNA, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î</NUMEX>¼l
          tailing buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 mmol/l</ENAMEX> potassium cacodylate [pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.2</NUMEX>],
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 mmol/l CoCl</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX>/l DTT), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 mmol/l dATP</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> terminal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transferase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX>) were added, and incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX>, followed by heat inactivation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min.
          To amplify the cDNA non-specifically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed
          with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 mmol</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/l Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.0</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX>/l
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX>/l MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX>/l dNTP, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U Taq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Î¼mol/l X-</ENAMEX>(dT) 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 primer</TIMEX> (ATG TCG TCC AGG CCG CTC TGG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AAA TAT GAA TTC-</ENAMEX>dT 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated DNA Technologies</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incorporated</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of amplification were
          performed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 min at 94Â°C</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 min at 42Â°C</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min</ENAMEX> at
          72Â°C, plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> s extension per cycle. Afterward, 5U Taq
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> was added, followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an additional 25</NUMEX>
          cycles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>.
          For gene-specific amplification, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼l</NUMEX> of
          nonspecifically amplified cDNA was amplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Î¼ l 10</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/l Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.0</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 mmol</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/l KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mmol/l MgCl</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 Î¼mol/l dNTP</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.625</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U Taq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX>. The cycling program was:
          94Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">58Â°C: IL-2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX>),
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">72Â°C</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX>, followed by a final
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">extension</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> min. For nested amplification, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼l</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amplified PCR</ENAMEX> reaction mixture was added to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> PCR
          reaction mixture (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 mmol</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/l Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> [pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.0</NUMEX>],
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 mmol/l KCl, 1.5 mmol/l MgCl</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 Î¼mol/l dNTP,</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U Taq</ENAMEX> DNA polymerase). The cycling program was:
          94Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">72Â°C</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
          cycles, followed by a final extension for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> min. The PCR
          products were then separated by electrophoresis through
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.0%</NUMEX> agarose. The primers were designed to be within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bp of the 3</ENAMEX>' end of each mRNA. The primers used were as
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>.
          To confirm that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were amplified from
          the corresponding genes, the nucleotide sequences of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were analyzed. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products
          of each cytokine from a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequenced</ENAMEX>. All the sequences of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were
          identical to the previously published sequences (data not
          shown).
          To confirm that each well contained only one cell
          after sorting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VÎ²</ENAMEX> mRNA was analyzed by single-cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VÎ²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-specific primers. In the wells
          analyzed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR VÎ²</ENAMEX> was detected (data not
          shown).
        
        
          Statistical analyses
          To analyze correlations between cytokines and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expressions, and to compare
          frequencies of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor-expressing cells
          between different <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">T-cell</ENAMEX> subsets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>'s exact
          probability test was used.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytokine</ENAMEX> and activation marker expression by
          individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rheumatoid</ENAMEX> synovial tissue CD4 +memory T
          cells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytokine</ENAMEX> and activation marker expressions by
          individual CD4 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissues
          were analyzed by employing a single-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> method.
          Expressions of mRNAs were analyzed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">152</NUMEX> individual
          synovial tissue CD4 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells sorted from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCR CÎ²</ENAMEX> mRNA was detected. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytokine</ENAMEX> and
          activation marker expressions by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> synovial tissue CD4
          +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">RA1</NUMEX>) are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
          Frequencies of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells that expressed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">activation marker mRNA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium are
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. IL-2, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> were not expressed
          by the synovial tissue CD4 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells, whereas
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> of cells expressed the other mRNAs.
        
        
          Correlation of the expression of cytokines by
          rheumatoid synovial tissue CD4 +memory T cells
          Few correlations between cytokine and activation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marker</ENAMEX> mRNAs were observed. Notably, no cells contained
          mRNAs for both IFN-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î±, cytokines that are thought
          to define <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Th1</TIMEX> phenotype [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. However, the frequency
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX>-positive cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-positive cells was
          significantly higher than that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-negative cells
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Moreover, the frequency of TRANCE-positive
          cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±-positive cells was also significantly
          higher than that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±-negative cells.
        
        
          Correlation of cytokine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor
          expression by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue CD4 +memory T
          cells
          Varying percentages of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells expressed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CXC</ENAMEX> chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> as shown in Tables 4and 5.
          Thus, for example, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells
          expressed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCRb</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CCR7</NUMEX> mRNAs, whereas <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">expressed CXCR3</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">76%</NUMEX> expressed CXCR4 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNAs</ENAMEX>. The
          frequency of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CCR5</NUMEX>-positive cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-positive cells
          was significantly higher than that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-negative
          cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>), whereas the frequency of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CCR6</NUMEX>-positive
          cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î±-positive cells was significantly higher
          than that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î±-negative cells, and the frequency of
          CCR7-positive cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-positive cells was
          significantly higher than that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-negative cells.
          Furthermore, the frequency of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CXCR4</NUMEX>-positive cells in
          TRANCE-positive cells was significantly higher than that
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX>-negative cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytokine</ENAMEX> and activation marker expression by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peripheral blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and
          a normal donor
          Expressions of cytokine and activation marker mRNAs
          was also analyzed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> individual peripheral blood CD4
          +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells sorted from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>
          individual peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells sorted
          from a normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>. Frequencies of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells
          that expressed cytokine and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">activation marker mRNA</ENAMEX> are
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>. IL-2, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± were not
          expressed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T
          cells, whereas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX> of cells expressed the other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markers</ENAMEX>. The most striking difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial
          tissue and peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells was the
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± expression in the former, but not in the
          latter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± were not expressed by normal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peripheral blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells, although they were
          expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells.
          Variable frequencies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T
          cells expressed chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor mRNAs</ENAMEX>. Except for
          significantly decreased expressions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5 and CXCR4</TIMEX>,
          there were no differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor
          expressions by synovial tissue and peripheral blood CD4
          +memory T cells. In peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells,
          there was a significant correlation between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> expressions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR6</ENAMEX> expressions ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P <0.05; Table 7</ENAMEX>). In addition,
          CD154 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CXCR3</ENAMEX> expressions correlated ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.005</NUMEX>). No other correlations
          were detected (data not shown).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The present study employed single-cell PCR technology to
        analyze cytokine mRNA expressions by unstimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        synovial tissue CD4 +memory T cells immediately after
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">isolation</ENAMEX>, without 
        in vitro manipulation. The results
        are consistent with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> nature of rheumatoid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inflammation</ENAMEX>. These data showed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial
        CD4 +memory T cells produced IFN-Î³ mRNA. Previous studies [
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 5, 6</ENAMEX>] reported that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial T cells
        expressed IFN-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> by immunohistologic analysis.
        Although there is some variation in the results obtained
        with the different methodologies, both results are
        consistent with the conclusion that there is a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> bias in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3, 23</ENAMEX>]. It is noteworthy that no individual synovial
        CD4 +memory T cells expressed both IFN-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA,
        even though these are the prototypic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Th1 cytokines</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>].
        These results imply that, in the synovium, regulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± must vary in individual cells, even though
        both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Th1</TIMEX> cytokine mRNAs can be expressed.
        The present data showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> expression correlated
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ but not with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± expression by synovial CD4
        +memory T cells. It has been reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> expression
        is upregulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial fluid and synovial tissue T
        cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11, 12</TIMEX>], and that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5 Î” 32</TIMEX> deletion may have
        an influence on clinical manifestations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>],
        suggesting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX> might play an important role in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        Recently, it has been claimed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 15</TIMEX>] that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">preferentially</ENAMEX> expressed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Th1</TIMEX> cell lines. In the present
        study, however, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX> was not expressed by all IFN-Î³
        expressing cells. Moreover, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX> expression did not
        correlate with expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial CD4
        +memory T cells, although it correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³ .</ENAMEX>
        Therefore, it is unclear whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR5</ENAMEX> is a marker of Th1
        cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium.
        Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, and
        the expression correlated with CCR7 expression. It has been
        reported that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 1.5%</NUMEX> of synovial T cells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">express IL-10</ENAMEX> by immunohistochemistry [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>], and that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovial</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD4 +T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> have the potential to express <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>]. Recently, it was reported [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>] that, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>,
        CCR7 +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells express lymph-node homing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and lack immediate effector function, but
        efficiently stimulate dendritic cells. However, because <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> tissue CD4 +memory T cells expressed CCR7 and there
        was a correlation between <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> production and CCR7
        expression, these cells may play a unique role in the
        synovium as opposed to in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. By producing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>,
        they may exert an immunoregulatory function. In addition,
        it is interesting to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> expression also
        correlated with expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX>. Although it is
        possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> produced by these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> inhibited
        T-cell activation in the synovium, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX> expressed by
        these same cells might function to activate dendritic cells
        and indirectly stimulate T cells, mediating inflammation in
        the synovium. These results imply that individual T cells
        in the synovium might have different, and sometimes
        opposite functional activities.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± was expressed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> of the synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells, and the expression correlated with CCR6
        expression, which is expressed by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX> of the synovial CD4
        +memory T cells. However, there were no LT-Î±-expressing CD4
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+T</ENAMEX> cells that also produced IFN-Î³, although <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">synovial</ENAMEX> CD4
        +memory T cells that produced each cytokine were found in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abundance</ENAMEX>. It has been reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR6</ENAMEX> is expressed by
        resting peripheral memory T cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>], whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î±
        expression is associated with the presence of lymphocytic
        aggregates in synovial tissue [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. The correlation between
        the expression of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> markers therefore suggests the
        possibility that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR6</TIMEX> might play a role in the development
        of aggregates of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells that are characteristically
        found in rheumatoid synovium.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX> is known to be expressed by activated T cells,
        and can stimulate dendritic cells and osteoclasts [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. Of
        note, TRANCE-mediated activation of osteoclasts has
        recently been shown [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>] to play an important role in the
        damage to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> found in experimental models of inflammatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. Recently, the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX> in rheumatoid
        synovium was reported [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 25</TIMEX>]. It is therefore of
        interest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX> was expressed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovial</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells. Of note, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX> expression
        correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CXCR4</ENAMEX> expressions.
        Especially noteworthy was that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±-positive cells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expressed TRANCE</ENAMEX>. In concert, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRANCE</ENAMEX> expressed by
        this subset of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells might make them
        particularly important in mediating the bony erosions that
        are characteristic of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        Interestingly, there was a correlation between
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral blood CD4
        +memory T cells. Production of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> differs from
        that in the mouse, in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> production does not appear
        to be restricted to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Th2</NUMEX> cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. As noted here, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">peripheral CD4 +T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> could express both IFN-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD154</TIMEX> expression correlated with
        CXCR3 by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells. It has been claimed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]
        that CXCR3 was preferentially expressed by 
        in vitro generated Th1 cells.
        However, in the present study CXCR3 did not correlate with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ expression. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNAs were
        expressed 
        in vivo by peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T
        cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA was not detected, whereas
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± were not detected from healthy
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. These findings indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> peripheral blood
        CD4 +memory T cells are stimulated 
        in vivo , but that they do not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA. Previous studies have documented the
        presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> in circulating T cells of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 27</TIMEX>]. The present studies indicate that
        the frequency of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells that express IFN-Î³ in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and synovium is comparable, although the
        percentages that secrete IFN-Î³ are not known. These results
        imply that activated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells migrate between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and synovium, although the direction of the
        trafficking is unknown. The presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA in
        synovium but not in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> indicates that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory cells
        are further activated in the synovium, and that these
        activated CD4 +memory T cells are retained in the synovium
        until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± mRNA decreases.
        In conclusion, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +memory T cells are biased toward Th1
        cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium and peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. In the synovium,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LT</ENAMEX>-Î± were produced by individual cells, whereas
        in the rheumatoid blood no LT-Î±-producing cells were
        detected. Furthermore, there were modest correlations
        between individual cells that expressed particular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokines</ENAMEX> and certain chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor mRNAs</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
