
  
    
      
        Introduction
        The synovial tissue in rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>)
        contains synovial fibroblasts and stromal cells as well as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX>. Synovial stromal cells and fibroblasts are
        thought to proliferate 
        in situ [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. On the contrary,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">macrophages</ENAMEX> do not proliferate, but rather differentiate
        from monocytes that migrated from the peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, and
        are activated to differentiate in the synovial tissue.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macrophages</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium secrete many inflammatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mediators</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-1, IL-6, IL-8</ENAMEX>, tumor necrosis factor-Î±
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX>] and PGE 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) and a variety of matrix
        metalloproteinases, and are thought to play a central role
        in the inflammation and joint destruction characteristic of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. The number of macrophages in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">correlates</ENAMEX> significantly with clinical symptoms and the
        degree of joint damage [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. Understanding the regulation
        of macrophage accumulation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium should
        therefore provide insight into the inflammatory nature of
        rheumatoid synovitis.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migration</ENAMEX> of peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood monocytes</ENAMEX> is likely to be
        influenced by chemokines. A number of chemokines, including
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, monocyte chemotactic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">protein-1</TIMEX> (MCP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), macrophage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inflammatory protein-1Î±</ENAMEX> (MIP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Î±</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î²</ENAMEX>,
        epithelial-derived neutrophil attractant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78</TIMEX>, and regulated
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>), are known to be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial fluid [ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4,</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5, 6, 7, 8</ENAMEX>]. A number of specific chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>
        including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR1</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR8</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CXCR4</ENAMEX> are also known
        to be expressed by peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood monocytes</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9, 10</ENAMEX>].
        Despite this information, the specific chemokine-chemokine
        receptor interactions involved in the recruitment of
        monocytes into the rheumatoid synovium have not been fully
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">delineated</ENAMEX>.
        To address this issue, we examined <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor
        expression by peripheral blood monocytes, and also analyzed
        the capacity of supernatants from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial stromal cells
        to induce monocyte migration. The data indicate that MCP-1
        secreted by synovial stromal cells plays a major role in
        attracting monocytes to the synovium, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> may
        also contribute.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Antibodies</ENAMEX> and reagents
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Biotinylated</ENAMEX> mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCR1 monoclonal antibody</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">mAb</NUMEX>), mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCR2</ENAMEX> mAb conjugated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phycoerythrin</ENAMEX> (PE), mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCR6</ENAMEX> mAb conjugated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>, mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CXCR1</ENAMEX> mAb conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>,
          mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CXCR2</ENAMEX> mAb conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>, mouse
          anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CXCR5</ENAMEX> mAb conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX>, mouse anti-human
          CCR3 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX>, mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> mAb
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">24822.111</NUMEX>), mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8 mAb</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6217.111</NUMEX>), mouse
          anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">33036.211</NUMEX>), mouse anti-human CCR5
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mAb</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">45531.111</NUMEX>), and biotinylated goat IgG anti-human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems Inc</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>). Mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CCR5</ENAMEX> mAb conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> and
          mouse anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CXCR4</ENAMEX> mAb conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pharmingen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA). Mouse
          anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD14</ENAMEX> mAb conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> or PE, and
          Streptavidin conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mouse IgG1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> was prepared from
          hybridoma cell lines purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mouse IgG2A</ENAMEX> conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> IgG2B
          conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> IgG1
          conjugated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA)
          were used for negative controls for flow cytometry.
          Recombinant human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interferon-gamma</ENAMEX>
          inducible protein <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> (IP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>), and stromal cell derived
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-1Î±</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>. Trizol
          reagent, deoxyribonucleaseI, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SuperScriptII</ENAMEX> reverse
          transcriptase were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco BRL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). Taq polymerase was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promega</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oligo</ENAMEX> dT and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ficoll</ENAMEX>/isopaque were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> with high-glucose,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RPMI-1640</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco BRL</ENAMEX>.
          Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays (ELISAs) for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î²</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> were purchased from R&D
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems</ENAMEX>, and transwell membranes (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î¼m pore size in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wells</ENAMEX>) were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Costar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>). The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TMB</ENAMEX> microwell peroxidase substrate system was purchased
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KPL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Stromal cell lines and fibroblast lines
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> stromal cell line (SCL) was established from
          synovium as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. In brief,
          College of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rheumatology</ENAMEX> criteria [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>] was obtained
          following informed consent, and dissociated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagenase</ENAMEX> and trypsin. Dissociated cells were cultured
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> conditioned
          medium, which was prepared by incubation of peripheral
          blood mononuclear cells from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> in
          RPMI-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1640</NUMEX> medium with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 h.</TIMEX> The cultures were
          then maintained for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 2 months</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCLs</ENAMEX> were
          cloned by limiting dilution. Clones were thereafter
          maintained and replenished with fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> medium with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FBS</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 3-4 days</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> clone (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sy77</NUMEX>) was used in
          the present experiments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> tissues from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were also dissociated with collagenase and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trypsin</ENAMEX>. Dissociated cells were cultured in DMEM
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> conditioned medium and
          used as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RA6/1</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">RA8/3</NUMEX>) after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4-10 passages</TIMEX>. An
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCL</ENAMEX> was also established from osteoarthritis synovium
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">OA5/26</NUMEX>) using the same procedure. A skin fibroblast line
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBHG</ENAMEX>) was also established from a healthy human skin
          sample.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCL</ENAMEX> and fibroblast culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX>, osteoarthritis (OA) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCL</ENAMEX>, and skin fibroblasts
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Ã— 10 5</ENAMEX>) were seeded in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-well culture plates
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costar</ENAMEX>) with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 U/ml</ENAMEX>
          penicillinG, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml gentamicin and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L-glutamine</ENAMEX>, and cultured for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX>. After culturing,
          the cells were washed once and the medium was changed to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 U/ml penicillinG, 10 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          gentamicin, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml L-glutamine with or without 2
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml TNF-Î±.</ENAMEX> To assess chemokine mRNA expression, cell
          lines were harvested after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 h</TIMEX> of culture, then suspended
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trizol</ENAMEX> and stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-80Â°C</TIMEX>. Supernatants were
          collected after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX> and stored at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-80Â°C until</TIMEX> use for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration</ENAMEX> assay and quantification of chemokines.
        
        
          Peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) were
          isolated from heparinized blood of healthy adult
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> by density sedimentation using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ficoll/isopaque.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> were cultured with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> red blood
          cells (SRBC) treated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">70 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>, and rosette
          negative cells were collected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ficoll</ENAMEX>/isopaque
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sedimentation</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expression by monocytes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expression by monocytes was
          assessed by dual immunofluorescence flow cytometry
          following staining with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD14</NUMEX> mAb and anti-chemokine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor mAbs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACScan; Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>). For staining
          chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼l</NUMEX> of each mAb was used for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Ã—
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 5cells</TIMEX> suspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î¼l staining buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>) in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          instructions.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migration</ENAMEX> assay
          Cell migration was assessed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well chemotaxis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chambers</ENAMEX> fitted with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5.0 Î¼m</NUMEX> transwell membranes.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supernatants</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">550 Î¼l</ENAMEX>) of cell lines cultured in various
          conditions were added to the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          5SRBC rosette negative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î¼l <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> were added to the upper <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>. In blocking
          experiments, the supernatants were cultured with blocking
          mAbs specific for chemokines <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> before
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRBC</ENAMEX> rosette negative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBMC</ENAMEX> were incubated with
          blocking mAb to chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h at 4Â°C</TIMEX> before
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> in some experiments. The transwell membranes were
          removed after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90 min</TIMEX> of incubation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>, and migrated
          cells in the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> were harvested by pipetting.
          The cells were stained with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD14</NUMEX> mAb conjugated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX>, and they were suspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">110</NUMEX> Î¼l <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>. All of the cells were analyzed by flow cytometry and
          CD14 +cells were counted.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolation and reverse transcriptase-polymerase
          chain reaction
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCLs</ENAMEX> and fibroblasts using
          Trizol reagent in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          instructions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> micrograms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">extracted RNA</ENAMEX> was
          treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U DNaseI</ENAMEX> to eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, and reverse
          transcribed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U SuperScriptII</ENAMEX> reverse
          transcriptase at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX> min using oligo dT primers
          in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions.
          Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) was carried out with Taq
          polymerase using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> Î¼l cDNA (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denaturation</ENAMEX> and extension
          conditions were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 min and 72Â°C</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>,
          respectively. The annealing period was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 min</NUMEX> for each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>, and the temperature was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">62Â°C</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">56Â°C</ENAMEX> for
          the other chemokines and Î²-actin. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were
          resolved by electrophoresis on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX> agarose gels and
          identified with ethidium bromide staining. Firstly,
          Î²-actin expression was examined using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26-30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of
          reverse transcriptase-PCR (RT-PCR) to amplify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>,
          and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.3 Î¼l</NUMEX> cDNA to adjust the amount of cDNA of each
          sample precisely. After resolving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products on
          agarose gels and identifying the relevant bands with
          ethidium bromide, the optimal amounts of cDNA for
          analysis were then determined. Chemokine expression in
          this amount of cDNA was examined using <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 32, 35, 38</TIMEX>,
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplification, and the results in
          the linear part of the amplification curve are reported
          in the figures.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> primers
          The primer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> for Î²-actin was <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">GTC CTC TCC CAA</ENAMEX> GTC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAC ACA</ENAMEX> (forward) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CTG GTC TCA AGT CAG TGT ACA GGT</ENAMEX> AA
          (reverse), that of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CTG CGC CAA CAC AGA AAT TA</ENAMEX>
          (forward) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ATT GCA TCT GGC AAC CCT AC</ENAMEX> (reverse), that
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCC TCC AGC ATG AAA GTC TC</ENAMEX> (forward) and TAA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AAC AGG GTG TCT GGG GA</ENAMEX> (reverse), that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> was CCA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CGT GTT GAG ATC ATT GC</ENAMEX> (forward) and TGG AAG ATG GGA AAG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTG AG</ENAMEX> (reverse), that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CGC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TGT CAT CCT CAT</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TGC TA</ENAMEX> (forward) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GCT GTC TCG AAC TCC TGA CC</ENAMEX>
          (reverse), that of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î±</ENAMEX> was TGC AAC CAG TTC TCT <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GCA TC</ENAMEX>
          (forward) and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">ACA GGG GAA CTC TCA GAG CA</ENAMEX> (reverse), and
          that of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î²</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">CTG GGT CCA GGA GTA CGT GT</ENAMEX> (forward)
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ACA GTG GAC CAT CCC CAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AG</ENAMEX> (reverse).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>
          Concentrations of chemokines were measured by sandwich
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX> paired 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">t</ENAMEX> test was used to compare the
          effect of CD14 cell migration, and the blocking effect of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mAbs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">t</ENAMEX> test was used to evaluate
          chemokine production by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCLs</ENAMEX> and the fibroblast line.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expression by peripheral blood
          monocytes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expression by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD14</NUMEX> +monocytes was
          examined using flow cytometry. Representative examples
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) and asummary of staining results (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>) are
          presented. CXCR3 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CXCR4</ENAMEX> were expressed by a high
          frequency of monocytes in all healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. More than
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">one-half</ENAMEX> of monocytes expressed CCR2, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR1</TIMEX>, and
          CXCR2 in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> cases, although a minimal number
          of monocytes from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> expressed these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>.
          Expression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR6 and CXCR5</TIMEX> by monocytes was minimal in
          all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. CCR1 was expressed by few monocytes in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, whereas <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20-40%</NUMEX> of monocytes of the other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> expressed CCR1. These results suggest that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR1</TIMEX>,
          CCR2, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CXCR1</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR3</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CXCR4</ENAMEX> are
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to be involved in chemokine-mediated
          trafficking of monocytes.
        
        
          Supernatants of cell lines attract monocytes
          To examine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SCLs</ENAMEX> derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium can
          attract monocytes efficiently, migration of monocytes in
          response to culture supernatants of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA SCLs</ENAMEX> and
          fibroblasts was examined (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Supernatants of all
          cell lines attracted significantly more monocytes than
          medium alone ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>). Those supernatants
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> induced the migration of significantly more
          monocytes than the supernatants of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA SCL</ENAMEX> and skin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Chemokine mRNA production by cell lines
          Production of proinflammatory chemokine mRNA by the
          various cell lines was assessed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCLs</ENAMEX> expressed a number of proinflammatory chemokine
          mRNAs, including <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î±</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î²</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA SCL</ENAMEX> also expressed these same chemokine mRNAs
          with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î²</ENAMEX>. The fibroblast line
          expressed mRNAs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX>, but not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î±</ENAMEX>, and MIP-1Î².
        
        
          Chemokine production by cell lines
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chemokines</ENAMEX> secreted into the culture supernatants of
          cell lines were measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Production of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> was greater than that by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> SCL
          and the fibroblast line. The cell lines produced low
          levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MIP1-Î²</TIMEX> were not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detected</ENAMEX> (data not shown).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> play a role in migration of
          monocytes
          Blocking experiments were carried out using mAbs to
          determine the chemokines that contribute to monocyte
          migration induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and
          anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mAbs</ENAMEX> decreased monocyte migration
          significantly, with the effect of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> being
          consistently greater than that of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>. Anti-CCR5
          blocking mAb did not effect monocyte migration. The
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CCR5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> did have blocking activity, however, since
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration of T</ENAMEX> cells induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">500 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) was
          blocked by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> (data not shown).
        
        
          Stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± induces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX> to produce
          more chemokines and attract more monocytes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> were stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, and chemokine
          production and the capacity of supernatants to influence
          monocyte migration were examined to assess the influence
          of inflammatory cytokines on chemokine production and
          monocyte trafficking. Supernatants from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> SCLs
          stimulated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX> produced more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>), and attracted more monocytes
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) than those that were unstimulated.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> play major roles in monocyte
          migration by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± stimulation
          Anti-MCP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mAb and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> mAb significantly
          inhibited monocyte migration by supernatants of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> SCLs
          stimulated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-Î±.</ENAMEX> Anti-IP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mAb and anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CCR5</NUMEX> mAb
          did not inhibit monocyte migration significantly (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        The results of this study indicate that supernatants of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SCL</ENAMEX> derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue can attract more
        monocytes from peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA SCL</ENAMEX> and skin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and, to a lesser degree, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> played the
        major roles in SCL-induced trafficking of monocytes. These
        results begin to provide an explanation for the extensive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of myeloid cells in rheumatoid synovium.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX> induced more monocyte migration after
        stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, one of the major inflammatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokines</ENAMEX> produced in the rheumatoid synovium.
        Peripheral blood monocytes express many chemokine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9, 10</ENAMEX>], including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR1</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR8</TIMEX>, and
        CXCR4. The current analysis indicates that, along with
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR2</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CXCR3</ENAMEX> are also expressed
        by monocytes. CCR1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CXCR3</TIMEX>, and
        CXCR4 notably appear to be expressed by monocytes obtained
        from most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.
        Ligands of these chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to
        be involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">monocyte</ENAMEX> trafficking. These ligands would
        include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-3</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CCR1</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-2</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-4</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-5</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CCR2</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î±</ENAMEX>, and MIP-1Î²
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CCR5</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CGP-2</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CXCR1</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GROÎ±</ENAMEX>, and
        epithelial-derived neutrophil attractant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CXCR2</NUMEX>), IP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        and MIG (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CXCR3</NUMEX>), and stromal cell derived <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-1</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">CXCR4</NUMEX>)
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migration</ENAMEX> assays using supernatants of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> were
        employed to determine which of these chemokine and receptor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interactions</ENAMEX> might be involved in monocyte migration in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium.
        Stromal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> are one of the important cell populations
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCL</ENAMEX> can produce many cytokines, chemokines,
        and can promote viability and functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activation</ENAMEX> of T
        cells and B cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 15, 16</TIMEX>]. The current findings also
        indicate that supernatants of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> attract more
        monocytes than the supernatants of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA SCL</ENAMEX> and skin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX>. This result suggests that the supernatants
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> may contain more chemokines than or different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemokines</ENAMEX> to those of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA SCL</ENAMEX> or fibroblast lines and,
        therefore, are able to attract additional monocytes. This
        is likely to contribute to the more marked accumulation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monocytes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> synovium.
        An analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokines</ENAMEX> produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX> indicated
        that these cells expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNAs</ENAMEX>, and also
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">secreted MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>. It is noteworthy that there were
        some discrepancies between mRNA expression and protein
        production. From the mRNA expression, we expected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> SCLs
        to produce reasonable amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î±</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î²</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX>, however, secreted only small amounts of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIP-1Î²</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">secretion</ENAMEX> was not detected.
        According to previous reports, mRNAs of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> were found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX> or fibroblasts, but only MCP-1
        was reported to be secreted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX> or fibroblasts
        without cytokine stimulation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 5, 17, 18</ENAMEX>]. The current
        study indicates a wider profile of chemokine expression and
        secretion by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX>, and also a greater production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCP-1</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX> compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA SCL</ENAMEX>, implying a
        greater proinflammatory potential.
        Experiments with blocking mAbs were carried out to
        examine the chemokines in the supernatants of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCL</ENAMEX> that
        accounted for monocyte migration. The data were consistent
        with the conclusion that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and, to a lesser extent,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> accounted for the capacity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX> supernatants to
        stimulate monocyte migration. Whether additional cytokines
        produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCL</ENAMEX> also contributed to monocyte migration
        is currently not known, but the combination of the
        chemokine data and the mAb blocking results suggests that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> play a dominant role in monocyte migration
        measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCL</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± is one of the major cytokines produced in
        inflammatory sites such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium, and it is thought
        to play a central proinflammatory role [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. We examined
        the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± on monocyte migration induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCL</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> stimulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± secreted more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> than those that were unstimulated, and began to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">produce IP-10</ENAMEX>. Moreover, supernatants of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±-stimulated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA SCLs</ENAMEX> attracted more monocytes in migration assay. MCP-1
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> played the main roles in monocyte migration
        induced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±-stimulated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA-SCL</ENAMEX>, as documented by
        blocking experiments.
        It has recently been reported that T cells expressing
        CCR5 gather at inflammatory sites such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> or multiple
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sclerosis</ENAMEX>, and that interactions between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX> and its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligands</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIP-1Î±</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MIP-1Î²</ENAMEX>) are thought to be
        important in the accumulation of inflammatory cells at
        these sites [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19, 20, 21</TIMEX>]. CCR5 expressed by monocytes,
        however, was not apparently active in transmitting
        transmigratory signals. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> is also the ligand of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR1</TIMEX>,
        but the major <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> is thought to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>. In
        this regard, expression of CCR1 by monocytes was lower than
        that of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> blocked
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75% and 20%</NUMEX> of migration of monocytes, respectively.
        According to this information, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> is unlikely to play a
        major role in monocyte migration by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> SCL
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatants</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> has been shown to play an important role in the
        development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in MRL-lpr <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>], whereas the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration</ENAMEX> of monocytes into inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> was reduced
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the CCR2</TIMEX>-deficient mouse [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. These results are
        consistent with the current findings, demonstrating the
        important role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> in monocyte migration. Blocking the
        effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> has, however, also been shown to be
        effective in ameliorating collagen-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in
        DAB<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and adjuvant-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in rats [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> might, therefore, play a different role in the
        initiation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">inflammatory arthritis</ENAMEX> in experimental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> compared with propagating chronic inflammation in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        The overlapping roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in the migration
        of inflammatory cells have recently been highlighted in
        studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">neutrophil</ENAMEX> trafficking. It was reported that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> plays a role in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">neutrophil</ENAMEX> trafficking in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inflammation</ENAMEX>, although neutrophil trafficking was
        previously believed to be regulated only by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>, and not
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>]. These previous results, together with the
        current data, indicate that both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> play major
        roles in regulating the trafficking of myeloid cells into
        inflammatory sites.
        The role of specific chemokines in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> is still
        controversial, and further investigation is necessary to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">delineate</ENAMEX> to specific roles of these effector molecules.
        Moreover, the role of tissue cells in regulating the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration</ENAMEX> of inflammatory cells into the synovium is also
        not fully established. The current data, however, strongly
        imply that monocyte accumulation in rheumatoid synovium is
        regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCL</ENAMEX> via production of the chemokines <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCP-1</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">enzyme</NUMEX>-linked immunosorbent assay; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IP-10</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma inducible protein</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> = monoclonal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCP-1</ENAMEX> = <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monocytechemotactic protein-1</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIP</ENAMEX> =
        macrophage inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">osteoarthritis</ENAMEX>; PBMC
        = peripheral blood mononuclear cells; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phycoerythrin</ENAMEX>;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">= rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> = regulated upon activation,
        normal T cell expressed and secreted; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> = reverse
        line; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SRBC</ENAMEX> = sheep red blood cells; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± = tumor necrosis
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">factor-Î±</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
