
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> is an autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> that is characterized by
        persistent local and systemic inflammation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 3</ENAMEX>].
        Aggressive forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> are thought to be driven by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>-lymphocyte activity, leading to the rapid erosion of bone
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Activated Tm</ENAMEX> are found in the perivascular
        regions of the inflamed synovium, and T cells accumulate in
        the synovial fluid [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 5, 6</ENAMEX>]. It appears that memory T
        cells retain the potential to traffic through the synovium
        and lymphatics and recirculate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, as evidenced
        by the increased numbers of activated memory T cells found
        in the blood of some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6, 7, 8</ENAMEX>]. It is not
        known, however, whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tm</ENAMEX> migrate into the synovium and
        undergo activation and further differentiation, or whether
        activation occurs in regional lymph nodes before migration
        into the inflammatory site.
        
        In vitro studies [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9, 10</ENAMEX>] have
        demonstrated that synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells proliferate poorly
        and produce decreased levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-2</ENAMEX> in response to mitogen
        or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>, as compared with peripheral blood T cells from
        healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Although such findings
        suggest that synovial T cells might be partly anergic, more
        recent studies have indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> found in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium were postactivated cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Synovial T</ENAMEX> cells were
        activated as assessed by expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CD40 ligand/CD154,</ENAMEX>
        and were also efficient helpers for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-cell</ENAMEX> immunoglobulin
        production [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 10, 11, 12, 13</TIMEX>]. Previous studies in animal
        models [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 15</TIMEX>] suggested that a balance exists between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunoregulatory IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Th1 cells</ENAMEX> and
        IL-4-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Th2 cells</ENAMEX>. Dominance of either subset can
        result in a chronic disease <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Moreover, induction of
        Th2 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX>-mediated disease model of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> led to amelioration of
        autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. Thus, it is possible that, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>,
        there is biased differentiation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-secreting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proinflammatory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Th1 CD4 +T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX>, and insufficient
        differentiation of immunoregulatory <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-producing Th2
        cells.
        Human memory T cells acquire the ability to secrete IL-4
        late during 
        in vivo differentiation. Our previous
        studies and work by others have demonstrated that all of
        the 
        in vivo differentiated IL-4-producing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells reside within the mature memory (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD27</NUMEX> -)
        subset of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 18, 19</TIMEX>]. Thus, early memory
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD27</NUMEX> +) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells cannot secrete <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> after a
        brief 
        in vitro stimulation. Previous
        studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 18</TIMEX>] suggested that early memory T cells
        represent an uncommitted precursor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, from which
        both IL-4-producing and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing effector cells can
        be generated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium appears to contain an
        increased number of phenotypically mature memory T cells as
        compared with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. However, the majority of memory T
        cells found in the synovium bear the phenotype of early Tm
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>].
        Therefore, the present study was undertaken to examine
        the cytokine effector status of synovial memory T cells and
        the functional status of immature memory cell precursors of
        cytokine-producing effector cells. For these experiments,
        Tm were isolated from the blood of normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, and
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAST</ENAMEX>. Intracellular cytokine expression
        was assessed by flow cytometry immediately after isolation
        and a brief 
        in vitro stimulation, or after 
        in vitro priming designed to generate
        IL-4-producing effector T cells.
        The results suggest that a deficiency in the generation
        of adequate numbers of regulatory IL-4-producing effector
        cells in the synovium might be a contributing factor to the
        perpetuation of chronic inflammation.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Antibodies</ENAMEX> and reagents
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAbs</ENAMEX> used included the following: anti-CD3 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">OKT3</TIMEX>;
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collection</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>),
          anti-CD8 (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">OKT8</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collection</ENAMEX>),
          anti-CD16 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">B73.1</NUMEX>; generous gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr G Trinchieri</ENAMEX>, The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wistar Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), anti-CD19
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dako, Glostrup</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>), anti-CD45RO (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCHL1; Dako</ENAMEX>), and
          anti-CD45RA (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2H4</TIMEX>; gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dr C Morimoto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>)
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 18</TIMEX>]. Anti-CD28 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">28.2</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phycoerythrin</ENAMEX> (PE)-labeled
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-2</NUMEX>, PE-labeled anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>, and fluorescein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isothiocyanate</ENAMEX> (FITC)-labeled anti-IFN-Î³ was from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). FITC-labeled anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX>,
          and PE-labeled or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum</ENAMEX> red-labeled anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> was from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Recombinant IL-4</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">recombinant IL-15</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Neutralizing antihuman <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFN-Î³ antibody</ENAMEX> was from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endogen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Culture medium contained
          RPMI1640 with penicillin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 U/ml</ENAMEX>), gentamicin (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-glutamine (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml), and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> normal human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serum</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>].
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>
          All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had an established diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, as
          defined by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> revised criteria of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of Rheumatology</ENAMEX> for the classification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. All
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had long-standing, active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were
          obtained after informed consent, as approved by the UT
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern Institutional Review Board</ENAMEX>. The data shown
          were obtained from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (age range <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29-78</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>). Matching <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and synovial fluid were obtained
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Peripheral blood alone was obtained
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> and synovial fluid samples were obtained
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Matching <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and synovial tissue
          samples were obtained from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at the time of
          surgery. An additional synovial tissue sample was
          obtained from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Cell preparation
          Mononuclear cells were isolated from synovial tissue
          by treating the synovial tissue with collagenase briefly
          at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> with constant shaking. The cells were washed,
          filtered through nylon mesh, and briefly adhered to
          plastic petri dishes at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> to deplete residual
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblast</ENAMEX> and monocytes [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7, 9</ENAMEX>]. Mononuclear cells were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or synovial samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
          or sex-matched and age-matched healthy adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
          by ficoll density centrifugation. Cells were washed and
          incubated with neuraminidase-treated sheep red blood
          cells, and purified by negative selection panning as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. The cells were incubated with
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX>, anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD19</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B73.1</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2H4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mAbs</ENAMEX>. After panning,
          the recovered cells were routinely <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">greater than 99%</NUMEX> CD3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">+</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> CD4 +, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> enriched for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +cells.
        
        
          Cell culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells were immediately stimulated after isolation
          with ionomycin (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 Î¼M</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), phytohemagglutinin (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wellcome Diagnostics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), and
          phorbol myristate acetate (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) in the
          presence of monensin (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼M</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> h and were fixed
          in paraformaldehyde for subsequent intracellular cytokine
          analysis. In some experiments, T cells were primed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> before cytokine analysis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Ã—10</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5cells/ml</ENAMEX>) were cultured in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costar</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Where indicated, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were coated
          with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> mAb (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">OKT3</NUMEX>) before addition of T cells.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Medium contained 10 U/ml recombinant IL-2, 5 ng/ml</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">recombinant IL-15</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml recombinant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, anti-CD28
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mAb</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) and, where indicated, neutralizing
          anti-IFN-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>). After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 week</TIMEX> in culture
          the cells were harvested and counted. The cells were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">washed</ENAMEX>, and incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> h in medium containing IL-2
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/ml</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-15</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) before restimulation. In
          preliminary experiments the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-4</ENAMEX> during the
          rest phase did not increase the number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-producing
          cells detected on subsequent restimulation. Restimulation
          and intracellular cytokine analysis were carried out as
          described above for immediately stimulated T cells [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>].
        
        
          Flow cytometry
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 Ã— 10 5</ENAMEX>) were stained with saturating
          amounts of directly conjugated mAb and analyzed on the
          fluorescence-activated cell sorter (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACScan; Becton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). For intracellular staining
          of cytokines, cells were stimulated as described above.
          The cells were harvested, washed, fixed with
          paraformaldehyde, perme-abilized with saponin, and
          blocked with rodent serum. The cells were stained with
          directly conjugated mAbs to human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cytokines</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen</ENAMEX>)
          and analyzed by flow cytometry [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. Stimulated cells
          that were stained with irrelevant mAbs were used as
          controls. Analysis was carried out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 4cells</TIMEX> for each
          sample.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          percentages of cells that expressed each cytokine were
          determined using the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tailed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX>'s 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> -test, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Rank</ENAMEX>
          Sum when appropriate. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.05</ENAMEX> was considered
          statistically significant.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Enrichment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFN-gamma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> in freshly
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isolated RA</ENAMEX> synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells
          Initial experiments delineated cytokine production by
          freshly isolated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells obtained from
          matching samples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX>. A representative
          sample is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">patient1</ENAMEX>). The majority of
          peripheral blood T cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> secreted IL-2
          alone, whereas fewer cells secreted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> alone or in
          combination with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX>. By contrast, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells
          isolated from the synovial fluid demonstrated a
          significant increase in the percentage of cells that
          produced IFN-Î³ alone or in combination with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX>, whereas
          a decrease was observed in the percentage of cells that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">secreted IL-2</ENAMEX> alone. Few cells from peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or
          synovial fluid produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>.
          Matching samples obtained from the peripheral blood
          and synovial tissue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were also assessed for
          cytokine expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> patient <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). As was
          observed in the synovial fluid, memory T cells isolated
          from the synovial tissue contained a decreased percentage
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-2</NUMEX>-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> and an increased percentage of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing cells. Thus, T cells isolated from the
          rheumatoid synovial tissue and fluid demonstrated a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">polarized Th1</ENAMEX> cytokine profile.
          As a control, the cytokine profiles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tm</ENAMEX> from normal
          adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> were examined (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">normal1</ENAMEX>). As
          observed for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, the majority of
          cells produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX> alone, whereas fewer cells produced
          the combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX> Relatively infrequent
          cells expressed a highly polarized phenotype by producing
          either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> alone or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> alone.
          A compilation of the frequency of cells that produced
          each cytokine from a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
          After a brief 
          in vitro stimulation, the majority
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tm</ENAMEX> obtained from normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX> alone (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> Â±
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>; mean Â± SEM). Fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> produced the combination of
          IL-2 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>). Relatively infrequent cells
          expressed a highly polarized phenotype by producing
          either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> alone (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>). Less than
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> produced the combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and
          IL-4.
          Cytokine secretion profiles of freshly isolated Tm
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) also demonstrated that most
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">secreted IL-2</ENAMEX> alone (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>), whereas fewer cells
          produced <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">IL-2</NUMEX> in combination with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>). There
          was no significant difference between the normal T cells
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA T</ENAMEX> cells for these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Of note, there was a
          significant ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>) increase in the
          percentage of cells that secreted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> alone compared
          with normal cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>), whereas there
          was no difference between normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX> in the
          number of cells that secreted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> alone (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>) or in
          the frequency of those rare cells that produced the
          combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0%</NUMEX>).
          cells isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) that produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX> alone (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>
          Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX>) when compared with normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>) or RAPB ( 
          secreted the combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>),
          which was significantly greater than the percentage of
          the same subset in normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>) or RAPB ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>). The percentage of
          RASF cells that produced IFN-Î³ alone (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX>) was also
          significantly increased over the percentage of such cells
          in normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.002</NUMEX>) or RAPB ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.002</NUMEX>) T cells.
          Significantly fewer cells produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> alone (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0%</NUMEX>) as
          compared with normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>) or RAPB ( 
          cells that produced the combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>
          Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0%</NUMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAST Tm</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) also contained a decreased
          percentage of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-2</NUMEX>-secreting cells (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX>), which did
          not differ significantly from that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX>, but did
          differ significantly from that in normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>). The percentage of
          cells that produced both IFN-Î³ and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>) did not
          differ significantly from that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX>, but was
          significantly greater than the frequencies observed in
          normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>) or RAPB ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAST</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">effectors</ENAMEX> secreted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> alone. This was not
          different from the percentage found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX>, but was
          significantly greater than the percentage of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.005</NUMEX>) or RAPB ( 
          significant difference in the number of synovial tissue
          cells that produced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> alone (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-4</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0%</NUMEX>), as compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX>, normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX>.
          Thus, T cells isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAST</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX> demonstrated
          a decrease in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-2</NUMEX>-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>, with a concomitant
          increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> when compared with
          normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB Tm</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rheumatoid</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells demonstrate defective
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">responsiveness</ENAMEX> to differentiation signals in vitro
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Peripheral blood</ENAMEX> and synovial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tm</ENAMEX> were than examined in
          an 
          in vitro culture system in order to
          determine the relative capacity of differentiation
          signals to modulate cytokine production. Our previous
          studies with normal T cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>] demonstrated that this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> effectively generates polarized IFN-Î³-producing or
          IL-4-producing effector cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3shows the composite
          cytokine profiles of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +T cells obtained from
          cultures primed with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> and cytokines in the
          absence or presence of anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> mAb. As seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3,</ENAMEX>
          stimulation of normal T cells after priming with
          anti-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD28</TIMEX> alone resulted in a significant decrease in the
          percentage of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX>) compared
          with cells immediately stimulated after isolation, and a
          significant increase in the percentages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX>
          versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>). After
          priming with a low dose of anti-CD3 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>; middle
          panel), the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> decreased
          further and the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-secreting cells
          increased. As previously shown, the generation of
          IL-4-secreting cells was optimally induced by priming
          with anti-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD28</TIMEX> alone and was inhibited by costimulation
          with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>].
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX> demonstrated a distinct
          pattern of responsiveness. Whereas the percentage of
          IL-2-secreting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> decreased after 
          in vitro priming with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> as
          compared with freshly isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX>), a
          greater decrease was observed after priming with low dose
          anti-CD3 (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX>), and the cells were resistant to further
          modulation by higher concentrations of anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX>. Of note,
          the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-2</ENAMEX> production by 
          in vitro primed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA T</ENAMEX> cells was less
          marked than observed with normal T cells. An increased
          percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> was observed after priming,
          and the peak response was achieved in the presence of low
          concentrations of anti-CD3 (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX>). Again, the
          induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ production in RAPB memory T cells was
          less than noted in normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. IL-4-producing cells
          were generated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> memory T cells by stimulation with
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX>, and these were inhibited by the presence of
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> mAb. The percentage of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX>)
          generated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> memory T cells was less than was
          generated from normal T cells (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX> primed with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> exhibited a
          decrease in the percentage of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-2</NUMEX>-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX>
          versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX>) and an increase in the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
          secreting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX>) as compared with freshly
          isolated cells. Synovial fluid T cells were deficient in
          the ability to generate IL-4-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>), which
          was in contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB T</ENAMEX> cells were
          refractory to priming by high concentrations of anti-CD3
          mAb, the synovial fluid T cells responded to anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> in
          a dose-dependent manner. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> derived from synovial
          tissue were also relatively refractory to 
          in vitro priming as compared with
          normal blood T cells. Synovial tissue T cells contained
          an increased percentage of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48%</NUMEX> versus
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37%</NUMEX>) and a small decrease in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23%</NUMEX> versus
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34%</NUMEX>) after 
          in vitro priming with anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-secreting cells (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>) could be
          generated from synovial tissue memory T cells after 
          in vitro differentiation, although
          in lesser numbers than from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX> and normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priming</ENAMEX> in the presence of anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD3</NUMEX> reduced the
          percentages of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-2</NUMEX>-producing and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>,
          while increasing the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-secreting
          cells.
        
        
          Effect of anti-IFN-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma</ENAMEX>; antibody on the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-secreting effector cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          synovial fluid T cells
          In order to determine whether cytokine production by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rheumatoid T</ENAMEX> cells was resistant to modulation in the 
          in vitro priming cultures because
          of the secretion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, the 
          in vitro priming was also carried
          out in the presence of anti-IFN-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. As shown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, the addition of increasing concentrations of a
          neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> had little effect on the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of cytokine-producing cells from either normal
          synovial fluid or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells. Then we examined
          whether the combined effects of anti-IFN-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> and
          IL-4 could influence the effector phenotype of cells
          isolated from the synovium. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tm</ENAMEX> were
          isolated from matching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX>, and were cultured
          under conditions that optimized the generation of
          IL-4-secreting effector cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB Tm</ENAMEX> generated a
          marked increase in the percentage of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-producing cells
          when primed with the combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-4</ENAMEX> and anti-IFN-Î³
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. In contrast, T cells from the synovial fluid of
          the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> generated virtually no IL-4-producing
          cells and few IL-2-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>, despite supplemental
          IL-4 and anti-IFN-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>.
          As a control, cell growth during the priming cultures
          was monitored in the presence or absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>. As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, synovial T-cell
          growth was not inhibited by the addition of anti-IFN-Î³
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>. These data suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB Tm</ENAMEX> have
          the capacity to generate IL-4-producing or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing effector cells, whereas memory T cells
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX> are inhibited in their capacity to become
          IL-4-producing effector cells. Further studies indicated
          that anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> mAb and cytokines enhanced synovial fluid
          Tm growth <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately fourfold</NUMEX> above the initial input
          cell number. Synovial fluid T cells cultured in medium
          alone underwent a fourfold reduction in cell number,
          whereas cells cultured with cytokines alone increased in
          number by an average of twofold (data not shown). These
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> further support the conclusion that synovial fluid T
          cells were responsive to signals delivered by the
          combination of anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> and cytokines.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAST</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF</ENAMEX> were deficient in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-secreting cells as
        compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAPB</ENAMEX> after a brief 
        in vitro stimulation. Thus, mature
        IL-4-secreting effector cells were found to be decreased in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium but not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>.
        There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> major mechanisms by which IL-4
        production might be inhibited in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium. One
        mechanism could be through the selective recruitment of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing effector cells. For example, it has been
        suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium have
        been selectively recruited on the basis of expression of
        chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> found in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rheumatoid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">synovium</ENAMEX> express <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CCR5</TIMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells found at
        sites of parasitic infection express CCR4 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CCR3</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>]. However, the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemokine</ENAMEX> receptor expression in
        the recruitment of T cells to these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> is unknown. This
        possibility cannot be the full explanation of the current
        observations in light of the finding that synovial tissue T
        cells had the capacity to differentiate into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-secreting
        effector <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in 
        in vitro cultures. Thus, some
        synovial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> remained responsive to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>- and
        anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX>-mediated signaling in the priming cultures. A
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mechanism for suppression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-4</ENAMEX> production in the
        rheumatoid synovium could be through regulatory signals
        received in the local microenvironment. This remains a
        likely possibility because studies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">murine</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> have
        shown that only the most highly differentiated T cells
        obtain a polarized cytokine secretion profile that cannot
        be altered by external stimuli [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> possibility
        is that precursor cells of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> rapidly migrate
        out of the synovium, perhaps being unresponsive to
        retention signals.
        Although the exact mechanism that is operative in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovium</ENAMEX> remains to be elucidated, our ongoing studies are
        focused on determining the phenotype and response defect of
        these highly polarized Th cells.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tm</ENAMEX> isolated from rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or synovium contained
        increased numbers of cells with the capacity to produce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ after a brief 
        in vitro stimulation, compared with
        the same subset isolated from the periphery of normal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. A strong mitogenic stimulation was employed in
        order to obtain the maximum cytokine-secreting potential of
        the effector <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. We have previously demonstrated
        that staining for intracellular cytokines correlated with
        cytokine secretion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. However, intracellular cytokine
        analysis proved to be a more sensitive method for detecting
        cytokines, such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2 and IL-4</TIMEX>, and also made it possible
        to determine the percentage of cells producing each. It
        should be noted that longer incubations did not result in a
        substantial increase in the number of cytokine-secreting
        cells detected in this assay. These studies corroborate
        previous studies that demonstrated that synovial T cells
        are enriched in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> on initial isolation
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. The results suggest that these memory cells appear
        to have undergone biased differentiation into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> cells,
        perhaps as a result of signals received in the synovial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microenvironment</ENAMEX>. The small increase in the number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> found in rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> may well
        reflect the recirculation of memory T cells previously
        activated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7, 23</ENAMEX>].
        Tm were used for these studies because it has been shown
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7, 9</ENAMEX>] that the majority of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium
        are of the memory subset. Therefore, a potential concern
        was that the 
        in vitro priming protocol might
        select for cells that are already committed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ or
        IL-4 production, rather than generate new effector cells.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, however, highly polarized effector T cells arise
        late in the differentiation pathway [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 18, 19</TIMEX>]. Whereas
        early memory T cells, identified by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +, CD27
        +phenotype, have the potential to secrete <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³,
        these cells cannot produce <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">IL-4</NUMEX> and few produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ in
        the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-2</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 19</TIMEX>]. Only mature memory cells,
        identified by the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD45RO</ENAMEX> and the loss of CD27
        cell-surface expression, have the capacity to secrete IFN-Î³
        or IL-4 alone. We have previously shown that the 
        in vitro priming protocol used in the
        present study induces the differentiation of early
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncommitted</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD27</NUMEX> +memory T cells into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-producing
        effector cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. Thus, it was hypothesized that the
        uncommitted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early CD4</TIMEX> +, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD27</NUMEX> +memory cells that were
        isolated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> maintained the
        capacity to differentiate into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-producing effector
        cells. The majority of T cells that are found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        synovium belong to the early memory subset [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. Therefore,
        the defective generation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial
        fluid under conditions that induced IL-4-producing effector
        cells from blood memory T cells suggested that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rheumatoid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">microenviroment</ENAMEX> played an important role in
        selecting or modifying the precursor effector memory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        CD28 is expressed by most human T cells and is thought
        to be critical for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T-cell</ENAMEX> differentiation. CD28 is also
        important during <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T-cell</ENAMEX> receptor-mediated activation, IL-2
        production, and the prevention of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">anergy</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. Recent
        studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 26, 27</TIMEX>] have indicated that there were
        increased numbers of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD28 -T</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the periphery
        and synovium of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Therefore, the lack of
        expression of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD28</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells represented a
        potential explanation for the abnormal memory T-cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">differentiation</ENAMEX> observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> blood and tissue and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">deficiency</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-producing effector cells from the
        synovial fluid after 
        in vitro priming. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +,
        CD28 -cells are a minor subset of T cells, representing
        less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> of peripheral <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells from the most
        chronically active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1%</NUMEX> from
        healthy control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>], and are therefore
        unlikely to account for the broad defect in memory T-cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> found here. We have observed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +,
        CD28 -cells in the periphery represent a unique subset that
        is restricted to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD27</NUMEX> -population (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis L</ENAMEX>,
        unpublished observation). As noted above, although there
        were increased numbers of well-differentiated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +, CD27
        -cells in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium, these cells represented the
        minority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tm</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. Therefore, the inability to modulate
        effector <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> responses in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RASF samples</ENAMEX> could not be
        explained by the absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD28</TIMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF T</ENAMEX> cells
        were capable of cell growth in response to anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> mAbs
        and cytokines. This finding is in agreement with previous
        studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>] demonstrating that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">CD28</NUMEX> signaling pathway
        was intact in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells.
        The present studies also demonstrated that synovial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluid Tm</ENAMEX> lacked the capacity to generate IL-4-secreting
        effector <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in numbers similar to those found in the
        periphery. Our previous studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>] demonstrated that
        IL-4 was required during the 
        in vitro priming cultures to generate
        IL-4-producing effector cells from non-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-producing early
        memory precursor cells. Therefore, one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> in the
        current studies was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA T</ENAMEX> cells might require exogenous
        IL-4 to generate IL-4-producing effector cells.
        An additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing effector
        cells might inhibit potential <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> precursors from
        differentiating or expanding in these cultures, although
        previous studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29, 30, 31</TIMEX>] demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        indirectly affected the generation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-secreting cells
        through the activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-presenting cells. It
        should be noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-presenting cells were depleted
        from the memory <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">T-cell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> before priming in the
        present studies, and therefore this possibility was only a
        minor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.
        Both the addition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> to the priming cultures and
        the presence of anti-IFN-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody ensured</ENAMEX> that potential
        IL-4-secreting precursor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> had optimal conditions
        for differentiation. Blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ activity during 
        in vitro priming with a neutralizing
        anti-IFN-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> had little effect on the number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-secreting effector cells detected on subsequent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restimulation</ENAMEX>. Moreover, the availability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> had
        little impact on the generation of either subset. Thus, the
        inability to generate IL-4-producing effector cells from
        RASF precursor cells was not simply explained by the
        presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-producing effector cells or the lack of a
        subset of fully differentiated IL-4-producing T cells in
        the initial memory cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Recent studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>]
        have suggested that there is an intrinsic defect in the
        development of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-producing effector cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Therefore, it is possible that the apparent
        disordered differentiation of effector cells becomes more
        marked at inflammatory sites such as in the rheumatoid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovium</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 32</TIMEX>].
        It is interesting to note that both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-2</ENAMEX> production and
        IL-4 production appear to be downregulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RASF T</ENAMEX> cells.
        Previous studies [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>] have shown that mature memory (CD45RO
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+, CD27 -</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells isolated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> have the
        same capacity as early memory (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD45RO</NUMEX> +, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD27</NUMEX> +) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T
        cells to produce <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">IL-2</NUMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX> appears to
        be downregulated [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. It should be noted that IL-2
        production was not decreased in T cells obtained from
        osteoarthritic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tm</ENAMEX> obtained from
        other tissues, such as inflamed tonsil, expressed levels of
        IL-2 that were similar to those in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis L</ENAMEX>,
        unpublished observation). Therefore, migration into tissue 
        per se does not induce downregulation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-2</ENAMEX> production. Recent studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>] have attributed
        the lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-2</ENAMEX> production by synovial <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +T cells to a
        defect in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">T-cell</ENAMEX> receptor-mediated signal transduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cascade</ENAMEX>. However, in the present studies we made use of
        stimuli that bypassed the early steps in the T-cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-mediated signaling cascade and found that there
        was defective <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-2</NUMEX> production in cells stimulated
        immediately on isolation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovium, whereas
        these same cells were completely competent for IFN-Î³
        production. Thus, it is interesting to speculate that IL-2
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-4</ENAMEX> are downregulated in the rheumatoid synovium by
        some active repressor mechanism induced by the synovial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microenvironment</ENAMEX>. Although recent studies have indicated
        that redox balance alterations were critical in determining
        whether cells can produce IL-2 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33, 34</TIMEX>], it is not known
        whether this influences <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> production, or has it been
        determined whether readjustment of redox balance in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovial T</ENAMEX> cells could correct the deficiency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>.
        Few studies have used similar techniques to assess
        cytokine production in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, synovial tissue, and synovial
        fluid obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunohistology</ENAMEX> is
        routinely carried out on synovial tissue sections, whereas
        enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays are employed to
        determine cytokine profiles of serum and synovial fluid [
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 11, 12, 13, 31</TIMEX>]. Therefore, it has remained difficult to
        determine the potential impact of these compartments on
        T-cell function in rheumatoid inflammation. In the current
        studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA T</ENAMEX> cells from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> compartments produced
        increased amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ on immediate stimulation.
        However, the cytokine profiles diverged when assessed after
        
        in vitro priming. Whereas, synovial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tissue Tm</ENAMEX> were deficient in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> compared with
        matching <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, these cells retained the ability to
        generate IL-4-producing effector cells. In this regard,
        recent studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>] have suggested that synovial tissue
        cells were selectively responsive to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX> produced in the
        synovium, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX> induced increased production of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, but not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2 and IL-4</TIMEX>. Those studies support the
        hypothesis that the synovial microenvironment may play a
        role in skewing T cells toward a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> phenotype. The finding
        that IL-4-producing effector cells could be generated from
        synovial tissue T cells once removed from that environment
        suggests that all of the cells were not yet terminally
        polarized to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Th1</NUMEX>-like effector cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, synovial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluid T</ENAMEX> cells appeared to have been more affected by the
        synovial microenvironment than synovial tissue T cells
        because, regardless of the 
        in vitro priming conditions, these
        cells yielded increased percentages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and
        were deficient in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>.
        The present data suggest that synovial fluid T cells are
        those that have passed through the synovium, whereas
        synovial tissue T cells are a mixed population of recently
        migrated cells and those that have been retained in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovium</ENAMEX>. Whether the inability of synovial fluid memory T
        cells to generate IL-4 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> is the result of
        activation, differentiation, or prolonged exposure to the
        synovial microenvironment, the data clearly indicate that a
        majority of synovial fluid memory T cells appear to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polarized IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ effector cells.
        In summary, the present studies show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> blood and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synovial T</ENAMEX> cells contain increased numbers of polarized
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ effector cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial T cells also demonstrated
        a deficiency in the ability to generate IL-4-producing
        effector cells. The diminished ability to generate IL-4
        effector cells from synovial T cells 
        in vitro suggests that the rheumatoid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microenvironment alters T-cell</ENAMEX> effector function and
        thereby perpetuates the chronic inflammatory disease
        state.
      
    
  
