
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Systemic sclerosis</ENAMEX> (SSc) is a connective-tissue disease
        characterized by progressive thickening of the dermis,
        often accompanied by insufficiency of internal organs, such
        as the lungs, heart, or kidneys [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. These manifestations
        are due to the excessive accumulation of extracellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">matrix proteins</ENAMEX>, predominantly type I collagen, in the
        affected tissues [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. The cause of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> is unknown but the
        early stage is characterized by a dense mononuclear cell
        infiltrate in tissues, suggesting that activation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> system results in the development of tissue fibrosis
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3, 4</ENAMEX>]. A prominent humoral abnormality in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> is
        manifested by the presence of anti-nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
        The circulating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-topoisomerase</ENAMEX>-I (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>Topo I; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scl-70</ENAMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> are highly specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>], and they are
        found in sera from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 to 70%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. The presence
        of anti-Topo-I antibodies is associated with diffuse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">cutaneous</ENAMEX> involvement and pulmonary interstitial fibrosis [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>] and is considered a predictive marker of diffuse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX>.
        Human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> topoisomerase I (Topo I) is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">765</NUMEX>-amino-acid
        nuclear enzyme [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>] involved in topological changes of DNA
        structure [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>]. It plays key roles in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX>,
        transcription, and recombination. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo I</ENAMEX>
        catalytic process, a transient covalent linkage, termed the
        'cleavable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>', is formed between the enzyme and DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strand</ENAMEX> nicks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camptothecin</ENAMEX> (CPT) and its derivatives
        specifically target <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> by binding noncovalently to
        these cleavable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>, stabilizing them and interfering
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA religation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. As a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>'s action,
        single- and double-strand DNA breaks are generated, leading
        to premature termination of replication and inhibition of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>]. Cells can repair DNA breaks caused by
        low doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>, whereas higher doses lead to cell death [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>]. Since many neoplastic cells are characterized by high
        levels and/or activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 15</TIMEX>], this enzyme
        has become one of the cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> for anticancer
        therapy [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 17</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CPT</ENAMEX> derivatives such as topotecan and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">irinotecan</ENAMEX> (CPT-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) are currently used in the treatment of
        various <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 17, 18</TIMEX>]. Only limited side effects,
        such as manageable neutropenia, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who received
        high doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> have been reported [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>].
        The mechanism responsible for the production of
        anti-Topo-I antibodies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> is not fully understood.
        Recent studies suggest that activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Topo-I-</ENAMEX>reactive T
        cells is responsible for the induction and propagation of
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. At present, the
        origin of their target autoantigen is not clear.
        Significantly, the disappearance of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>,
        possibly because of removal of the autoantigen, has been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with favorable outcomes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. Because of the
        potential pathogenic role of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Topo I</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX>, we undertook
        this study to evaluate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> of noncytotoxic
        concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> for the treatment of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX>. We have focused on the effects of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo I</ENAMEX>
        inhibitor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>, on collagen production by dermal
        fibroblasts obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with diffuse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and
          healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>. The patient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>) with a mean age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39.5</NUMEX>
          Â± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2.6 years</TIMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> fulfilled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
          College of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rheumatology</ENAMEX> criteria for the diagnosis of SSc
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>]. The control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> with a
          mean age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41.0</NUMEX> Â± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3.3 years</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Cell culture
          Dermal fibroblasts were obtained from clinically
          affected skin (on the dorsal forearm) of the SSc patients
          and from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healthy donors</ENAMEX> matched with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, age, and gender. The control fibroblasts were
          obtained within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> biopsy and were
          processed in parallel. For the experiments, cells were
          starved for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 h</TIMEX> before the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> in DMEM<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">/1%</NUMEX>
          fetal bovine serum (FBS).
        
        
          Reagents
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> was purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and
          dissolved in dimethyl sulfoxide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). Aliquots of
          stock solution (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 mM</NUMEX>) were stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-70Â°C</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Determination of collagen types and of elastin
          production
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collagen</ENAMEX> and elastin deposition in cell and matrix
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">layers</ENAMEX> was determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solid-phase ELISA</ENAMEX> with
          antibodies against goat anti-collagen I (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemicon</ENAMEX>,
          Temecula, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), mouse anti-collagen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), mouse anti-collagen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telios</ENAMEX>), or
          mouse anti-elastin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), at dilutions recommended by
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.
          To determine the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on newly synthesized
          collagenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, we used an established method of
          metabolic labeling with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3H</TIMEX>]proline followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrophoresis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. The results were visualized by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoradiography</ENAMEX>. The intensity of bands of collagenous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was quantitated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>-Image (Densitometry
          Software, version <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.55</NUMEX>). The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on total
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein synthesis</ENAMEX> was examined using metabolic labeling
          with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35S</TIMEX>]methionine followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoradiography</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA preparation</ENAMEX> and northern blot analysis
          Fibroblasts were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> at concentrations
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-9to 10 -6mol/l</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted
          and analyzed by northern blotting as described elsewhere
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. Membranes were sequentially hybridized with
          radioactive probes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Î±2</TIMEX>(I) procollagen and
          scanned with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhosphorImager</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics, Inc</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvale</ENAMEX>, CA) for mRNA quantitation.
        
        
          Transient transfection and chloramphenicol
          acetyltransferase assays
          Transient transfections of normal dermal fibroblasts
          were performed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼g</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-353</NUMEX> fragment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Î±2</NUMEX>(I)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">COL1A2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> linked to the chloramphenicol
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acetyltransferase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene by the calcium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">phosphate/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> coprecipitation technique as described
          elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> values were corrected to reflect the
          efficiency of transfection relative to the co-transfected
          pSV-Î²-galactosidase vector (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          Statistical signifance was evaluated in paired
          analyses using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX>'s paired 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">t</ENAMEX> test or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Wilcoxon</ENAMEX> test
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nonparametric</NUMEX>), depending on the data distribution. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX>
          values are expressed as means Â± <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEM</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX>
          significance was defined as a 
          P value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> or less (see
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supplementary</ENAMEX> material).
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on production of collagen
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">protein</ENAMEX>
          The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on the production of types I, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX> collagen by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and normal dermal
          fibroblasts was examined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX> using fibroblast cell
          and matrix layers (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a,b,c). Incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> for
          24 h significantly decreased the expression of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX> types, although the degree of inhibition varied
          among the different collagens. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 -7mol/l</ENAMEX>
          decreased collagen production more in SSc than in healthy
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> fibroblasts (by, respectively, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68% and 48%</NUMEX> for
          type I, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38% and 15%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21% and 7%</NUMEX> for type
          statistically significant. The reduction of type I
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX> expression by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX> was also
          demonstrated by immunocytochemistry and indirect
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunofluorescence</ENAMEX> (data not shown). To assess the effect
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on production of other extracellular matrix
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX>, the effect on elastin was measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>: no
          effect was found in either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SSc</ENAMEX> or control fibroblasts
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1d).
          The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on newly synthesized collagenous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins secreted</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> was examined in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
          pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and healthy control fibroblasts in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX>
          independent experiments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> at concentrations from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-8to 10 -6mol/</ENAMEX>l significantly decreased secretion of
          collagenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 50%</NUMEX> in both cell types
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a,b). The responsiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and healthy
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> fibroblasts to different doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> was also
          compared. No major differences were observed at the three
          highest doses used (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 -8to 10 -6mol/l</ENAMEX>), but SSc
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> appeared to be slightly more sensitive to the
          lowest dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 -9mol/l</ENAMEX>). Secreted collagenous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were inhibited by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.06</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> fibroblasts
          versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.03</NUMEX> in healthy control fibroblasts ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.09</NUMEX>). The total protein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synthesis</ENAMEX> was not affected by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">CPT</ENAMEX> treatment, even at the
          highest dose used (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 -6mol/l</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2c). The number of
          cells after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> treatment was not significantly decreased
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>), indicating that the doses used were not
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytotoxic</ENAMEX> to fibroblasts. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> is cytotoxic mainly to
          S-phase cells, and its effects are dependent on cell type
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. In general, human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> are more resistant
          than neoplastic cells or lymphoblasts to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA-</ENAMEX>damaging
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. Although it has been shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> at
          higher concentrations induces cell cycle arrest in
          proliferating dermal fibroblasts [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>], it is unlikely
          that the inhibition of collagen production was related to
          cell cycle arrest, because our experiments were performed
          with confluent, serum-starved cells. Taken together, the
          experiments presented in this part of the study suggest
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> is a relatively specific inhibitor of
          collagenous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> production in dermal fibroblasts.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COL1A2</ENAMEX> mRNA
          The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">COL1A2</TIMEX> steady-state mRNA levels
          was evaluated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and healthy control
          dermal fibroblasts in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> independent experiments. CPT
          treatment resulted in a dose-dependent decrease of COL1A2
          mRNA expression levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and healthy control
          fibroblasts as demonstrated by northern blot analysis.
          Note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX> mRNA levels were not inhibited by CPT
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3a). The highest dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 -6</NUMEX>) resulted in
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 60%</NUMEX> inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COL1A2</ENAMEX> mRNA levels in both SSc
          and healthy control fibroblasts (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3b,c). These
          results suggest that the inhibitory effects of CPT occur,
          at least partially, through regulating the levels of
          expression of collagen mRNA.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on activity of COL1A2 promoter
          The transcriptional activity of the human COL1A2
          promoter fragment (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-353</ENAMEX>) linked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene
          was examined in transient transfection assays after CPT
          treatment. Consistent with the mRNA data, the maximal
          inhibition of collagen promoter activity was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), suggesting that the inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on the
          COL1A2 gene occurs at the transcriptional level. As
          previously reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> has no effect on the activity of
          the control vector [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. The activity of the collagen
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">promoter</ENAMEX> was inhibited by much lower doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-12and 10 -10mol/l</ENAMEX>) than those that inhibited collagen
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> levels (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 -8to 10 -6mol/l</ENAMEX>). This probably reflects
          the difference in sensitivity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> between exogenous
          and endogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> due to the protective role of
          chromatin surrounding the endogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DNA Topo</ENAMEX> I is an essential enzyme involved in such
        crucial cellular functions as replication and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX>. This study was undertaken to determine
        whether inhibition of its activity by noncytotoxic doses of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that selectively <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX>, could reverse
        the activated phenotype of fibroblasts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>, an alkaloid that exists in nature and has been
        used for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> in traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, is a
        prototype of a new class of anticancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. It is
        commonly used in 
        in vitro experimental model systems
        to study the mechanisms of action of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinically</ENAMEX> approved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, irinotecan and
        topotecan, are semisynthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">derivatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> that differ
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> in toxicity profiles and water solubility but not
        in the mechanisms of action [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 17</TIMEX>].
        Our results show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> significantly inhibits the
        synthesis of collagen by dermal fibroblasts from patients
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX>. The production of types I, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX> collagen
        was significantly inhibited in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and healthy control
        dermal fibroblasts without affecting total protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synthesis</ENAMEX>. The inhibitory mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> was further
        examined using COL1A2 as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> collagen gene.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> inhibited <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">COL1A2</NUMEX> steady-state mRNA levels and
        promoter activity by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX>, indicating that it directly
        inhibits transcription of this collagen gene. It is not
        known why collagen genes, and particularly type I collagen,
        are more sensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> than other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. The drug either
        may directly interfere with the transcription of collagen
        genes or may influence signaling pathways that regulate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX> gene expression.
        The role of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Topo I</ENAMEX> in the initiation of transcription
        has previously been shown [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. These previous studies
        have revealed that Topo I can act as either an activator or
        a repressor, depending on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> and the presence of
        other transcription factors [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. It has been proposed
        that Topo I may be directly involved in transcription of
        interstitial collagen genes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>]. The nucleotide sequences
        of these genes contain specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> motifs that constitute
        high-affinity Topo I binding sites [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> such DNA
        motifs reside within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the COL1A2</TIMEX> promoter [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>]. Further
        studies are needed to determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Topo</ENAMEX> I plays a
        direct role in the regulation of type I collagen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX>.
        Recently, a new role for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> has been proposed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>]. It
        has been shown to activate transcription factor NF-ÎºB in
        various cell types, including a fibroblastic cell line. The
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> involves degradation of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cytoplasmic IÎ</ENAMEX>ºBÎ± by the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway.
        Topotecan, a clinically approved derivative of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>, showed
        similar effects. The activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> may be
        directly related to the mechanism of CPT COL1A2 gene
        regulation. It has been shown that the inhibitory effect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± on COL1A2 gene transcription is mediated via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-ÎºB [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>]. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> may inhibit COL1A2 by a mechanism involving
        activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-ÎºB.</ENAMEX> This hypothesis could be tested using
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA topoisomerase poisons</ENAMEX> known to induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>].
        Despite significant progress towards understanding the
        pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fibrotic diseases</ENAMEX>, effective
        treatment is still lacking. Specific compounds that have
        the potential to inhibit collagen production such as CPT
        and the recently described inhibitor of geranylgeranyl
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transferase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>] may prove to be clinically useful in
        the treatment of fibrosis.
      
      
        Conclusion
        In conclusion, our study shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> has a potent
        selective inhibitory effect on collagen gene expression;
        however, the specific molecular mechanisms of action are
        presently not known and will require further study.
        The inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on collagen gene expression
        suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> may be an effective
        treatment for limiting fibrosis in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Supplementary methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>
          Dermal fibroblasts were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diffuse SSc</ENAMEX> and healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> group
          consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>),
          whose mean age was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39.5</NUMEX> Â± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2.6 years</TIMEX> (range <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30-51</NUMEX>). All
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> fulfilled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College of Rheumatology</ENAMEX>
          (formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Rheumatism Association</ENAMEX>) criteria for
          the diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>]. They were recruited from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dermatology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warsaw Medical School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warsaw</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division of Rheumatology</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immunology</ENAMEX>,
          Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of South Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> enrolled in the study had been
          recently diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and their disease duration
          was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1 month</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 year</TIMEX>. When the skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">biopsy</ENAMEX> was
          performed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were not receiving any treatment
          known to influence collagen synthesis or deposition. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> with a mean age
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41.0</NUMEX> Â± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3.3 years</TIMEX> (range <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23-60</NUMEX>). Informed consent was
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> before each
          biopsy was performed.
        
        
          Cell culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> dermal fibroblast cell lines were established from
          biopsy specimens obtained from clinically affected skin
          (on the dorsal forearm). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> dermal fibroblasts, from
          healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> matched for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, age, and gender with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> cell lines, were obtained by skin biopsy
          within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> biopsy and were processed
          in parallel. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biopsy</ENAMEX> was dissociated enzymatically by
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.25%</NUMEX> collagenase type I (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>)
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum (FBS) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HyClone</ENAMEX>). The
          fibroblasts were cultured in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> gentamicin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). For experiments, cells were
          starved in serum-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-medium</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> h
          before the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) in DMEM<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">/1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> used for experiments were from passages three
          to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>.
        
        
          Reagents
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) was dissolved in dimethyl sulfoxide
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). Aliquots of stock solution (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 mM</NUMEX>) were stored
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-70Â°C</TIMEX> and diluted further in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS/DMEM</ENAMEX> immediately
          before each experiment.
        
        
          Determining production of collagen types I, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX> and of elastin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fibroblasts</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 4cells/well) were seeded in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well
          flat-bottom culture plates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and
          treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h. Deposition</ENAMEX> of collagen and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elastin</ENAMEX> in cell and matrix layers was determined by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solid-phase ELISA</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against goat
          anti-collagen I (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemicon</ENAMEX>), mouse anti-collagen III
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telios</ENAMEX>), mouse anti-collagen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telios</ENAMEX>), or mouse
          anti-elastin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), at dilutions recommended by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of newly synthesized collagenous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX>, fibroblasts were plated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-well plates and
          grown to visual confluency. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was changed to
          serum-free medium (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA/DMEM</ENAMEX>) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ascorbic acid</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h. Cells</ENAMEX> were treated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> (from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-9to 10 -6mol/l</ENAMEX>) in the presence of ascorbic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next 48 h. 20 Î</TIMEX>¼Ci/ml of [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3H</TIMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proline</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEN</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was added during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last 24 h of</TIMEX>
          incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX>. Medium was harvested from each well
          and cells were trypsinized and counted. Medium was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dehydrated</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SpeedVac</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savant, Holbrook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          Aliquots of media normalized for cell number were
          denatured by boiling them in the SDS sample buffer and
          were loaded on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> SDS-polyacrylamide gels. After
          electrophoresis, gels were enhanced by immersion in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,5</NUMEX>-diphenyloxazole (PPO) and visualized by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoradiography</ENAMEX>. The intensity of collagenous protein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bands</ENAMEX> was quantitated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>-Image.
          The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> on total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein synthesis</ENAMEX> was
          studied using metabolic labeling with [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35S</TIMEX>]methionine
          followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE and autoradiography. Fibroblasts
          were grown to confluence in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-well plates, starved for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 h</TIMEX>, and treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 24</TIMEX> h. After CPT
          treatment, cells were incubated in methionine-free medium
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼Ci/ml of [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35S</TIMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">methionine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEN</ENAMEX>) was
          added for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 4</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">h. Cells</ENAMEX> were solubilized in RIPA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> [pH8<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.0</NUMEX>], <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.02%</NUMEX> sodium
          azide, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> phenylmethylsulfonyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NP-40</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">deoxycholate</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼M sodium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orthovanadate</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein concentrations</ENAMEX> were normalized
          for cell number and separated by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA preparation</ENAMEX> and northern blot analysis
          Fibroblasts were grown to confluence in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS/DMEM</ENAMEX>
          and then incubated in serum-free medium. The cells were
          treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> at concentrations from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -9to 10
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-6mol/l</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted and analyzed by
          northern blotting as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>].
          Membranes were sequentially hybridized with radioactive
          probes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Î±2</TIMEX>(I) procollagen and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX> and scanned with a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhosphorImager</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics, Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvale</ENAMEX>, CA)
          for mRNA quantitation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> and healthy dermal fibroblast
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA samples</ENAMEX> were analyzed together.
        
        
          Assays of transient transfection and
          chloramphenicol acetyltransferase
          Transient transfections of normal dermal fibroblasts
          were performed by the calcium phosphate/DNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coprecipitation</ENAMEX> technique as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>].
          Briefly, the cells were grown to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> confluence in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100-mm</ENAMEX>
          2dishes in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS/DMEM</ENAMEX> and were transfected with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼g
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plasmid DNA</ENAMEX> containing the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-353</NUMEX> fragment of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX> Î±2(I) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> linked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> gene
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-353 COL1A2/CAT</ENAMEX> construct). The pSV-Î²-galactosidase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control vector</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼g</NUMEX>) was co-transfected to
          allow normalization for transfection efficiency. The day
          after transfection, cells were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> (at
          concentrations from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-12to 10 -6mol/l</ENAMEX>), and incubation
          was continued for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 24</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">h. CAT</ENAMEX> assays were
          performed as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. Cell extracts
          normalized for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> concentration were used to measure
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> activity, and the values obtained were corrected to
          reflect the efficiency of transfection relative to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-transfected pSV-Î²-galactosidase vector.
        
      
      
        Abbreviations
        anti-Topo I = anti-topoisomerase I; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> = bovine serum
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">albumin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> = chloramphenicol acetyltransferase; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">COL1A2</TIMEX> =
        type Î±2(I) collagen; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPT</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camptothecin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">modified Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">enzyme</NUMEX>-linked
        immunosorbent assay; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> = fetal bovine serum; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX> =
        error of the mean; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSc</ENAMEX> = systemic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sclerosis</ENAMEX>; Topo I =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">topoisomerase I.</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
