
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BALB</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/c</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> immunized with human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> proteoglycan
        (PG) (aggrecan) develop <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 3, 4</ENAMEX>].
        Autoantibody production precedes the first clinical
        symptoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. While these anti-PG
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoantibodies</ENAMEX> alone do not transfer <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoantibodies</ENAMEX> significantly hasten the onset of disease
        and cause PG to be released from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6, 7</ENAMEX>].
        B cells proliferate and differentiate into
        immunoglobulin-secreting plasma cells under the influence
        of a combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cytokines</ENAMEX> derived from T cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>].
        IL-4, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T helper</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Th</ENAMEX>)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cytokine, regulates the switch from
        IgM/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">IgG1</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgE</ENAMEX> in activated B cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9, 10</ENAMEX>].
        However, the 
        in vivo dependency on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> for the
        IgG1 response is controversial [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 12, 13</TIMEX>]. The Th1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokine IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ is important 
        in vitro and 
        in vivo for enhancement of IgG2a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretion</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 15</TIMEX>]. Th1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Th2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cytokines</ENAMEX> also function to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ig</ENAMEX> isotypes. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ antagonizes
        IL-4-induced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IgG1</NUMEX> responses at the level of IgG1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 17</TIMEX>], whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-4</ENAMEX> has the ability to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suppress IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-driven IgG2a responses [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>].
        We have previously shown that PG-specific antibodies
        increase the severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and that PG-induced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX>-type disease dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. We
        therefore were interested in finding out how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and IL-4
        regulate isotype expression of the PG-specific antibodies
        and if an autoantibody isotype contributes to the severity
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BALB</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/c</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were purchased from
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Laboratory</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bar Harbor</ENAMEX>, ME, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">BALB/c</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterozygous</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">homozygous nude mice</ENAMEX> were obtained from
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Cancer Institute</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          Breeding pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BALB/c IL-4-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deficient mice</ENAMEX> were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klinische Forschergruppe</ENAMEX> fÃ¼r Rheumatologie
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freiburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>). CD40-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BALB/c</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were
          purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taconic</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germantown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Preparation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage PG monomer</ENAMEX> (aggrecan) and
          immunization
          Human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> was obtained during joint-replacement
          surgery and high-density PG was prepared as described
          elsewhere [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 5</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Female BALB/c</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (wild-type or gene
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deficient</ENAMEX>) were injected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">intraperitoneally</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 0, 21</TIMEX>,
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼g</NUMEX> of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> PG measured as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, in adjuvant, as described elsewhere [ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2,</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>].
        
        
          Measurement of immunoglobulin isotypes
          Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>) was used to
          measure isotype-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> in serial dilutions
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000 to 1</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62,500</NUMEX>) of sera. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> plates were coated
          with either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> Î¼g human PG or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">¼g mouse</ENAMEX> PG, as
          described elsewhere [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5, 18</ENAMEX>]. PG-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">IgG</ENAMEX> isotypes
          were detected with peroxidase-labeled rabbit anti-mouse
          IgG1 or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IgG2a</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zymed Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, CA,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). IgG1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgG2a myeloma proteins</ENAMEX> were used for a
          standard curve.
        
        
          Assessment of cytokine production by spleen cells
          in vitro
          Spleens were obtained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 week</TIMEX> after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> injection
          with PG, as described elsewhere [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. Cells were
          stimulated in the presence or absence of PG (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">20 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>)
          and a capture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> was used to measure the released
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>].
        
        
          Assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>
          The severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in each paw was graded
          according to an established scoring system [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3, 5</ENAMEX>] as
          follows: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0</ENAMEX>, normal; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, mild <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">erythema</ENAMEX> and/or swelling,
          usually in one or two toes; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, moderate erythema and/or
          swelling of the paw; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, more diffuse erythema; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, severe
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">erythema</ENAMEX> and swelling affecting the entire paw (maximum
          score for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paws</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inflammation</ENAMEX> and joint
          swelling were recorded twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> by the same
          individual in a blinded manner.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> test was used to compare
          nonparametric data for statistical significance. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> values less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> were
          considered significant.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          PG-specific IgG1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isotype</ENAMEX> dominates despite a higher
          ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ to IL-4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BALB</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/c</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> immunized with human PG generated a
          PG-specific <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IgG1</NUMEX> isotype response which was significantly
          higher than the PG-specific IgG2a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isotype</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a).
          However, when the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Th1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Th2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cytokines</ENAMEX> was
          measured from splenocytes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> immunized with PG,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ was produced at a significantly higher
          concentration than either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-4</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a). These
          results reveal a dichotomy between the isotype of the
          PG-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> response (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IgG1</NUMEX>) and the secretion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX> The discrepancy could be reconciled if the
          PG-specific IgG1 response is independent of T cells.
          We therefore assessed the PG-specific response in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterozygous</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">homozygous nude mice</ENAMEX> and in
          CD40-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Whereas heterozygous <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">nude mice</ENAMEX>
          generated essentially the same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> response to PG as
          wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1b), no or very little anti-PG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was detected in homozygous nude or
          CD40-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1b). These results show that
          the human and murine PG-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> responses are
          dependent on the interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells and B
          cells.
        
        
          IL-4 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ regulation of the PG-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IgG1/IgG2a</ENAMEX> isotype response
          To find out if the PG-specific IgG1 response is
          dependent on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, we immunized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with
          PG and measured the PG-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgG1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IgG2a</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">isotypes</ENAMEX>.
          Whereas the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IgG1</NUMEX> response to human PG was unaffected
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a), the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-4</ENAMEX> significantly reduced the
          IgG1 response to mouse PG in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2b). The most striking observation, however, was the
          dramatic increase in PG-specific IgG2a response in IL-4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deficient mice</ENAMEX>. There was a sixfold increase in the IgG2a
          response in the absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a,b). These
          results show that the PG-specific IgG1 response was
          marginally dependent on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endogenous</ENAMEX> IL-4
          dramatically suppressed the PG-specific IgG2a
          response.
          To find out if IFN-Î³ induced a PG-specific IgG2a
          response 
          in vivo, the PG-specific IgG2a
          response was examined in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. The IgG2a
          antibody responses to both human and mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGs</ENAMEX> were lower
          in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> than in wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a,b). These
          results show that the PG-specific IgG2a response was
          dependent on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX> If IFN-Î³ concentrations regulated
          IgG1, reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ should be permissive for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IgG1</TIMEX>;
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, however, there was no increase
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IgG1</TIMEX> response to either human or mouse PG (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2a,b).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthritis</ENAMEX> is associated with an increase in
          IgG2a
          We studied the induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          deficient in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ to find out if there is a
          correlation between the isotype of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. In wild-type and IL-4 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deficient mice</ENAMEX>, paw
          swelling began <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.6</NUMEX> Â± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6.6 days</TIMEX> after the last injection
          with PG, whereas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, swelling
          began much later at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36.8</NUMEX> Â± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6.2 days</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). The
          incidences of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in wild-type and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-deficient
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were much higher than in the PG-immunized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> score was
          significantly higher in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-deficient than in the
          wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, not
          only was the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> lower
          than in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, but also their reduced
          susceptibility was further mirrored in the significantly
          less severe paw swelling (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). These data show that
          endogenous cytokine concentrations dramatically affect
          both the onset and the severity of inflammation.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Because PG-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> is dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, it
        is considered to be a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX>-type disease [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 18</ENAMEX>].
        Paradoxically, we observed higher concentrations of the
        IgG1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isotype</ENAMEX> than of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IgG2a</NUMEX> isotype. To resolve this
        apparent paradox, we examined the anti-PG responses in
        cytokine-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. We found that in the absence of
        IL-4, the PG-specific IgG1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isotype</ENAMEX> was only minimally
        affected. These 
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vivo</ENAMEX> experiments are very
        different from those describing a dramatic 
        in vitro effect of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> on IgG1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induction</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9, 10</ENAMEX>], but are similar to other studies that
        showed partial elimination of IgG1 
        in vivo, either using neutralizing
        antibodies to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX> or blocking the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-4 receptor</ENAMEX> with
        antibodies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 12, 13, 19</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility was that the
        large carbohydrate content of PG might have a promoting
        interaction with B cells in a mitogen-like manner, thus
        permitting production of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IgG1</TIMEX>. However, nude <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and
        CD40-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> did not generate a PG-specific IgG1
        response and such a response was also independent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX>
        Taken together, these results are in contrast to the
        IL-4-dictated IgG1 switch response. Rather, they suggest
        that the PG-specific IgG1 response, at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BALB</ENAMEX>/c
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, may be regulated 
        in vivo by other,
        as-yet-unidentified, cytokine(s) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 20, 21, 22</TIMEX>].
        In contrast to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IgG1</TIMEX>, the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IgG2a</ENAMEX> isotype
        showed a strong inverse correlation with the concentration
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endogenous IL-4</ENAMEX>. In the absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, the IgG2a
        response was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times greater than in wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. This
        finding demonstrates that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-4</ENAMEX> plays a critical role in
        regulating the PG-specific IgG2a response. The role of this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokine</ENAMEX> in the suppression of IgG2a 
        in vivo has not been well studied.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IgG2a</NUMEX> response was only minimally enhanced after 
        in vivo treatment with anti-IL-4
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>], but it was increased in immunized
        IL-4-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. Since there is no evidence that
        IL-4 directly inhibits <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IgG2a</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">transcription</ENAMEX> in B cells, this
        cytokine very likely suppresses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ response, either
        directly or indirectly. Indeed, the significant reduction
        of the PG-specific IgG2a response in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        suggests that the response is controlled by this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon</ENAMEX>.
        We have found that the development of PG-specific
        antibodies correlates with the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>,
        and that PG-specific autoantibodies increase the severity
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. We show here that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> deficient in IL-4
        develop <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> that is significantly more severe than in
        wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. The pathogenic role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IgG2a antibody</ENAMEX>
        was also described in a model of autoimmune hemolytic
        anemia [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]; however, these IgG2a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autoantibodies</ENAMEX> were not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathogenic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that are deficient in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FcÎ³</ENAMEX> receptor III [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>]. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> observations taken together suggest the
        possibility that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">IgG2a</NUMEX> PG-specific autoantibodies
        elicit a pathogenic effect through an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Fc</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-mediated
        mechanism.
        PG-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> is considered a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>,
        characterized by a higher ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ to IL-4 [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. Our
        finding that treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-4</ENAMEX> inhibits IFN-Î³ suggests
        that IL-4 could mediate a shift from a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> to a Th2
        response 
        in vivo [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. In addition to the
        effects of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> production, this cytokine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibits</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> responses, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and macrophage
        increase in inflammatory cytokine production in
        IL-4-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> may also contribute to exacerbation of
        PG-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. In adjuvant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, which may not
        be dependent on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> is increased in the
        absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-4</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. This finding suggests that IL-4
        inhibits <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">adjuvant arthritis</ENAMEX> by its anti-inflammatory
        properties and not by an alteration in isotype expression.
        Paradoxically, in collagen-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>), disease
        is suppressed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">IL-4</NUMEX>-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> is also
        different from PG-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in regard to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX> In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and some other organ-specific autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ functions in a protective role, so that in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> disease is exacerbated [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29, 30</TIMEX>].
        Whether the difference between PG-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
        is due to the autoantigen or to genetic differences in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">mouse strains</ENAMEX> is not clear at present.
      
      
        Conclusion
        Th1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Th2</ENAMEX> cytokines regulate PG-specific autoantibody
        IgG isotypes and susceptibility to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. In the
        absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX>, the production of PG-specific IgG2a
        isotype was dramatically enhanced and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> was
        significantly more severe. IL-4 may exert its effect
        through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, since in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, both the
        PG-specific IgG2a response and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> were suppressed.
        The correlation between PG-specific autoantibody isotype
        and development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> suggests a pathological role
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IgG2a</TIMEX> isotype in disease.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> = collagen-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">enzyme</NUMEX>-linked
        immunosorbent assay; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Th = T helper</ENAMEX>; PG = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proteoglycan</ENAMEX>; IFN
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">= interferon; IL</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interleukin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEM</ENAMEX> = standard error of the
        mean.
      
    
  
