
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) is characterized by synovial
        tissue leukocyte infiltration and angiogenesis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . The
        neovascularization process in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> is dependent on the
        balance between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">angiogenic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">angiogenic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> include growth factors, cytokines,
        chemokines, adhesion <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and proteolytic enzymes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        ] . These factors, which are released by endothelial cells
        and macrophages, have been shown to play an important role
        in the pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] .
        Tie <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> constitute a family of endothelial
        tyrosine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinase receptors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] . There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> members
        in this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, termed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie1 and Tie2</TIMEX> (also known
        as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tek</ENAMEX>). Tie1 is an orphan receptor, whereas the ligands of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie2 receptor</ENAMEX> have been identified as angiopoietin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ang</ENAMEX>)-1
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . Ang-1 has been shown to be responsible
        for recruiting and sustaining periendothelial support cells
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . It has been reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> disrupts blood
        vessel formation in the developing embryo by antagonizing
        Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autophosphorylation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tie2</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] .
        Transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> models of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tie2/Ang-1</ENAMEX> result in embryonic
        lethality due to absence of remodeling and sprouting of
        blood vessels [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] . The physiologic roles of the Tie2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and its ligands are limited to angiogenic
        processes that occur subsequently to the earlier
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vasculogenic</ENAMEX> and angiogenic actions of vascular endothelial
        growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (VEGF) and its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> orchestrate optimal blood vessel formation [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ] .
        Little is known about the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie receptors</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ligands</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue. To determine
        which of these angiogenic factors may play a role in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, we
        investigated both the distribution and the levels of mRNA
        for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> in synovial tissue obtained
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, compared with that from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoarthritis</ENAMEX> (OA) and normal tissues.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Antibodies</ENAMEX> and immunohistochemistry
          Synovial tissues (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 Î¼m</ENAMEX>) were fixed in cold acetone for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>. Endogenous peroxidase was quenched by
          treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX>. Synovial tissues were
          pretreated with either <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> horse or goat serum for one
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour at 37Â°C</TIMEX> before application of primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>.
          Indirect immunoperoxidase staining was performed at 37Â°C
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vector Elite ABC</ENAMEX> kits (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vector</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burlingame</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and diaminobenzidine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkegaard</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaitherburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) as a chromogen [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] .
          The polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>, goat antihuman <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> and
          Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and rabbit antihuman <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie1 and Tie2</TIMEX>, were purchased
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          Additionally, goat antihuman <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie1 and Tie2</TIMEX> antibodies
          were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antibodies</ENAMEX> did not cross-react with other members
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Macrophage</ENAMEX> identity was confirmed by reactivity of
          cells with the mouse antihuman mAb, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD11c</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mountain View</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbit antihuman von</ENAMEX>
          Willebrand <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dako, Carpinteria</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was used
          to identify endothelium. Isotype-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> was used as
          a negative control.
        
        
          Cell culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> quantification and western blot
          analysis
          Cell culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA purification</ENAMEX>, reverse transcription,
          standard dilution preparation, real-time reverse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quantification</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TaqMan</ENAMEX>) and western blot analysis are
          detailed in the supplementary material.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Ang-1
          Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, was expressed on synovial lining cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX>) to a significantly higher degree than in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>) and normal (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>) cells ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Ang-1
          staining on macrophages was also significantly higher in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX>) compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>) and normal cells (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0%</NUMEX>) ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> staining
          present on vascular endothelium was upregulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86%</NUMEX>) compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX>) and normal synovial tissues
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>). The inflammatory and vascularity scores were higher
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue in comparison to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> and normal. In
          accordance with the staining data, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue
          demonstrated significantly higher <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> mRNA expression
          compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> and normal tissues. Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mRNA expression
          was not detected in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> fibroblasts (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Ang-2
          The expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> was detected on synovial
          lining cells, macrophages and vascular endothelium (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The data demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> was expressed on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>) and the vascular endothelium (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX>) in
          synovial tissue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> more strongly than in the
          tissue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (macrophages <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX>, endothelium <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX>)
          and normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> (macrophages <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX>, endothelium <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX>).
          Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> was detected in the synovial vascular
          smooth muscle cells (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX>) from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> only.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> mRNA expression pattern was similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ang</ENAMEX>-2
          immunostaining on vascular endothelium. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> mRNA
          expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue was similar to that from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and both were significantly higher than
          normal. Interestingly, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fibroblasts</ENAMEX>,
          Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mRNA was expressed at low levels compared to that
          found in whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> or normal synovial tissue (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Tie1
          Tie1 expression was found to be significantly higher
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue lining cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">79%</NUMEX>, OA
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX>) and macrophages (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX>) compared to normal
          synovial tissue (lining cells <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24%</NUMEX>, macrophages <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX>) using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Tie1
          immunostaining on endothelial cells was significantly
          higher in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX>) in comparison to OA
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>) and normal (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX>) synovial tissue. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Tie1</NUMEX> positive
          immunostaining on vascular smooth muscle cells was
          similar in all test <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX>, normal <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX>).
          Additionally, all disease <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> demonstrated minimal
          percentages of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tie1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> staining on synovial tissue
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphocytes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>, normal <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>) and fibroblasts (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX>, normal <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunohistochemistry</ENAMEX> studies using the goat antihuman
          Tie1 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX> showed
          predominantly endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell staining</ENAMEX>, and minimal
          staining on macrophages and fibroblasts. Tie1 mRNA
          expression was significantly higher in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue
          compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-fold), normal synovial
          tissue (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.5</NUMEX>-fold) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue fibroblasts
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-fold). Western blot analysis also confirmed the same
          pattern of expression.
        
        
          Tie2
          Tie2 was significantly upregulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and OA
          synovial tissue lining cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68%</NUMEX>),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72%</NUMEX>) and smooth muscle cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX>) compared to normal synovial tissue ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>) using the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Endothelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> showed relatively
          high Tie2 positive staining in all disease <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX>, normal <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49%</NUMEX>). Only synovial tissue from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> demonstrated positive staining for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie2</TIMEX> on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphocytes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had similar patterns of
          Ang-2 (on cell lining and endothelial cells), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie1</TIMEX> (on
          lining cells, macrophages, smooth muscle cells,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphocytes</ENAMEX> and fibroblasts) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie2</TIMEX> (on lining cells,
          macrophages, endothelial cells and vascular smooth muscle
          cells) expression on various synovial tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-Tie2 antibody</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX> demonstrated
          positive staining mainly on endothelial cells and minimal
          staining on macrophages and fibroblasts. Tie2 mRNA levels
          were significantly higher in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue compared
          to OA synovial tissue (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.9</NUMEX>-fold), normal synovial tissue
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-fold) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue fibroblasts (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.6</NUMEX>-fold).
          Tie2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expression by western blotting followed the
          same pattern as the mRNA expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie receptors</ENAMEX> and the ligands <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> appear
        to be involved in the later stages of vessel growth and
        remodeling [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8 13</ENAMEX> ] . Transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with gene deletions [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 13</NUMEX> ] or overexpression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] exhibit early
        embryonic lethality secondary to defects in the developing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vasculature</ENAMEX>.
        Ang-1 was more highly expressed in synovial tissue from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> than in either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">OA</ENAMEX> or normal synovial tissues;
        expression in OA tissue was similar to normal. Positive
        cells included lining cells, macrophages and endothelial
        cells. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> was most upregulated on endothelial
        cells. The results obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> analysis confirmed
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue had significantly higher <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> mRNA
        expression than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> and normal synovial tissue. Hence, no
        Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mRNA expression was detected in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> fibroblasts (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie</ENAMEX> receptor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is known to be expressed on
        endothelial cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . Otani 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ang</ENAMEX>-2
        positive staining on macrophages and endothelial cells in
        choroidal neovascular membranes. Macrophages are key
        angiogenesis effector cells that produce a number of growth
        factor stimulators and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, proteolytic enzymes and
        cytokines that can activate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or more</NUMEX> steps in the
        angiogenesis cascade [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17</NUMEX> ] . Recent studies have
        shown that angiopoietins promote postnatal
        neovascularization by potentiating angiogenic cytokines
        such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10</ENAMEX> ] .
        
        immunohistochemical analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial biopsies
        revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> mRNA and protein localized to
        subsynovial macrophages, lining cells, vascular smooth
        muscle cells and fibroblasts within the pannus, which are
        the putative target of this cytokine [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19</NUMEX> ] . The
        localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> is similar to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX>, which
        further supports the crucial role of the interaction
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between these two pathways</TIMEX>. Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> modulates VEGF-stimulated
        reorganization of endothelial cells and promotes vascular
        network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maturation</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 20</ENAMEX> ] . Additionally, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ang-1</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> are chemotactic and are involved in recruiting
        endothelial cells to initiate and accelerate
        endothelialization of blood vessels [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22</NUMEX> ] .
        We detected <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> immunopositive cells in synovial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lining</ENAMEX>, macrophages and vascular endothelium. Vascular
        smooth muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">immunostaining</ENAMEX> was found only in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. In
        agreement with our finding, it has been reported that
        primary cultured macrophages and precursor macrophage cell
        lines mainly express <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . In contrast to
        Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> was distributed in a similar pattern in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> compared to normal synovial tissues (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The
        dominance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in OA
        synovial tissue are in agreement with the inactive VEGF
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor 1 pathway</ENAMEX> (angiogenic pathway) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . The
        Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mRNA expression pattern correlates with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ang</ENAMEX>-2
        immunostaining detected on endothelial cells. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        synovial tissue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> showed a lower percentage of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staining</ENAMEX> in all the cell types compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX>. Low Ang-2
        mRNA expression was also detected on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> fibroblasts.
        Interestingly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ang-2</ENAMEX> acts as an agonist for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie2 receptors</ENAMEX>
        expressed on fibroblasts [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . Since the
        neovascularization process is dependent on the dominance of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">angiogenic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>, the higher <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> mRNA
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expression compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial
        tissue is of importance. It has been shown that increasing
        amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> can block the chemotactic activity of
        Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in endothelial cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ang-2</ENAMEX> alone did not
        stimulate corneal neovascularization, but the combination
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> resulted in longer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> with greater
        circumferential extent than those seen with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> alone [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
        ] . This suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> expression in the absence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VEGF</ENAMEX> leads to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel regression</ENAMEX>, whereas expression of
        Ang-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> potentiates angiogenesis.
        Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, Tie1
        expression was detected on all cell components examined,
        including a percentage of synovial lining cells,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX> and smooth muscle cells in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX>. Synovial
        tissues from normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, and those with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX>, had
        considerably lower positive immunostaining on endothelial
        cells compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> tissues. Immunohistochemical analysis
        performed with anti-Tie1 from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX> in synovial
        tissues supports its expression mainly on endothelial
        cells. However, western blot analysis for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie1</TIMEX> also
        performed with an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>, showed
        higher relative abundance of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie1</ENAMEX> in whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and OA
        synovial tissue homogenates compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> fibroblasts
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). In accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> data, the mRNA
        levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie1</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue were upregulated
        compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue, normal synovial tissue and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> fibroblasts. Since the ligand for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie1 receptor</ENAMEX> is
        not known, it is difficult to speculate if there is any
        correlation between this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tie2</ENAMEX> and its ligands.
        In agreement with previous studies, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tie1 receptor</ENAMEX> was
        detected on vascular endothelial cells [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4 25</ENAMEX> ] and
        recently on synovial lining cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . It has been
        shown that tumor necrosis factor-Î± and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> activate
        membrane-associated metalloproteinases that release soluble
        Tie1 from the cell surface of endothelial cells and thereby
        decrease <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">membrane-bound</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tie1</ENAMEX> expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . The
        upregulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tie1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> and protein expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> is
        not consistent with these findings and this may be due to
        the fact that the inflammatory milieu in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue
        is far more complex than the 
        in vitro system.
        Using the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> we showed
        that Tie2 expression was significantly upregulated both in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue lining cells, macrophages,
        endothelial cells and vascular smooth muscle compared to
        normal synovial tissue. In accordance with Otani 
        et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] and Uchida 
        et al. [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] we detected Tie2
        immunostaining on endothelial cells and fibroblasts in all
        disease <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Tie2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immunostaining</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX> confirmed the expression of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>
        mainly on endothelial cells. Tie2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> and protein
        expression followed the same pattern of expression as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie1</TIMEX>.
        There are some possible reasons why the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunohistochemistry</ENAMEX> studies performed with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>
        Biotechnology/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX> antibodies differ. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX> antibodies detected epitopes on the
        carboxy terminus whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX> antibodies
        recognized the extracelluar domain (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> terminus or the
        ligand binding domain) of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie1 and Tie2</TIMEX>. There is also some
        variability between individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> patient samples, however,
        we attempted to use the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> patient samples in
        performing immunohistochemistry with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. Additionally, the results obtained from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> and western blot analysis confirm our findings.
      
      
        Conclusion
        It is noteworthy that the activating ligand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> is
        exclusively higher than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> at the mRNA and protein
        levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial tissue compared to that from patients
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> and normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Hypothetically, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial
        tissue the dominating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> induces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Tie2</TIMEX> pathway,
        whereas in normal synovial tissue higher <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-2</ENAMEX> presence
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">blocks Ang-1</ENAMEX> binding to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Tie2</NUMEX> and inhibits its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autophosphorylation</ENAMEX>.
        In conclusion, the dominance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ang-1</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ang</ENAMEX>-2
        expression favors active neovascularization in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> synovial
        tissue. Multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> are probably required to regulate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angiogenesis</ENAMEX>. It may be that the inhibition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> and
        Tie2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> might be an effective therapeutic modality in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ang</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">angiopoietin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> = bovine serum albumin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> =
        fetal bovine serum; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMVEC</ENAMEX> = human microvascular endothelial
        cell; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX>= <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">osteoarthritis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> = polymerase chain reaction;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> = reverse transcription
        polymerase chain reaction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> = standard error; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tie</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor tyrosine kinase</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VEGF</ENAMEX> = vascular endothelial
        growth factor.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary</ENAMEX> material
        
          Materials and methods
        
        
          Patient population
          Synovial tissues from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX>,
          undergoing arthroplasty or synovectomy, who fulfilled the
          criteria set by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College of Rheumatology</ENAMEX> were
          obtained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Review Board</ENAMEX> (IRB) consent [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] . Normal synovial tissues were obtained from
          fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">autopsies</ENAMEX> or amputations. Synovial tissues were
          snap frozen in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Optimal Cutting Temperature</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCT</ENAMEX>) compound
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elkhart</ENAMEX>, IN, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Microscopic analysis
          Synovial tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> including lining cells,
          macrophages, lymphocytes, fibroblasts, smooth muscle
          cells and endothelial cells were graded for
          immunostaining by a frequency of staining scale, scored
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0%</NUMEX> indicates no staining and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> indicates
          that all cells were immunoreactive. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five 400Ã—</NUMEX> fields were
          examined per section by a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologist</ENAMEX> in a blinded
          study. Selected sections were analyzed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> additional
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were analyzed using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kruskal Wallis</ENAMEX> test. There
          were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 to 15</NUMEX> patient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> values < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> were considered
          to be significant.
        
        
          Cell culture
          Fibroblasts were isolated from synovial tissues that
          had been minced and digested in a solution of dispase,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagenase</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX>. Synovial tissue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cultured</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell Park Memorial Institute</ENAMEX> (RPMI)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1640</NUMEX>
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBS</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> penicillin/streptomycin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P/S</ENAMEX>) and used at passage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or older</TIMEX>, at which time
          they were a homogeneous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of fibroblasts.
          Human microvascular endothelial cells (HMVECs)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioWhittaker</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) were cultured in endothelial cell
          growth medium-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> for microvascular cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioWhittaker</ENAMEX>,
          Walkerville, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and were used between passages 3
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>. Upon confluence, the cells were passaged by brief
          trypsinisation as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . HMVECs
          were used as positive controls for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tie1 and Tie2</TIMEX> protein
          expression in western blot analysis.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> purification
          Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was prepared from synovial tissue by an acid
          phenol method according to the procedure described by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chomczynski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacchi</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼g</NUMEX>) was digested
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> units of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Ã—</NUMEX> reverse transcription
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco/Life Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>)
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> units of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNase</ENAMEX> inhibitor (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco/Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> at
          37Â°C. Sodium acetate (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 M</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pH4.0</ENAMEX>) was added (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of the
          total volume), and the solution was extracted with one
          volume each of water-saturated phenol and chloroform
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Itasca, IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was precipitated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ethanol</ENAMEX>, washed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, then air-dried. The
          pellet was dissolved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/Î¼l.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Reverse transcription
          Reverse transcription of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was performed using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î¼g
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> in a total volume of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼l</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was reverse
          transcribed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superscript II RT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco/Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) according to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s specification. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25Â°C</TIMEX>,
          the enzyme was incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 minutes and</TIMEX>
          thereafter inactivated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>. The
          solution was diluted to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 Î¼l</NUMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were reverse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcribed</ENAMEX> simultaneously.
        
        
          Standard dilution preparation and PCR
          All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reactions were performed on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prism</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7700</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sequence Detection System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer Applied</ENAMEX>
          Biosys-tem, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). For each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> run, a master mixture
          was prepared on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Ã—</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Platinum PCR</ENAMEX> buffer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco/Life Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM
          MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> mM of each deoxynucleoside
          triphosphate, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.2 Î</NUMEX>¼M each primer, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> units <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">platinum</ENAMEX> Taq
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco/Life Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The diluted reverse transcription sample (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 Î¼l</ENAMEX>)
          was added to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î¼l</NUMEX> of the PCR mix. The thermal cycling
          conditions were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of the denaturation step at
          95Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>, annealing at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX> and
          an extention step at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products
          were extracted from agarose gels and purified. Serial
          dilutions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were then prepared which ranged
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 1to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 10molecules [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] . The sequence for the
          designed Tie <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and ligands are shown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Real-time quantitative <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> using the TaqMan
          system
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> primer and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TaqMan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fluorogenic probe</ENAMEX> were
          designed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Primer Express</ENAMEX> program v <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.01</NUMEX> (Perkin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elmer Applied Biosystem</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TaqMan</ENAMEX> probe
          carries a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAM</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-carboxy-fluorescein</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> dye and
          a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAMRA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6-carboxy-tetramethyl-rhodamine</NUMEX>) quencher dye
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mega Bases</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) The quantity of cDNA of
          the gene of interest was directly related to the
          fluorescence detection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAM</ENAMEX> after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX>. The amount
          of cDNA was calculated using a comparative C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> method and the standard curve method
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ABI PRISM 7700 User</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulletin No. 2</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. The calibration curves showed a
          strong linear correlation, with correlation coefficients
          between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.96</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.99</NUMEX>. In both methods, the estimated
          amount of the gene of interest was normalized by the
          compensate for variations in quantity and for differences
          in reverse transcription efficiency.
          Briefly, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 Î¼l</NUMEX> of the cDNA was in a reaction of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î</NUMEX>¼l
          that contained final concentrations of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Ã—</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Platinum</ENAMEX> PCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco/Life Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>),
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î¼M</NUMEX> dNTP, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> nM each primer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mega Bases</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> nM FAM-TAMRA probe
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mega Bases</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> 636 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">BD 636</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>
          units <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">platinum Taq DNA polymerase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco/Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The thermal cycling
          conditions included <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">94Â°C</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>, followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
          cycles of amplification at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX> and 60Â°C
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX> for denaturing and annealing-extension,
          respectively. All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were amplified in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triplicate</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Western blot analysis
          Synovial tissues were homogenized in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ml conical
          centrifuge tube containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ml of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Complete Mini</ENAMEX> protease
          inhibitor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail homogenization</ENAMEX> buffer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Synovial tissue homogenization
          was completed on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> using a motorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">homogenizer</ENAMEX>,
          followed by sonication for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>. Homogenates were
          centrifuged at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> Ã—g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX>, filtered through a
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.45 Î¼m</NUMEX> pore size filter (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedpore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and
          stored at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-80Â°C until</TIMEX> use. Complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Mini</ENAMEX> protease
          inhibitor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 ml</NUMEX>) was added to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMVECs</ENAMEX> for lysis. The concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> in each synovial tissue and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysate</ENAMEX> was
          determined using a bicinchoninic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid assay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> as the standard. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Protein</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extracts</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î¼g</NUMEX>) were mixed with an equal volume of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2Ã—</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laemmli</ENAMEX>'s sample buffer. Equal amounts of each sample
          were loaded and run on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE gel and transferred
          to nitrocellulose membranes using a semi-dry
          transblotting apparatus (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bio-Rad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          Nitrocellulose membranes were blocked with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat milk</ENAMEX>
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tris</ENAMEX>-buffered saline <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tween</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tris</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">137</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>,
          pH7<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> Tween <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 minutes</TIMEX> at room
          temperature. Blots were incubated overnight with
          anti<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-Tie1</ENAMEX> and anti-Tie2 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>) at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5000</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tris</ENAMEX>-buffered saline <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Tween</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat milk</ENAMEX>. Blots were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and then
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">horseradish-peroxidase-conjugated</ENAMEX> antibody
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:10,000 dilution) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> at room temperature. All
          blots were developed using the enhanced chemiluminesence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reagents</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) as per the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions.
        
      
    
  
