
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Synovial tissues isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with rheumatoid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) display biologic properties that differ from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'normal</ENAMEX>' synovium, and there is a rapidly expanding
        catalogue of biochemical and molecular changes that
        underlie this phenotype [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . We have investigated the
        feasibility of using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moloney</ENAMEX> murine <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX> virus (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMLV</ENAMEX>)
        based vectors to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constitutively</ENAMEX> express cloned genes in
        primary human fibroblast-like synovial cells (FLS), with
        the long-term objective of defining the contributions of
        specific signaling pathways and inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> to
        the destructive phenotype of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        Prior studies have suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MoMLV</ENAMEX>-based vectors
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transduced FLS</ENAMEX> with relatively low efficiency [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5</NUMEX> ] .
        We designed experiments to determine if viral titer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">influenced FLS</ENAMEX> transduction by concentration of retrovirus.
        In these experiments, we used a modified MoMLV vector
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">pRET2</NUMEX>), designed to improve transcriptional stability in
        primary cells. We also employed the enhanced green
        fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (EGFP) as a virally encoded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transgene</ENAMEX>
        to optimize a rapid and efficient superspeed centrifugation
        technique for concentration of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX>. Viral
        particles were concentrated to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">8colony</ENAMEX> forming units
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cfu</NUMEX>)/ml by superspeed centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> 
        g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX>. Up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of
        primary human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FLS</ENAMEX> were transduced 
        in vitro following a single exposure
        to concentrated viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Cell Culture
          Murine fibroblast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3T3</NUMEX> cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">amphotropic</ENAMEX> PA317
          packaging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix E</ENAMEX> ecotropic packaging cells
          were cultured in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX>)-high <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glucose</ENAMEX> (GIBCO-BRL, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX> island, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>)
          supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> heat-inactivated fetal bovine serum
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIBCO-BRL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX> island, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 U/ml penicillin,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> streptomycin, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> mM L-glutamine. The FLS
          cultures were established from synovial tissues obtained
          during joint replacement surgery in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] .
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> were cultured in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> heat-inactivated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human AB</ENAMEX> serum (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioWhittaker, Walkersville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          fetal bovine serum, penicillin, streptomycin, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-glutamine. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> were used between the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tenth</ENAMEX> passage.
        
        
          Construction of retroviral vector and producer
          cells
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> cDNA was PCR amplified from pEGFP-1
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and subcloned into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pRET2</TIMEX>,
          a modified version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MoMLV</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MFG</ENAMEX> retroviral
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX>, designed to optimize gene expression in primary
          cell lines. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">pRET2</NUMEX> incorporates long-terminal repeats
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">myeloproliferative sarcoma</ENAMEX> virus [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , and a
          point mutation in the primer binding site [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . A
          vector expressing the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cyclooxygenase-2</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX-2</ENAMEX>) cDNA
          was constructed in the same backbone (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pRET2</TIMEX>.COX2).
          Amphotropic viral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> were established in PA317
          cells (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Material</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Concentration of viral supernatant by superspeed
          centrifugation
          Fresh medium was added to subconfluent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> cell
          monolayers, collected <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours later</TIMEX>, and filtered (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.45</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼M</ENAMEX>) prior to use. Centrifugation was performed at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4Â°C</NUMEX> in
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorval</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RC-5B</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">centrifuge</ENAMEX>, using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> or GSA rotors.
          Following centrifugation, the supernatant was aspirated
          and saved for analysis. The viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pellet</ENAMEX> was resuspended
          in fresh medium by gentle pipetting.
        
        
          Quantitation of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> by slot blot
          hybridization
          Viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was quantitated using a slot blot
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hybridization</ENAMEX> technique. See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Material</ENAMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> details.
        
        
          Quantitation of retroviral titer by flow cytometry
          based expression analysis for EGFP
          We developed a flow cytometry assay to rapidly measure
          the titer of infectious viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">particles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). This
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> takes advantage of the fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">properties</ENAMEX> of
          the EGFP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transgene</ENAMEX>. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Ã— 10 5NIH</NUMEX> 3T3 cells were
          transduced with serial dilutions of supernatant. The
          transduction efficiency was measured by flow cytometry,
          and viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX> was calculated at limiting dilution
          according to the following formula:
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cfu/ml</ENAMEX>) = (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 5target</NUMEX> cells) Ã— (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX>+
          cells)/ volume of supernatant (ml).
          See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Material</ENAMEX> for full details.
        
        
          Transduction of primary human FLS
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> were plated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well dishes at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          5cells/well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> were cultured with viral supernatant
          plus protamine sulfate (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>. Cells were
          analyzed for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transgene</ENAMEX> expression <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX> after
          infection.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Concentration of viral supernatant
          To determine if viral titer influenced the
          transduction efficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX>, we optimized a superspeed
          centrifugation protocol for concentration of viral
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatant</ENAMEX>. Prior studies reported improved transduction
          of primary cells with retro-virus concentrated by
          centrifugation at 6000 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10 11</ENAMEX> ] . We
          systematically evaluated different centrifugation
          parameters to minimize the time required for maximal
          concentration while preserving viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">infectivity</ENAMEX>. A
          virally encoded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">EGFP transgene</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13 14</NUMEX> ] was used to
          monitor viral concentration and infectious titer. We
          concentrated viral supernatant <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-fold in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as few as four</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> by centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> 
          g , with complete recovery of
          infectious viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">particles</ENAMEX>. This data is presented in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Material</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Figs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">s1</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">s2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">s3</TIMEX>,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">s4</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Retroviral transduction of primary human
          synoviocytes
          Concentrated virus was tested for its ability to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">transduce</ENAMEX> primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX>. As shown in Figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2and Table 1</ENAMEX>,
          concentration of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX> increased FLS
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transduction</ENAMEX>. We found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.2</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.2%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> expressed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> following transduction with unconcentrated
          supernatant, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41.3</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.7%</NUMEX> for 10X
          concentrated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.01</ENAMEX>, compared with
          unconcentrated supernatant), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47.3</NUMEX> Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.8%</NUMEX> for 100X
          concentrated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.01</ENAMEX>, compared with
          unconcentrated supernatant).
          To provide confirmation that improved transduction of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> was associated with an increase in the intracellular
          expression of a virally encoded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transgene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> were
          transduced with a vector encoding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human COX-2</ENAMEX>
          (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pRET2</TIMEX>.COX2). The expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COX-2</ENAMEX> was measured by
          western blot on whole cell lysates [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . A substantial
          increase in net <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COX-2</ENAMEX> expression was observed following
          transduction with both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">10X</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100X</ENAMEX> concentrated viral
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatant</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        We are characterizing molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathways</ENAMEX> involved in
        synovial pathophysiology by overexpression of biologically
        relevant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transgenes</ENAMEX> and dominant negative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX>. The limited expansion potential of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX>, combined with
        the low efficiency of existing methods, stimulated a
        systematic examination of various transduction techniques
        to identify a rapid and efficient method for stable genetic
        modification of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX>. In this manuscript, we report a
        retroviral vector system and transduction protocol with the
        capacity to express a viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transgene</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> or more of
        primary human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FLS</ENAMEX> after a single exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX>. We have
        subsequently used this methodology to successfully express
        a panel of transgenes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L Crofford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K McDonagh</ENAMEX>,
        unpublished observations). We believe this approach will be
        of value to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> addressing similar mechanistic
        questions in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX>.
        Previous studies exploring the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recombinant MoMLV</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vectors</ENAMEX> concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> were relatively resistant to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transduction</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 4 5</NUMEX> ] , limiting enthusiasm for this
        approach. The basis for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> was unclear, but
        could be attributable to many factors including vector
        design, viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX>, or biologic features inherent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX>.
        Our experiments differ from prior studies of retroviral
        gene transfer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> in several important respects that may
        impact on the observed results. First, our viral backbone
        is a modified MoMLV vector that incorporates genetic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">myeloproliferative sarcoma</ENAMEX> virus long-terminal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repeats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B2</ENAMEX> mutation) associated with resistance to
        transcriptional silencing following proviral integration in
        primary cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] . While we did not perform a detailed
        comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> using the modified and
        unmodified vector backbones, preliminary experiments
        suggested that the modified vector was superior (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J Yang</ENAMEX>,
        unpublished observations). A similar, modified MoMLV vector
        has been used to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stably</ENAMEX> express <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> in human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX>
        stromal cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] , another fibroblast-like primary cell
        type. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> distinction is the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transgene</ENAMEX>, whereas prior studies relied on lacZ or
        beta-galactosidase. The expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> is readily
        detectable in living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> by fluorescence microscopy or
        flow cytometry, and expression can be monitored serially
        over time in a single culture. In contrast to staining for
        lacZ, which is often complicated by background staining
        from endogenous galactosidase activity, there is no
        significant background staining with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX>. We do not know
        if analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> expression is more or less sensitive
        than analysis for lacZ expression, although we believe it
        provides more reproducible and quantitative data due to the
        absence of background staining.
        Using this vector system, we observed a low 
        ex vivo transduction efficiency (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14.2</NUMEX>
        Â± <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.2%</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> with unconcentrated supernatant (titer of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6cfu/ml</ENAMEX>) that was roughly comparable to prior reports.
        Centrifugal concentration of viral supernatant by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10- to</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-fold significantly increased the efficiency of viral
        transduction, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> or more of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> in
        several independent experiments using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> lines from
        separate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. Concentration of supernatant to viral
        titers exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 7cfu/ml appeared to have the greatest
        quantitative impact on improving transduction efficiency.
        Increasing viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 8cfu/ml yielded an additional
        increase in transduction efficiency in some, but not all
        experiments. This observation suggests that factors in
        addition to viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX> may limit the maximum number of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transduced FLS</ENAMEX> observed using these culture conditions.
        Lentiviral vectors have the capacity to transduce
        nonreplicating cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] , and may represent an
        alternative to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MoMLV</ENAMEX>-based vectors for some
        applications.
      
      
        Conclusion
        We report a retroviral vector system and transduction
        methodology that achieve stable transgene expression in
        primary human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FLS</ENAMEX> with efficiencies of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 50%</NUMEX>.
        These results establish the feasibility of using widely
        available retroviral gene transfer techniques to study the
        biologic impact of overexpression of specific regulatory
        and inflammatory molecules in primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary</ENAMEX> material
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Introduction</ENAMEX>
          Synovial cells play a central role in the
          pathophysiology of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">inflammatory arthritis</ENAMEX>. Much of our
          understanding of this biology has been derived from the
          study of primary fibroblast like synovial cells cultured
          from arthritic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> after arthroscopic biopsy or
          surgery. Stable genetic modification of primary synovial
          cells is an approach that may be useful in defining the
          roles that specific signaling pathways or inflammatory
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> play in the joint destruction associated with
          rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. As our understanding of this
          biology improves, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have also proposed that
          gene transfer to primary synovial cells could be
          developed as a therapeutic approach to the treatment of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">inflammatory arthritis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] .
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recombinant</ENAMEX> retroviral vectors are widely used in the
          laboratory, and in experimental clinical applications, to
          introduce new genetic material into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> genome in a
          stable form. Retroviral packaging cells routinely yield
          viral supernatants with titers in the range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 5to 10
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6cfu/ml</ENAMEX> or higher, and titers of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 10</NUMEX> 7cfu/ml may be
          achieved in some cases. Physical methods to concentrate
          viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatants</ENAMEX> have been pursued with mixed results.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultracentrifugation</ENAMEX> can be used to physically concentrate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MoMLV</ENAMEX>-based retroviral particles, but viral infectivity
          is impaired secondary to damage to the envelope <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
          Pseudotyped retroviruses containing the vesicular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stomatitis</ENAMEX> virus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> are more robust, and can be
          concentrated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX>-fold by ultracentrifugation
          without significant loss of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">infectivity</ENAMEX>. However,
          because of the toxicity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">vesicular stomatitis</ENAMEX> virus
          G glycoprotein, only transient methods of virus
          production have been described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S1 S2</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowles</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX> previously reported a
          superspeed centrifugation technique for concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recombinant</ENAMEX> retrovirus [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MoMLV</ENAMEX> based recombinant
          retrovirus was concentrated over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-fold by
          centrifugation at 6000 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX>.
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Supplementary Materials</ENAMEX> and methods
        
          Cell culture
          The murine fibroblast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3T3</ENAMEX> cell line (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCL</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>) and
          the amphotropic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">retroviral</ENAMEX> packaging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> line PA317 (CRL
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9078</TIMEX>) were obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX>
          Collection (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix E</ENAMEX> ecotropic
          packaging cell line was obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Gary Nolan</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">amphotropic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> cells
          A transinfection technique was used to rapidly
          establish a polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">amphotropic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> line of
          moderate to high titer. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The pRET2</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pRET2</TIMEX>.COX2
          plasmids were transfected into ecotropic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix E</ENAMEX>
          packaging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> by the calcium phosphate precipitation
          method, using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ProFection</ENAMEX> kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Retroviral supernatant was collected <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> after
          transfection, filtered through a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.45 Î</NUMEX>¼M filter (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nalgene</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml protamine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sulfate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elkins-Sinn, Inc.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cherry Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), and
          incubated with amphotropic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PA317</ENAMEX> packaging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. The transinfection procedure was repeated twice.
          Following transinfection with ecotropic viral
          supernatant, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">PA317</NUMEX> cells were transduced with
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the pRET2</TIMEX>.EGFP vector, as determined by fluorescence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microscopy</ENAMEX>. The successful transinfection of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pRET2</TIMEX>.COX2
          into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PA317</TIMEX> was confirmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">G418</ENAMEX> selection. These
          polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> of PA317 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> cells were used
          as the source of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX> for subsequent viral
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transduction</ENAMEX> and concentration experiments. The presence
          of replication competent retrovirus was excluded by PCR
          for viral envelope coding sequence in genomic DNA
          isolated from virally transduced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3T3</ENAMEX> target cells
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">primers: 5</ENAMEX>'-AAG-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GTGGTAAACCAGGGGGATC-3</ENAMEX>' and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5'-TGAGCAGCT-TCATGCCGCTATC-3</ENAMEX>').
        
        
          Quantitation of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> by slot blot
          hybridization
          A nylon transfer membrane (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micron Separations Inc.</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westborough</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was soaked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10X</TIMEX> SSC for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> min
          and inserted into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRL</ENAMEX> convertible filtration manifold
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRL Life Technologies Inc.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> was washed twice with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î¼l</NUMEX> of 10X SSC
          immediately before sample loading. Retroviral supernatant
          samples were directly loaded onto the membrane without
          further preparation. After application of the sample to
          the membrane, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
          Î¼l of 10X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>. The membrane was cross-linked with UV
          light (Stratalinker <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1800</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stratagene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>)
          and stored for analysis by hybridization. An EGFP probe
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fragment</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">~800</NUMEX> base pairs) was prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> and
          labeled with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32P</NUMEX>-dCTP (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Life Science Inc.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Heights</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) using a kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prime-It RmT</ENAMEX>,
          Stratagene, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Jolla</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The membrane was
          prehybridized for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">42Â°C</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ml of
          hybridization buffer (final concentrations: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>
          formamide, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">5X Denhardt</ENAMEX>'s solution, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, 5X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSPE</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Î¼g</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">denatured herring sperm DNA</ENAMEX>), and hybridized with
          the denatured <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> overnight in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ml of hybridization
          buffer at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42Â°C</TIMEX>. The membrane was washed twice with 2X
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSPE</ENAMEX> at room temperature for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with
          0.1X <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">SSPE/0</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, and twice with
          0.1X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSPE</ENAMEX> at room temperature for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min. The
          autoradiograph was visualized by exposing the membrane to
          X-ray film at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">-80Â°C</NUMEX> with an intensifying screen.
        
        
          Quantitation of retroviral titer by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX> based
          expression analysis for EGFP
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3T3</NUMEX> cells were plated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well tissue culture
          dishes at a density of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 5cells</NUMEX> per well. The following
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, the medium was replaced with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ml of fresh medium
          containing a defined volume of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX>,
          supplemented with protamine sulfate (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>). After
          exposure to viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>, the medium
          was replaced with fresh, virus-free medium and the cells
          were cultured for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an additional 48 hours</TIMEX>. At the
          conclusion of the experiment, the cells were trypsinized
          and analyzed by flow cytometry on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPICS XL</ENAMEX> (excited by
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">488</NUMEX> nm light, using a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">530 Â± 15 nm</NUMEX> bandpass filter to
          detect the signal on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FL1</TIMEX>) to determine the percentage of
          cells expressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX>. In all cases, serial dilutions of
          viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX> were tested.
        
      
      
        Supplementary Results
        
          Optimization of the centrifugation protocol
          
            Duration of centrifugation
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supernatant</ENAMEX> collected from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the RET2</TIMEX>.EGFP producer
            cells was centrifuged at 6000 
            g for time periods varying
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1 and 20 hours</TIMEX>. After centrifugation, the
            supernatant was collected and saved for quantitation of
            residual viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">particles</ENAMEX>. The viral <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> were
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuspended</ENAMEX> in a thirtieth of the original volume of
            the supernatant. As measured on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3T3</NUMEX> cells by flow
            cytometry, viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX> increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14-fold</NUMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of centrifugation, and appeared to plateau after
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> of centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.34</NUMEX> Ã— <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 7cfu/ml</ENAMEX>
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supplementary Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). There was a proportional
            decline in the viral titer of the postcentrifugation
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatant</ENAMEX>. Even following concentration for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">as long</TIMEX>
            as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 hours</TIMEX>, the infectivity of the recombinant virus
            was preserved.
            To confirm the viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX> derived by expression
            analysis, we performed slot blot hybridization analysis
            on viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> in the postcentrifugation supernatant and
            the resuspended viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pellet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supplementary Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
            Following centrifugation at 6000 
            g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX>, most retroviral
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was concentrated in the viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pellet</ENAMEX>. Almost no
            retroviral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> remained in the postcentrifugation
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supernatant</ENAMEX> after centrifugation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX>.
          
          
            Relative centrifugal force
            To further optimize the concentration procedure, we
            examined a range of relative centrifugal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> (RCF).
            The time of centrifugation was fixed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> and
            the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCF</ENAMEX> was varied in a range from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> 
            g . Following centrifugation, the
            viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pellet</ENAMEX> was resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundredth</NUMEX> of the
            original volume. Viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX> was quantitated by
            expression studies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3T3</NUMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supplementary Fig</ENAMEX>.
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) and slot blot hybridization analysis (Supplementary
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). We observed a progressive rise in viral titer
            as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCF</ENAMEX> was increased from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> 
            g . At a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCF</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> 
            g , the titer of the resuspended
            pellet reached a plateau value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX> Ã— <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 8cfu/ml.</ENAMEX>
            Further concentration of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">particles</ENAMEX> was not
            achieved by increasing RCF above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> 
            g . Viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">particles</ENAMEX> were not
            detectable by expression assay or by slot blot
            hybridization analysis in the post-centrifugation
            supernatant at an RCF of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> 
            g or higher. The expression data
            also suggested that centrifugation at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCF</ENAMEX> as high as
            30,000 
            g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> did not affect
            viability of the recombinant retrovirus.
          
        
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Discussion</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> are the principal cell type of sublining
        synovial tissue. Proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> is observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, a
        debilitating condition that affects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of
        adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> worldwide. Primary FLS cultures can be
        established following arthroscopic biopsy or surgical
        resection of synovium from the joint. Protease digested
        synovial tissues placed in culture rapidly yield
        fibroblast-like cells. After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> passages, these primary
        cultures are depleted of macrophage-like type A
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synoviocytes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S3</TIMEX> ] . Doubling time is stable between the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> passages, but marked reduction in
        proliferation rate occurs in later passage cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S4</TIMEX> ]
        .
        Retroviral mediated gene transfer is a commonly used
        technique to stably introduce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> into primary cells. The
        titer of retroviral supernatant is one of several factors
        that influence transduction efficiency. A variety of
        strategies have been employed to physically concentrate
        retroviral particles in an attempt to further increase
        viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX> and improve the efficiency of target cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transduction</ENAMEX>. Centrifugation of retroviral supernatant is a
        potentially attractive approach to viral concentration
        because of the wide availability of centrifuge equipment,
        the simplicity of the technique, and the theoretical
        potential for rapid processing of large sample volumes.
        Concentrated recombinant retrovirus, generated by
        super-speed centrifugation of retroviral supernatant, has
        been used to improve the transduction efficiency of primary
        cells, including hepatocytes [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] and endothelial cells [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> ] . In these prior reports, concentration was
        accomplished by centrifugation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCF</ENAMEX> of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX> 
        g . We used a recombinant retrovirus
        encoding the green fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> to optimize a
        protocol to rapidly and efficiently concentrate retrovirus
        by superspeed centrifugation. Our studies indicate that the
        time necessary to recover essentially all viral particles
        can be reduced to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> by increasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCF</ENAMEX> to
        20,000 
        g . The protocol does not appear to
        adversely affect the infectivity of the viral preparation,
        as the functional viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">titer</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3T3</NUMEX> cells closely
        matched the titer that was predicted by the degree of
        concentration. Although it has been reported that
        centrifugation may result in concurrent concentration of
        noninfectious viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">particles</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of viral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transduction</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S5</TIMEX> ] , we have been able to substantially
        increase the transduction efficiency of primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> using
        concentrated viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">supernatant</ENAMEX> produced by our protocol.
        This optimized technique may be useful in generating high
        titer retroviral supernatants from production lots of
        relatively modest titer. We anticipate that this method
        will be effective in concentrating other pseudotyped MoMLV
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vectors</ENAMEX> and lentivirus based vectors, though additional
        testing will be required to evaluate its suitability for
        each vector system.
        While our studies were not initiated with the objective
        of developing a therapeutic protocol, these results may
        also have implications for clinical studies. The 
        ex vivo genetic modification of FLS
        has been proposed as a potential approach to the treatment
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S6 S7</ENAMEX> ] . In these studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> are cultured
        from synovial tissue obtained by synovectomy, transduced
        with retroviral supernatant 
        ex vivo , and injected into another
        joint of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>. Approval for these clinical
        studies was based on 
        ex vivo transduction data in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">preclinical animal</ENAMEX> models [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S8 S9</ENAMEX> ] . Essentially, all data
        on transduction efficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> was derived using
        retroviral vectors that express lacZ or beta-galactosidase.
        Although most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> have obtained 
        ex vivo transduction efficiencies of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cultured FLS</ENAMEX> in the range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>, some have reported
        transduction efficiencies <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 20%</NUMEX>. Preactivation of FLS
        with tumor necrosis factor Î±, however, may increase
        transduction efficiency levels to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 30%</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">S8</TIMEX> ] .
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cfu</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> forming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COX-2</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">cyclooxygenase</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EGFP</ENAMEX> = enhanced
        green fluorescent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fluorescence</NUMEX>-activated
        cell sorting; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLS</ENAMEX> = fibroblast-like synovial cells; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MoMLV</ENAMEX> =
        Moloney <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">murine leukemia</ENAMEX> virus; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> = polymerase chain
        reaction; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCF</ENAMEX> = relative
        centrifugal force.
      
    
  
