
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) is a significant, chronic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> that afflicts <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> of the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in most
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Joint damage typically occurs before
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are diagnosed, and most of the joint destruction
        occurs within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 2 years</TIMEX> of diagnosis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Therapeutic drugs</ENAMEX> such as sulfasalazine and methotrexate
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTX</ENAMEX>) only slow the progression of the disease, suggesting
        that these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> fail to adequately quell the underlying
        pathophysiology of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] .
        Tumor necrosis factor alpha (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-α</ENAMEX>) is elevated in sera
        and synovial fluid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, suggesting that it
        may play a role in the pathology of the disease [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
        Soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF-α receptor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neutralizing antibodies</ENAMEX> against
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α have been shown to prevent collagen-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . Furthermore, a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF-α</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hTNF-α</ENAMEX>)
        transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Tg197</NUMEX>) develops a chronic, progressive
        polyarthritis with histologic features in common with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> ] . Weight loss and joint swelling in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> are
        correlated with expression of hTNF-α mRNA in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
        ] and hTNF-α concentrations in the serum [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] .
        Previously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keffer</ENAMEX> 
        et al. [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] showed that progression
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> could be prevented by treatment
        with anti-TNF-α <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibody</ENAMEX> (mAb). In this study,
        we utilized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Tg197</TIMEX> mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> to further assess whether
        anti-TNF-α treatment can ameliorate established disease in
        both young and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Tg197 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and anti-TNF-α mAb treatment
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heterozygous</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Tg197</NUMEX> transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, obtained from Dr
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Kollias</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellenic Pasteur Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Athens</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , were identified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> analysis using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'-modified hTNF-α gene. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> experimental
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were used. 'Young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>' were enrolled
          into the study when they developed clinical signs of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8 weeks of age</TIMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          was maintained disease-free with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kg</NUMEX> of anti-TNF-α
          mAb <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> starting at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks of age</TIMEX>; when they reached
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 weeks of age</TIMEX>, the treatment was stopped and these
          'aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>' were allowed to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> before they
          were enrolled into the study. The enrollment criteria for
          both young and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> required them to have a clinical
          score of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 2</NUMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> limbs. The experimental
          protocols were approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centocor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Care</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Use Committee</ENAMEX>.
          The murine anti-TNF-α mAb used in this study binds
          with high affinity to hTNF-α and prevents binding to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF</ENAMEX> receptor [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . Anti-TNF-α mAb was administered by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intraperitoneal</ENAMEX> injection at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kg</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> and the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in the control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> received <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> injections
          of saline.
        
        
          Clinical scores
          Clinical scores were based on a previously described
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">scoring</ENAMEX> system [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] modified as follows: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0</ENAMEX> (normal), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          (edema or distortion of paw or ankle joints), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          (distortion of paw and ankle joints), or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX> (ankylosis of
          wrist or ankle joints). The sum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> paws was
          scored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>, with a maximum possible score of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> per
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Histologic processing of joints
          Specimens were processed and scored as described
          previously [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] and in the supplementary
          material.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> assay
          Serum <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were separated from whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, which
          was collected by intracardiac puncture at baseline and at
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3, 6</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 weeks</TIMEX> post-treatment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serum</ENAMEX> levels of hTNF-α
          were determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:2</ENAMEX> dilution according to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biosource International</ENAMEX>,
          Camarillo, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolation and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RNase</ENAMEX> protection assay
          Samples were prepared as described in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary</ENAMEX> material and analyzed in an RNase
          protection assay according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          instructions (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PharMingen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          All data are expressed as means ± standard deviation
          unless noted otherwise. Statistical significance was
          tested using analysis of variance for multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. If
          significant differences were found, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>-wise testing was
          performed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tukey</ENAMEX>'s test. The level of significance
          for all comparisons was set at 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> < <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Amelioration of established polyarthritis by
          treatment with anti-TNF-α mAb
          Increased cartilage turnover and repair in response to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insult</ENAMEX> has been observed in young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, whereas aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          show decreased cartilage turnover after closure of the
          growth plate [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . Therefore, anti-TNF-α treatment was
          evaluated in both young (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7-8-week-old</ENAMEX>) and aged
          (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27-28-week-old</TIMEX>) Tg197 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with established <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>.
          The mean clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> score at baseline was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>), indicating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> was established at the
          commencement of treatment. The clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> score
          increased progressively in the saline-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and
          these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were humanely killed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. In contrast,
          the clinical arthritic score was markedly decreased in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, both young and aged, treated with anti-TNF-α,
          indicating a marked suppression of their arthritic
          symptoms (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a,1b). <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mice</ENAMEX> in the saline-treated group
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progressively</ENAMEX> lost weight, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> in the anti-TNF-α
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> showed a significant weight gain throughout the
          study (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supplementary Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The arthritic score
          (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 1 to 16</TIMEX> post-treatment; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a,1b) and weight
          gain (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 5 to 16</TIMEX> post-treatment; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supplementary Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> treated with anti-TNF-α were significantly
          improved in comparison with the saline-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in
          both young and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. More importantly, the arthritic
          scores for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> treated with anti-TNF-α were
          significantly improved in comparison with the baseline
          score from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks 4</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> in both young and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a,1b). These results indicate that disease
          progression was not just prevented but was reversed
          following anti-TNF-α treatment.
        
        
          Effects of treatment with anti-TNF-α mAb on joint
          histopathology
          All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> were scored in a blinded fashion for
          synovitis, bone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">erosions</ENAMEX>, and cartilage degradation using
          a predefined scoring system. The mean histologic scores
          for each treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> at various time points are shown
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Saline</ENAMEX> treatment was followed by increased
          histologic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> for synovitis, bone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">erosions</ENAMEX>, and
          cartilage damage relative to that observed at baseline.
          Anti-TNF-α treatment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 weeks</TIMEX> significantly reduced
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> histologic scores relative to the baseline
          score in young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the three
          histologic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> in aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supplementary Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
          After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 weeks</TIMEX> of anti-TNF-α treatment, synovial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inflammation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone erosions</ENAMEX> were almost completely
          resolved in both young and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, and a significant
          reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage degradation</ENAMEX> in comparison with
          baseline was maintained in young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Cartilage
          degradation in aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> treated with anti-TNF-α was
          similar to that at the baseline measurement and
          significantly lower than that in the saline treatment
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supplementary Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
          Representative tissue sections of the ankle joints
          from young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Evidence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritic disease</ENAMEX> was readily observed at baseline (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          3a,3b), and the disease continued to progress in
          saline-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, with increased cell
          proliferation and inflammatory cell infiltration, erosion
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>, and loss of proteoglycan from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cartilage</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3c,3d). However, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 weeks</TIMEX> of
          anti-TNF-α treatment, improvements in all
          histopathological parameters were observed with both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staining</ENAMEX> procedures (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3e,3f). No visible evidence of
          bone or cartilage erosion was observed and all signs of
          cellular proliferation and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">infiltration</ENAMEX> disappeared. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteoglycan</ENAMEX> content of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> was notably
          improved. Extended treatment with anti-TNF-α (for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>) maintained normal joint architecture (data not
          shown). These results demonstrate that blocking hTNF-α
          reverses joint inflammation and promotes joint healing in
          this model of polyarthritis.
        
        
          Inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and other proinflammatory
          cytokines
          To define the underlying mechanisms by which
          anti-TNF-α mAb ameliorated joint inflammation and
          structural damage, the levels of various proinflammatory
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> were examined. First, circulating hTNF-α levels
          as detected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> were more than halved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 3</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and the reduction was sustained for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 weeks</TIMEX> after
          treatment with anti-TNF-α mAb in comparison with
          saline-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4a). In addition, murine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">IL-6, IL-1β, and IFN</ENAMEX>-γ mRNA, which are expressed in the
          arthritic joint tissues, were clearly diminished
          following anti-TNF-α treatment when total joint <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was
          examined by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RNase</ENAMEX> protection <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">assays</TIMEX> (see Supplementary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). When the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">murine IL-6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1β</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ
          mRNA were standardized to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">glyceraldehyde-3-phosphate</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dehydrogenase</ENAMEX> (GAPDH) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4b,4c<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX>d), a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-fold
          reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">murine IL-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-γ was observed in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">aged animals</ENAMEX> treated with anti-TNF-α in comparison with
          those treated with saline at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> post-treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          4b,4c). Interestingly, local expression of murine TNF-α
          mRNA was not affected by treatment with anti-TNF-α
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX>, suggesting that hTNF-α plays a crucial role
          in the pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTX</ENAMEX> is the most widely used disease-modifying
        antirheumatic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> for the treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. However, MTX
        treatment rarely results in complete <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> remission [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
        ] and only slows the progression of joint erosion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
        In addition, long-term treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTX</ENAMEX> is associated
        with pulmonary [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver toxicities</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] and other
        side effects. Therefore, a treatment option that
        facilitates reversal of joint damage and has longer
        effectiveness and fewer side effects is desirable.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Experimental arthritis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> have contributed to the
        basic understanding of joint disease and to the development
        of effective antiarthritic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] . Several models
        have been used to mimic human <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, ranging from immunization
        with cartilage components to infection with joint trophic
        organisms [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Blocking TNF-α</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 22</ENAMEX> ] or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> ] in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> has routinely shown benefit, although
        some questions remain regarding the role of these cytokines
        in mitigating joint inflammation versus preventing
        cartilage degradation and bone erosion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] .
        Using the Tg197 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, we have shown that maintenance
        anti-TNF-α therapy, initiated after joint inflammation and
        erosions have occurred, allows damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> to heal.
        Specifically, anti-TNF-α <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> proved equally effective in
        reversing joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synovitis</ENAMEX> and erosions both in young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>,
        where an active repair process to damage occurs, and aged
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, where the repair process has relatively slowed.
        However, the repair of cartilage damage was different
        between young and aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Cartilage in young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
        treated with anti-TNF-α was significantly improved relative
        to saline-treated and baseline <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. By comparison,
        treatment of aged <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with anti-TNF-α prevented further
        cartilage damage but did not improve histological scores
        relative to baseline values. Mechanistically, the
        therapeutic effect of anti-TNF-α appears to be due to
        either neutralization of soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hTNF-α</ENAMEX> or inhibition of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hTNF-α</ENAMEX> production in the diseased joint. Additionally,
        other proinflammatory cytokine mRNAs were decreased in the
        local diseased tissues either through suppression of
        inflammatory cell infiltration or inhibition of cytokine
        production. Moreover, anti-TNF-α treatment resulted in a
        modest inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">murine IL-1β</ENAMEX> production in the
        diseased joint, which is consistent with previous findings
        that anti-TNF-α <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> inhibits the generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-1</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX>-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> in
        rheumatoid synovial cultures [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27</NUMEX> ] . Our study provides
        preclinical evidence supporting the use of anti-TNF-α mAb
        in ameliorating arthritic pathology.
        The progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> observed in Tg197 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> is
        similar to the pathology in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Recent
        clinical data indicate that the blockade of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α
        significantly reduces the signs and symptoms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX>
        ] and inhibits the progression of structural damage [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31</NUMEX>
        ] . It remains to be seen whether extended anti-TNF-α
        therapy might permit regeneration of articular cartilage
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> in established human disease, where multiple
        etiological pathways may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> disease
        syndrome [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX> ] . Nevertheless, it is likely that much
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> pathology involves <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">TNF-α activation</ENAMEX>, and the
        results from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Tg197</TIMEX> model provide a sound scientific
        rationale for the therapeutic benefits observed following
        anti-TNF-α treatment in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        Progression of established polyarthritis in the Tg197
        hTNF-α transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> can be reversed by treatment with
        anti-TNF-α mAb, as shown by significant improvement in
        clinical and histological scores.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        Anti-TNF-α = anti-tumor necrosis factor alpha; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> =
        enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hTNF-α</ENAMEX> = human tumor
        necrosis factor alpha; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon; IL</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interleukin</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mAb</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibody</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mRNA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messenger</ENAMEX> ribonucleic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTX</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">methotrexate</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> = polymerase chain reaction;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α = tumor necrosis factor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alpha</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary</ENAMEX> material
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary</ENAMEX> materials and methods
          
            Histologic processing of joints
            Joint tissues from wrists, ankles, elbows, and knees
            were fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> buffered formalin <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>,
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decalcified</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> formic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 days</TIMEX>, dehydrated,
            and then embedded in paraffin. Specimens were cut
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">longitudinally</ENAMEX> to the midline, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-m</ENAMEX> sections mounted
            for staining with hematoxylin and eosin or toluidine
            blue. Joint sections stained with hematoxylin and eosin
            were scored for synovitis and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone erosions</ENAMEX>, as
            described elsewhere [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . Sections stained with
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">toluidine</ENAMEX> blue were scored for cartilage degradation
            (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>, normal staining; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, some loss of staining; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2,</ENAMEX>
            moderate loss of staining; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, weak staining; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, very
            weak staining; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, no visible staining). Specimens were
            examined using light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">microscopy</ENAMEX> and scored in a blinded
            fashion with regard to treatment.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolation and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RNase</ENAMEX> protection assay
            Excised ankle and paw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> were immediately frozen
            in liquid nitrogen and processed in a freezer/mill
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEX Certi-Prep, Metuchen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) with liquid
            nitrogen at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2-minute</TIMEX> pulses. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was isolated from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>
            ml chloroform, precipitated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> ml isopropyl
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, and resuspended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 l</TIMEX> diethyl
            pyrocarbonate-treated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> micrograms of total
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> from each sample was used for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">RNase</ENAMEX> protection
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mCK -2b</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-3b Multi-Probe Template Sets</ENAMEX>,
            PharMingen, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), exposed to a Phosphor
            screen, and quantified by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phosphorimager</ENAMEX> with the use
            of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Image Quant</ENAMEX> software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvale</ENAMEX>,
            CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The signal-intensity ratio of different
            cytokine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">messenger RNA</ENAMEX> (mRNA) to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX> was
            determined.
          
        
      
    
  
