
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> is a potent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">monocyte</ENAMEX>/macrophage regulatory
        cytokine that inhibits expression of proinflammatory
        mediators [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Monocytes/macrophages</ENAMEX>, B cells, murine
        Th2 cells, and some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD8</NUMEX> +cells produce <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macrophages</ENAMEX> rapidly produce proinflammatory cytokines such
        as tumor necrosis factor alpha (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1 and IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
        after activation with lipopolysaccharide or IFN-Î³, while
        production of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> is delayed. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> is produced it
        functions in an autoregulatory fashion to suppress
        proinflammatory cytokine mRNA expression and protein
        production [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6 7</NUMEX> ] . In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> suppresses the
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MHC class II</ENAMEX> molecules and costimulatory
        molecules such as intercellular adhesion molecule <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 and B7</TIMEX>,
        leading to reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">T-cell</ENAMEX> macrophage interactions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9 10</NUMEX> ] .
        The selective suppression of Th1 cell activity is
        believed to be due to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX>, a
        differentiation factor for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Th1 cells</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] . The
        release of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reactive oxygen</ENAMEX> and nitrogen intermediates by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX> is also suppressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">by IL-10</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] . In
        addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> stimulates the production of cytokine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-1 receptor antagonist</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . In
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> is produced by
        synovial membrane cells and is found at high levels in the
        synovial fluid [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ] . It has been shown that
        suppression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> production by synovial cells is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with increased levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±,
        suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> plays a suppressive role in
        rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> joints [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . It was also observed
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> directly stimulated proteoglycan synthesis and
        reversed the cartilage degradation induced by activated
        mononuclear cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . These immunosuppressive
        activities indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> is a potential therapeutic
        approach for autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>.
        In <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> models of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, systemic treatment with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> and adenovirus-mediated transfer of viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        moderately suppresses the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, but is
        significantly more effective when combined with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-4</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21 22 23 24</NUMEX> ] . The evidence for the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        is further supported by the fact that 
        in vivo anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> treatment
        accelerates disease in collagen-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>) [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> ] .
        Most studies focused on investigating the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        in models of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> have involved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of
        neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>, large amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, or gene
        therapy in experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. While these studies are
        helpful in broadly defining the function of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX>, it is
        difficult to determine the cytokine dose and timing by
        these means. To address the effects of complete elimination
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 
        in vivo on the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and
        to understand the mechanism responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        regulation, we examined the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">homozygous IL-10 -/-IL-10</ENAMEX>-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>, antigens, and immunization
          procedure
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were generated as previously
          described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . The original genetic background of
          these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> was a mixture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> 129/Ola and
          C57BL<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/6</NUMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were backcrossed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">DBA/1</NUMEX>
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> and further backcrossed for an
          additional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DBA/1</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bar Harbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>.
          All <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were typed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> mutation by PCR
          using primer sets that detect either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DBA/1</ENAMEX> wildtype
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX>) or the mutated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> gene. In addition, splenocytes
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> activated 
          in vitro did not produce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were maintained in sterilized
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bedding</ENAMEX> and food with acidified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. Chicken type II
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX> was used for generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> as
          described elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . Male and female <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WT</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">heterozygous IL-10 +/-and IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were immunized
          once with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">¼g chicken type II collagen emulsified</ENAMEX> in
          complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s adjuvant (CFA) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Difco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intradermal</ENAMEX> injection at the base of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tail</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> were examined for the onset of joint swelling
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other day</TIMEX>. A standard scoring system based upon
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redness</ENAMEX> and swelling of each paw (ranging from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0 to 4</TIMEX> for
          each paw, thus resulting in a possible maximum severity
          score of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>) was used for the assessment of disease
          severity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Histologic</ENAMEX> studies were performed to determine
          the extent of joint damage. At the end of the experiment,
          hind paws were dissected, fixed, and decalcified before
          being embedded in paraffin, and were sectioned at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> Î¼m as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . Sagittal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were
          stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H & E.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Assessment of cytokine production by spleen cells
          in vitro
          Spleens were obtained at various time points after
          immunization with collagen. Single cell suspensions were
          prepared as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . Splenocytes
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.0</NUMEX> Ã— <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 6cells/ml</ENAMEX>) were incubated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falcon</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisher Scientific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RPMI-1640</ENAMEX> media containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 U/ml</ENAMEX>
          penicillin, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml streptomycin, 2</ENAMEX> mM L-glutamine, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">mM 2-ME</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pyruvate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> mM nonessential amino
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acids</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEPES</ENAMEX>. Cells were stimulated in the
          presence or absence of collagen (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ was
          measured from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> supernatant using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OptEIA</ENAMEX> mouse
          cytokine detection system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD PharMingen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Measurement of immunoglobulin isotypes
          An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX> was used to measure isotype-specific
          antibodies in serial dilutions (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:500-1.:2500</ENAMEX>) of sera.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> plates were coated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼g <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> type II
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collagen</ENAMEX>-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">IgG</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isotypes</ENAMEX> were detected
          with peroxidase-labeled rabbit anti-mouse IgG 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> or IgG 
          2a (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zymed Laboratories</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>,
          CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Titrated concentrations of IgG 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and IgG 
          2a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">myeloma proteins</ENAMEX> were used to
          generate a standard curve, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgGs</ENAMEX> were detected
          with the same labeled rabbit anti-mouse IgG 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> or IgG 
          2a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antiserum</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Flow cytometry
          Flow cytometry was performed on freshly isolated
          spleen cells. Immunofluorescence staining of cell surface
          markers was performed using FITC-labeled antibodies
          against CD3, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B220</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD11b</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD11c</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BD PharMingen</ENAMEX>).
          FITC-labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat IgG isotypes</ENAMEX> were used as controls. FcRs
          were blocked using anti-FcR <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody (24G2</ENAMEX>). Flow
          cytometric analysis was performed using a FACS
          Caliburflow cytometer utilizing CELLQuest software
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          Analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> score and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> incidence
          at different time points were carried out using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nonparametric Mann</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney U</ENAMEX> test. Student's 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">t</ENAMEX> test was used for statistical
          analysis of all other data. Analyses were performed using
          SPSS software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPSS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Augmented CIA</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">DBA/1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice lacking IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          To determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> functions as an endogenous
          inhibitor of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">inflammatory arthritis</ENAMEX>, we examined the
          development of disease using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> model. Male and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">female WT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 +/-</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">littermates</ENAMEX> were
          immunized with collagen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFA</ENAMEX> intradermally. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> from
          the male and female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were pooled because there was no
          significant difference between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
          All <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> succumb to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> but the time of onset
          was somewhat delayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 +/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> compared
          with that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a). Interestingly,
          the number of arthritic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 +/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> began to
          recede after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day 35</TIMEX>, whereas all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were still
          arthritic at the time of termination of the experiments,
          although with reduced severity. Arthritis severity in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> was significantly exacerbated in comparison
          with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 +/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1b).
          Inflamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> showed typical histopathological
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abnormalities</ENAMEX> described previously (synovial
          proliferation, leukocyte infiltration, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> and bone
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">erosions</ENAMEX>) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30</NUMEX> ] , which correlated well with the
          severity of the clinical symptoms.
          Taken together, the results described demonstrate that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> is important for controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> severity.
        
        
          Anticollagen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> is reduced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-deficient
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mice</ENAMEX>
          Induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> is dependent on B cells, and high
          doses of antibodies are pathogenic when transferred to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">naÃ¯ve</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> can affect both the
          viability and the production of immunoglobulin by B cells
          [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX> ] . To determine whether the augmentation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
          correlated with an alteration in anticollagen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>,
          we collected sera from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> at the time of sacrifice.
          Interestingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> produced significantly less
          anticollagen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> than either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WT</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 +/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Both the IgG 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and the IgG 
          2a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isotypes</ENAMEX> of anticollagen antibodies
          were substantially reduced.
          These results suggest that a decrease in anticollagen
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> may be the result of a requirement for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> in
          B-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> production.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ levels are reduced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-deficient
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mice</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ production is observed early in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX>-immunized <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, and progressively increases with
          the time of clinical manifestation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. Although
          the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ correlates with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> appears
          to play a dual role in disease activity. Anti-IFN-Î³
          treatment early in the course of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> suppresses
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX>, whereas neutralization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ late in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease exacerbates arthritis</ENAMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> exhibit exacerbated disease [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> ] .
          We were therefore interested in determining whether
          the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX>-immunized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 +/-</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>.
          Splenocytes were isolated from immunized <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cultured</ENAMEX> in the presence and absence of collagen (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ levels were significantly suppressed in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> in comparison with either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WT</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">+/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
          These results confirm that reduced levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
          were associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">exacerbated arthritis</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX>-immunized <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. These data also suggest that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> positively regulates IFN-Î³, either directly or
          indirectly.
        
        
          CD11b +expansion correlates with reduced
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          Matthys 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . recently showed that the
          enhanced severity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFN-Î³ receptor</ENAMEX>-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          immunized with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II collagen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFA</ENAMEX> is due to an
          expansion of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> produce reduced levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, we were
          interested in determining whether there was a specific
          expansion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +cells.
          Although the spleen cell number increased in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.42 Ã— 10 8Â± 0.17</NUMEX>) in comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">WT mice</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.84 Ã— 10 8Â± 0.23</NUMEX>), there was a specific expansion of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +cell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The spleen from WT <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          contained <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.7%</NUMEX> CD11b +cells, whereas the spleen of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> contained <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.5%</NUMEX> CD11b +cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). When the
          percentage of cells was corrected for cell number, there
          was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.7</NUMEX>-fold increase in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the spleen of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. The net number of T cells, B cells, and
          dendritic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> was not significantly different.
          These data are consistent with the inhibitory effects
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ on expansion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +cells. The data suggest
          that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> is important for controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> and/or
          other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytokines</ENAMEX> involved in the process of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +cell
          expansion.
          In an attempt to understand the mechanism responsible
          for the expansion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +macrophages in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>,
          we examined cytokines associated with inflammation and
          Th1 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell phenotype</ENAMEX>. We were unable to detect any
          difference in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX> or TNF-Î± levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          in comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">WT mice</ENAMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX> was
          significantly increased in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>).
          These results suggest the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX> may
          play a role in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +cell expansion.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> appears to play an important role in the
        regulation of several autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> models. Treatment
        with recombinant <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, in proteoglycan-induced
        reduced disease severity, and neutralizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> with
        antibodies exacerbated disease [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 22 23</NUMEX> ] . The
        present data are consistent with previous results and show
        that a complete absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> exacerbates inflammation
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37 38 39</NUMEX> ] . The anti-inflammatory properties of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> suggest that endogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> may function as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> of proinflammatory mediators 
        in vivo [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . It is interesting,
        however, that disease severity inversely correlates with
        the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        may control disease activity via regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        responses.
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> is considered a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX>-type disease mediated
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ in the pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> is
        not clearly understood. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> appears to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate
        functions, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> promoting as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> limiting [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> ] . Neutralization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ with antibodies early in the
        course of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> exerts a suppressive effect, whereas
        anti-IFN-Î³ treatment late in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease enhances arthritis</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> ] . Also, disease severity in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> is enhanced in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, and loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> receptor
        turns <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> normally resistant to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> into an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX>-susceptible strain [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ thus
        provides a dominant protective effect in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. The reduction
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> is consistent with the
        disease-limiting properties of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX> These results suggest
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> plays an unexpected role in regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        production in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>.
        Recent work by Matthys 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . demonstrates that the
        protective effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ is dependent on the presence of
        the mycobacterial component of the adjuvant [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . Only
        when <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> are immunized with collagen in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFA</ENAMEX> is there an
        increase in disease severity in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IFN-Î³ receptor</ENAMEX>-deficient
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Ablation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> is associated with
        extramedullary hemopoiesis and expansion of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +cells.
        Consistent with this observation, a similar increase in
        CD11b +cells was observed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. These data
        suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> controls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ concentration 
        in vivo and that the reduced level of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> contributes to expansion of CD11b
        +cells and increase in disease severity. The increase in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX> we observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> may account for the
        increase in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> +cells as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX> is known for its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hematopoietic</ENAMEX> properties [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX> ] .
        In addition to the cellular immune response,
        anticollagen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> are required for the development of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. In the studies presented, despite the increase
        in disease severity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10 -/-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, anticollagen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> are reduced. This reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> levels
        may be a direct effect on B cells due to a loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> or
        may be an indirect effect due to downregulation by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX>
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> cytokine IFN-Î³ is important 
        in vitro and 
        in vivo for enhancement of IgG 
        2a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretion</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] . It is expected
        that loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ should result in a reduced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collagen</ENAMEX>-specific IgG 
        2a response, but it is unexpected that
        the IgG 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> response would also be reduced. These
        results indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> has a direct effect on
        maintaining <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> production in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. In addition, loss
        of the anti-inflammatory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> appears to
        overdrive the requirements for high levels of anticollagen
        antibodies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        In summary, these results suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> is an
        important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> of inflammation 
        in vivo . In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, a deficiency in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> leads to an increase in disease severity. The
        corresponding reduction in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ levels and the expansion
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX>+ cells suggests a potential mechanism for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFA</ENAMEX> = complete <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freund</ENAMEX>'s adjuvant; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> = collagen-induced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis; ELISA</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">enzyme</NUMEX>-linked immunosorbent assay; FACS
        = fluorescence-activated cell sorting; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> = fluorescein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isothiocyanate; H & E</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hematoxylin</ENAMEX> and eosin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon; IL</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interleukin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> = major
        histocompatibility <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> = polymerase chain
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reaction; Th</ENAMEX> cells = T helper cells; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± = tumor necrosis
        factor alpha; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WT</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">DBA/1</NUMEX> wildtype.
      
    
  
