
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Osteoclasts are large, multinucleated bone-resorbing
        cells derived from the monocyte-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">macrophage</ENAMEX> lineage [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] .
        Their bone-resorbing capacity is unique; no other cell
        shares this capability. Osteoclasts are critical for both
        the continuous remodeling of normal bone tissue as well as
        the repair of fractured bones [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . During normal bone
        remodeling, osteoclast-mediated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone resorption</ENAMEX> is balanced
        by osteoblast-mediated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX> formation, resulting in the
        maintenance of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">skeletal bone mass.</ENAMEX> As a consequence,
        osteoclast dysregulation leads to osteoporosis (decreased
        bone mass caused by excess osteoclast activity) or to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteopetrosis</ENAMEX> (increased bone mass caused by insufficient
        osteoclast activity). Considering the tremendous morbidity
        and cost of metabolic bone diseases [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , improving our
        molecular understanding of osteoclast development and
        function is critical towards the design of therapies to
        combat these prevalent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>.
        The molecular signals required for osteoclastogenesis
        have recently been elucidated [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 4 5</NUMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Receptor-activator of NFÎºB</ENAMEX> ligand (RANKL), a tumor necrosis
        factor superfamily ligand expressed by stromal cells,
        osteoblasts, and activated T cells, binds to its cognate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor-activator of NFÎºB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANK</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">macrophages/monocytes</ENAMEX>, inducing a signal that gradually
        transforms the macrophages into osteoclasts over a period
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] . While this interaction occurs
        largely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone microenvironment</ENAMEX>, it has been shown
        that monocytes from the spleen, peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, and
        synovium are all capable of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX>-dependent osteoclast
        formation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . Convincing evidence has been generated
        indicating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANK-RANKL</ENAMEX> interaction is absolutely
        required for osteoclastogenesis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] ; in the absence of
        these molecules, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">osteoclastogenesis</ENAMEX> cannot occur [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ]
        .
        While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANK-RANKL</ENAMEX> signal is absolutely required for
        osteoclastogenesis, the efficiency of this process is
        influenced by cytokines. The proinflammatory cytokines
        tumor necrosis factor alpha, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> augment
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoclastogenesis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10 11</ENAMEX> ] , while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-10</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-12</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-18</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ antagonize osteoclastogenesis 
        in vitro [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13 14 15</NUMEX> ] . It is
        probable that cytokines play a vital role in the delicate
        balance of bone remodeling, and that therapies based upon
        their natural biological function can be designed.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cytokine</ENAMEX> secreted primarily by activated T
        cells and NK cells whose role in bone biology is only
        beginning to be clarified. It was originally characterized
        as a powerful macrophage activator that upregulated nitric
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oxide</ENAMEX> (NO) production and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> expression in macrophages [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> ] . It has since been shown to stimulate antiviral and
        antibacterial activities, to differentiate Th0 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> toward
        Th1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fates</ENAMEX>, and to activate endothelial cells for leukocyte
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adhesion</ENAMEX> (reviewed in [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18</NUMEX> ] ).
        With respect to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">osteoclast</ENAMEX> formation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ is known to
        potently inhibit RANKL-mediated osteoclastogenesis in both
        spleen-derived macrophage cultures and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone marrow</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coculture</ENAMEX> systems [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21</NUMEX> ] . It has also been
        demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> defective in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ signaling have a
        more rapid onset of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone resorption</ENAMEX> compared
        with wild-type <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, suggesting a protective role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        in early <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22</NUMEX> ] .
        There are situations, however, in which the
        anti-osteoclastogenic effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ are not so clear.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ is not highly expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> of patients
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> such as erosive
        tuberculoid leprosy [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24</NUMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">psoriatic arthritis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
        ] are associated with high <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Th1</NUMEX> cytokines such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>
        ] . In these conditions, tissue destruction has been shown
        to correlate with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Th1</NUMEX>-mediated immune responses and the
        production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, indicating that osteoclastogenesis may
        occur in the presence of elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
        Furthermore, several clinical studies have failed to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demonstrate efficacy of IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> as an
        anti-osteoclastogenic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> to prevent bone loss [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29 30</NUMEX>
        ] . There seem to be situations in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> does not act
        as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-osteoclastogenic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> has
        been shown to be efficacious in the treatment of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoporosis</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] .
        In the present study, we demonstrate that early exposure
        to RANKL renders osteoclast precursors resistant to the
        effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, including inhibition of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoclastogenesis</ENAMEX>. These effects were irreversible and not
        caused by inhibition of proximal signaling at the level of
        STAT1 or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TRAF6</TIMEX>, suggesting that resistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ is
        caused by a complex differentiation program specifying the
        osteoclast fate. These data may help explain the
        contradictory findings regarding the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ as an
        inhibitor of osteoclastogenesis, and also suggest a model
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">erosive disease</ENAMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ whereby
        osteoclast precursors are exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> before they
        enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-rich environment.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cytokines</ENAMEX> and growth factors
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX>, macrophage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>-stimulating factor,
          tumor necrosis factor alpha, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          GST-mRANKL was generated as described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human RANKL</ENAMEX>
          was a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunex</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and was used to
          verify the efficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GST-RANKL protein</ENAMEX> as verified by
          splenic osteoclast induction.
        
        
          Cell culture and animals
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RAW264.7</ENAMEX> mouse macrophage cell line was obtained
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manassas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and grown in a humidified <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>
          
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> environment at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. Cultures were
          maintained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>) supplemented with
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> penicillin/streptomycin.
          RAW cell osteoclasts were generated by plating exactly
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5000</TIMEX> RAW <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> per well in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well dish with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST-RANKL</ENAMEX> or additional cytokines and culturing for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-5
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. In some cultures, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ was
          delayed to allow for an early effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX>.
          Osteoclasts were large, multinucleated cells, and
          expressed high levels of tartrate-resistant acid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphatase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRAP</ENAMEX>). For western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blots</ENAMEX>, RAW cells were
          grown in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-well dishes at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> cells/well with the
          same cytokine treatments.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CBA/</ENAMEX>BL6 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Labs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bar Harbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) were
          sacrificed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and spleens aseptically removed.
          Splenocytes were mechanically dissociated by disruption
          through steel mesh, and red blood cells were lysed using
          a hypotonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ammonium chloride solution</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82.9</NUMEX> g ammonium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chloride</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 g potassium</NUMEX> bicarbonate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.37</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g EDTA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 l</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterile water</ENAMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10Ã—</NUMEX> solution). The remaining white
          cells were plated in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> cells/well
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml murine macrophage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>-stimulating factor
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>) to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preferentially</ENAMEX> maintain monocyte
          proliferation. Large, multinucleated, TRAP +osteoclasts
          were generated by further addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 ng/ml GST-RANKL</ENAMEX>
          and culturing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-6 days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) was added on
          various days in some cultures.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TRAP staining</ENAMEX> and quantitation
          Cultures were stained with the osteoclast-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marker TRAP</ENAMEX> using a kit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). In
          osteoclast precursors, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> induced increasing TRAP
          expression until virtually <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> of mononuclear cells were
          highly TRAP-positive. Fusion and multinucleation
          subsequently occurred in proportion to the magnitude of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> stimulus.
          Osteoclasts were counted using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> equivalent
          methods, optimized for the extent of osteoclastogenesis.
          For extremely robust osteoclast cultures, manual tracing
          and digital quantitation of a photographed osteoclast
          area was the best measure due to extensive fusion and
          multinucleation between cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Less robust
          cultures with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80-150 osteoclasts</NUMEX> per well were more
          accurately quantitated by counting individual osteoclasts
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). For cultures utilizing lower levels of RANKL
          and low osteoclast numbers, densitometric quantitation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRAP</ENAMEX> was a more sensitive measure of osteoclastogenesis
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2d).
        
        
          Purification of GST-RANKL
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST-RANKL</ENAMEX> was purified as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ]
          . Briefly, a fragment of murine RANKL cDNA was cloned
          inframe into the pGEX-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4T</NUMEX> vector (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Pharmacia</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BL21 bacteria</ENAMEX> (Amersham
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>) induced with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IPTG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 hours</TIMEX>
          at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30Â°C</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacteria</ENAMEX> were lysed, and soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> were
          recovered using glutathione-agarose beads (Amersham
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmacia</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein purity</ENAMEX> was assessed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coomassie Blue</ENAMEX> by comparison with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99%</NUMEX> pure BSA standards
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and shown to of equivalent purity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a). The
          bioactivity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST-RANKL</ENAMEX> was verified by RAW cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoclastogenesis</ENAMEX> and TRAP expression before
          experimental use. A dose of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST-RANKL</ENAMEX> had
          equivalent bioactivity to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml eukaryotically
          expressed human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RANKL protein</ENAMEX> (donated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immunex</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          NO measurement
          NO production was measured by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Greiss</ENAMEX> reaction
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), which spectrophotometrically
          detects nitrite, a stable breakdown product of NO whose
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> reflects NO production. RAW cells were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plated</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates, and were stimulated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GST-RANKL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 ng/ml</ENAMEX>) and/or IFN-Î³ (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 ng/ml</ENAMEX>). Cell
          supernatants were harvested and reacted with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sulfanilamide</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> naphthyl-ethylenediamine. A
          standard curve was constructed using dilutions of sodium
          nitrite, and the absorbance was measured at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX> nm.
          Similar data were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-normalized data
          to control for variation in cell number or
          proliferation.
        
        
          Western blotting
          Cells were lysed with hypotonic lysis buffer with
          protease <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche/Boehringer Mannheim</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirty</ENAMEX> micrograms of cytoplasmic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lysates</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼g nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lysates</ENAMEX> were loaded onto <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE gels and immunoblotted using chemiluminescent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. Short exposures of blots were also performed
          to verify that signals shown did not result from blot
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overexposure</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) except anti-actin, which was purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Flow cytometry
          After red blood cell lysis, a single cell suspension
          was incubated with antimurine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD16/32</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) to block <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Fc</ENAMEX> receptor-mediated antibody
          binding. Cells were then labeled with
          phycoerythrin-conjugated anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD11b</NUMEX> antibodies
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen</ENAMEX>) or fluorescein-conjugated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> (a gift from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M Tondravi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Red Cross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were acquired using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACScalibur</ENAMEX> instrument (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckton Dickenson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bedford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and were analyzed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cellquest</ENAMEX> software (version
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beckton Dickenson</ENAMEX>). CD11b expression followed a
          normal-type distribution in all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> indicative of one
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, and the mean fluorescent intensity was thus
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of measure. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANK</ENAMEX> staining indicated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX>, and the relative size of the high RANK
          expressing (RANKhi) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> was thus expressed on a
          percentage basis.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ potently and irreversibly inhibits
          RANKL-induced osteoclastogenesis
          To evaluate the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ on
          osteoclastogenesis, we utilized the mouse macrophage cell
          line RAW264<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX> (RAW <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX>) or splenic macrophages from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">CBA/</ENAMEX>BL6 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> as osteoclast precursors. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> have
          been demonstrated to recapitulate critical aspects of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">osteoclast</ENAMEX> formation and activity, including bone
          resorption, expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">calcitonin</ENAMEX> receptor,
          multinuclear fusion, and TRAP expression [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 34</ENAMEX> ] .
          A dose of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> generated numerous large,
          multinucleated osteoclasts. Lower doses induced the
          osteoclast-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marker TRAP</ENAMEX> in mononuclear cells but
          generated substantially fewer osteoclasts (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1a,1b). A
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ was sufficient to potently and
          irreversibly inhibit osteoclastogenesis in the presence
          of maximal doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The exposure also
          induced a stellate cellular morphology consistent with
          that of an activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">macrophage</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). The rapid and
          irreversible effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ on osteoclast inhibition
          indicate a dominant effect of this cytokine over RANKL
          via induction of monocyte differentiation toward the
          activated macrophage fate, as opposed to the osteoclast
          fate, when concomitantly administered.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RANKL-pretreated RAW cells</ENAMEX> are resistant to the
          anti-osteoclastogenic effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
          The different kinetics between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-mediated
          macrophage activation (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME"><24 hours</TIMEX>) and RANKL-medicated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoclastogenesis</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-5 days</TIMEX>) prompted us to investigate
          the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ on RANKL-pretreated cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
          Pretreatment of RAW cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX>
          rendered them resistant to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³; these mononuclear cells
          formed multinuclear osteoclasts despite the presence of
          maximally inhibitory doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 ng/ml</ENAMEX>).
          To characterize this RANKL-mediated resistance to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, we performed a series of dose-response and time
          course experiments. Pretreatment with lower doses of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> was unable to overcome IFN-Î³ inhibition, indicating
          that resistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ required high levels of RANKL
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretreatment</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4a,4b). The duration of RANKL
          pretreatment was also important; the longer the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretreatment</ENAMEX> phase, the greater the resistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4c). Together these data show that pretreatment
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> increases resistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-mediated
          osteoclast inhibition in a dose-dependent and
          time-dependent manner.
          The mechanism by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> reciprocally
          inhibit each other in pre-osteoclasts is independent of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TRAF-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STAT1</ENAMEX> signal transduction. Since it is well
          established that RANK signaling is mediated primarily
          through <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TRAF6</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ signaling is mediated
          primarily through <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">STAT1</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36 37</NUMEX> ] , we examined their
          expression by western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blot</ENAMEX>. We failed to observe
          significant degradation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TRAF6</TIMEX> after stimulation with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ or RANKL in short-term or long-term cultures (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          5a,5b).
          Interestingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">STAT1 phosphorylation</ENAMEX> and
          nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">translocation</ENAMEX> was retained in pre-osteoclasts
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5c). This result was confirmed by electrophoretic
          mobility shift assays and the absence of detectable
          amounts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STAT1 antagonists SOCS1</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SOCS3</TIMEX> (data
          not shown). These results show that late pre-osteoclasts
          are capable of signaling via <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">JAK-STAT1</ENAMEX>, and suggest that
          signaling events distal to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TRAF6 and STAT1</TIMEX> modulate the
          resistance of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> pretreatment inhibits IFN-Î³-induced
          macrophage activation
          We next investigated whether other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ effects
          besides osteoclast inhibition were blunted in
          RANKL-pretreated cells. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-induced NO production in
          macrophages was blunted in osteoclasts, probably due to
          specialization for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone resorption</ENAMEX> in the latter
          differentiated cell (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). Pretreatment with RANKL
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibited IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-induced NO production in a dose-dependent
          and time-dependent manner (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6b,6c).
          To expand these findings, we investigated the
          regulation of the cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">markers CD11b</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANK</ENAMEX> in
          response to induction by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>). Both
          markers were strongly upregulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX> Consistent
          with our prior results, concomitant treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> showed dominance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ upregulation,
          while pretreatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> showed impaired
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upregulation</ENAMEX>. These data support the hypothesis that
          sensitivity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ decreases with increasing osteoclast
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> and that the mechanism by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ reciprocally inhibit each other in pre-osteoclasts
          is mediating the irreversible commitment into the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoclast</ENAMEX> or activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">macrophage lineages</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The role of cellular immunity (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Th1</NUMEX>) in inflammatory bone
        loss such as that seen in osteomyelitis and erosive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> remains unclear. The resolution of this issue is
        further clouded by the apparent contradictory findings that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ is an extremely potent anti-osteoclastogenic factor [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> ] but it can be found at high levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteolysis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX> ] . To reconcile this controversy we
        performed a series of experiments aimed at understanding
        how IFN-Î³ could induce either bactericidal effects via
        macrophage activation or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">osteoclastic bone resorption</ENAMEX>, by
        influencing the same progenitor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in the same bone
        environment.
        We demonstrate that pre-osteoclasts stimulated with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> are rendered resistant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        induced inhibition of osteoclastogenesis, NO production,
        and upregulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CD11b</ENAMEX> and RANK surface expression.
        Surprisingly, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> is not mediated by inhibition
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">JAK-STAT1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STAT1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">phosphorylation</ENAMEX>, nuclear
        translocation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-binding capabilities are all
        preserved in the late pre-osteoclast. Together this
        evidence suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> modifies IFN-Î³ effects
        downstream of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">STAT1</TIMEX>.
        The present results predict that timing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        exposure will be an important determinant of its biological
        function during 
        in vivo osteoclastogenesis. In the
        case of circulating or peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">macrophages</ENAMEX> that have not
        encountered osteoclastogenic quantities of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        rapidly induces macrophage activation and subsequent NO
        production, recruiting these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> for immune responses.
        The dominance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX>, which we observed 
        in vitro (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 ng IFN-Î³ counteracts 200</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ng RANKL</ENAMEX> when simultaneously administered), probably allows
        this macrophage activation to occur even in the presence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> expressed on circulating, activated T cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 40</NUMEX> ]
        . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone microenvironment</ENAMEX>, however, more abundant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">osteoblasts</ENAMEX>/stromal cells may influence
        certain monocytes to commit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">osteoclast</ENAMEX> lineage [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> ] .
        The present results predict that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ will not activate
        these cells, as they have received an early RANKL signal.
        The strength of the early RANKL signal may be altered in
        the setting of inflammatory bone diseases such as
        rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, in which high levels of RANKL
        expressed on either synovial cells or infiltrating T cells
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43 44</NUMEX> ] may induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">osteoclast</ENAMEX> formation despite the
        presence of exogenous or endogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX>
        The potency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ as a macrophage activator and
        osteoclast inhibitor suggests a prominent role for T cells
        and/or NK cells in the regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone resorption</ENAMEX>, as
        these cells constitute the major source of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . A
        link between activated T cells and osteoclast inhibition by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> has been highlighted in a report by Takayanagi 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al .</ENAMEX>, providing the first 
        in vivo evidence that the immune
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> may influence osteoclastogenesis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] .
        Interestingly, other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have demonstrated that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activated T</ENAMEX> cells induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">osteoclastogenesis</ENAMEX> via
        upregulation of surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RANKL</ENAMEX>, presenting a dilemma
        regarding the role of activated T cells in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoclastogenesis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 40 45</NUMEX> ] .
        It is possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ expression by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activated T</ENAMEX> cells may be a major mechanism by which T cells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> the fate of osteoclasts, and that relative
        expression of both molecules will dictate whether
        osteoclasts are induced or inhibited. The present results
        suggest that the influence of activated T cells on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoclasts</ENAMEX> will probably change depending on when and
        where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> cells encounter the osteoclasts. Bone-resident
        macrophages pre-exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> in the stromal environment
        may be resistant to the immunoregulatory effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³,
        and may thus be better suited for bone-remodeling tasks. In
        contrast, peripheral blood macrophages not exposed to RANKL
        may be more responsive to the macrophage-activating
        immunoregulatory effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³, and may thus be better
        suited for antimicrobial activities.
        effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> remain elusive. Based on the
        phenotype of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">knockout mice</ENAMEX>, it has become clear that TRAF6
        is the critical adapter molecule required for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANK</ENAMEX>
        signaling during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">osteoclastogenesis</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . The importance
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TRAF6</ENAMEX> has been further explored in deletion studies,
        which correlated its various domains with its
        osteoclastogenic potential [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] . A link between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        and RANK signaling via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRAF6</ENAMEX> has also been demonstrated in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone marrow cultures</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ was shown to
        accelerate the degradation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TRAF6</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] . In our
        studies, however, we failed to observe this TRAF6
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">degradation</ENAMEX>, as its expression remained constant in both
        short-term and long-term cultures under conditions where
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ completely inhibited osteoclastogenesis. While this
        discrepancy could be explained by the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAW</ENAMEX>
        cells represent a stage of pre-osteoclast differentiation
        that is not sensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IFN-Î³-mediated TRAF6 degradation,</ENAMEX>
        the present studies clearly indicate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ can inhibit
        osteoclastogenesis via a completely different
        mechanism.
        The retention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jak-STAT1</ENAMEX> signaling in RANKL-stimulated
        pre-osteoclasts is intriguing, given their demonstrated
        insensitivity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX> Since it is known that osteoclasts
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47 48</NUMEX> ] , it begs the question as
        to why this pathway remains operant. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility is
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-induced <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">STAT1</NUMEX> activation in osteoclasts leads to
        the expression of a unique set of genes that is distinct
        from that in macrophages. Future studies designed to
        understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ signaling in mature osteoclasts are needed
        to resolve this issue.
        It is noteworthy to point out that the
        dominant/irreversible inhibitory effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ on
        osteoclastogenesis are fundamentally different to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">transient/</ENAMEX>reversible inhibitory effects of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-4</TIMEX> on this
        process, which are mediated by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">STAT6</TIMEX> inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activation</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49 50</NUMEX> ] . In the present article, we
        demonstrate that RANKL-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">osteoclastogenesis</ENAMEX> cannot be
        recovered following exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX> In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . have demonstrated that
        pre-osteoclasts do not lose their potential to
        differentiate into mature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">osteoclasts</TIMEX> following a similar
        exposure to IL-4 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> ] . It thus appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        anti-osteoclast activity is mediated by inducing terminal
        differentiation away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">osteoclast</ENAMEX> lineage, while
        IL-4 directly interferes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> signaling during
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">osteoclastogenesis</ENAMEX>. Collectively, these findings are
        consistent with the observations that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Th1 cells</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with erosive disease [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39 50 51</NUMEX> ] , that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³
        does not have antiresorptive activity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52 53 54</NUMEX> ] , and
        that IL-4 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibits bone resorption</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55 56 57</NUMEX> ] .
        The present results underscore the importance of
        developing a complete understanding of osteoclastogenesis 
        in vivo with regard to location,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, and the signal transduction pathways involved. It is
        probable that signals such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ will be interpreted
        differently by precursors at various stages of development,
        with consequent effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. Future studies in this
        area are needed to better understand how T cells producing
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> mediate immunity and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone resorption</ENAMEX>,
        and to better elucidate their role in the pathogenesis of
        diseases such as osteomyelitis and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">erosive arthritis</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        We have demonstrated, using 
        in vitro methods, that osteoclast
        precursors exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-2 days</TIMEX> can be rendered
        resistant to maximal osteoclast-inhibitory doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX>
        These IFN-Î³-resistant pre-osteoclasts produced low levels
        of NO upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³ stimulation and were resistant to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN</ENAMEX>-Î³-induced, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-induced and RANKL-induced surface
        expression, suggesting a broad resistance to the cellular
        effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jak-Stat1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pathway</ENAMEX> was intact in these
        cells, indicating that downstream transcriptional events
        are involved in the inhibition. These results imply a model
        for arthritic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> in which macrophage precursors
        entering an inflamed joint are exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANKL</ENAMEX> and are
        subsequently rendered resistant to the
        anti-osteoclastogenic effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IFN-Î³</ENAMEX> expressed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activated T</ENAMEX> cells in the synovium.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> = bovine serum albumin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fluorescence</NUMEX>-activated cell sorting;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fc</ENAMEX> = crystallizable fragment; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> = fluorescein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">isothiocyanate; IFN</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interferon; IL</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interleukin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> =
        major histocompatibility <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX> = nuclear factor; NO =
        nitric <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxide</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANK</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-activator of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎºB; RANKL</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptor-activator of NFÎºB</ENAMEX> ligand; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Th = T</ENAMEX> helper cells;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRAP</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tartrate</NUMEX>-resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid phosphatase</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
