
  
    
      
        Introduction
        The association between smoking and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) has been widely reported [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21</NUMEX> ] and was recently reviewed [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
        ] . The specific association between smoking and rheumatoid
        factor (RF)-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> is well known and meets the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradford Hill</ENAMEX> criteria for causation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] , namely
        strength, consistency, plausibility, experimental evidence,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coherence</ENAMEX>, temporality, and biologic gradient of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 7 8 16 17 20</NUMEX> ] .
        The term 'interaction' refers to a conditional
        relationship between an independent variable and the
        dependent variable. An interaction exists when the
        relationship between an independent variable 
        x and an outcome variable 
        y varies according to the value of
        another covariate 
        z . The presence of a statistically
        significant interaction would suggest the presence of an
        underlying biologic effect modification and provide
        epidemiologic clues to the etiology and pathogenesis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ]
        .
        Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, hormonal risk factors for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> include age at
        menarche, progestin use [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] , oral contraceptive use [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> ] , termination of pregnancy [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] , lactation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] ,
        and short fertile period [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidemiologic</ENAMEX> studies do
        not consistently show that smoking confers an increased
        risk among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Indeed, even a protective effect of
        smoking on risk for developing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> has been described among
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . The smoking-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> risk is more consistent
        across studies on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Thus, the risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> conferred by
        smoking depends on the sex of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. If reports of
        this interaction effect were confirmed [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] , then this
        would suggest the presence of an underlying sex-specific
        factor that modifies the association between smoking and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Therefore, we conducted a population-based case-control
        study, including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1095</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> identified in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Finland RA Database</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1530</TIMEX> control individuals
        living in the same district.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> and method
        
          Cases and controls
          Cases were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> drawn from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Finland RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Database</ENAMEX>, located at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jyväskylä Central Hospital</ENAMEX>,
          which is the only rheumatology <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District of Finland</ENAMEX> (population <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">263 869</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>). All
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were diagnosed to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Finland RA Database</ENAMEX> includes demographic
          measures, treatments, and outcomes of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1993</TIMEX>. As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, the database contained information on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1763</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1495</TIMEX> of whom were still alive. The control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> was a random sample drawn from the general
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. To obtain a population sample, the names and
          addresses of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central District</ENAMEX>
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> were obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> Statistics
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> (with the permission from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministry of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Affairs and Health</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX>). Statistics of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> obtains the majority of its data from diverse
          administrative registers, and produces <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of all
          Government statistics in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Finland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX>stat.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fi</ENAMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics Committee of Jyväskylä Central Hospital</ENAMEX> approved
          the study.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> collection
          A questionnaire was mailed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1495</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> patients
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. A reminder letter was sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks later</TIMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">non-responders.</ENAMEX> The response rate for questionnaires
          among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate patients</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73%</NUMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> = <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1095</TIMEX>) and that among candidate
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77%</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1530</TIMEX>). Functional status in
          activities of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> living was measured using the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX>
          version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Assessment Questionnaire</ENAMEX> (score
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">range 0-3</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] . Pain and global status were assessed
          on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100-mm</ENAMEX> visual-analog scale (range <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0-100</ENAMEX> from best to
          worst). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> on date of birth, height and weight, sex,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of education, and current and previous smoking
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">habits</ENAMEX> (never/ever) were collected. In addition, clinical
          features of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were obtained from the database.
          Seropositivity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ig-M</ENAMEX>) was defined according to
          laboratory references (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">>30 kU/l</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of us (TS)
          assessed radiographs of hands and feet according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larsen</ENAMEX> method, and the presence or absence of radiologic
          erosions was recorded as a dichotomous variable.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were analyzed in two stages. The initial stage
          was to test the hypothesis that there is a primary
          interaction between sex and smoking. This was performed
          by including a pair-wise product term (i.e. smoking×sex)
          in addition to the individual variables in a logistic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regression</ENAMEX> model in which the dependent variable was case
          versus control status. The 
          P value calculated for the
          interaction term in the logistic regression model was
          used to determine statistical significance. If this
          showed the presence of a statistically significant
          interaction, then a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> stage of analyses was
          performed. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> stage, parallel case-control
          analyses were performed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> using
          multivariable logistic regression. The independent
          variables in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> were age, education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> mass
          index, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Assessment Questionnaire</ENAMEX> disability index,
          self-reports of pain and overall health assessments, as
          well as a smoking variable. The last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">covariates</ENAMEX> were
          included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> because these can potentially
          confound the smoking-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> relationship. Separate regression
          analyses were performed to assess the effect of both the
          smoking variables (current smoking and past smoking) on
          the risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Forward or backward stepwise selections
          were not used, and all clinically important covariates
          were included in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the multivariable</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>. We performed
          Student's 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> -test to compare differences in
          mean values and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pearson's χ 2test</ENAMEX> to compare differences
          in proportions. Analyses were performed using STATA
          ®Version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX> software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stata Corporation</ENAMEX>, College
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Station</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Results
        The mean age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62 years</TIMEX> (range <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19-96</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX> were female; the mean age of control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55 years</TIMEX> (range <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-91 years</TIMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72%</NUMEX> were
        female. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, the mean disease duration was
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11.3 years</TIMEX> (range <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>-47 years), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68.6%</NUMEX> were RF-positive,
        and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> had erosions in their hand or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> radiographs.
        proportion of seropositivity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX>; 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.29</NUMEX>), frequency of erosive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60.3%</NUMEX>; 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.84</NUMEX>), or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> duration (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11.7</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> versus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10.5 years</TIMEX>; 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.06</NUMEX>) between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        In preliminary logistic regression analyses in which any
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> was the dependent variable of interest, sex exhibited a
        statistically significant interaction with current/past
        smoking (all 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>). Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> there was
        significant interaction between age and past smoking ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>) but not with current
        smoking ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.13</NUMEX>). Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> there were no
        statistically significant interactions between age and
        current smoking ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.12</NUMEX>) and age and past smoking ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.97</NUMEX>). Subsequent analyses were
        performed separately for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1shows</ENAMEX> comparisons between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> by sex. Among both sexes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were older,
        less well educated, more disabled, and reported poorer
        general health and increased functional disability and pain
        in comparison with control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. Female patients
        were less likely to report past or current smoking than
        were female control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, there was no
        statistically significant difference in the proportion of
        current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>,
        but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were more likely to have smoked in the past
        than were control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the multivariable</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, we adjusted for age, body
        mass index, level of education and indices of functional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disability</ENAMEX>, pain, and general health. Parallel analyses
        looking at the effect of smoking on the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> were
        performed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subgroups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> defined by presence or
        absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> as well as all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> (Tables 2and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        Multivariable analyses for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>) showed that
        there was no significant association between current or
        past smoking and RF-positive or RF-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Although
        not statistically significant, the magnitude of risk was
        consistently <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 1.0</NUMEX> in both RF-positive and
        RF-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>), past smoking was consistently
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with RF-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> (odds ratio <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>
        confidence interval <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.9</NUMEX>). Neither current nor past
        smoking was associated with RF-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Overall, past
        smoking (odds ratio <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> confidence interval <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.2</NUMEX>)
        but not current smoking (odds ratio <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> confidence
        interval <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.7</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX>) was associated with increased risk for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Discussion
        In the present study we confirmed the earlier
        observation that smoking is a risk factor for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but
        not in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1 17</ENAMEX> ] . In addition, we statistically
        tested and confirmed the interaction between smoking and
        sex, thereby providing evidence in support of a biologic
        interaction between smoking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        Smoking is known to be associated with production of RF
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6 16 20</ENAMEX> ] ; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> production, in turn, often precedes the
        development of clinical disease [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 16</NUMEX> ] . Furthermore, it
        appears to be independent of HLA-DR restricted immune
        response [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . In our study, we found that this paradigm
        held well for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Why could it be? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
        the explanations for this could be that the immunologic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cascade</ENAMEX> triggered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">smoking</ENAMEX> and leading to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> production
        and subsequently to clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> is modulated differently in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. The most obvious biologic difference
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is the hormonal milieu, although
        other sex-specific factors cannot be ruled out. In our
        analyses we found a significant age-smoking interaction
        among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> - an observation that is not inconsistent with
        this hypothesis.
        Although we were not able to test this hypothesis
        directly in our data (because the relevant reproductive
        variables were not available), a review of the literature
        gives some clues. In studies conducted in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>-only
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cohorts</ENAMEX>, the presence of association between smoking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        appeared to be dependent on menopausal status of study
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. In a population-based study conducted in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, which examined postmenopausal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> only, a
        dose-dependent effect of smoking was evident (relative risk
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> for current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> versus never smokers <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.0</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ]
        . On the other hand, data from the prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nurses</ENAMEX>
        Health Study [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] , which examined all (primarily
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">menstruating</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-55 years</TIMEX>, did not show a
        past smoking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Health</ENAMEX>
        Cohort Study [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] , the effect size of smoking was
        relatively modest (relative risk <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.39 and 1.49</NUMEX> for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        and RF-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, respectively) as compared with that in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> study. Interpreting our findings of an interaction
        between smoking and sex in the light of published data, we
        propose that being a menstruating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> acts as a biologic
        effect modifier that blocks the smoking-RF-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> pathway. We
        did not have the information on menopausal status to test
        this hypothesis directly. Instead, we conducted multiple
        pair-wise interaction tests between age and smoking for men
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> separately. Interestingly, we found that there
        was a significant age-smoking interaction among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but
        not among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. This smoking-sex effect modification
        paradigm we propose not only might explain a lack of
        increased risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women smokers</ENAMEX>, but also
        provides a theoretical basis for the observation that
        smoking reduces the risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] .
        There are several areas of substantial strength in the
        present study. First, the study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were drawn
        from a population-based register of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (i.e. a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rheumatology</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> in which all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> living in
        the particular referral area are followed) and the control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were drawn from the same, geographically
        well-defined general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, the participation
        rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were good.
        Validated diagnoses and exposures were used. The smoking
        histories were also validated using hospital medical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>, by comparing the questionnaire response with the
        information from the standard clinical history and physical
        examination. Finally, the numerical strength of this study
        provided sufficient statistical power to quantitate the
        risk of smoking on RF-positive and RF-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        separately.
        The potential limitations of the study also must be
        addressed. By design, the study was an unmatched
        case-control study. The control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were younger
        than the cases. Many control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were younger than
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>. This may lead to arguments that control
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> were not old enough to have developed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and
        that an age-matched design would have been more
        appropriate. However, such a bias does not explain our
        observations as the age differential was found in both men
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. In addition to performing tests of interaction
        between age and smoking, we adjusted for the effect of age
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">multivariable</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>. To address the concern that
        successive birth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> are associated with lower
        prevalence rates of smoking and leading to bias in our
        findings, analyses were repeated, adjusting for the effect
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">calendar year</TIMEX> of birth. We found that the results were
        essentially the same. We believe that matching by age would
        have been, overall, disadvantageous to the study because
        such an approach would not allow us to study important
        interactions between age and other covariates.
        Unfortunately, data on the temporal sequence of smoking and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, as well as on any dose-response <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>, were not
        available and could not be analyzed.
        The differences in the risk estimates for current
        smoking and past smoking may appear counter-intuitive. The
        explanation lies in the case-control design of the study.
        Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">smoking</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> can independently increase the risk for
        mortality; the potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who are also continuing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> are more likely to have died than are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> in
        the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, thus never entering the study [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>
        ] . This differential mortality could have resulted in an
        underestimation of the association between current smoking
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. However, it is unlikely that there is a difference
        in smoking-related mortality between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of such
        a magnitude as to cause the observed sex differential.
        Another equally plausible explanation would be that the
        diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> might have led to lifestyle changes,
        leading to cessation of smoking. However, there is little
        evidence to suggest that onset of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> would affect smoking
        behavior in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in a different manner (i.e. there
        is no published literature or rationale for supposing that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> tend to take up or quit smoking differently
        when they develop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>).
      
      
        Conclusion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> presented in this report suggest that factors
        related to the sex of an individual modify the effect of
        smoking on the risk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidemiologic</ENAMEX> studies that do
        not explore and account for the significant smoking-sex
        interaction are likely to show inaccurate and even biased
        estimates of the association between smoking and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Our
        smoking, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, and, in addition, their effect modification by
        sex-related factors like menopause.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> = rheumatoid factor.
      
    
  
