
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Although juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX> (JRA) is the most
        common cause of disability in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, its etiology is
        unknown. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immune</ENAMEX> dysregulation appears to play a key
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathogenic</ENAMEX> role, as circulating autoantibodies are common
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with certain JRA clinical subtypes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4 5</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6 7</NUMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> recent studies have shown a highly significant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> between early-onset pauciarticular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JRA</ENAMEX> and
        circulating antibodies to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>-kDa nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein DEK</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] . Although circulating DEK <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> have
        subsequently been found in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> with other
        autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX> ] , these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> studies did
        reveal that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JRA</ENAMEX> are significantly more likely
        to have anti-DEK <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> than are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> without
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatic disease</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> with pauciarticular-onset JRA
        were also significantly more likely to have anti-DEK
        antibodies than were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with polyarticular-onset or
        systemic-onset <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JRA</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatic diseases</ENAMEX>. Among
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with pauciarticular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JRA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> autoantibodies were
        significantly more common in those with JRA-associated
        uveitis than in those without eye <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 9</NUMEX> ] . DEK
        reactivity was also found to be strongly associated with
        onset of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JRA</ENAMEX> subtype before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 6 years</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> is a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that is not structurally
        related to any known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] .
        Although it may also participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
        processing [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 15</NUMEX> ] , we have identified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA-binding protein</ENAMEX> that recognizes the TG-rich peri- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ets</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>) regulatory element in the
        human immunodeficiency virus type 2 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV-2</ENAMEX>) enhancer [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ]
        . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> site is important in mediating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> enhancer
        stimulation in activated T cells and monocytes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18 19</NUMEX> ]
        , suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> may play an immunomodulatory role as
        it participates in transcriptional activation through this
        and related <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>.
        Observed sequence similarity between the DEK-binding
        site in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV-2</ENAMEX> and the highly conserved <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box regulatory
        element in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> II gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> pointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box
        as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> possible related site. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Y binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> class
        II gene <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box anchors a complex assembly of nuclear
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that occupies several regulatory elements over a
        great distance [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21 22</NUMEX> ] . In the 
        DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y</ENAMEX> box, a reverse CCAAT
        motif with a partially overlapping TG-rich sequence shares
        sequence identity with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV-2</ENAMEX> DEK-binding site at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). In the 
        DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> allele, which is highly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with predisposition to autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25 26 27</NUMEX> ] , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box contains a single-nucleotide
        polymorphism that reduces sequence identity to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        positions. We hypothesized that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> could bind in a
        sequence-specific manner to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box motifs in the
        promoter regions of several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> II MHC <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, and that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>- and allele-specific <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box polymorphisms could affect
        DEK binding activity. In this study, we examine the
        characteristics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequences of 
        DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">DQA1*</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DQB</ENAMEX> , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRB</ENAMEX> . We also confirm participation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Y in the 
        DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box binding complex and
        localize specific DEK binding within this sequence. As the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box promoter element is crucial to the regulation of MHC
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">class</ENAMEX> II gene expression, sequence-specific binding to this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motif</ENAMEX> indicates a potential role for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> in modulating
        normal and abnormal immune response.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Cell culture and preparation of nuclear
          extracts
          Cultured cell lines were grown and harvested and
          nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">extracts</ENAMEX> were prepared from resting cells as
          previously described [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] .
        
        
          Preparation of partially purified recombinant DEK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">protein</ENAMEX>
          Construction of the poly-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">histidine</NUMEX>-tagged DEK
          bacterial expression vector is described elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ]
          . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Full-length DEK</ENAMEX> or antisense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> was prepared from
          cultures grown from individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> to log phase,
          induced with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mm isopropyl thiogalactose, and harvested
          by centrifugation after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Recombinant protein</ENAMEX> was
          purified from bacterial lysates in accordance with the
          published method for the QIA 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valencia</ENAMEX>,
          CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) with variations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffers B</ENAMEX> and D as noted in
          Additional file: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>. Procedures were carried out at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>;
          dialyzed recombinant DEK <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (rDEK) was stored at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-80Â°C.</ENAMEX>
          Additional file 1
          
          Buffer B (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6 M urea</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M NaH</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 PO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tris-l</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M KCl</ENAMEX>), used for
          cell lysis and protein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">elution</ENAMEX>, was prepared with the
          addition of imidazole (final concentration <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 mm</NUMEX>) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">urea</ENAMEX> (final concentration <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>). Qiagen
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ni-NTA Superflow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">resin</ENAMEX> was equilibrated with modified
          buffer B before being combined with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell lysate</ENAMEX>. The
          cell lysate-resin combination was incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1.5 hours</TIMEX>. Purified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was eluted from the column
          with buffer B containing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">100-250</ENAMEX> mm imidazole. The
          presence and size of rDEK bands were verified by western
          blotting. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein</ENAMEX> in positive elution fractions was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">refolded</ENAMEX> to native <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> by serial dialysis against
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer D</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 mm HEPES</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M KCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> mm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mm
          dithiothreitol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mm phenylmethylsulfonyl <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glycerol</ENAMEX>) containing stepwise decreasing concentrations
          of urea (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6 M</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4 M</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 M</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, no urea for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX>).
          Click here for file
        
        
          Preparation of FLAG-DEK
          A FLAG-tagged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> adenoviral vector constructed by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan Vector Core</ENAMEX> was used to transduce
          T98G <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (ATCC) by incubation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> before
          harvesting for immunoprecipitation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FLAG-DEK</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunoprecipitated</ENAMEX> using anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FLAG resin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma-Aldrich,</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          instructions and was eluted by competition with peptide
          containing three FLAG recognition epitopes.
        
        
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSAs</ENAMEX>)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSAs</ENAMEX> were carried out as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ]
          , using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.25</NUMEX> ng of radiolabeled oligonucleotide probe
          (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Ã— 10 4counts</NUMEX> per minute) per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15 Î</NUMEX>¼l binding reaction
          and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼g</NUMEX> of nuclear extract (except as noted) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><1</NUMEX> Î¼g
          of rDEK. For competition EMSAs, unlabeled double-stranded
          oligonucleotide was added to reaction mixtures before the
          radiolabeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> supershift of binding
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complexes</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼l anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-YA antibody</ENAMEX> (gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JP-Y Ting</ENAMEX>)
          or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼l</NUMEX> high-titer anti-DEK human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serum</ENAMEX> (gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W Szer</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> ] ) or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-3 Î</ENAMEX>¼l control human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">serum</ENAMEX> was added to the
          binding reaction, and the mixture was incubated on ice
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> before the probe was added.
        
        
          Sequence of oligonucleotide probes and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>
          See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
        
        
          Measurement of apparent dissociation constants
          using EMSA
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 32P end</TIMEX>-labeled oligonucleide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 nM</NUMEX>) was
          incubated with immunoprecipitation-purified FLAG-rDEK in
          a range of concentrations from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one tenth</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times the
          estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          d[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">app</ENAMEX>] (apparent dissociation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">constant</ENAMEX>) as described elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein</ENAMEX>-bound
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was separated from free probe as for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSA</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Ã— TBE
          (Tris-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">borate</NUMEX>-EDTA buffer: Tris 89 mM, borate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX> mM, EDTA
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 mM</TIMEX>). The dried gel was exposed to a phosphor screen
          overnight, and the bands were quantified using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Molecular Dynamics Storm 840 Phosphorimager</ENAMEX> with
          Image-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quant Software</ENAMEX>. The data were fit via nonlinear
          least-squares regression to the single-site binding
          isotherm:
          % free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          d[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">app</ENAMEX>] /(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          d[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">app</ENAMEX>] + [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>]).
          From this equation, the apparent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          d corresponds to the protein
          concentration at which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> is bound [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ]
          .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">DNAse I</ENAMEX> protection assay
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">148-bp</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> included 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> promoter sequence from
          -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-200</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> primer (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 ng</NUMEX>) for probe sequence was
          end-labeled with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32PÎ³</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T4</ENAMEX> polynucleotide kinase
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Biolabs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), and was column
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purified</ENAMEX>. Labeled antisense primer (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">200 ng</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> ng
          unlabeled sense strand primer (or vice versa) were used
          in each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50.5-Î</NUMEX>¼l <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reaction, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> mM dNTP, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM
          MgCl 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 , 5 Î¼l</ENAMEX> 10X <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR Buffer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼g Namalwa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genomic DNA</ENAMEX>. 
          Taq polymerase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) was
          added at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80Â°C</TIMEX> after a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">94Â°C</NUMEX> 'hot start,' initiating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>
          cycles of PCR: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">94Â°C</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> s, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> s, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">72Â°C</ENAMEX> for
          90 s, with final extension at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min. PCR
          products were purified with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Pure PCR Product</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purification Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roche Applied Science</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>,
          IN, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and then used at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.5 Ã— 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4CPM/2 Î¼l</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase I</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digestion</ENAMEX> reaction and footprinting gel followed
          published techniques [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box binding activity in nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">extracts</ENAMEX> is gene-
          and allele-specific
          The similarity of the 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV-2</ENAMEX> DEK-binding site (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> led us to
          investigate whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> in nuclear extracts binds to MHC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">class II Y</ENAMEX>-box regulatory elements 
          in vitro . With a double-stranded
          oligonucleotide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> containing the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1</ENAMEX>*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence, EMSAs
          revealed similar binding activity in nuclear extracts
          from B lymphoid (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Namalwa</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> lymphoid (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jurkat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEM</ENAMEX>),
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monocytoid</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">U937</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HeLa</ENAMEX> cell lines (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), and in
          nuclear extracts from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SKW 6.4</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B</ENAMEX> lymphoid), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KG-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphoid</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HL-60</ENAMEX> (monocytoid) cell lines (not shown).
          Electrophoretic patterns with a probe corresponding to
          the 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence, which
          diverges from the 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence by a
          single base <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> within the highly conserved reverse
          CCAAT sequence, appear to vary with the cell type, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> appears weaker than with the 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
          Competition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSAs</ENAMEX> demonstrated sequence-specificity of
          the 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box binding activity
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3a). Unlabeled 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> oligonucleotides
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">successfully</ENAMEX> competed for strong binding activity seen in
          nuclear extracts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Namalwa</ENAMEX> B cell line (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3a,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">lanes 3</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), whereas unlabeled 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence competed
          less well (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3a, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 and 6</TIMEX>). There was no
          competition when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box reverse CCAAT motif was
          mutated at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3a, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 and 8</TIMEX>),
          nor with the unrelated HIV-1 ÎºB sequence (lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>). DEK
          has been shown to bind to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> site [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] ,
          but oligonucleotides containing this sequence also failed
          to compete significantly (lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>), suggesting that
          factors other than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> play a role in determining the
          specificity of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Y is the
          predominant nuclear factor binding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] ,
          and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> site does not contain the reverse
          CCAAT sequence required for NF-Y binding.
          The consensus ( 
          HLA-DRA ) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box sequence differs
          from the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1</ENAMEX>*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box by a single
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nucleotide</ENAMEX> immediately 5' of the reverse CCAAT pentamer;
          this single-nucleotide polymorphism significantly changes
          the electrophoretic pattern (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3b) in comparison with
          that seen with the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1*0101</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1</ENAMEX>*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> oligonucleotide also
          competes poorly with the consensus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3b, lanes <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5-6</ENAMEX>). Divergence of the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1</ENAMEX>*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
          position within the required <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">NF</ENAMEX>-Y binding site reduces
          its ability to compete with the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRA Y</ENAMEX>-box probe (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3b, lanes
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7-8</ENAMEX>) as much as does mutation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> nucleotides
          within the CCAAT sequence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3b, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9-10</TIMEX>).
        
        
          Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-Y</ENAMEX> participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1Y</ENAMEX>-box
          binding complex
          Participation of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Y in the 
          DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was
          confirmed by using high-titer anti-DEK antiserum (gift of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W Szer</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] ) and monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-YA</ENAMEX>
          subunit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box binding factor (gift of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JP-Y Ting</ENAMEX>)
          to further retard the mobility of the 
          DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box binding complex
          ('supershifting') (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, lanes 3-4</ENAMEX>). Preincubation of
          Namalwa cell nuclear extracts with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-YA</ENAMEX>
          also retards the binding complex (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, lane 5</ENAMEX>),
          leaving a residual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arrow</ENAMEX>) which can be attributed
          to distinct DEK binding activity. Preincubation with both
          antibodies results in further <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX> of the binding
          complex to form a doublet (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4, lane 6</ENAMEX>). The same
          electrophoretic patterns were seen after preincubation of
          nuclear extracts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEM T</ENAMEX> lymphocytoid cell line
          with anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NF-YA antibodies</ENAMEX> (data not
          shown).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recombinant DEK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein binds</ENAMEX> in a
          sequence-specific manner to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">DQA1Y</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> but not to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRA</ENAMEX>(consensus) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX> box
          Having established that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Y in nuclear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extracts</ENAMEX> participate in the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1</ENAMEX>*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> binding complex, we
          used recombinant full-length <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> (rDEK) to determine
          whether it alone can bind to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box motifs and to examine
          how gene- and allele-specific sequence polymorphisms
          alter its binding. The 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1</ENAMEX>*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence does
          bind <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rDEK</ENAMEX> specifically, with unlabeled probe sequence
          competing successfully for binding (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5a, lanes <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-6</ENAMEX>).
          In contrast, despite its identity at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> positions,
          unlabeled consensus ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRA</ENAMEX> ) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box sequence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5a,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">lanes 7-8</ENAMEX>) competes very poorly against the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1</ENAMEX>*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box probe. 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5a,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">lanes 9-10</ENAMEX>) competes only slightly less well than does 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> , indicating that a
          change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> at position <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7</ENAMEX> does not prevent rDEK
          binding. Mutation of the reverse CCAAT sequence, however,
          eliminates effective competition for binding to the 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5a,
          substitution of adenine at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> in the 
          DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box for guanine in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consensus Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence significantly strengthens DEK
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX>, as do bases at positions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 and 6</TIMEX> in the reverse
          CCAAT sequence.
          Further characterization of rDEK binding to the
          polymorphic 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence and to the
          consensus ( 
          HLA-DRA ) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box sequence
          establishes a relative hierarchy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> binding activity
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5b). With the 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, unlabelled 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> sequence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5b, lane
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) competed less well than did unlabelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRA Y</ENAMEX>
          box sequence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5b, lane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCAAT</ENAMEX> mutant sequence
          (not shown) did not compete for binding. Inability of the
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA-DRA Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence to compete
          with the 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> again indicates the
          relative importance of the adenine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue immediately 5</ENAMEX>'
          to the reverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCAAT</ENAMEX> for DEK binding. With the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRA Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          5b, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-10</TIMEX>), the unlabelled probe sequence competes
          less well than do any of the other <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box sequences,
          suggesting that rDEK alone binds to this sequence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonspecifically</ENAMEX> and with low affinity.
        
        
          Quantitative assessment of rDEK binding to related
          DQ-and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DR- Y</ENAMEX>-box sequences
          Quantification of the apparent dissociation constant
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          d[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">app</ENAMEX>] ) for rDEK binding to related
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">class II MHC Y</ENAMEX>-box motifs validates the relative
          hierarchy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> binding activity described above, and
          further emphasizes the contribution of gene-specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box polymorphisms to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> binding activity. As shown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> binds more strongly to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box sequences in
          either 
          DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allele</ENAMEX> than it does to any of
          the other 
          DR - or 
          DQ -related <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box sequences. It
          binds least well to the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRA</ENAMEX> (consensus) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box motif, with a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          d[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">app</ENAMEX>] that is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately five</NUMEX>
          times that for the 
          DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          d[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">app</ENAMEX>] for DEK binding to 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DQB</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately four</NUMEX> times
          that for the 
          DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX>, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          d[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">app</ENAMEX>] for DEK binding to the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRB Y</ENAMEX>-box sequences, especially the
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRB</ENAMEX> alleles associated with the DR4
          haplotype, are intermediate between the two extremes.
          Once again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A-to-G</ENAMEX> substitution at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Y box</ENAMEX> appears to strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> binding to the 
          DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box in comparison with the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRA Y</ENAMEX> box; allelic variation in the
          nucleotide at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence (as in 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> and in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">DR4</NUMEX>-associated
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRB Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence) may also
          mediate subtle differences in DEK binding to otherwise
          identical sites. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>-specific sequence polymorphisms
          outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box per se could also explain why
          dissociation constants differ where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box sequences are
          identical, as in the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DQB</ENAMEX> and 
          DRB consensus motifs.
        
        
          Localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> binding within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> footprinting with recombinant protein further
          defined the physical interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> and the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1</ENAMEX>*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box element (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). Using the noncoding strand as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, consistent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX> is seen over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> at position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7</TIMEX>, which is
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polymorphic</ENAMEX> in the 
          DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> allele (A-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">substitution</ENAMEX>) and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRB</ENAMEX> alleles associated with the
          DR4 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">haplotype</ENAMEX> (C-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> substitution). Consistent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protection</ENAMEX> is also seen at position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>, adjacent to the
          A-for-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> substitution that diverges from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box
          consensus sequence, although there is no protection of
          the divergent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> itself at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase I</ENAMEX>
          protection by recombinant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> extends over the length of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box sequence, including bases within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Y
          binding site (reverse CCAAT sequence), again suggesting
          that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> may interact.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-presenting cells upregulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> II
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX> in response to immune stimulation. We have
        previously shown that activation of promyeloid cells causes
        dephosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> and diminished DEK binding to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> long terminal repeat [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17 32</NUMEX> ] . In this study, we
        show that rDEK can bind to the 
        DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> in nuclear
        extracts participates in the 
        DQA1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box binding complex 
        in vitro . Thus, we propose a model
        in which intracellular signaling modulates the ability of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> to bind <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, causing alteration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> II
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcription</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Transient transfection</ENAMEX> experiments in
        cultured cell lines have not proved useful in examining
        this model, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> is highly expressed in most cells of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">hematopoietic</ENAMEX> lineage, and further overexpression has
        resulted in apparently nonspecific downregulation of
        transcriptional activity (as might be predicted from [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ]
        ). For this reason, we are currently pursuing other
        experimental approaches.
        The 
        DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> promoter <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">QAP 4.1</NUMEX>),
        in which a single-base-pair polymorphism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> box
        significantly diminishes transcriptional activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] ,
        is a component of the so-called susceptibility haplotype
        for autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. The 
        DQA1*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> allele is strongly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with early-onset pauciarticular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JRA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 24</NUMEX> ] and with increased risk for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juvenile dermatomyositis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SjÃ¶gren's syndrome</ENAMEX> with
        high autoantibody production [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27</NUMEX> ] . In our proposed
        model, aberrant class <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">II</ENAMEX> MHC regulation could result from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">altered DEK</ENAMEX> binding and/or interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Y, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aberrant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> II expression may alter or enhance
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivity</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DEK-</ENAMEX>derived or other self peptides. The
        C-terminal region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX>, which contains the putative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>-binding domain, appears to be most antigenic [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ]
        (and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K Sitwala</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DM Markovitz</ENAMEX>, unpublished observations),
        raising the possibility that altered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> binding may expose
        other masked epitopes. Development of antibodies to DEK
        could even be a primary event in the pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JRA</ENAMEX>,
        with disruption of nuclear events due to penetration of
        anti-DEK <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> into living cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . It remains
        to be determined whether anti-DEK <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> are directly
        involved in the pathogenesis of autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, or if
        they result from generally enhanced immunoreactivity.
      
      
        Conclusion
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> specific findings in this report support a
        potential role for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> as a transcriptional modulator of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> II expression. One is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> binds to the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1 Y</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> in a sequence-specific
        manner. Another is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF</ENAMEX>-Y and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> both participate in
        the HLA-DQA*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>-box binding complex, which coordinates
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DQ protein</ENAMEX> expression. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEK</ENAMEX> binds differentially to
        specific <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box sequences found in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DQA1</ENAMEX>(*<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX> and 
        *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0501</TIMEX> alleles) and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA-DRA</ENAMEX> , consistent with
        observations of 
        DQA1 gene-specific cell-surface
        expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] and allele-specific promoter activity [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> ] . The specificity of rDEK binding to these and other,
        related <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Y</NUMEX>-box sequences (including 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA-DQB</ENAMEX> and 
        HLA-DRB alleles associated with the
        DR4 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">haplotype</ENAMEX>) may correlate with a predisposition to
        autoim-mune disease seen with certain HLA haplotypes.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bp</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">base pair</ENAMEX>(s); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMSA</ENAMEX> = electrophoretic mobility shift
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay; FLAG = Five NH</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> -terminally deleted epilope; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHC</ENAMEX> =
        Major histocompatibility <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIV</ENAMEX> = human
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">immunodeficiency</ENAMEX> virus; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JRA</ENAMEX> = juvenile rheumatoid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis; K</ENAMEX> 
        d[<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">app</ENAMEX>] = apparent dissociation constant;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> = polymerase chain reaction; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">peri</NUMEX>- 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ets</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rDEK</ENAMEX> = recombinant DEK
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
