
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Tumor necrosis factor (TNF) has been implicated in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> and pathogenicity of infectious diseases and
        autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX>, such as septic shock, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypotension</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4</NUMEX> ] . It plays a pivotal role in the
        inflammatory cascade and, together with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, has
        been shown to mediate the acute-phase response [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] .
        Confirmation of its significance in disease comes from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> of clinical trials using anti-TNF therapy to treat
        rheumatoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Crohn's disease</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8 9 10</NUMEX> ] .
        Bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lipopolysaccharide</ENAMEX> (LPS), or endotoxin, is
        found only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gram</ENAMEX>-negative bacterial cell walls; it can on
        its own induce the acute inflammatory response and the
        clinical characteristics associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. After
        administration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> and other inflammatory mediators
        are released [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 12</NUMEX> ] . Infusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> initiates an
        inflammatory process leading to a phenotype that is
        indistinguishable from bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] .
        Recent work on tristetraprolin (TTP) has provided a new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> on the regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> biosynthesis. TTP
        (also referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NuP475</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TIS11</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">GOS24</NUMEX>) is a member
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc-finger proteins</ENAMEX> that was originally
        identified through genetic screens designed to identify
        immediate early response genes [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16 17 18</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was
        shown to be an unusually proline-rich <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> with a
        predicted molecular weight of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33.6</NUMEX> kDa. Its name derives
        from the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPPPG</ENAMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid repeats</ENAMEX> that
        are conserved across species. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cys</ENAMEX>-Cys-Cys-His
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCCH</ENAMEX>) zinc fingers, which are responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> binding
        [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 19</NUMEX> ] . There are no studies of the subcellular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">localization</ENAMEX> or the regulation of expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native</ENAMEX> TTP
        in freshly isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> or tissue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transfection</ENAMEX> studies
        using nonhematopoietic cell lines or prolonged cell culture
        have suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> is found in both cytoplasm and the
        nucleus [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21 22 23 24</NUMEX> ] .
        A deficiency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> is associated with a profound
        proinflammatory phenotype. TTP-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> exhibit
        cachexia, with dermatitis, medullary and extramedullary
        hyperplasia, erosive polyarthritis, and autoimmunity with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoantibodies</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . This phenotype is similar to that
        observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> that overexpress <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . In agreement
        with these data, TTP-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were shown to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overproduce TNF</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> injections of a neutralizing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> eliminated the predominant features of this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenotype</ENAMEX>. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with the double deletion of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF</ENAMEX> receptor (TNFR)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> do not manifest the
        aggressive inflammation observed in TTP-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. In
        contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> deficient in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TNFR-2</ENAMEX> show a more
        severe phenotype, suggesting a protective role for this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
        The increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> biosynthesis in TTP-deficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
        is associated with increased mRNA stability [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . TTP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">binds</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AU</ENAMEX>-rich element (ARE) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' untranslated
        region of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> mRNA, which regulates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> mRNA turnover 
        in vivo [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] . The interaction
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP/TNF</ENAMEX> and the ARE promotes the turnover of TNF
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> also regulates the stability of GM-CSF
        through the ARE, and therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">TTP deficiency</ENAMEX> is associated
        with increased production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM-CSF</ENAMEX> and with myeloid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperplasia</ENAMEX>. This is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-dependent effect, since the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenotype</ENAMEX> is not affected by the removal of either TNFR-1
        or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">-2</NUMEX> or by the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF antibody</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] . Recent
        studies have suggested a potential interaction between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX>
        and both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-3</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8</ENAMEX> via the ARE in their mRNA [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29 30</NUMEX> ]
        .
        All studies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> expression to date have relied on
        transfected cells and cell lines; there have been no
        studies on the localization of expression of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP</ENAMEX>, or
        on its regulation 
        in vivo or in freshly isolated normal
        cells. To examine the kinetic relation between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>
        production and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> expression in models of septic shock, we
        developed an intracellular flow cytometric assay. By this
        method, expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was determined in peripheral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood leukocytes</ENAMEX> after the response to 
        in vitro stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>. TTP
        was initially upregulated in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in response to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, as shown by flow cytometry and confocal microscopy.
        The contribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> to this LPS-induced upregulation
        was confirmed using a humanized monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>.
        The kinetics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> production was also examined in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> infused with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>. After 
        in vivo exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, the initial
        rise in TTP expression correlated with the plasma TNF
        level. We also observed secondary increases in some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, without parallel increments in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>. These
        observations suggest that there are multiple factors
        involved in the regulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generation</ENAMEX> of antihuman TTP polyclonal
          antibody
          A peptide corresponding to the C terminus (amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">302-328</ENAMEX>) of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP</ENAMEX> was synthesized, purified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPLC</ENAMEX>,
          and coupled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLH</ENAMEX> (keyhole limpet hemocyanin;
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macromolecular Resources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Collins, CO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          Anti-human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP polyclonal antibody</ENAMEX> was generated by
          immunization of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">white rabbits</ENAMEX> with the
          KLH-coupled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>terminal peptide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneMed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The rabbit antiserum obtained was
          affinity-purified by passage over a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sulfolink</ENAMEX> column
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) to which disulfide linkage of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">peptide</ENAMEX> had been used to immobilize the peptide.
          Specificity in Western blotting and flow cytometry was
          evaluated by detection of exogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> in transfected
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells and by blocking this activity with peptide [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          ] .
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> vector constructs
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human TTP</ENAMEX> cDNA was generated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">THP-1 RNA</ENAMEX>
          and cloned into the pcDNA <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3.1His-C</TIMEX> vector (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), which encodes a histidine and epitope
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EXPRESS-TAG</ENAMEX>) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-terminus</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>.
          Orientation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloned DNA</ENAMEX> and the integrity of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequences</ENAMEX> were confirmed by sequencing with the ABI
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prism Dye Terminator Cycle Sequencing</ENAMEX> kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PerkinElmer</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wellesley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), and searched against the published
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX> (TTP accession no. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">M63625</NUMEX>) on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI Database</ENAMEX>
          using the BLAST search program.
        
        
          Transient transfection
          Human embryonic kidney <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manassas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) were plated at a density of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160,000</NUMEX> cells per cm 2in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>-well plates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g</ENAMEX>) or
          the TTP parental vector pcDNA3.1 His-C (control) was
          mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼l</NUMEX> of serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell Park</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Institute</ENAMEX>) medium. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was mixed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î</NUMEX>¼l
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lipofectamine 2000</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">reagent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies</ENAMEX>,
          Rockville, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) in a total volume of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î¼l</NUMEX> of
          serum-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RPMI</ENAMEX> per cm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2of</NUMEX> cells, incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 hours</TIMEX>,
          and followed by the addition of an equal volume of media
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> fetal calf serum.
        
        
          Cell preparation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">THP-1</ENAMEX> (generously provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P Guyre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth</ENAMEX>
          Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jurkat</ENAMEX> (ATCC), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cell lines were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cultured</ENAMEX> in RPMI complete medium (CM), consisting of RPMI
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> heat-inactivated fetal bovine serum, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> ml
          of sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pyruvate</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX>/l of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX>-glutamine, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX>/l
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hydroxyethylpiperazine</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>'-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-ethanesulfonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>),
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mmol</ENAMEX>/l of nonessential amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.25 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml of
          amphotericin, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml gentamicin (all from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">BioWhittaker</ENAMEX>,
          Walkersville, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> -5M <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-mercaptoethanol
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transfected</ENAMEX> and
          nontransfected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells were harvested using trypsin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Technologies</ENAMEX>), washed twice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>, resuspended to
          a concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Ã— 10 6cells/ml</ENAMEX>, and fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">methanol</ENAMEX>-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polysciences Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warrington</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). THP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were incubated with and without
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.1 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml ( 
          Escherichia <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coli</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">055:B5</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>), or
          with and without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 U/ml</ENAMEX>). In addition, infliximab
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Remicade Â®</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centocor Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malvern</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), was also incubated with and without
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or TNF to determine how much effect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> has on TTP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induction</ENAMEX>. Preliminary studies on TNF-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎ</ENAMEX>ºBÎ±
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylation</ENAMEX> determined the optimum concentration for
          inhibition with infliximab. After incubation, the cells
          were washed in staining buffer and fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX>.
          Leukocytes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">healthy donors</ENAMEX> were isolated by
          dextran sedimentation from heparinized peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>.
          In some experiments, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> was combined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> with RPMI CM
          and incubated with or without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> Î¼g/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>. At the
          indicated times, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> was mixed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> dextran (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">150</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kDa; Polysciences</ENAMEX>) in prewarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> and left at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> to sediment the red blood cells preferentially.
          The white-cell supernatant was then aspirated,
          centrifuged, and mixed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX>. After centrifugation,
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell pellet</ENAMEX> was resuspended with staining buffer
          (prechilled to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4Â°C</NUMEX>) consisting of phosphate-buffered
          saline <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼g/</ENAMEX>ml sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">azide</ENAMEX>.
          The white cells were then counted using <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> solution
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">violet</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> acetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> in distilled
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">water</ENAMEX>), washed as before, and resuspended to a
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Ã— 10 6cells/ml</ENAMEX> with staining
          buffer.
        
        
          Immunofluorescence staining
          To detect extracellular antigens, cells were pipetted
          into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well polypropylene plate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costar</ENAMEX>), and the
          plate was centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> 
          
            g 
           for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min. The cells and reagents were kept at 4Â°C
          for the remainder of the experiment. The supernatant was
          aspirated, and the cells were resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX> human IgG
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) in staining buffer to block nonspecific binding.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allophycocyanin</ENAMEX> (APC)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">conjugated</NUMEX> CD14 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton, Dickinson</ENAMEX>
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was added, and the cells were
          incubated for a further <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> min in the dark. The cells
          were then washed once in staining buffer and residual red
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood cells lysed</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lysing</ENAMEX> solution (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>). After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min the cells were washed twice with
          staining buffer and fixed overnight in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX>.
          To detect intracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX>, fixed cells were washed
          twice in permeabilization buffer (consisting of staining
          buffer with the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/ml saponin</ENAMEX>), centrifuged
          as before, and incubated for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 min at 4Â°C</NUMEX> in blocking
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX>, consisting of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> IgG with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat powdered milk</ENAMEX>
          for leukocytes in permeabilization buffer. The plate was
          centrifuged, the supernatant was aspirated, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3.8 Î</NUMEX>¼g
          per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Ã— 10 5cells</NUMEX> of anti-TTP rabbit polyclonal or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAKO A/S, Glostrup</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>) was added
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 min more</TIMEX>. After incubation, the cells were washed
          in permeabilization buffer and resuspended in
          FITC-conjugated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ab</ENAMEX>') 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>-binding fragment) donkey
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antirabbit IgG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">25 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson ImmunoResearch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. Cells were washed with
          permeabilization buffer and then with staining buffer.
          They were resuspended with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> and stored in
          the dark at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C until</TIMEX> analysis. For the infliximab
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibition</ENAMEX> experiments, a goat polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to TTP
          was used (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnology Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA)
          with a secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">swine antigoat</ENAMEX> FITC-conjugated IgG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). Preliminary experiments showed that the
          affinity of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was equivalent to that
          of the rabbit polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>.
          In the LPS infusion study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TruCount</ENAMEX> Â®calibration beads
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>) were quantitatively added to the
          stained cells. Enumeration of individual leukocyte counts
          was then completed using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Quest Â®software.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX> analysis and confocal microscopy
          Analysis by flow cytometry was completed using a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAC-SCalibur</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>). Contaminants, such as
          red cells and cell debris, were removed by forward and
          side scatter gating; in addition, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD14</TIMEX> versus side
          scatter was used to create gates to differentiate
          lymphocytes, monocytes, and neutrophils. Fluorescein
          fluorescence was detected through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, APC
          fluorescence was assessed using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> were acquired and analyzed using the CellQuest
          Â®application on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Macintosh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G3</ENAMEX> computer. For each
          sample, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 2000</TIMEX> monocytes were collected and the
          mean fluorescence intensity was evaluated. Calibration
          was done using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainbow Microspheres</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spherotech Inc</ENAMEX>,
          Libertyville, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), with final values expressed as
          the milliequivalents of soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluorescein</ENAMEX> (MESF) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ]
          .
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells were sorted for the brightest FITC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluorescence</ENAMEX> using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACStar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> flow cytometer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>). Cells were collected into tubes containing
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> Î¼l fetal calf serum, centrifuged, and resuspended in
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX>. The cells were stored <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at 4Â°C
          in the dark. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP/FITC</ENAMEX>-stained white blood cells or THP-1
          cells were centrifuged and resuspended in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX> as
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells. Nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">staining</ENAMEX> was done using propidium
          iodide <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). For confocal microscopy, cells
          were pipetted from the base of the settled cell
          suspension and placed onto a glass slide with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prolong</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Â®Antifade</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) to inhibit
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quenching</ENAMEX>. The cells were then covered with a cover slip
          protected with clear nail polish.
          Microscopy for FITC-conjugated TTP analysis was
          completed using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MRC1024</ENAMEX> laser scanning confocal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">microscope</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Cells were
          scanned for fluorescence using the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">488</NUMEX>-nm line from a
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-mW <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kr/Ar</ENAMEX> laser and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> photodetectors (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">522/32</NUMEX>-nm
          dichroic for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> fluorescence and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">585</NUMEX>-nm longpass for
          propidium iodide fluorescence). A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">63Ã— Plan-APO 1.4 NA</ENAMEX>
          objective (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Zeiss Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thornwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was used
          in conjunction with an iris setting of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.5</NUMEX>, which allowed
          for detection of optical sections of the fluorescence
          image that were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 0.5 Î¼m</NUMEX> thick.
          Representative images were selected from the slices
          though the center of the cells after sectioning through
          the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          LPS infusion
          Consenting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> were given an intravenous bolus
          of endotoxin in accordance with a protocol approved by
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional and Scientific Review Boards</ENAMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norris Cotton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One month</TIMEX> before
          admission and again just before admission, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>' physical wellbeing and health were assessed,
          and current <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> were noted. The infusion was
          conducted in the intensive care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</ENAMEX> with continuous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supervision</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 12 hours</TIMEX>. Blood pressure, heart
          rate, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> temperature were evaluated throughout this
          period.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinical Center</ENAMEX> reference endotoxin (CCRE), lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">133,</ENAMEX>
          derived from 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> Pharmacopeia
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> ] ), was injected
          intravenously at a dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4 ng/kg.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> consecutive
          baseline <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood samples</ENAMEX> were taken, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 10</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> min
          before infusion, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were taken at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.45</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2, 4,</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 12, 24, 48</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 hours</TIMEX> after infusion, from a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peripheral</ENAMEX>, indwelling, venous catheter directly into a
          heparinized syringe (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sedimented</ENAMEX> in dextran, extracellularly stained for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CD14</TIMEX>,
          and fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formaldehyde</ENAMEX>. The cells were stored
          overnight at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> and then stained for intracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX>.
          A human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF ELISA kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">R&D Systems</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MN</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was used to determine the concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> in
          plasma from peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, in accordance with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± standard was made
          up as directed to read a maximum concentration of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pg/ml</ENAMEX> and a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15.6</NUMEX> pg/ml.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          Analysis was by one-way analysis of variance (ANOVA)
          with post hoc <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonferroni</ENAMEX> adjustment (all-means
          comparison) test, using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graphpad Â®Prism</ENAMEX> version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.00</NUMEX>
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graphpad Software</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Results
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Optimization</ENAMEX> and specificity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> polyclonal
          antibody
          To determine the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimal</ENAMEX> working concentration of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP antibody</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells transfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> were fixed,
          permeabilized, and stained at various concentrations of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IgG</ENAMEX> control. There was a
          concentration-dependent increase in fluorescence (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          1a), which was standardized using fluorescent
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microspheres</ENAMEX> in order to compare different experiments
          and cell types [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . The optimum concentration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was determined to be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3.8 Î¼g</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Ã— 10 5cells</NUMEX>,
          where the intensity curve began to flatten. At higher
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentrations</ENAMEX>, the MESF value for the control sera
          increased concordantly, indicating nonspecific binding.
          Specificity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was determined by
          blocking with the identical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptide sequence</ENAMEX> used to
          generate the polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. In the presence of
          blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> peptide, at concentrations either <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 or 50</TIMEX>
          times the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP antibody</ENAMEX> used, the detection of
          the TTP <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> within the transfected cells was nearly
          eliminated (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1b).
          Confocal sectioning of transfected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells showed
          that the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP protein</ENAMEX> was primarily in the
          cytoplasmic fraction (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1c). Z sections taken every
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 Î</NUMEX>¼m through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> showed little, if any, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> within
          the nucleus. In nontransfected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells, a small amount
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was detected by flow cytometry and confirmed by
          confocal microscopy. Transfected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells expressed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
          times as much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> as the untransfected cells at the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimal</ENAMEX> working concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. Preincubation
          of the nontransfected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> peptide blocked
          the activity, confirming its identity. These results
          confirmed our previously published data in which Western
          blot analysis showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was localized in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cytoplasmic</ENAMEX> extract of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">THP-1</ENAMEX> cell line
          Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> biosynthesis in macrophages is rapidly
          triggered by treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, the effects of this
          endotoxin on TTP expression were examined. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">THP-1 cells</ENAMEX>, a
          human myelomonocytic cell line, were incubated with and
          without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.1</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 24 hours</TIMEX>. At
          representative time points, a sample was removed and
          stained with either anti-TTP or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">IgG</ENAMEX> control, as
          described in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Materials</ENAMEX> and methods. The addition of LPS
          rapidly increased the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2a). Increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> were detectable <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> after
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulation</ENAMEX> and were still evident in the cytosol <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX>
          after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> treatment. Analysis of the cells by confocal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microscopy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2b) confirmed the upregulation and
          indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was expressed intracellularly,
          relatively homogeneously but confined to the cytoplasm.
          These data show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> stimulation rapidly increases
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human TTP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expression in the cytoplasm. The
          kinetics of induction by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> parallels that seen with TTP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> in bone-marrow-derived murine macrophages [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ]
          .
        
        
          In vitroTTP induction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> in peripheral blood
          leukocytes
          Modulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> expression by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> was subsequently
          examined in normal peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leukocytes</ENAMEX>. Whole blood
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> was incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> alone
          or with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.1</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 24 hours</TIMEX>. At periodic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> points, a sample was taken and leukocytes were
          purified by dextran sedimentation, fixed, permeabilized,
          and then stained with either anti-TTP or control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. In leukocytes, constitutive expression of TTP
          ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 9 Ã— 10 3to 35 Ã— 10 3MESF</NUMEX>.
          Monocytes constitutively expressed over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as
          much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> as either lymphocytes or neutrophils (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
          Stimulation with LPS 
          in vitro produced an increase in
          TTP expression in all leukocyte subpopulations. This was
          maximal <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> after stimulation. TTP levels increased
          to a higher maximal level in monocytes than in other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leukocytes</ENAMEX> (+<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.5</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 3MESF; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3a). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>-color flow
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytometry</ENAMEX> indicated that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">CD4</NUMEX> +and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD8 +T</ENAMEX> lymphocytes
          expressed equivalent amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> (data not shown). The
          kinetics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> induction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> was consistent and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monophasic</ENAMEX> in all leukocytes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3i). The change in TTP
          expression was greatest in neutrophils and least in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphocytes</ENAMEX>. Since lymphocytes lack Toll-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> 4
          and express little or no CD14 [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] , we conclude that
          the induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> was occurring
          indirectly, presumably through stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>,
          although other cytokines, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>,
          could contribute to this response.
          LPS-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> upregulation was confirmed in all cell
          types by confocal microscopy. Analysis confirmed an
          increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> in neutrophils <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> after stimulation
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Similar data were obtained for lymphocytes and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monocytes</ENAMEX> (data not shown). Distribution in resting
          levels and after stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> was primarily
          cytosolic, which is in accord with our data for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX> and
          THP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells.
        
        
          Correlation of in vivoTTP production with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> after
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> bolus
          To study the kinetics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> induction 
          in vivo , we infused <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kg</NUMEX> of
          clinical-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">endotoxin</ENAMEX> at time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Blood</ENAMEX> was drawn before the infusion and at specified
          intervals afterwards, and aliquots were analyzed for
          leukocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> counts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> expression, and plasma TNF
          levels.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> counts of all the leukocyte subpopulations in
          all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> fell rapidly, as seen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX> after
          infusion in all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4a,4b<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,4</NUMEX>c), in
          concordance with published data [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35 36</NUMEX> ] . Beyond the
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-hour</TIMEX> time point, the neutrophil <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count increased,
          reaching a peak at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX>. It then decreased to
          baseline values at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4a). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lymphocyte</ENAMEX> and
          monocyte data showed similar initial kinetics. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphocyte</ENAMEX> and monocyte curves were biphasic, peaking at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX>, dropping to baseline at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX>, and beginning
          a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> increase at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plasma TNF</ENAMEX> levels were analyzed throughout the study.
          The circulating TNF level increased to a peak at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>
          after infusion (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4d). After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX>, there was no
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">detectable TNF</ENAMEX> in any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>. This
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monophasic</TIMEX> peak was consistent with findings in other
          studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] .
          Analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> expression in leukocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>
          before and after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> infusion revealed a biphasic
          induction, with an initial peak occurring within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX>
          and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5a,5b<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,5</NUMEX>c). Baseline and
          maximum TTP expression in each cell type for each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteer</ENAMEX> is presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. The expression and
          initial upregulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> in all
          leukocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> was consistent with the data found 
          in vitro . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neutrophils</ENAMEX> responded
          rapidly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> infusion, reaching an initial peak within
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> of infusion, although the average increase in the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> appears to be moderate (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>). Analysis of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monocytic TTP</ENAMEX> showed an increase in expression, peaking
          at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5b). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lymphocyte</ENAMEX> TTP expression peaked at
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX>, which was later than the initial peak response
          of neutrophils and monocytes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5c). A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, more
          dramatic, rise, which did not parallel changes in plasma
          TNF levels (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5d), was observed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> after
          infusion in all leukocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> contribution in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> induction of TTP
          The human 
          in vivo studies described here show
          increases in circulating plasma <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> that preceded TTP
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induction</ENAMEX> in all the leukocyte types investigated. This
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation</ENAMEX> is consistent with the hypothesis that LPS
          mediates induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> through the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>.
          However, this hypothesis does not explain the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> rise
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> we observed 
          in vivo , which was not associated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>. To examine this phenomena in more detail, THP-1
          cells were cultured with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or TNF in the presence of
          blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. The antibody sequesters <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> in the
          supernatant, preventing its interaction with TNF
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. LPS induced greater TTP expression than TNF
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6a,6b). When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells were stimulated with LPS
          in the presence of the blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, the TTP
          response was reduced but not eliminated (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6a). In
          fact, the initial induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> detectable during the
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> was unaffected, suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> was not
          solely responsible for the LPS-induced rise. In contrast,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">THP-1 cells</ENAMEX> was completely
          blocked in the presence of the blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> antibody
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6b).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        This study is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to evaluate the expression and
        regulation of endogenous human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP</ENAMEX> in myeloid and lymphoid
        cells. It is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to examine the subcellular
        localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">native TTP protein</ENAMEX> in freshly isolated
        cells, since all previous studies relied on prolonged cell
        culture or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">transfection</ENAMEX>/overexpression approaches using
        cell lines [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21 22 24 25</NUMEX> ] . We show that endogenous
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human TTP</ENAMEX> is expressed in neutrophils, lymphocytes, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monocytes</ENAMEX>. They are significant in their demonstration that
        native human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP</ENAMEX> is totally cytoplasmic; there was little
        evidence of nuclear localization in these studies, an
        observation that is consistent with previous work with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human TTP</ENAMEX>, in which immunoblotting showed cytoplasmic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">localization</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
        The discrepancy between our findings and findings of
        nuclear localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> may be due to several factors [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21 22 24 25</NUMEX> ] . First, most of those studies did not
        measure endogenous TTP but usually relied on transfection
        of cell lines, perhaps resulting in mislocalization due to
        the presence of an epitope tag or overexpression [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21 22</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24 25</NUMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, by definition, those cells were largely
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cycling</ENAMEX> and thus were not representative of normal
        hematopoietic cells. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> or rat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was used in
        those studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21 22 25</NUMEX> ] . Although highly conserved,
        it is possible that human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP</ENAMEX> is subtly different from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rodent TTP</ENAMEX>. We think this unlikely, as immunoprecipitation
        studies of bone-marrow-derived murine macrophages show
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">murine</ENAMEX> TTP predominantly in the cytoplasmic fraction [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ]
        . This matter requires further analysis once improved
        antibodies to murine TTP are generated.
        Our studies clearly showed human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP</ENAMEX> in lymphocytes and
        neutrophils, in addition to monocytes. Early work by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carballo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] showed the importance of
        macrophages, not lymphocytes, in the development of the
        phenotype associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">TTP deficiency</ENAMEX>. This highlights
        the importance of macrophages in the production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>,
        supported by current hypotheses on the pivotal role of this
        cell type in TNF overproduction in autoimmune <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>
        ] . Thus, our findings suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> serves an entirely
        different role in other leukocytes, relative to their role
        in regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cytokine</ENAMEX> production by macrophages, and that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> production is not simply regulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX>.
        Despite these potential differences in the function of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human TTP</ENAMEX> based on cell type, our studies show a common
        pattern of induction by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> in monocytes, neutrophils, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lymphocytes</ENAMEX>. The upregulation of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP</ENAMEX> occurs rapidly,
        within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first hour</TIMEX> of stimulation. This is consistent
        with murine data demonstrating that upregulation occurs
        within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 min</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> stimulation, remaining high for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . Using confocal imaging, we found <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was
        primarily detected in the cytoplasmic fraction, confirming
        our earlier immunoblotting studies [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
        LPS stimulation of peripheral blood leukocytes 
        in vitro revealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TTP-</ENAMEX>induction
        kinetics analogous to that observed for THP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells. We
        used a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood assay</ENAMEX>, since the cytokines produced
        after 
        in vitro incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> are
        analogous to those produced after 
        in vivo infusion, providing an
        important model of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> ] . Baseline expression of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was higher in monocytes than in either lymphocytes or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neutrophils</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lymphocytes</ENAMEX> responded the least to LPS
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stimulation</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monocytes</ENAMEX> responded the most.
        Monocytes were not followed beyond <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> after
        stimulation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, because of the low numbers of cells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retrieved</ENAMEX>, probably due to upregulation of adhesion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">molecules</ENAMEX> (ICAM-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX> ] .
        The induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> expression by either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LPS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> has
        not been studied in an 
        in vivo system before. In this study,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> were infused with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and the
        subsequent changes in leukocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> expression
        in leukocyte subpopulations, and levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> were
        followed over a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72-hour</TIMEX> period. Although there was some
        individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">variability</ENAMEX> in the overall kinetics, basal
        levels and the initial induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> were within
        the range observed 
        in vitro (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tables 1and 2</ENAMEX>). All cell
        types showed an increase in TTP expression within the first
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX>. Interestingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was induced by LPS 
        in vivo more slowly (after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> vs
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-2 hours</TIMEX>) and to a lesser degree in the lymphocyte
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> than in neutrophils or monocytes. The absence of
        LPS-signal transducers (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CD14</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toll</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor 4</ENAMEX>) on most
        lymphocytes relative to monocytes and neutrophils may
        account for this altered expression [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42 43</NUMEX> ] . Since
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lymphocytes</ENAMEX> express TNF <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> itself can induce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> mRNA expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] , these data are consistent with
        the interpretation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> induction in lymphocytes is
        transduced not by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> binding, but by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> produced by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monocytes</ENAMEX> and/or neutrophils acting on lymphocytes.
        The initial fall in leukocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> count observed 
        in vivo is in accord with published
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 35 36</NUMEX> ] . The numbers of monocytes and
        neutrophils dropped within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first hour</TIMEX>, by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately</TIMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98% and 76%</NUMEX>, respectively, and of lymphocytes, by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> after
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX>. This decrease is consistent with data suggesting
        that the reduction in leukocytes results from a decrease in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">granulocytes</ENAMEX> and monocytes as they become activated,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migrating</ENAMEX> and adhering to vascular endothelium [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX> ] .
        This drop in cell numbers was followed by an increase in
        all leukocyte <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> and
        continuing through the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72-hour</TIMEX> time point. This raises the
        issue of whether the apparent changes in TTP expression
        were due, in part, to differential rates of margination by
        leukocyte subpopulations. Since the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> induction
        seen in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first hour</TIMEX> 
        in vivo approximate those seen 
        in vitro , we believe that this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induction</ENAMEX> reflects the increased synthesis and expression
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> by all leukocyte subpopulations and is consistent
        with the kinetics of their mRNA induction [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> are reportedly involved in a
        negative-feedback loop, in which increases in TNF
        concentration are associated with induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        In these studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, which induces the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> ] , produced a rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> of
        stimulation. Although the initial rise in TTP 
        in vivo paralleled a rapid and
        considerable increase in plasma <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, late
        increases in intracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> did not reflect TNF levels.
        This change may have been mediated by other cytokines
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-1Î², IL-8</ENAMEX>) whose levels have been shown to increase with
        kinetics that parallel this rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 46 47</NUMEX> ] .
        Alternatively, the late rise in cytoplasmic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> may be due
        to release from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone marrow</ENAMEX> of leukocytes that have
        high levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> or an adaptive response to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endotoxemia</ENAMEX>.
        TNF overproduction mediates both <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and chronic
        inflammatory disorders such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Its production may be
        modulated at transcriptional, post-transcriptional, and
        post-translational levels [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48 49 50</NUMEX> ] . Many of the
        effects observed after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> stimulation can be attributed to
        subsequent production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>. Moreover, infusion of TNF
        initiates inflammatory processes, with a resulting
        phenotype that is indistinguishable from bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] . We investigated the contribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> in the
        LPS-mediated induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> in THP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> cells using a
        blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> expression was
        almost completely eliminated by incubation with the TNF
        inhibitor, proving the direct effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> on TTP
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">induction</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, however, induced much greater levels of TTP
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">THP-1 cells</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> did. In the presence of blocking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF antibody</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was initially unaffected
        but began to decline after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 hour</TIMEX>, suggesting that LPS
        itself may mediate the initial increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> and showing
        that the prolonged induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> is dependent on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        We have shown through an intracellular staining assay
        that human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP</ENAMEX> expression is modulated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>.
        LPS-induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> was partly dependent on the production
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>. The ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> to induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TTP</ENAMEX> independently of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> may account for the earlier response observed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neutrophils</ENAMEX> and monocytes that have LPS-signaling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">transduction</ENAMEX> molecules. In contrast, lymphocytes
        demonstrate a delayed and lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> response and are
        probably responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>, or other cytokines, produced by
        myeloid cells. In addition, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> rise in TTP expression
        was observed 
        in vivo , which did not correlate
        with any detectable rise in TNF concentration, implying
        that there are additional factors involved in the
        regulation of this intracellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> is a
        predominant proinflammatory cytokine, particularly in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and chronic inflammatory disorders suggesting that
        the role of its negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX>, may be of
        functional importance in the development and pathogenesis
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. Investigating any potential abnormalities in
        expression or regulation may prove to be a valuable
        therapeutic intervention.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APC</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allophycocyanin</ENAMEX>; ARE = <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AU</ENAMEX>-rich element; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CM</ENAMEX> =
        complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">enzyme</NUMEX>-linked immunosorbent assay;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fluorescence</NUMEX>-activated cell sorting; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FITC</ENAMEX> =
        fluorescein isothiocyanate; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interleukin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KLH</ENAMEX> = keyhole
        limpet hemocyanin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lipopolysaccharide</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MESF</ENAMEX> =
        milliequivalents of soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluorescein</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX>
        necrosis factor; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNFR</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TNF</ENAMEX> receptor; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TTP</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tristetraprolin; WBC</ENAMEX> = white blood cell.
      
    
  
