
  
    
      
        Introduction
        In diarthodial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> provides a smooth
        surface that enables <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> to articulate and to withstand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">compressional</ENAMEX> and shear stress [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . Embedded in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> are chondrocytes that respond to biochemical and
        physical stimuli to maintain this tissue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cartilage</ENAMEX> is
        primarily composed of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II collagen</ENAMEX> and proteoglycan,
        which are synthesized by the chondrocytes. In addition,
        chondrocytes produce enzymes, such as the matrix
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metalloproteinases</ENAMEX> (MMPs), that degrade the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ]
        . In <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>, an imbalance of these processes in favour
        of degradation results in a loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX>. For the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, this is manifested as a degeneration of joint
        function, loss of mobility and concomitant increased
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and mortality [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] . For the clinician, this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imbalance</ENAMEX> identifies a need for therapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to
        prevent cartilage loss [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] .
        In identifying targets for therapeutic intervention, it
        is important to note that the loss of collagen, rather than
        proteoglycan, is correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> severity [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] .
        Furthermore, whereas lost proteoglycan is replaced rapidly,
        degraded collagen is resynthesized very slowly [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] .
        Consequently, understanding collagen degradation and
        providing therapeutics to prevent it are valuable aims.
        Within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">collagenase-1</ENAMEX>) and MMP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">collagenase-3</ENAMEX>) are expressed in arthritic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX>, and
        efficiently degrade type II collagen [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> is more
        effective than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> in cleaving <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">type II collagen</ENAMEX>, but it
        is debated which is the principal collagenase 
        in vivo [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX> ] . These enzymes
        have been implicated in the pathology of rheumatoid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>) and osteoarthritis (OA), and have long been
        therapeutic targets [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . Historically, inhibition of
        MMP-active sites has been a strategy; however, with
        wide-ranging side-effects and lack of efficacy, these
        studies are proving unfruitful in providing an effective
        drug [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] .
        Although the etiologies and pathologies of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> and OA
        pro-inflammatory cytokines are present, resulting in an
        inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage degradation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ]
        . As further evidence for the role of pro-inflammatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokines</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, anti-tumor necrosis <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-Î±</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX>)
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-interleukin</ENAMEX> 1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>) therapies can reduce
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inflammation</ENAMEX> and retard the progression of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> as
        assessed radiographically [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] . However, side-effects
        with these approaches, such as the development of lymphomas
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using anti-TNF-Î± therapies, demonstrate that
        alternative therapies are needed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        An alternative approach to the prevention of cartilage
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">degradation</ENAMEX> is the inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX> by targeting either
        the expression of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> or the synthesis of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>. Triterpenoids are a novel family of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid</ENAMEX>-like
        compounds with weak anti-inflammatory properties [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        Synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">triterpenoids</ENAMEX> have been produced with the aim of
        achieving increased potency [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20</NUMEX> ] .
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-Cyano-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,12</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dioxoolean</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,9</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dien</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>-oic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (CDDO) is a
        synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">triterpenoid</ENAMEX> that has been shown to inhibit
        expression of the inflammatory genes inducible nitric oxide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synthase</ENAMEX> and cyclo-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">oxygenase</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 21 22</NUMEX> ] . In a recent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> expression were induced with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>,
        a known pro-inflammatory mediator 
        in vivo in joint tissues [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . It
        was shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> could inhibit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-induced
        expression of these pro-inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX>. These findings
        make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> an attractive molecule to study as a potential
        anti-arthritic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.
        Here we report quantification of the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> on
        gene expression in the human chondrosarcoma cell line
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SW-1353</ENAMEX> with the use of real-time reverse-transcriptase
        polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR). To ensure that the
        chondroprotective effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> are not limited to this
        cell line, we studied its effects on human primary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chondrocytes</ENAMEX>. We found that, at concentrations that do not
        induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apoptosis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> effectively inhibits the induction
        of both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and MMP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> gene expression by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1</ENAMEX> in these
        cells. Whereas the inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> requires
        pretreatment, inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> does not. We have
        recently reported the role of the inhibitor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-ÎºB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎºB</ENAMEX>)
        family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bcl</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1-induced MMP-1</ENAMEX> expression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ]
        . Here we show that overexpression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> can partly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abrogate CDDO</ENAMEX>'s inhibitory effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> in SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX>
        cells, suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> might be a target for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Materials, cells and cell culture
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> was kindly provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dr Tadashi Honda</ENAMEX> and Dr
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Gribble</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth College</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SW-1353</ENAMEX> chondrosarcoma cells were purchased from
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Type Culture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Collection</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stable SW-1353</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cell lines</ENAMEX> carrying a pBkRSV vector
          with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> expression insert were created as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . Freshly excised, macroscopically
          normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cartilage</ENAMEX> and synovium from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">OA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> undergoing
          knee replacement surgery were obtained from a local
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orthopedic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dartmouth Hitchcock Memorial Hospital</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). These tissues constitute waste from
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. Under our current protocol with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee for Human Subjects</ENAMEX> as mandated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIPPA</ENAMEX>, we did
          not collect subject information. We therefore made no
          selection on the basis of age or sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cartilage</ENAMEX> and
          synovium were degraded in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml collagenase (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">St</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>, with shaking at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">r.p.m.</ENAMEX>, and cells were cultured to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> passage
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">chondrocytes</NUMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> passages (synovial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fibroblasts</ENAMEX>).
          SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells (normal or stably transfected with
          pBkRSV-Bcl-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>), human primary chondrocytes, or synovial
          fibroblasts were cultured in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s
          medium (DMEM) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal bovine serum
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyclone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">penicillin</ENAMEX>/streptomycin and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L-glutamine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cellgro; Mediatech, Herndon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) before
          use in experiments.
        
        
          Assay of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>'s effects on chondrocytes and
          fibroblasts
          At the beginning of each experiment, chondrocytes or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> synovial fibroblasts were washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with
          Hanks balanced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt solution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cellgro</ENAMEX>) to remove traces
          of serum, and placed in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DMEM</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> lactalbumin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hydrolysate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Cells were
          cultured for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> as a pretreatment, or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> was added at the same time as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml recombinant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">time 0</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). After a
          further <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 hours</TIMEX> of culture with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>, total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was
          harvested with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIzol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>) and assayed for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> expression by using quantitative
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dehydrogenase</ENAMEX> (GAPDH) was assayed to normalize data.
          Reverse transcription and quantitative real-time PCR
          methods were as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . MMP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX> used were as follows: upper,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TGGCATTGCTGACATCATGA-3</ENAMEX>' ; lower,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GCCAGAGGGCCCATCAA-5</ENAMEX>'. The product size was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX> base
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pairs</ENAMEX>. A plasmid containing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cDNA</ENAMEX> (provided by Dr
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Lopez-Otin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oviedo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>) was used to generate an
          MMP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> standard curve. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primers</ENAMEX> and standards for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>,
          Bcl-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX> were as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and use of standard curves were as
          described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Measurement of programmed cell death by staining
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX> 33342
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SW-1353</ENAMEX> and human primary chondrocytes were seeded at
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Ã— 10 4cells</NUMEX> per well in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-well plates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Lakes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). At <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60-90%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confluence</ENAMEX>, cells were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> nM to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX>)
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 hours</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33342</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) was then added to each well to
          detect cells with condensed chromatin, a hallmark of
          programmed cell death. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> of incubation at
          37Â°C, cells were examined under a fluorescent microscope
          as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] .
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          Analyses of real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> data were performed with
          unpaired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tailed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student</ENAMEX>'s 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> -tests on triplicate wells
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cultured</ENAMEX> simultaneously.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> in SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells
          Previous work suggested that preincubation with CDDO
          was required for the effective inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-induced
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMP</ENAMEX> gene expression in SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . To quantify
          the effect of altering the period of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> preincubation,
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">300 nM CDDO</TIMEX> was added to SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells simultaneously
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> before treatment with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytokine</ENAMEX>. We found that SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells expressed very low
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">basal</ENAMEX> levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>, and that these were not
          significantly affected by incubation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> induced the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>, and
          these were significantly inhibited when the cultures were
          pretreated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>, the respective
          decreases being <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.1</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>). In addition, when
          added simultaneously with the cytokine, CDDO
          significantly inhibited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-induced expression of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>, but not that of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>. Under these circumstances,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> expression was decreased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). The different
          profiles for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> inhibition when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> was
          added simultaneously with the cytokine suggest a
          difference in the action of the inhibitor on the
          expression of each enzyme.
          Previously, with the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> blotting,
          dose-response assays in SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells showed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM
          was the lowest dose of CDDO sufficient to decrease the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-induced expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . This
          was confirmed by using quantitative real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>. Doses
          below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nM</ENAMEX> did not decrease MMP expression, whereas
          those above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼M resulted in poor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA harvests</ENAMEX> and low
          expression of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMPs</ENAMEX> (data not shown). This effect at
          higher doses might be due to the reported apoptotic
          effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] . To examine for such effects,
          SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells were treated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> under
          serum-free conditions, and then <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-1</ENAMEX> was added for a
          further <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 hours</TIMEX>. Cells were stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX> 33342
          and examined under a fluorescent microscope. Doses of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼M CDDO</ENAMEX>, with or without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-1</ENAMEX>, did not increase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> compared with control (medium alone) or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1</ENAMEX>
          (data not shown). However, a dose of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î</NUMEX>¼M caused
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX> in SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells, as seen in lower cell
          numbers, changed morphology and an increased number of
          fluorescing cells. These data demonstrate that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM
          and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX>, doses that inhibit MMP gene expression, CDDO
          does not cause programmed cell death.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> time-course in human primary
          chondrocytes
          As described in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Introduction</ENAMEX>, the aim of studying
          the triterpenoids is to develop a therapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> for
          the treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. We were therefore interested
          in studying the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> in human primary cells.
          Quantitative real-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> revealed that human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chondrocytes</ENAMEX> expressed low levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> in
          the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>, and increased levels with addition
          of the cytokine (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Figs</ENAMEX> 2a,2b). Pretreatment of cultures
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> resulted in a decreased
          expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1-induced MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>. MMP-1
          expression was decreased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99%</NUMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">96%</NUMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>). As was observed with
          SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> expression was significantly
          decreased when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> was added simultaneously with the
          cytokine: we observed a decrease of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.1</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> expression was
          not significantly inhibited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> added simultaneously
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> on expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> in human
          primary chondrocytes
          In the same time-course experiment, we assayed for the
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎºB</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> that we have
          previously shown to have a role in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> expression. We
          found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> was inducible with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> in human primary
          chondrocytes, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> significantly inhibited this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expression</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2c). In a similar manner to MMP-1
          inhibition, the decreased expression was observed only
          after preincubation of the cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>
          (Figs 2a,2c). This was in contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>, whose
          inhibition was possible without pretreatment with CDDO
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2b). These results present further evidence of a
          link in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> expression, and indicate that
          both molecules are similarly affected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> dose-response study in human primary
          chondrocytes
          To examine the effects of increasing doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> in
          human primary chondrocytes, cells were preincubated for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼M</NUMEX>), or with medium
          alone, before the addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-1</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 hours</TIMEX>. Figure
          3shows that human primary chondrocytes have low basal
          expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX>, and that they are
          increased in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>. Increasing doses of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> resulted in a decreased expression of each gene. For
          example, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> expression was inhibited by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.1</NUMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>, by
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49%</NUMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>, and by
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83%</NUMEX> ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>) by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>. Similar
          patterns emerged for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99%</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bcl</ENAMEX>-3
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61%</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86%</NUMEX>) in response to the respective doses
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>, all results being significant. Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoechst</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33342</NUMEX>, we assayed for potential toxicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> in human
          primary chondrocytes: we found decreased cell numbers and
          increased apoptosis at or above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼M</NUMEX> CDDO (data not
          shown). Lower concentrations did not result in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apoptosis</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> in OA
          synovial fibroblasts
          In parallel with the study on human primary
          chondrocytes, we examined the effects of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">300 nM CDDO</TIMEX> on
          synovial fibroblasts excised from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> synovium. There were
          low basal expressions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX>, which
          were increased in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> and inhibited by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>, following the trends observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SW-1353</ENAMEX> and human
          primary chondrocytes (data not shown).
        
        
          Effect of overexpression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> on the inhibition
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> by CDDO
          To examine further the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-induced
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> expression, we used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SW-1353</ENAMEX> cells stably
          transfected with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> expression construct. These
          cells were pretreated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> and
          then cultured with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 hours</TIMEX>. In the presence of
          empty vector, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> induced both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>, and
          their expression was decreased by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48% and 46%</NUMEX>,
          respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). In cells stably transfected with
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> expression plasmid, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> induced MMP-1
          expression to levels <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX>-fold higher than in the cells
          transfected with empty vector (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4a). In comparison,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> expression was not significantly altered by the
          overexpression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4b). Furthermore, the
          presence of exogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> sustained <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> expression in
          the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> in comparison with cells expressing
          empty vector. When cultured in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>, cells transfected with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> expressed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.6</NUMEX>-fold
          more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> than did cells transfected with the empty
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vector</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4a). In contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> did not sustain
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> expression in CDDO-treated cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4b). Thus,
          Bcl-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, which is repressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>, preferentially
          contributes to MMP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> gene expression.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        In a previous study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX> blot analysis showed that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">treating SW-1353</ENAMEX> cells with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> before
        treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-1</ENAMEX> inhibited the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] . In the present study we used quantitative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">real-time RT-PCR</ENAMEX> to examine the action of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> on the
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> in SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells and in two
        primary cultures: human primary chondrocytes and OA
        synovial fibroblasts. We have shown in a quantitative
        manner that in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> cell types, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> are
        inducible with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> inhibits the expression
        of these collagenases, with optimal inhibition being
        observed after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> of pretreatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>.
        Differing effects were found on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> enzymes: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> was
        inhibited more than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>. In addition, significant
        inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> did not require the pretreatment of
        cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>. In addition, the observation that synovial
        fibroblasts respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> in a similar manner to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chondrocytes</ENAMEX> suggests that the inhibitor can act in all
        cells of the joint to decrease the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and
        MMP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>.
        In the human primary chondrocytes and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> synovial
        fibroblasts, we assayed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>'s effects on Bcl-3
        expression. We have recently described the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX>,
        an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎºB</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, in the signaling pathways of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1</ENAMEX>
        leading to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> expression in SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells and rabbit
        synovial fibroblasts [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . We found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1</ENAMEX> could
        induce the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> had a direct
        effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> expression through cooperation with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">NF-ÎºB1/p50.</ENAMEX> In the present study we found that Bcl-3
        expression was inducible by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1</ENAMEX> in human primary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chondrocytes</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> synovial fibroblasts. In addition,
        we found that pretreatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> decreased the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-induced expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> in these cells.
        Furthermore, with the use of SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells stably
        transfected with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> expression plasmid, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> could
        sustain the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>, but not that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>,
        against inhibition by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>. These data show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX> gene
        expression is a target of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> in chondrocytes and suggest
        that this might contribute to decreased <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> expression.
        Consistent with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is the finding that pretreatment
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> is required for the inhibition of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>, unlike that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>. We speculate that, during
        this period, the inhibitor is entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> and
        altering the expression of components of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1</ENAMEX>
        signalling pathway. Bcl-3 is decreased by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> during this
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">preincubation</TIMEX> period, and it might be one of several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> involved in MMP expression whose own expression is
        lowered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>.
        In all cell types, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CDDO</ENAMEX> inhibited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-induced
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> mRNA more effectively than that of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX>. This might be due to the much lower MMP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
        expression in all tissues examined. There is disagreement
        over which collagenase predominates in cartilage
        degradation 
        in vivo [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX> ] . It is therefore
        of interest to find the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> expressed compared
        with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SW-1353</ENAMEX> and human primary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chondrocytes</ENAMEX>. For example, in human primary chondrocytes
        (Figs 3a,3b), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1 induced MMP-1</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> molecules per
        molecule of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> was expressed at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.06</NUMEX>
        molecules per molecule of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX>-fold
        difference. These results suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-1</ENAMEX> expression
        might be a dominant target for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-1</ENAMEX> in chondrocytes.
        It is interesting to note that there was significant
        variation of both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> expression in the
        primary human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chondrocyte</ENAMEX> experiments. In excising
        chondrocytes from the extracted knees of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, great
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> was taken to remove only tissue that seemed
        macroscopically normal, with the aim of excluding cells of
        diseased tissue. When these cells were cultured with medium
        alone, they expressed low levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX>,
        similar to those found in unstimulated SW-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1353</NUMEX> cells. These
        results support the contention that the cells were in a
        basal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, unaffected by the environment of the diseased
        knee from which they had been extracted. Furthermore, both
        enzymes were consistently increased by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1</ENAMEX> and inhibited
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>. Thus, the observed variation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMP</ENAMEX> expression is
        probably due to genetic variability and not to experimental
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">artifacts</ENAMEX>.
        Naturally occurring triterpenoids, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ursolic acid</ENAMEX>,
        have been found to have mild anti-inflammatory effects [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> ] . These have been improved with the development of
        synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">triterpenoids</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>, offering a potential
        therapeutic tool for the treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and other
        diseases [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21</NUMEX> ] . Furthermore, it has been reported
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> at high doses (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5-10 Î¼M</ENAMEX>) can have pro-apoptotic
        effects, ideal for the treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX> but of concern
        with regard to chondrocyte cell death [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] . However,
        we found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>, at concentrations that decrease MMP-1
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> expression (namely <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> nM and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX>), did not
        cause cell death. The inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> on MMP-1
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MMP-13</ENAMEX> expression, as well as that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX>, is very
        encouraging for future applications of triterpenoids in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritic disease</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> is an early-generation synthetic
        triterpenoid, and further modifications continue to be
        made. Further analysis of these compounds will provide
        additional information about their mechanisms and potential
        as therapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        Inhibition of collagen loss is crucial to minimizing
        cartilage destruction in the arthritides. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MMP-1</ENAMEX> and MMP-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
        have been identified as the significant enzymes involved in
        this process 
        in vivo . We examined a novel,
        synthetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">triterpenoid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX>, as a potential inhibitor of
        collagenase expression. We found that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CDDO</ENAMEX> inhibited the
        expression of these enzymes in a chondrocyte cell line,
        human primary chondrocytes and synovial fibroblasts.
        Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> decreased the expression of the
        pro-inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bcl-3</ENAMEX>, suggesting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> possible
        mechanism of action. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> is an early-generation
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">therapeutic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> with great potential for the treatment of
        the arthritides and other inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDDO</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2-cyano-3,12-dioxoolean-1,9-dien</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>-oic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMEM</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAPDH</ENAMEX> =
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NF-ÎºB; IL</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interleukin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMP</ENAMEX> = matrix metalloproteinase;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">osteoarthritis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatoid arthritis</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> =
        tumor necrosis factor-Î±.
      
    
  
