
  
    
      
        Synopsis
        
          Introduction
          A spectrum of autoantibodies is now known to be
          specifically associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. There continues to be
          uncertainty as to what stage of the disease each of these
          autoantibodies develop, and whether they are associated
          with unique clinical features.
        
        
          Aims
          To help address these questions, a spectrum of
          autoantibodies known to be associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> in a cohort
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with early synovitis was evaluated.
        
        
          Methods
          An inception cohort of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">238</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> having peripheral
          joint synovitis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than 12 months</TIMEX> duration was
          evaluated clinicially then followed prospectively for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> were classified as having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> on the basis
          of fulfilling the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> criteria. Serum samples collected
          at the time of the initial evaluation were tested for
          anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> using immunoblotting, and to
          (pro)filaggrin (AFA), anti-CCP, and calpastatin
          (anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA-1</ENAMEX>) using enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay
          techniques. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX> were detected using immunoflurescence on
          human epidermal tissue. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> was tested by nephelometry.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DRB1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">alleles</ENAMEX> were determined using sequence specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primers</ENAMEX>. Initial and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 year</TIMEX> radiographs were evaluated
          for the presence of erosions.
        
        
          Results
          Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">238</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with synovitis of recent onset in
          the cohort, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX>) met <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> criteria, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">102</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">96%</NUMEX>) of whom
          met the criteria on their initial visit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diagnoses</ENAMEX> in the
          remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> included <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">22</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX>) with reactive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>) with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">psoriatic arthritis</ENAMEX> or another
          form of spondylarthropathy, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>) with another
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">well-defined rheumatic</ENAMEX> diagnosis, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX>) with
          undifferentiated <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were
          significantly older than the nonRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46 ± 13</NUMEX>
          versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39 ± 13</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>), had higher mean
          swollen joint count (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13.8 ± 9.7</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.3 ± 2.3</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>), and higher
          C-reactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (CRP) level (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.9 ± 1.9</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX> ±
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1summarizes</ENAMEX> the
          prevalence of the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> diagnosed as having RF-positive (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>+) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>,
          RF-negative (RF-) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, and nonRA. Regarding the
          characteristics of these tests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> had the highest
          sensitivity at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX>, and all the other antibodies
          individually were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 50%</NUMEX> sensitive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>,
          anti-CCP were greater than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, while RF
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80-90%</NUMEX> specific, and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA-33</ENAMEX> and
          anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA-1</ENAMEX> was not specific for this diagnosis. The data
          further indicate that adding any one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>,
          anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, or anti-CCP to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> increases the specificity for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 to 90%</NUMEX>. In the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>, the presence of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more of these antibodies carried a sensitivity of
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 31%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF- RA</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Sa</ENAMEX> being the most specific
          at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX>. Overall, there was a high degree of correlation
          between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> or anti-CCP, this being highest
          between anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> and anti-CCP (odds ratio, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13.3</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.001</NUMEX>). Despite this high
          level of correlation, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were
          positive for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> autoantibodies,
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57%</NUMEX> were positive for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>, suggesting considerable
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">variability</ENAMEX> in individual reactivity patterns.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> has been shown in multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> to be
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DRB1</ENAMEX> alleles encoding for the shared
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epitope</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>). In this study, as illustrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>,
          the presence of each of these autoantibodies was
          significantly associated with having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> shared epitope
          alleles, even when only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were
          considered.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Sa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were predominantly
          male (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.01</NUMEX>), had significantly
          higher swollen joint counts (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 ± 12</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 ± 9</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX>), and higher CRP levels
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.6</NUMEX> ± <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 mg/dl</ENAMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/dl; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.03</NUMEX>) at the initial visit.
          Despite subsequently begin treated with significantly
          higher doses of prednisone (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.8 ± 6.0</NUMEX> mg/day versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX> ±
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.01</NUMEX>), the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>-positive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had a higher frequency of erosions than the
          rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.03</NUMEX>). Neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the disease severity measures, and
          analyses evaluating all the other autoantibodies failed
          to reveal a similar trend.
        
        
          Discussion
          Despite a well-documented lack of specificity, RF
          continues to be a central part of the definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>,
          primarily because of its favourable sensitivity profile.
          In our cohort, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> had a sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX>, a specificity
          of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87%</NUMEX>, and an overall accuracy of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> for the diagnosis
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, anti-CCP were all highly specific
          for this diagnosis, and when any of them were present in
          conjunction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>, the specificity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> approached
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>. Potentially of more importance to the clinician is
          the diagnostic value of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> is not
          detectable. Our data indicate that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 31%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF- RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had any of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> or anti-CCP, and
          that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> was the most specific for this diagnosis.
          This modest level of sensitivity suggests that testing
          for this spectrum of autoantibodies carries little
          advantage over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> alone in diagnosing early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, and antiperinuclear factor (APF) have all
          been proposed to identify a common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> present in the
          skin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (pro)filaggrin. It has continued to be
          puzzling why a skin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> would be targeted relatively
          specifically in a disorder that is primarily articular. A
          potential explanation for this may relate to the
          demonstration that citrulline appears to be an essential
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent</ENAMEX> of the antigenic determinants recognized by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APF</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>. The citrulline rich (pro)filaggrin
          molecule makes an ideal substrate for detecting this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivity</ENAMEX>. Moreover, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX>, which, unlike
          (pro)filaggrin, is detectable in rheumatoid synovium, has
          recently been shown to also be citrullinated. It is thus
          possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APE</ENAMEX>, and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> all recognize
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more citrullinated antigens. Despite this
          possibility, the modest degree of concordance between
          them in individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> sera suggests that it is
          unlikely that a single <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> is involved in generating
          these responses.
          This study provides evidence suggesting that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>
          antibodies appear to be a marker for a subset of early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> whose disease may be more severe and erosive.
          Moreover, it was determined that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, and
          anti-CCP were all highly associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>, particularly
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> copies. We examined a spectrum of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          severity indicators including the number of swollen
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joints</ENAMEX>, CRP level, and presence of early radiographic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">erosions</ENAMEX>. Our data indicate that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> was more highly
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with these measures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> severity than any
          other parameter, including the most accepted prognostic
          indicators, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>.
          In conclusion, it is demonstrated that antibodies
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> against putatively citrullinated antigens
          including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SA</ENAMEX>, filaggrin, keratin, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> are the most
          specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, and are detectable early in the disease
          course. It will be of interest to find out whether the
          cumulative prevalence of specific autoantibody subsets
          tends to increase over time, as this would suggest that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivities</ENAMEX> continue to evolve over the course of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthropathy</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autoantibodies</ENAMEX> can be detected in a spectrum of
        rheumatic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> where they may be highly associated with
        distinct clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">syndromes</ENAMEX>. These are often helpful for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagnosis</ENAMEX>, and to some extent, prognosis. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> is
        detected in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with established <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">is an integral part</ENAMEX> of the definition of this disorder.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Sa</ENAMEX> have all been shown to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, and appear to be more specific than RF
        for this disease [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9</ENAMEX>]. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>,
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11, 12</TIMEX>] and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA-1</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>] have also been shown to
        be prevalent in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient populations</ENAMEX>, but not specific
        for this disease.
        There is an evolving understanding of the antigens to
        which these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> are directed, although
        their ultimate pathogenic role, if any, continues to be
        unclear. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APF</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX> identify epitopes carried by
        keratin, profilaggrin and filaggrin, respectively [ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3, 6,</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, 15</TIMEX>]. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> follow a common post-translational
        pathway, which involves a peptidyl-arginine to citrulline
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deimination</ENAMEX>. This modification appears to be central to
        specific antigenicity, giving rise to epitopes recognized
        by sera from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 17</TIMEX>]. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sa antibodies</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> towards an unknown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> that is abundant in
        placental tissue and rheumatoid synovium [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>].
        Interestingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sa antigen</ENAMEX> also appears to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citrullinated</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-33 antibodies recognize the A2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> found in the heterogeneous
        ribonucleoprotein of the splicosome [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> are directed towards domains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 and 4</NUMEX> of
        calpastatin, the natural inhibitor of calpains, which are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the cysteine proteinases that have been
        implicated in articular damage [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>].
        This spectrum of autoantibodies has been evaluated
        primarily in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with well-established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        A number of important questions are unresolved regarding
        the stage of the disease at which each of these antibodies
        arise, and whether indeed some may antedate the clinical
        expression of this disorder. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX> or APF
        could sometimes antedate the appearance of clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> by
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> has been reported [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 21, 22</TIMEX>]. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, AFA
        and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> have been reported to be present in early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> studied have generally been
        small, and the clinical characterization of the patients
        not detailed [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 8, 9, 23, 24</ENAMEX>]. Anticyclic citrullinated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX> (anti-CCP) has recently been evaluated in a cohort
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with early synovitis, and was found to be more
        specific than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> for early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, while having comparable
        sensitivity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>].
        Recently, the clinical features and human leukocyte
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antigen</ENAMEX> (HLA) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> of a well-characterized cohort
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with synovitis of recent onset were presented [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>]. In the current study, we sought to determine the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevalence</ENAMEX> and diagnostic value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> associated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoantibodies</ENAMEX> in this heterogeneous cohort of patients
        with early synovitis. Sera obtained within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> of
        symptom onset were tested for these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>, and their
        presence was related to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> features and subsequent
        clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a 1 year</TIMEX> period. Our data indicate
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, and anti-CCP are all highly specific for
        early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, but demonstrate only a modest degree of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concordance</ENAMEX> in the sera of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>
        identifies a subset of male <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with severe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two hundred</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were recruited
          to an early synovitis study at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of</ENAMEX>
          Health (protocol <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX>-AR-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">194</NUMEX>). The study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had
          persistent synovitis (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">>6</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>) of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX>
          peripheral joint, which had been present for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 1</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with traumatic, septic, and crystal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">induced arthritis</ENAMEX> were specifically excluded.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> underwent a complete clinical evaluation. The
          number of swollen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> was determined by evaluating for
          the presence of effusion and/or synovial thickening in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX>
          peripheral <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> (hips were excluded). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> were
          then followed clinically over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 1 year</TIMEX> period. Routine
          laboratory data were obtained on each visit, including an
          evaluation of acute phase reactants. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anteroposterior</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lateral radiographs</ENAMEX> of the hands and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> were either
          available for evaluation or obtained at the time of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX>. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> set of radiographs was obtained at
          the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 year</TIMEX> visit. All radiographs were evaluated for the
          presence of erosions. Although a proportion of the
          radiographs were felt to have 'possible' or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'questionable</ENAMEX>' erosions, only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with definite
          erosions on either set of radiographs were included in
          the definition of erosions. At the completion of the year
          of observation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were diagnosed as having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          had all met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1987</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College of Rheumatology</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACR</ENAMEX>) criteria [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>] on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> visit. If a patient
          had met ACR criteria, but with follow up was
          unequivocally diagnosed as having another
          well-characterized <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">rheumatic disease</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> was
          not included in the definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Detection of autoantibodies
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IgM RF</ENAMEX> was measured by nephelometry, and a level
          ><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU/ml</ENAMEX> was considered positive. Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> antibodies
          were detected by immunoblot, as previously described [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>]. A partially purified preparation of placental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antigen</ENAMEX> was provided by one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HAM</ENAMEX>), and the
          western <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blot assay</ENAMEX> performed blindly by another (GS).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA-33</ENAMEX> was detected using immunoblot, as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. Filaggrin was obtained from human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">epidermis</ENAMEX> and purified using reversed phase
          coupling to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX> were detected by
          enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX>) as previously
          described [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 5</ENAMEX>]. The cutoff level for positivity (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OD</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.15</NUMEX>) was determined on the basis of results of sera from
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> middle-aged (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-65 years</TIMEX>) blood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. Antibodies to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> were evaluated after generating a cyclic peptide from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">linear</ENAMEX> citrulline containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX>, by substituting
          serine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residues</ENAMEX> by cysteine. Anti-CCP were detected using
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX> as previously described with the linear peptides [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">peptides</ENAMEX> had an unmodified arginine rather
          than citrulline. The cutoff level for positivity (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OD</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.3</NUMEX>) was determined on the basis of generating <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>
          specificity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> in previous assays using local normal
          controls. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX> were detected using immunoflurescence.
          Sections of human breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">epidermis</ENAMEX> were used, and the
          slides were read independently by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CZ</ENAMEX>). Any slides in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> did not agree were
          reread, and a consensus agreed. In all cases, the
          detected autoantibodies were of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">IgG</ENAMEX> class. The
          results were not corrected for total IgG levels.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA</ENAMEX> typing
          HLA-DR typing was done by the molecular polymerase
          chain reaction-sequence specific primers methods using
          specific oligonucleotide sequences as primers as
          previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shared</ENAMEX> epitope (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>) alleles
          included DRB1 *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0101</TIMEX>, *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0102</TIMEX>, *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0401</TIMEX>, *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0404</TIMEX>, *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0405</TIMEX>, *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0408</TIMEX>,
          *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1001</TIMEX>, *<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1402</TIMEX>.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patient groups</ENAMEX> were compared using analysis of
          variance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kruskal-Wallis</ENAMEX> test for continuous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variables</ENAMEX>, and using the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chi</ENAMEX>-squared test for
          proportions. The significance level for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>
          between individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autoantibodies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HLA-DRB1</ENAMEX> alleles
          was adjusted for multiple comparisons using the
          Bonferroni method. Statistical analysis was performed
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epi Info</ENAMEX> statistical software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Disease</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>:
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cdc</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/epo/epi/epiinfo.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Prevalence of the autoantibodies in the patient
          cohort
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1indicates</ENAMEX> the prevalence of a spectrum of known
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoantibodies</ENAMEX> and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> associated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> diagnosed as having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF- RA</ENAMEX>, and nonRA.
          In total, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">87</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were RF-positive, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> of whom did
          not meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> criteria any point during the study period,
          and were classified as having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">undifferentiated arthritis</ENAMEX>.
          Antinuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were detected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65/238</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX>)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and were of comparable prevalence in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient groups</ENAMEX>. Less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in all
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> demonstrated antibodies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSB</ENAMEX>, dsDNA,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ribonucleoprotein</ENAMEX> (RNP), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sm</ENAMEX>. Of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> associated
          antibodies tested, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, anti-CCP, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX> were
          all significantly more prevalent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>+ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> group
          compared with either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF- RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or the nonRA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
          Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were detected in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> of the cohort
          Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were detected in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in
          the cohort. Please note, the prevalence of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX> was significantly higher in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF- RA</ENAMEX> group
          compared with the nonRA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.01</NUMEX>), but there were no
          differences in the prevalence of the other autoantibodies
          between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient groups</ENAMEX>. In total, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">90/106</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX>)
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">75/132</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57%</NUMEX>) of the nonRA patients
          had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> associated antibodies.
        
        
          Diagnostic value of antibodies for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          The diagnostic value of the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> had the highest sensitivity at
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX>, and all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were individually less
          than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> sensitive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> and anti-CCP were
          greater than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX> were
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80-90%</NUMEX> specific, and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA-1</ENAMEX> was not specific for this
          diagnosis. The data further indicate that adding any one
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, or anti-CCP to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> increases the
          specificity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 to 90%</NUMEX>. In the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>,
          the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more of these antibodies carried a
          sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 31%</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF- RA</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Sa</ENAMEX> being
          the most specific at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX>. At the completion of the study,
          of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">37/132</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX>) nonRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> positive for one of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, or anti-CCP, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> had some form of
          spondylarthropathy, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> had a connective tissue disease,
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> continued with a diagnosis of 'undifferentiated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arthritis</ENAMEX>'.
        
        
          Correlation between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> in patient
          sera
          Previous studies have generally suggested a high
          degree of correlation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> sera between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, anti-CCP, and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>. We tested the correlation
          between these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> sera. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correlation</ENAMEX> was highest between anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>
          [odds ratio (OR), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13.3</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.001</NUMEX>), and lowest between
          anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX> (OR, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.09</NUMEX>). In total, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
          had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> antibodies, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64%</NUMEX> of whom had
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. Of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> were in fact positive for
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>,
          anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>). Only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were positive for all
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> antibodies.
          Seropositivity for anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX> was determined on
          the basis of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELISA</ENAMEX> cut-off level as described in the
          Methods section. The relationship between the titers of
          these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>, and between each of them and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>,
          was examined. There was a significant correlation in the
          titers of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX> in individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sera</ENAMEX> ( 
          r =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.46</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.001</NUMEX>). Titers of both
          anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX> were not correlated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> titers. When
          only anti-CCP-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were examined, the mean
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> titer was significantly higher in the RF-positive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>) compared with the
          RF-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.07 ± 0.55</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.6</NUMEX> ±
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.34</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>). A similar tread was seen
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, although this did not reach statistical
          significance. Of note also, the mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> titer for
          RF-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who did not meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> criteria did not
          differ from the RF-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were diagnosed
          as having <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202 ± 172</ENAMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">169</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = not significant).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> are highly associated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> epitope in early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> has been shown in multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> to be
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HLA-DR</ENAMEX> alleles encoding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>. We
          sought to determine if specific autoantibodies were
          particularly associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> alleles in our cohort.
          These data are presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. Overall, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>
          alleles were highly associated with the diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
          (OR <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.0</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.0001</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>,
          and anti-CCP were all associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> alleles,
          particularly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> copies. Interestingly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6/6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
          *<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">0101/ *</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0401</TIMEX> were positive for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of these
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoantibodies</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> antibodies identify a male predominant
          subset of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with severe disease
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4demonstrates</ENAMEX> that, in comparison with all other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Sa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were
          predominantly male (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.01</NUMEX>), had significantly
          higher swollen joint counts (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 ± 12</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 ± 9</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.02</NUMEX>), and higher CRP levels
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.6</NUMEX> ± <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3 mg/dl</ENAMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/dl; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.03</NUMEX>) at the initial visit.
          Despite subsequently being treated with significantly
          higher doses of prednisone (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.8 ± 6.0</NUMEX> mg/day versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX> ±
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>; 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.01</NUMEX>), the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>-positive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had a higher frequency of erosions that the
          rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX>; 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> =<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.03</NUMEX>). Table <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4further</TIMEX> indicates
          that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> was associated with the disease
          severity measures, and analyses evaluating all the other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoantibodies</ENAMEX> failed to reveal a similar trend (data not
          shown). Of interest, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> demonstrated
          the presence of nodules, and this feature was more
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> than with anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>. Analysis of
          the nonRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> did not reveal any clinically
          meaningful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> with any of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autoantibodies</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        A cohort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with synovitis of recent onset was
        evaluated and we sought to determine the prevalence and
        potential clinical utility of a spectrum of autoantibodies
        that has been shown to be associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. To date, most
        of the studies evaluating these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> have been in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with established, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">well-characterized disease</ENAMEX>, and
        their prevalence and diagnostic value in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        early inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> has not been defined. Our
        study evaluated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a few months</TIMEX> of the onset
        of synovitis, and then followed them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 1 year</TIMEX> period to
        determine the best clinical diagnosis. In particular, we
        sought to determine how sensitive and specific each of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX>, alone and in combination, were for early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. We
        utilized the accepted definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> using the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> ACR
        criteria [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. Of note, a large epidemiologic study of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with early <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">inflammatory arthritis</ENAMEX> found that the
        proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who met the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACR</ENAMEX> criteria increased
        if the criteria were applied cumulatively over a 5 year
        period [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. Although the duration of follow up in this
        study was shorter, we found that almost all of the patients
        who had met the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> criteria at the completion of the study
        period had done so on their initial visit.
        Despite a well-documented lack of specificity, RF
        continues to be a central part of the definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>,
        primarily because of its favorable sensitivity profile. In
        our cohort, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> had a sensitivity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX>, a specificity of
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87%</NUMEX>, and an overall accuracy of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> for the diagnosis of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> and anti-CCP were all highly specific for
        this diagnosis, and when any of them were present in
        conjunction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX>, the specificity for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> approached
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>. Potentially of more importance to the clinician is
        the diagnostic value of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> is not
        detectable. Our data indicate that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 31%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF- RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had any of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> or anti-CCP, and that
        anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> was the most specific for this diagnosis. This
        modest level of sensitivity suggests that testing for this
        spectrum of autoantibodies carries little advantages over
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> alone in diagnosing early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>.
        This study provides evidence suggesting that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>
        anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> appear to be a marker for a subset of early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> whose disease may be more severe and erosive.
        These data are consistent with observations in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French RA</ENAMEX>
        cohort, where anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> were associated with severe
        radiographic erosions [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. Indeed, it was determined that
        anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, and anti-CCP were all highly associated with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>, particularly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> copies. We examined a spectrum of
        potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> severity indicators including the number of
        swollen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX>, CRP level, and presence of early
        radiographic erosions. Our data indicate that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> was
        more highly associated with these measures of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> severity
        than any other parameter, including the most accepted
        prognostic indicators, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX>. In particular, there was
        a significantly higher prevalence of radiographic erosions
        in the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> compared with the rest
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, despite the fact that the
        anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had received significantly higher
        doses of prednisone and more disease modifying
        antirheumatic drug therapy. Interestingly, the
        anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>-positive subset in this cohort was strikingly
        predominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>-positive versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>; 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.001</NUMEX>). It has recently been
        shown that, in comparison with female <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, male <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> tended to develop erosions earlier in the disease
        course [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>]. The finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Sa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> both with male gender and with severe early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        further emphasizes the importance of gender differences in
        the clinical expression of this heterogeneous disease.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APF</ENAMEX> have been proposed to all identify a
        common <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> present in the skin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (pro)filaggrin [
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 3, 4, 5, 6</ENAMEX>]. It has continued to be puzzling why a skin
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> would be targeted relatively specifically in a
        disorder that is primarily articular. A potential
        explanation for this may relate to the demonstration that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citrulline</ENAMEX> appears to be an essential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent</ENAMEX> of the
        antigenic determinants recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APF</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX> [
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 17</TIMEX>]. The citrulline rich (pro)filaggrin molecule makes
        an ideal substrate for detecting this reactivity. Moreover,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sa antigen</ENAMEX>, which, unlike (pro)filaggrin, is detectable
        in rheumatoid synovium, has recently also been shown to be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">citrullinated</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. It is thus possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APF</ENAMEX>, and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX> all recognize one or more citrullinated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antigens</ENAMEX>. As with previous studies, the current study
        documents a good overall correlation between these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX>. Nevertheless, the data clearly indicate that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivity</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> does not capture that complete spectrum
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Sa</ENAMEX> reactivity. Indeed, it has been
        shown that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were positive for one or
        more of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were positive for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>, and
        that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 7%</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were positive for all of
        them. Similarly, previous studies evaluating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APF</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFA</ENAMEX> have shown varying degrees of discordance in the
        seropositivity of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient sera</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3, 4, 5, 14</ENAMEX>].
        Moreover, there was a spectrum of reactivity patterns seen
        when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> sera were tested against various citrulline
        containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peptides</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. Together, these data are most
        consistent with the hypothesis that individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> patients
        respond to unique antigenic determinants, that may
        preferentially be citrullinated, but that are likely
        distinct from those of targeted by other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        It was surprising to discover that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-33 antibodies
        were all but absent in this cohort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
        particularly in view of the previously reported prevalence
        of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20-40%</NUMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11, 12</TIMEX>]. This antibody
        was reported to have a prevalence of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 6%</NUMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX>
        cohort of early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. It should be pointed out
        that the testing for anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>, including that performed
        in the current study, was all performed in the same
        laboratory (GS). The reasons for this discrepancy are
        unclear, and may represent inherent differences in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> studied. Alternatively, it is possible that the
        development of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> reactivity increases as the
        diseases progresses. Longitudinal follow up of early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cohorts</ENAMEX>, such as the present <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, will help to further
        clarify this issue.
        In the current study, it was demonstrated that
        antibodies directed against putatively citrullinated
        antigens including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sa</ENAMEX>, filaggrin, keratin, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCP</ENAMEX> are the
        most specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RA</ENAMEX>, and are detectable early in the
        disease course. It will be of interest to find out whether
        the cumulative prevalence of specific autoantibody subsets
        tends to increase over time, as this would suggest that the
        continue to evolve over the course of the arthropathy.
      
    
  
