
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progression</ENAMEX> through the mammalian cell cycle requires
        that gene expression is coordinated with the activity of
        cell cycle control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>. A critical period is the
        transition from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G1</TIMEX> into the S phase, as cells become
        committed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> cycle. Binding of free <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">E2F/DP</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterodimers</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">E2F</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> generally activates transcription
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> required for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1 â†’</TIMEX> S transition and DNA
        synthesis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 3, 4, 5</ENAMEX>], whereas complex formation with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pRb</ENAMEX> or other pocket <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p107</ENAMEX> and pRb-2/p130
        silences transcriptional activities of downstream target
        genes [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6, 7, 8, 9, 10</ENAMEX>]. The resulting retinoblastoma
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rb</ENAMEX>)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">E2F</NUMEX> interaction not only blocks
        transcriptional activation by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">E2F</TIMEX>, but also forms an active
        transcriptional repressor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of cell
        cycle genes that can block transcription by recruiting
        histone deacetylase (HDAC) and remodeling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chromatin</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 13, 14</TIMEX>].
        Several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HDAC inhibitors</ENAMEX> mediate cell growth arrest
        and/or differentiation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 16, 17</TIMEX>]. We chose to examine
        the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPCs</ENAMEX>, which have been reported to induce
        terminal differentiation and/or apoptosis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 19, 20</TIMEX>] in
        many transformed cells. Although treatment with HMBA
        induces remission in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with myelodysplastic syndrome
        and acute myelogenoud <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>, it is not currently used
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">therapeutically</ENAMEX> because of the high dosage required
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">millimolar blood</ENAMEX> levels) and the accompanying toxic side
        effects (thrombocytopenia) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>].
        In this study, we report a novel mechanism of cell
        growth inhibition by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPCs</ENAMEX>, named
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX>, which is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2000</NUMEX>-fold more potent than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMBA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX> at
        least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hydroxamide in place of the amides in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMBA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> was reported to be a histone deacetylase inhibitor and
        caused accumulation of hyperacetylated histone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">H4</ENAMEX> in murine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">erythroleukemia</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. Very little is known about the
        anticancer mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> in epithelial cells; however,
        a recent study demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> diet, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> parts
        per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million</NUMEX> (ppm), fed to rats reduced
        methylenitrosouren-induced mammary tumor incidence by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX>,
        total tumors by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX> and tumor volume by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78%</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. In this
        study, we tested whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> has similar potency to
        inhibit cell growth in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> mammary epithelial cell
        lines, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wt</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM2H</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">null</ENAMEX>). We identified a
        novel mechanism for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> in cell growth arrest through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibition</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX>, concomitant with significant
        increases in the nuclear localization of pRb-2/p130
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-4</ENAMEX>, decreases in key molecules in DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synthesis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p21</ENAMEX>), and increases in histone
        H3 and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">H4 protein</ENAMEX> and acetylation levels. This study
        discusses the difference in recovery from cell growth
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibition</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mammary epithelial cell lines, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TM10</ENAMEX> and
        TM2H, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> removal from cultures.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Development of cell lines and cell culture
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TM2H</ENAMEX> cell lines chosen for this study
          were isolated from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different mouse mammary
          hyperplastic outgrowths: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX>, respectively, as
          described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. The parental TM10 outgrowth is a
          moderately tumorigenic outgrowth line 
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vivo</TIMEX> (time for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of the
          transplants to produce tumors, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 months</TIMEX>) that is
          karyotypically diploid and maintains wild type p53
          expression. TM2H, in contrast, is a highly tumorigenic
          outgrowth line 
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vivo</TIMEX> (time for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of the
          transplants to produce tumors, â‰¤ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 months</TIMEX>),
          karyotypically aneuploid (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> index = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.69</NUMEX>) and contains
          a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p53</NUMEX> mutation resulting in a null phenotype [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>].
          Exponentially growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TM2H</ENAMEX> cell lines in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">DMEM/F12</ENAMEX> media buffered with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 mM HEPES</TIMEX> at pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.6</NUMEX> with
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> adult bovine serum, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 ng/ml</ENAMEX>
          epidermal growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> (EGF) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5 Î¼g/</ENAMEX>ml gentamycin at
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60-70%</NUMEX> confluence were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> (courtesy of Dr
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Marks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Victoria Richon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Sloan</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kettering Cancer Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Cells were
          examined at the time points indicated for cell growth and
          cell cycle activities.
        
        
          Analysis of cell growth
          Cell growth rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM10</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> lines were
          determined using a [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3H</TIMEX>]-thymidine uptake assay, as
          described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. In initial studies, both cell
          lines were cultured in the absence or presence of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.1</NUMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 days</TIMEX>. Both cell lines were
          also cultured for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> at the
          concentrations already mentioned, followed by removing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for a subsequent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 days</TIMEX>. Based on the
          results of these studies, subsequent experiments examined
          asynchronously growing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TM2H</ENAMEX> cell lines in the
          presence or absence of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FACS</ENAMEX> analysis
          Exponentially growing cells at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60-70%</NUMEX> confluence at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> or treated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h were
          pulse-labeled for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BrdU</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St Louis</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The cell cultures were rinsed once with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX> buffered saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>), trypsinized for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 min</TIMEX>
          and rinsed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>. Cells were resuspended
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> Î¼l <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ml cold <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> ethanol
          overnight. Fixed cells were counted and, generally, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> Ã—
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 6cells</TIMEX> were transferred to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> ml <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polypropylene</ENAMEX> tubes,
          centrifuged at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3000</TIMEX> rpm for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> and the supernatant
          removed. Cells were stained for the newly incorporated
          BrdU for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> synthesis using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BrdU</ENAMEX> monoclonal antibodies
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conjugated</ENAMEX> to fluorescein isothiocyanate (FITC) and
          stained with propidium iodide for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> content following
          the protocol described in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton and Dickinson's</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) instructions for flow cytometric
          analysis.
        
        
          Nuclear and cytoplasmic extracts
          To obtain nuclei, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-6</ENAMEX>) Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 7cells</NUMEX> of each cell line
          grown in the presence and absence of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA were
          washed twice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, followed by suspension in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> ml
          nuclear buffer consisting of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> HPO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mM PMSF, 20 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          aprotinin, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml leupeptin, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mM Na 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> VO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 and 5</NUMEX> mM Î²-glycerophosphate. An
          additional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> ml nuclear buffer containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.7%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton</ENAMEX>
          X-100 was then added, after standing on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8-10</ENAMEX> min.
          The suspensions were examined for cell lysis
          microscopically, centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> rpm for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX> at
          4Â°C, and the supernatant designated the cytoplasmic
          fraction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> were washed once with nuclear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX>, and the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">extracts</ENAMEX> were prepared by
          resuspending the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pellets</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> ml buffer containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM HEPES</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.8</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> glycerol, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> mM MgCl
          
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PMSF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> mM
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTTl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> mM Na 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> VO 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaF</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml leupeptin, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mM Î²-glycerophosphate. Sonication was carried out on
          ice using an ultrasonicator <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGC Scientific</ENAMEX>,
          Caithersburg, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), and the mixtures were examined
          microscopically for complete break of the nuclei. The
          supernatants were designated as nuclear extracts after
          centrifugation of the mixtures, and the total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was
          determined in the nuclear and cytoplasmic fractions.
        
        
          Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blot</ENAMEX> and immunoprecipitation
          analysis
          Histones were isolated and lyophilized from nuclear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extracts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treated and untreated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell
          lines following a protocol described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>].
          Histone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were assessed for purification quality on
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> acrylamide gel including calf thymus histones as
          controls before western blot analysis was carried out.
          Histone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were resolved by electrophoresis using
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid-urea gel</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX>w/v urea, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>v/v acetic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">600 Î¼l TEMED</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.7</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> ammonium persulfate
          prepared as described elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>]. Gels were either
          stained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coomassie Brilliant Blue</ENAMEX> or equilibrated to be
          transferred into transfer buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.7%</NUMEX> acetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>). The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">gel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich</ENAMEX> was set up as usual except for the placement
          of the blotting membrane (because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> in this type
          of gel will migrate toward the negative electrode), and
          the procedure was continued as described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>].
          Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">histone</ENAMEX> was resolved into multiple bands and were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visualized</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coomassie</ENAMEX> blue gel. The acetylated histone
          isoforms were detected by immunoblot against acetylated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">histone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">isoforms</ENAMEX> using anti-H3 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> raised and
          characterized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dr Sharon Roth</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MD Anderson Cancer</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> (personal communication) or against acetylated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">histone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">isoforms</ENAMEX> using anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">H4</NUMEX> polyclonal antibody
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upstate Biotechnology Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Placid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          Western blot analysis for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> examined in
          this study was carried out on equal amounts of cellular
          fraction <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein extracts</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼g/sample</ENAMEX>) following a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protocol</ENAMEX> described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. Staining the gel with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coomassie Brilliant Blue</ENAMEX> for each experiment assessed
          equal loading control. TM10 and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM2H cells</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.65</NUMEX> Ã— <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3cells/cm 2</ENAMEX>) seeded in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">flasks</ENAMEX> grew for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX>, and
          were treated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h. Cellular</ENAMEX> fraction
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein extracts</ENAMEX> were prepared after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>]. Primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> used at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 Î¼g/ml were p21/Cip</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), pRb (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IF8</NUMEX>), p107
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">SD9</NUMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p130</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-20</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-20</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-4</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-20</ENAMEX>) and PCNA
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-20</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnology Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, CA,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). All <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> were examined for specificity prior
          to use. The secondary antibodies conjugated to
          horseradish peroxidase (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 : 5000-1</ENAMEX> : 15,000 dilution)
          were used followed by enhanced chemiluminescence
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">detection</ENAMEX> reaction as described by the manufacturer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amersham Pharmacia Biotechnology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amersham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bucks</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>).
          The immunoprecipitation assay followed by western blot
          analysis was as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          equal nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> extract (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 Î¼g/sample</ENAMEX>) was mixed with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> Î¼g anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">E2F</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> followed by the
          addition of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼l <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein A-sepharose beads</ENAMEX> (Amersham
          Biotechnology). The immune <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> was centrifuged, and
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> in the immune <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> were resolved by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE followed by western blot analysis using
          anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pRb</NUMEX>-2/p130 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> as already described for
          western blot analysis.
        
        
          Cyclin-dependent kinase assay
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TM2H</ENAMEX> cell cultures at control and treated
          with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h were examined for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">cyclin D1</TIMEX>, E,
          and A associated kinase activities as described
          previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. Briefly, cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein extracts</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼g</ENAMEX>) were precleared with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> preimmune normal
          rabbit serum followed by immunoprecipitation with either
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> Î¼g anti-cyclin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">D1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">polyclonal antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upstate</ENAMEX>
          Biotechnology), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î</NUMEX>¼g anti-cyclin A polyclonal antibody
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-19</ENAMEX>)-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmingen</ENAMEX>), or normal rabbit
          preimmune serum as a negative control. All antibodies
          were examined for specificity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. Immunoprecipitate
          complexes were examined for kinase assay following a
          procedure described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. The substrates
          utilized in the kinase assays were either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Histone</ENAMEX>-H1
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) or RB <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>). The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H1</ENAMEX> and pRb bands were scanned and
          quantitated densitometrically using a Phosphoimager
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvle</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Immunofluorescent staining
          Exponentially growing cells on slides were fixed in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paraformaldehyde</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEM</ENAMEX> buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> mM Pipes [pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.0</NUMEX>], <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM EGTA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, permeabilized in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triton X-100</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEM</ENAMEX> buffer at room temperature for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> min
          and rinsed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tween 20</TIMEX>, followed
          by incubation in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat dry milk</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBS</ENAMEX> + <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> Tween
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at room temperature. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BrdU</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPI</ENAMEX> double
          immunostaining, cells were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> in media
          supplemented with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5 Î¼M BrdU</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, cells were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubated</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2N</TIMEX> HCl for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> at room temperature prior
          to incubation with the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (this step was
          omitted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pRb-2/p130</TIMEX> immunostaining). Following washing
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times, cells were incubated in a (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 : 50</TIMEX>) dilution
          of mouse anti-BrdU monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehringer</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mannheim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. After
          washing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times, cells were then incubated in
          FITC-conjugated anti-mouse secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 : 400</ENAMEX>)
          dilution for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>, followed by washing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times
          with anti-fade equilibrating buffer and mounting in
          anti-fade mounting medium (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The same sequential steps were followed for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pRb-2/p130</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">immunostaining</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-pRb</ENAMEX>-2/p130
          monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Apoptosis
          Apoptotic activities in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the
          absence and presence of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA were examined by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
          procedures: the TACS 2TdT In Situ Apoptosis Detection
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trevingen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), and the DNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fragmentation Assay</ENAMEX> described elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>].
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell proliferation
          and morphology
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TM2H</ENAMEX> cell lines were used to investigate
          whether the status of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p53</ENAMEX> influences the outcome of SAHA
          treatment. The origin of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell lines was
          described <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>]. The rate of cell proliferation
          at concentrations of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA was
          examined by [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3H</TIMEX>]-thymidine assay at the indicated time
          points. The inhibitory effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> at concentrations
          of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> and higher on cell proliferation was profound
          on both cell lines after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h.</TIMEX> The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> cell
          proliferation continued to be inhibited during the
          following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 days</TIMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX>, whereas minimal
          growth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM2H</TIMEX> cell growth on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 3 and 4</TIMEX> was observed
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1A</ENAMEX>, C). After removing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> from the cultures
          following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> of exposure to all SAHA concentrations,
          TM10 cells continued to be inhibited at concentrations of
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> and higher during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following 4 days</TIMEX> of SAHA
          free cultures (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B), whereas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells resumed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proliferation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1D). These results suggest that SAHA
          induced a dose-dependent block in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX> on both
          cell lines. A <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î</NUMEX>¼M dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> was used in further
          experiments because this concentration seems to be
          unequivocally effective on cell growth inhibition on both
          cell lines after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX> of treatment. Furthermore, no
          apoptotic activity was observed after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 and 48</TIMEX> h of
          treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> in both cell lines (data not
          shown).
          The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> on blocking cell proliferation
          through blocking DNA synthesis was examined by BrdU
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2A), and the cell cycle profile by flow cytometric
          analysis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BrdU</ENAMEX> indices in the control TM10
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells, including all types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BrdU</ENAMEX> staining
          patterns, were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 and 34%</NUMEX>, respectively, indicating that
          the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM2H cells synthesizing DNA</ENAMEX> or in the
          'S phase' were more than double that of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM10 cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          2A). Upon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">¼M SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> cells per
          sample were counted stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BrdU</ENAMEX> against cells
          stained with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPI</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BrdU</ENAMEX> labeling indices dropped
          dramatically to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 and 6%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells,
          respectively. Furthermore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BrdU</ENAMEX> staining revealed the
          size and pattern of replication clusters, which are
          related to the general patterns of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX> in
          mammalian cell nuclei at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid</TIMEX> and late S phase [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>]. These data suggested that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> Î¼M SAHA was capable of
          inhibiting cell proliferation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">both TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell
          lines by blocking DNA synthesis, regardless of their
          differences in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells synthesizing DNA</ENAMEX>.
          These results were confirmed by flow cytometric
          analysis after staining cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BrdU</ENAMEX> for newly
          synthesized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and with propidium iodide for DNA
          content. The percentages of cells in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G1</TIMEX> and S phases
          in control <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> cells at the time of treatment were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX>, respectively, and those for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX>, respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B). The number of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells
          growth arrested in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> phase upon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment for
          24 h increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX>, compared with the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> increase in
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> line, concomitant with similar differences
          in the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> inhibited in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">G2/M</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phases</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 2B). This difference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> cell growth
          arrest between the two cell lines may be attributed to
          their differences in the initial number of cells
          distributed in each cell cycle phase before
          treatment.
          The shape and morphology of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM10</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells grown
          on slides in the presence and absence of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA were
          examined. The dimensions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> randomly selected cells of
          each cell line were measured using a microscope scale.
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TM2H</ENAMEX> mammary epithelial cells measured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.4</NUMEX> Â±
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.1 and 3.6 Â± 1.4 Î¼m</NUMEX> in width and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13.7 Â± 5.9 and 18.6</NUMEX> Â±
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8.0 Î¼m</NUMEX> in length, respectively. TM10 cells generally had
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> extensions, whereas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> extensions. TM10 and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM2H cells</ENAMEX> became flattened and
          increased in both nuclear and cytoplasmic volume after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">¼M SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment. Both cells exhibited less
          distinct intracellular borders (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The morphology
          of both cell lines was similar to cells committed to cell
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX>; however, these mammary cells grown on
          plastic dishes were unable to differentiate by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> on histone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and acetylation
          levels in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell lines
          It is not known whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> alters the protein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acetylation</ENAMEX> levels of various histones in the mammary
          epithelial cells. Changes in the acetylation or
          phosphorylation of histones result in alterations that
          can be visualized as changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> mobility on an
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid-urea gel</ENAMEX> following western blot analysis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 27</TIMEX>].
          These gels separate histones on the basis of charges as
          well as size, resulting in multiple bands for each
          histone that correspond to differently modified isoforms.
          These isoforms can be identified by their characteristic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mobility</ENAMEX> and by staining with antibodies specific to each
          histone isoform [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein</ENAMEX> and acetylation levels of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">histone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H3</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H4</ENAMEX> isoforms on histone samples isolated
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treated and untreated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TM10</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells
          stained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coomassie Brilliant Blue</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A) and by
          western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blots</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B) were examined to identify the
          potency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> as a histone deacetylase inhibitor on
          mammary epithelial cells. We focused on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3 and H4</TIMEX> because
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> are available and acetylation events in those
          histones have been studied. These results suggested that
          SAHA not only increased histone acetylation, as shown in
          H4 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A), but also increased histone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM2H cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4B). The increases in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and acetylation levels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3 and H4</TIMEX> in SAHA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">treated TM10</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TM2H</ENAMEX> cell lines were indicated by the
          strong staining with the acetylation specific antibodies
          of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3 and H4</TIMEX>, while the acetylated slow migrated isoforms
          showed smearing due to the increases in their protein
          level (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5B). We did not, however, observe differences
          in the initial acetylation levels between untreated TM10
          and TM2H cell lines.
        
        
          SAHA induced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hypophosphorylation</ENAMEX> of all the three
          pocket proteins
          Phosphorylation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major pocket <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rb</ENAMEX>,
          p107 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rb2/p130</ENAMEX>, were examined after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment, as
          each pocket <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> affects <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G1</TIMEX> and S phases of the
          cell cycle. Upon treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX>, a
          profound increase in hypophosphorylation of the three
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pocket proteins</ENAMEX> was observed in both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TM10</ENAMEX> and to a lesser
          extent in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells as compared with their control
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>, judged by the faster mobility of the Rb
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pocket protein</ENAMEX> isoforms on SDS gel (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). The
          difference in the level of hypophosphorylated pRb pocket
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein isoforms</ENAMEX> between the two cell lines treated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> may be attributed to differences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> and S phase
          cdk activity (examined in the following section). Results
          suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> induced cell growth arrest through
          dephosphorylation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pRb pocket <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, which may
          be related to inhibition in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G1/S</ENAMEX> phase cdk
          activities.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> inhibits multiple cyclin-associated kinase
          activities
          There are extensive studies on the relation between
          specific phosphorylation sites on pRb and its potential
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">transcription</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">repression</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32, 33, 34</TIMEX>]. It is well known
          that pRb phosphorylation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are recognized by specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cdks</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>], and that most of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> pRb-phosphorylation
          sites are sequentially phosphorylated throughout the cell
          cycle (reviewed in [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34, 35</TIMEX>]). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment resulted in
          G1 cell growth arrest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell lines,
          concomitant with the profound increase in
          dephosphorylation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pRb pocket <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>.
          Therefore, we examined cyclin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">D1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E and A cdk2</ENAMEX> activities
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell cultures after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h treatment with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> because they reflect kinase activities before,
          during and after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G1 â†’</TIMEX> S checkpoint, respectively. The
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyclin</ENAMEX>/cdk2 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> directly reflect the
          sequential events in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> synthesis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>]. The initial
          levels of cyclin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">D1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> and A associated kinase activities
          were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>- and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-fold higher in untreated TM2H
          compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> cells, respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 6A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B C</ENAMEX>).
          These results were predicted based on their differences
          in cell distribution throughout the cell cycle, as
          appeared in the cell cycle profile analysis, and may
          reflect the cell line differences in known p53 status.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyclin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">D1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> and A associated kinase activities decreased
          by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-, and fivefold, respectively, in TM10
          cells compared with control on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment, whereas
          only cyclin <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">D1</ENAMEX> and A associated kinase activities
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decreased</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>- and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6</NUMEX>-fold, respectively) in SAHA
          treated TM2H cells compared with control (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). These
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> inhibits multiple cdk
          activities, and the degree of inhibition was more
          profound in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10</TIMEX> verses TM2H cells.
        
        
          Effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p21</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCNA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">E2F</NUMEX>-4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> as a function of cell growth inhibition
          The difference in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> level of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p21/</ENAMEX>Cip1
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell lines was predicted based on
          their differences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX> status (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7A). Perinuclear
          localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p21</ENAMEX> was detected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only few TM2H</TIMEX> cells
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">null</ENAMEX>) when both cell lines were immunostained for
          p21, whereas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p21</TIMEX> was localized in both cytoplasmic and
          nuclear compartments in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wt</ENAMEX>) (data not
          shown). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p21</NUMEX> expression level decreased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> in TM10
          cells upon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7A). These results
          suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SAHA</ENAMEX> inhibited DNA synthesis in the presence
          or absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p21 protein</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCNA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 7</ENAMEX>] are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> â†’ S transition and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX>. Because such
          regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> can be present at different levels
          and in different molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> in nuclei as
          compared with the cytoplasm, separation of the two
          cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">compartments</ENAMEX> allowed an assessment of the
          site(s) at which these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> exert their primary
          activity unimpeded by artifacts that may result from
          intermixing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> compartments. In the untreated cells,
          the cytoplasmic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PCNA protein</ENAMEX> levels in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell
          lines were similar, but the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCNA</ENAMEX> in the nuclear
          fraction was fourfold higher in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells compared with
          TM10 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7B). The effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> was profound on
          the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">PCNA</ENAMEX> fraction in both cell lines, but minimal
          on the cytoplasmic PCNA fraction. The pronounced
          difference in the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCNA</ENAMEX> in growing versus
          arrested <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> is in accordance with the determinant role
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCNA</ENAMEX> plays in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> synthesis [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37, 38</TIMEX>].
          To further investigate the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> on
          inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX>, we examined <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> as a key
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1 â†’</TIMEX> S transition and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX>. The
          initial nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> level of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> in the untreated
          TM2H <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.8</NUMEX>-fold higher compared with the TM10
          cell line (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7C). Nuclear E2F-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> was completely
          abolished in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> cells after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment, and
          decreased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>-fold in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 7C). These results
          demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment also inhibits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">E2F</NUMEX>-1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels.
          It has been reported that expression of 
          E2F-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> does not change in
          relation to cell growth, although a modest increase can
          sometimes be observed in growing cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>]. E2F-4
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels were examined in the nuclear and
          cytoplasmic fractions in both cell lines with and without
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels did not change upon SAHA
          treatment in either fractions of either cell line (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          7D). It is noteworthy that the mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> in G1
          cell growth arrest may target the expression of specific
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX> involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> synthesis as it inhibited E2F-1
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCNA</ENAMEX>, but not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-4</ENAMEX>, suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> may cause
          different levels of histone acetylation at distinct
          regions of the genome.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rb2/p130</ENAMEX> subcellular localization and interaction with
          E2F-4 was examined in both cell lines in the absence and
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rb2/p130</ENAMEX> is an important
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cytoplasmic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-4</ENAMEX> and is capable of inducing
          nuclear localization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> upon cell growth
          arrest and differentiation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40, 41</TIMEX>]. Immunostaining
          analysis using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibody</ENAMEX> specific for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pRb2/</ENAMEX>p130
          revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pRb2/ p130</ENAMEX> nuclear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">localization</ENAMEX> in both cell lines treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX> compared with their controls (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 8A). To examine
          whether the increase in hypophosphorylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pRb2/</ENAMEX>p130
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) and its nuclear localization after SAHA
          treatment was associated with interaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-4</ENAMEX>, equal
          amounts of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein extracts</ENAMEX> were
          immunoprecipitated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E2F-4</ENAMEX> followed
          by western blot analysis against <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pRb2/p130</ENAMEX> antibodies.
          Interestingly, the results revealed an unequivocal
          increase in the nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pRb2/p130</ENAMEX> protein level
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-4</ENAMEX> in both cell lines treated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SAHA (Fig</ENAMEX>. 8B). These intriguing results indicate that
          the interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hypophosphorylated pRb2/p130</ENAMEX> with
          E2F-4 followed by enhancement in nuclear location after
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment is a novel mechanism in SAHA-mediating
          cell growth arrest.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        In this study, we present novel data on the mechanism of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> in cell growth arrest on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> mammary epithelial
        cell lines, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wt</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM2H</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">null</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> was
        able to increase histone <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">H3</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">H4 protein</ENAMEX> and acetylation
        levels, and caused a profound decrease in the protein
        levels of key molecules, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX>, essential for DNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">synthesis</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> significantly enhanced the
        interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">pRb2/p130</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-4</ENAMEX> and the nuclear
        localization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pRb2/p130-E2F-4</ENAMEX> complex. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> also
        resulted in the inhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G1/S</ENAMEX> kinase activities and,
        consequently, hypophosphorylation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pRb pocket
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX>, which led to G1 cell growth arrest and dramatic
        decreases in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX> in both cell lines. TM10 cells
        continued to be inhibited for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 days</TIMEX> upon removing SAHA
        after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> of treatment, whereas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM2H</NUMEX> cells were able to
        recover their proliferation potentials. A summary of the
        differences in the molecular status and cell cycle profile
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell lines before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment are
        summarized in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. These differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p21 protein</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BrdU</ENAMEX> index were predicted based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p53</NUMEX> status of these two
        cell lines and are in parallel with other reports on
        mammary tumors, where the absence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX> results primarily
        in greater proliferation response in the affected cell [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>]. No differences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">histone H3 and H4</TIMEX> acetylation levels
        were, however, observed in relation to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p53</NUMEX> status between
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> lines. It is not known at this point whether
        specific mutations of p53 alter the degree of histone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acetylation</ENAMEX> in cells. Histone acetylation and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> mutation
        appear not to be correlated in this study; nevertheless, it
        is necessary and more sensitive to examine histone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acetylase</ENAMEX> and deacetylase activities in correlation to p53
        status.
        The mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> in blocking DNA synthesis, as
        demonstrated by flow cytometric analysis, appeared similar
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">both TM10 and TM2H</TIMEX> cell lines, and implicated several
        events. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> increased histones <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3 and H4</TIMEX> protein
        levels after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX> of treatment, which could result in cell
        cycle arrest. It has been reported that upregulation of
        KIAA0128 gene expression, which has been implicated in
        activation of histone mRNA synthesis, was related to cell
        cycle arrest in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MCF-7 cells</ENAMEX> after treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX>]. As <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment increased histone (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3 and H4</TIMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and acetylation levels in both cell lines, this may
        have altered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of histones with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, thereby
        altering nucleosomal conformation and stability [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 44</TIMEX>].
        Local perturbations of chromatin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> can specifically
        affect the accessibility and/or function of transcriptional
        regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that bind <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA sequences</ENAMEX> in the region
        where histone acetylation or deacetylation took place [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HDAC inhibitors</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">trichostatin A</ENAMEX> and trapoxin,
        modulate gene expression in either a positive, negative or
        neutral fashion [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>]. Ample studies have demonstrated the
        implication of histone hyperacetylation in gene
        transcription but also in silencing gene expression of
        others [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 44, 45</TIMEX>].
        It is well known that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> regulates transcription of
        genes predominantly expressed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the G1 â†’</TIMEX> S transition
        such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyclins</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 5</ENAMEX>], cdks [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>], 
        E2F-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>], the 
        RB1 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> suppressor gene [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8, 47</ENAMEX>],
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA replication</ENAMEX> and repair enzymes and
        factors [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. It appears that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> has a profound
        inhibitory impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels of key molecules,
        E2F-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCNA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p21</ENAMEX>, essential for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX>. Based on
        previous reports, disintegration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyclin</ENAMEX>/cdk
        complexes important for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX> is correlated to
        E2F-1 expression level [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 5</ENAMEX>]. It is thus conceivable to
        interpret that the profound inhibition in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> and PCNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX> of exposure to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> may
        result in disintegration and deactivation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">D1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX> and A
        cdk2 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX>, which consequently leads to
        hypophosphorylation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rb</ENAMEX> pocket <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>. It is
        plausible to suggest that the inhibition in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> protein
        levels by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> was either at the transcription level or
        induction of the ubiquitin-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> ligase responsible for
        E2F-1 degradation, but not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-4</ENAMEX>, and this resulted in
        blocked DNA synthesis. Further work is necessary to prove
        whether the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> is at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> transcription
        level or on stability of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E2F-1 protein</ENAMEX>.
        The inhibition in nuclear p21 in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treated TM2H as
        well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> cells underscores that SAHA-arrested cell
        growth is through a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p53</NUMEX>-independent pathway. A recent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> indicated that the transcription of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p21</ENAMEX> Cip1and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> of acetylated histones associated with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> and coding regions of that gene were induced after
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.5</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> and fall by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> h in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T24</TIMEX> bladder
        carcinoma cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>]. Although we have utilized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> Î¼M
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX>, our results are in agreement with their data on the
        fall in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p21</TIMEX> level after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX> of treatment.
        A more intriguing and novel mechanism of SAHA-mediated
        cell growth arrest was the enhanced interaction and nuclear
        localization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rb2/p130-E2F-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> in both cell lines
        after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX> of treatment. It is well documented that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">E2F</NUMEX>-1
        possesses an intrinsic nuclear localization signal whereas
        E2F-4 is devoid of such signal [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49, 50</TIMEX>], and that the
        mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-4</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">localization</ENAMEX> has been documented
        to be through its interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rb2/p130</ENAMEX> pocket <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>,
        which impedes cell cycle progression [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39, 40</TIMEX>].
        Furthermore, recent studies demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rb2/p130</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">complexes with E2F-4</ENAMEX> actively represses <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> transcription
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell differentiation</ENAMEX> and growth arrest, and that this
        complex was considered the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> during the
        early <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">G1</NUMEX> phase [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39, 51, 52</TIMEX>]. Other reports suggest that Rb
        recruitment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HDAC1</TIMEX> activity repressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 13</TIMEX>].
        Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> increases acetylation of histones <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">H3 and H4</TIMEX>,
        it is not known whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> is able to inhibit all HDAC
        activities of all types of histones, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HDAC1</ENAMEX>, or
        whether the profound increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rb2/p130-E2F-4</ENAMEX> nuclear
        complex after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment may have an alternative
        pathway other than recruitment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HDAC1</TIMEX> activity.
        The difference between TM10 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wt</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM2H</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">null</ENAMEX>)
        cell cultures in response to removing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.5</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> following
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX> of treatment was significant. We suggest that
        it might reflect their difference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX> status. The TM10
        cells did not exhibit signs of cell proliferation or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'recovery</ENAMEX>' during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following 3-4 days</TIMEX>. TM2H cells, in
        contrast, recovered by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88%</NUMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> of treatment.
        Longer treatment may be necessary to inhibit TM2H (p53
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">null</ENAMEX>) mammary epithelial cells as preliminary results
        indicate TM2H <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> did not recover after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 days</TIMEX> of SAHA
        treatment (data not shown). We suggest that the difference
        in growth recovery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between TM10</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wt</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM2H</TIMEX> (p53
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">null</ENAMEX>) cell lines after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 days</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> may be
        attributed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> factors, both related to their p53
        status. Firstly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the p53</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM10</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wt</ENAMEX>) cells might have
        been acetylated upon treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼M</NUMEX> SAHA for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. Recent studies demonstrated acetylation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">p53</ENAMEX> in the
        C-terminal domain increased the DNA-binding capacity of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53, 54, 55</TIMEX>]. This event is obviously not present
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM2H</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">null</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>, although <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">TM10</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wt</ENAMEX>)
        have lost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64%</NUMEX> of their nuclear p21 during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment,
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">the remaining 36%</NUMEX> of the nuclear p21 plus the continued
        synthesis of p21 by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p53</TIMEX> activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55, 56, 57</TIMEX>] during the
        recovery period would maintain TM10 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in the inhibited
        state for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX>. TM2H <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">null</ENAMEX>),
        in contrast, lack both negative regulatory potentials of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acetylated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> and the availability of nuclear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">p21</TIMEX>.
        We conclude that the mechanisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX> inhibition of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA synthesis</ENAMEX> and cell growth arrest at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">G1</TIMEX> were similar in
        both TM10 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wt</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TM2H</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">p53</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">null</ENAMEX>) mouse mammary
        epithelial cell lines. A proposed mechanism of SAHA
        stresses the involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pRb2/p130-E2F-4</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">interaction</ENAMEX> and
        nuclear localization, which ultimately results in cell
        growth arrest and repression in nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E2F-1</ENAMEX> and PCNA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> levels, and the subsequent inhibition of DNA
        synthesis in both cell lines. However, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p53</NUMEX> status was
        critical in maintaining growth arrest in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">TM10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 days</TIMEX>
        after removing <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SAHA</ENAMEX> treatment, whereas TM2H <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (p53
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">null</ENAMEX>) recovered growth arrest under the same conditions. We
        therefore suggest that the dose and time regimen for
        histone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">deacetylase inhibitors</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAHA</ENAMEX>, may have to
        consider the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">p53</NUMEX> status of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancers</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX> = confidence interval; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPRD</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Practice</ENAMEX>
        Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Database; NA-NSAID</ENAMEX> = nonaspirin nonsteroidal
        anti-inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RR</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relativerisk</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UGIC</ENAMEX> = upper
        gastrointestinal complications.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX> = confidence interval;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPRD</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Practice Research Database; NA-NSAID</ENAMEX> =
        nonaspirin nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RR</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">relativerisk; UGIC</ENAMEX> = upper gastrointestinal
        complications.
      
    
  
