
  
    
      
        Introduction
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, the incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> has
        become one of the most rapidly increaing among malignant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tumours</ENAMEX>. With progress in understanding of the nature of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, diagnosis and treatments have been improved.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemotherapy</ENAMEX> has become more and more important and is
        considered to be a major treatment to avoid the recurrence
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> after surgery [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. Although the remission rate
        is higher in previously untreated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, relapse occurs
        soon. It has been reported that most initially responsive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> acquire a multidrug resistance (MDR) phenotype.
        Some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> even in their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> treatment.
        In metastatic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, the development of a MDR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenotype</ENAMEX> is primarily responsible for insensitivity to a
        new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>].
        Attention has been focused recently on the study of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for reversing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX>. Although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of compounds
        have been found 
        in vitro to be able to modulate the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> phenotype, their clinical application was limited owing
        to high toxicity 
        in vivo . The key to the clinical use
        of reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> therefore lies in searching for agents
        with low toxicity and high reversal activity [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. In the
        past, many progestogen compounds, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX> and
        medroxyprogesterone, have been shown to have reversal
        effects 
        in vitro [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 5, 6, 7</ENAMEX>].
        Unfortunately, the effective concentration to reverse drug
        resistance 
        in vivo is very difficult to achieve
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nomegestrol</ENAMEX> (NOM), a derivative of megestrol (MG),
        has very low toxicity. There is almost no incidence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">liver lesions</ENAMEX>, pituitory-inhibiting activity, cortisol-like
        activity or oestrogen-like activity, which are common in
        other progestogen compounds [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> might therefore be
        suitable for clinical use.
        In many previous studies on MDR reversal by compounds
        related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>, attention has been paid to the modulation
        of P-glycoprotein (<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-gp</ENAMEX>) function. The reversal mechanism
        consists of, for example, binding directly to P-gp,
        inhibiting the transport function of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">efflux</ENAMEX>,
        increasing the intracellular accumulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and
        changing lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mobility</ENAMEX> in the plasma membrane [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 10, 11</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>]. However, different compounds have different
        mechanisms. No results on the reversal effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> or on
        its mechanism were available. The present study was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> to the reversal activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adriamycin</ENAMEX> (ADR)-resistant (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">MCF7/ADR</ENAMEX>) cells, and to compare
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> with classic reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">verapamil</ENAMEX> (VRP),
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tamoxifen</ENAMEX> (TAM), droloxifene (DRO) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX>]. A possible
        reversal mechanism was explored by studying the cell cycle,
        intracellular drug accumulation and the expression of mRNA
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MDR1</TIMEX>, glutathione S<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">-transferase Pi</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ€</ENAMEX>),
        MDR-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (MRP) and topoisomerase IIÎ±
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX>).
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Cell line and cell culture
          The cell lines MCF7<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/WT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR-sensitive</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCF7/ADR</ENAMEX>
          were used in this study; they were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>] and maintained in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dulbecco</ENAMEX>'s modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium
          incubated at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 -95%</NUMEX> air at high humidity, and
          passaged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 2-3 days</TIMEX>. Cells were digested with mixture
          of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.025%</NUMEX> trypsin (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco BRL</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>).
          Medium for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells was further supplemented with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai Hualian Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd.</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>). Before use in experiments, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">MCF7/ADR</ENAMEX>
          cells were cultured in drug-free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 weeks</TIMEX>.
        
        
          The
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-(<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,5-dimethylthiazol-2-yl</NUMEX>)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">diphenyl</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2H</NUMEX>-tetrazolium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bromide</ENAMEX> (MTT) assay of cytotoxic activity
          Cells were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> (purchased as the acetate
          ester from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pharmaceutical College</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai Medical</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>) and other reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAM</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRO</ENAMEX> (a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xia Peng</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VRP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shanghai</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hualian Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> assays were
          performed as follows [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>]: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCF7/WT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCF7</ENAMEX>/ADR cells
          were each harvested with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX> trypsin<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/EDTA</ENAMEX> and counted.
          Cell lines were seeded into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well plates at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 4viable
          cells per well and left to attach to the plate for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h.
          After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 h</TIMEX>, the medium was changed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> containing or
          lacking test reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> or ADR. The final volume was
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î¼l</NUMEX> per well. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> was removed after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">72 h of</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubation</ENAMEX>. Other medium containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>)
          was added to each well in a volume of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 Î¼l</NUMEX> and
          incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 h.</TIMEX> The medium was then removed and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">180 Î</NUMEX>¼l
          of dimethyl sulphoxide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) was added to each well for
          half <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> at room temperature. A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well microtitre
          plate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynatech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chantilly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was used to
          determine 
          A 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">570</NUMEX> . The mean concentration in each
          set of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> was measured. To avoid interference by
          the red fluorescence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> concentrations above <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 Î¼M</NUMEX>, a
          blank well containing the corresponding ADR concentration
          without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> was set up and subtracted from the test well
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">absorbance</ENAMEX>. The absorbance of untreated controls was
          taken as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> survival, and the percentage inhibition was
          calculated as cell survival rate (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> - 
          B )/( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">U -</ENAMEX> 
          B ), and growth inhibition (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX>) =
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-cell survival rate (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">%</NUMEX>), where 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> (treated) is the absorbance of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug-</ENAMEX>treated cells, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> (untreated) is the absorbance of
          untreated cells and 
          B (blank) is the absorbance in the
          absence of both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX>.
          IC 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> values were determined graphically
          from relative survival curves.
          The fold reversal was calculated as IC 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR/IC</ENAMEX> 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> plus reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          chain reaction (RT-PCR) analysis
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> treatment
            Cells were subjected to mild treatment with trypsin
            and plated at a density of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">10 5cells/ml.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> was tested
            at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼M</NUMEX>; cells were passaged as usual. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2, 3</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
            and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>-containing medium was removed and
            cells were harvested.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolation
            Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted from the treated cell line
            or control samples with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIzol</ENAMEX> system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco BRL</ENAMEX>),
            in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions. The
            concentration and purity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> were quantified
            spectrophotometrically by measuring 
            A 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX> and 
            A 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX> ; the ratio 
            A 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">260 /</ENAMEX> 
            A 
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX> of pure <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> is approximately
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX>. The sample was stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-70Â°C</TIMEX>.
          
          
            Reverse transcription reaction
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> sample was added to a sterile RNase-free
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">micro</ENAMEX>-centrifuge tube, and nuclease-free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was
            added to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9.5 Î¼l</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> sample was heated to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70Â°C</NUMEX> for
            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>, then chilled on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. To this, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4 Î¼l</NUMEX> of a 5Ã—AMV
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> reaction buffer, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MgCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM
            dNTP, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rnasin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 U/Î¼l</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼l</NUMEX> of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oligo</ENAMEX>(dT) 
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/Î¼l</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼l</NUMEX> of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AMV RT</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U/Î¼l</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>) were added. The final volume
            was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼l</NUMEX>. This mixture was centrifuged shortly, then
            incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> h to allow the AMV RT enzyme to
            catalyse the formation of cDNA on the mRNA template.
            The enzyme was then inactivited by being heated to 95Â°C
            for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> min. The cDNA was stored at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-20Â°C</TIMEX> until required
            for analysis.
          
          
            PCR
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was set up as described previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. Two
            sets of primers were used in all reactions to yield the
            amplification of an endogenous control gene (Î²-actin,
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">383</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>) and the specific target genes of interest
            [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">157</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MDR1</TIMEX> (a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jian Lin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">203</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">139</NUMEX>
            bases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> independently (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]]. PCR
            amplification was performed on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX> product (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼M</ENAMEX>) incubated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U of</ENAMEX> 
            Taq <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA polymease</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promega</ENAMEX>) in a
            <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î</NUMEX>¼l reaction mixture containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 Î¼M 10 mM</NUMEX> dNTP,
            <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MgCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10Ã—</NUMEX> 
            Taq <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> polymerase buffer from
            Promega, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> pmol of internal standard gene upstream and
            downstream primers to minimize variations in
            amplification efficiency between tubes.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed with the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Amp</ENAMEX> PCR
            Systems <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9700</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perkin Elmer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Watsonville</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). For
            MDR1, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, after an initial
            denaturation at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> min, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of PCR
            amplification were performed, each cycle consisting of
            a denaturing step of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">94Â°C</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> min, annealing at
            54Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min</TIMEX>, and extension at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 min</TIMEX>,
            followed by a final step at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72Â°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min. For the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> gene, after an initial denaturation step of 95Â°C
            for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 min</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplification were
            performed, each cycle consisting of a denaturing step
            of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">95Â°C</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> s, annealing at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> s, and
            extension at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">73Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> s, followed by a final step at
            72Â°C for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> min. The amplified fragments were detected
            by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">w/v</ENAMEX>) agarose gel electrophoresis and staining
            with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.3 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml ethidium bromide (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was
            analysed on image analysis system IS1000 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpha</ENAMEX>
            Innotech, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Leandro</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The specific gene
            expression level was determined semiquantitatively by
            calculating the ratio of density metric value from
            specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> expressed in relation to the internal
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard</ENAMEX> (specific gene expression/Î²-actin
            expression).
          
        
        
          Immunocytochemistry staining
          Treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼M</NUMEX> NOM was performed as above (see
          RT-PCR). A smear was made from each cell sample; after
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">smear</ENAMEX> had dried in air, cells were fixed in acetone
          for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Immunocytochemistry</ENAMEX> was performed with an
          avidin-biotin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> immunoperoxidase method as
          described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhou</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>], with some modifications.
          Monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> against P-gp (JSB-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) was purchased
          from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boehringer Mannheim Biochemica</ENAMEX>; monoclonal
          antibodies against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dako Corporation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neomarker</ENAMEX>, respectively. In brief,
          after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> washes with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">phosphate-buffered</NUMEX> saline (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>),
          fixed cells in each smear were layered with the primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> against P-gp (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:20 dilution</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ€</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:25</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dilution) and TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:50 dilution</TIMEX>) and incubated
          overnight (a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> h). After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> washes with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, the cells were incubated with secondary antibody
          mixture of anti-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ig</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:200</ENAMEX> dilution; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huamei BG Co</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ltd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at room temperature. The
          cells were washed as before and then incubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
          complex (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:100</ENAMEX> dilution; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huamei BG Co Ltd</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 h</TIMEX> at
          room temperature. After being washed, cells were
          tetrahydrochloride dihydrate (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.02%</NUMEX> H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15-30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">min. Cells</ENAMEX> were
          washed again with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and counterstained with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">haematoxylin</ENAMEX>.
          In each assay, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> categories of staining were
          observed as defined previously [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. In brief, we first
          determined the staining grade I: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0</ENAMEX>, no staining; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, pale
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yellow; 2</ENAMEX>, brown yellow; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, brownish. Then we calculated
          the grade II according to the ratio of positive staining
          cells to total tumour cells: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0</ENAMEX>, no staining; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, less than
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11-50%</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51-75%</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 75%</NUMEX>. Finally,
          according to total grade (total grade = grade I Ã— grade
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>), the immunocytochemistry assay standard was
          determined as follows: total grade <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>, negative; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-3,</ENAMEX>
          feeble positive; 4 or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, weak positive; 6 or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, moderate
          positive; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 7</NUMEX>, strong positive.
        
        
          ADR accumulation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accumulation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> was monitored using a standard
          procedure by incubating <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCF7/ADR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Ã— 10 5/ml</ENAMEX>) for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> in the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX>) alone or in
          combination with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 or 5 Î¼M</NUMEX>). Cells were then
          harvested and washed twice with cold (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0Â°C</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, then
          placed in ice-water to block the reaction until analysis.
          After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX>, the fluorescence intensity of cells
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> 4/ml) was determined by flow cytometry (FCM)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAC-SCalibar; Becton Dickinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Cell cycle analysis
          Cells were plated at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Ã— 10 5/ml</NUMEX> in specific medium
          supplemented as above. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> h the medium was replaced
          with fresh medium containing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> alone or in combination
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼M</NUMEX>). The cells were harvested after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 h and</TIMEX>
          washed twice with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>, then fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">v/v</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>.
          The sample was concentrated by removing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> and
          treated with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">v/v) Triton X-100</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNase</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min. Staining</ENAMEX> of cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was performed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.05%</NUMEX>
          propidium iodide for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCM</ENAMEX> analysis was
          performed by acquiring a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Ã— 10 5nuclei</NUMEX>. Cell
          cycle analysis was performed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MultiCycle</ENAMEX> software
          package (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          Levels of statistical significance were evaluated with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> independent experiments by using
          Student's 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">t</ENAMEX> test. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P <0.05</ENAMEX> was considered
          statistically significant.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Enhancement of chemosensitivity in treated
          cells
          Cytotoxicity was expressed as the percentage growth
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inhibition</ENAMEX> compared with untreated control cells. MTT
          assays showed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> and other
          various reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> showed no toxicity towards the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> lines. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 Î¼M</ENAMEX>)
          for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX> the cell growth rate was normal compared with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> cells, as judged by staining with trypan blue.
          The results showed that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 10</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> significantly
          increased the sensitivity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX>, the
          degrees of reversal being <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>-fold, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-fold and 8</NUMEX>-fold,
          respectively (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1b). The reversal activity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼M</NUMEX> NOM was markedly stronger than that of the same
          concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) and was similar to
          that of the classic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agents VRP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAM</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/WT cells
          neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> nor other reversal compounds increased
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemosensitivity</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          MDR-related gene expression in NOM-treated
          cells
          
            MDR1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ mRNA expression
            After treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the MDR1</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€
            expression levels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells were modulated in a
            time-dependent manner. The expression of both mRNA
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX> began to decrease on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second day</TIMEX> ( 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P <0.05</ENAMEX> and 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.01</ENAMEX>, respectively), and
            reached the lowest level on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third day</TIMEX> (both 
            P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>). The expression
            level began to rise as detected on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth day</TIMEX> ( 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P >0.05</ENAMEX> and 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P <0.05</ENAMEX>, respectively), and
            reached a level close to that of untreated controls on
            the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>).
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> mRNA expression
            After treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> mRNA expression
            level of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells tended to decrease on the
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, with no statistical significance. No
            significant change was found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> expression
            level when measured on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> and
            tenth days after treatment in comparison with the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. No significant changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> mRNA
            expression levels were found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/WT cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
          
        
        
          Expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-gp, GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ and TopoIIÎ±
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteins</ENAMEX>
          MCF7/ADR cells had high expression levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-gp</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GSTÏ€ proteins</ENAMEX> and a moderate expression level of TopoIIÎ±
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. MCF7/WT cells expressed a high level of TopoIIÎ±
          only: <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-gp and GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expression were undetectable.
          After treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>, the expression levels of P-gp
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells gradually declined, the lowest
          level being on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third day</TIMEX>; on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth day</TIMEX> their
          expression levels began to rise. No marked difference
          whose TopoIIÎ± <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> expression was found before and
          after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> treatment in either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCF7/ADR</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">MCF7</NUMEX>/WT cells.
          The effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> on the expression of drug resistance
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> were similar to those of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> on mRNA expression
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Figs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4and 5</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          ADR accumulation and cell cycle changes in
          NOM-treated cells
          The accumulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells was much
          less than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/WT cells. Each cell line was treated
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 and 5</NUMEX> Î¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>. Marked increases in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intracellular</ENAMEX> ADR accumulation were found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR
          cells, the increases being <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.7</NUMEX>-fold, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX>-fold and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>-fold, respectively. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> did not increase ADR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/WT cells (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCM</ENAMEX> analysis was
          performed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells treated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> h with ADR
          alone or in combination with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>. The results
          showed that when the ADR concentration was increased from
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î¼M to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 Î¼M</NUMEX>, only a small increase in arrested cells at
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 M</ENAMEX> phase was found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells
          treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> alone. However, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> was used in
          combination with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼M <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>, a marked arrest was seen. NOM
          alone failed to induce any change in the cell cycle (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          7and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The overexpression of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-gp</ENAMEX> in tumour <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell membrane</ENAMEX> is
        considered to be the major mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P-gp</ENAMEX> is able
        to pump various anticancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> out of cells, thus
        resulting in a low intracellular drug concentration that is
        insufficient to kill tumour cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. To use compounds
        with low toxicity, or with none at all, to bind P-gp and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> its transport function is the most common method of
        reversing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Progesterone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX> belong to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">progestogen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX> is not a substrate
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-gp</ENAMEX>, it can directly bind to P-gp and block the
        transport of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">efflux</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX> is a strong reversal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agent</ENAMEX>: its capacity to increase intracellular accumulation
        of vincristine is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-fold that of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>].
        Previous results have shown that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> dose of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> mg MG
        resulted in a plasma concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Î¼M</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>]; however,
        to reverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î</NUMEX>¼M is necessary in theory. Because high
        doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX> induce vomiting, oedema, dizziness and
        androgen-like side-effects, the ideal effective
        concentration is difficult to obtain 
        in vivo . Therefore, the search for
        new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> with low toxicity is in progress to meet an
        urgent need for clinical applications.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> is a progestogen compound used in family planning.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, biological activities other than
        contraception have been found [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. Animal experiments
        have demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> has almost no toxicity. Its full
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemical</ENAMEX> name is
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,20-diketo-6-methyl-17-Î±-hydroxy-19-norpregna-4,6-diene</NUMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>].
        The present study has demonstrated that NOM
        significantly sensitizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCF7/ADR</ENAMEX> cell line to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> in a
        concentration-dependent manner, but has no similar effect
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/WT cells. The reversal effects of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 and 5</NUMEX> Î¼M
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>-fold, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-fold and 8</NUMEX>-fold, respectively. The
        enhancement of chemosensitivity to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> was stronger
        than that by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX>, a precursor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>, at corresponding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concentrations</ENAMEX> ( 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><0.05</NUMEX>). The reversal effect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> was similar to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VRP</ENAMEX>, which is a classical
        reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> with a high reversal activity; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> therefore
        also has a strong reversal activity.
        Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRO</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-oestrogen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAM</ENAMEX> is a
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-line <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> used in endocrinotherapy for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>.
        Anti-oestrogens can inhibit P-gp function by binding it [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>]. In our study, the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> was significantly
        greater than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRO</ENAMEX>.
        The development of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MCF7/ADR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> was induced by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">treating MCF7/WT</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> phenotype is not altered
        after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 months</TIMEX> of serial passaging in drug-free medium [
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24, 25</TIMEX>]. MCF7/ADR cells have been demonstrated to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overexpress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDR1/P-gp</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MRP genes</ENAMEX>.
        They are therefore good cell models for studying the effect
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> MDR.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Semiquantitative</ENAMEX> RT-PCR analysis is a sensitive and
        specific method [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 27</TIMEX>]. A variety of methods using
        either quantitative or semequantitative RT-PCR have been
        used to determine relative initial target mRNA levels in
        samples. However, in all of these methods undefined
        variations in amplification complicated the interpretation
        of results. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> use internal amplification
        standards in an attempt to correct for variations between
        tubes. In the present study, as in many other studies, we
        chose to use endogenous standards. The reference mRNA and
        target mRNA are usually processed together throughout the
        experiments, from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> extraction until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplification.
        This tends to minimize differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> yields between
        samples.
        It has been considered that the overexpression of
        MDR1<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/P-gp</ENAMEX> is a major mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> in tumour cells [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>]. A few studies have reported that some reversal agents
        can inhibit MDR1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/P</ENAMEX>-gp expression. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stein</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>] have found that cytokines
        such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">interleukin-2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">interferon-Î³</ENAMEX> and tumour necrosis
        factor-Î± were capable of decreasing the expression of MDR1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mRNA</ENAMEX> in the colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carcinoma</ENAMEX> cell lines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">HCT15 and HCT16</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liu</ENAMEX>
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>] treated MCF7/ADR cells
        with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> herb 
        Fructus psoraleae for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX> h and found
        that P-gp expression became undetectable. However, no
        results on whether or not progestogen can modulate the
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDR1/P-gp</ENAMEX> have been reported. The present
        study has demonstrated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> significantly inhibited
        MDR1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/P</ENAMEX>-gp expression on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third day</TIMEX> after treatment. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> mRNA expression level was very low, and that of P-gp
        almost ceased.
        It is worthy to note that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fifth day</TIMEX> after NOM
        treatment, the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDR1/P-gp</ENAMEX> began to increase
        again. This phenomenon was also observed when treating
        colon carcinoma cell line with cytokines [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. Some
        studies have also found that P-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gp antagonists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VRP</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cyclosporin A</ENAMEX> and reserpine could induce MDR1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/P</ENAMEX>-gp
        expression in the colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">carcinoma</ENAMEX> cell line <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LS180-Ad50</ENAMEX> [
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 32</TIMEX>]. A few papers have reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MDR1</TIMEX> expression after
        treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>] showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX>
        interacted with P-gp, inducing its expression in the
        granulose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> in preovulatory follicles to modulate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroid efflux</ENAMEX>. Our results show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> modulated the
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MDR1</ENAMEX> in a time-dependent manner. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 days</TIMEX>
        of treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MDR1</TIMEX> expression became elevated.
        From these findings it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> and other progestogen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">compounds</ENAMEX> show an effect of upregulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDR1</ENAMEX> expression in
        long-term treatment. It is unclear how NOM effects this
        time-dependent modulation of the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDR1/P-gp</ENAMEX>.
        If a similar modulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> phenotype occurs 
        in vivo , then the duration of
        treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> becomes important. It will be of prime
        importance to verify the time course for modulation by
        reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and to design appropriate clinical
        trials.
        In investigating the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-gp-induced MDR</ENAMEX> phenotype, the
        overexpression of some non-P-gp MDR-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> have
        been demonstrated. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are important in drug
        resistance in some tumour cell lines [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34, 35</TIMEX>]. We also
        observed the expression of the non-P-gp MDR-related genes
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX>. We found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> markedly decreased
        the level of expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ mRNA and protein with a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> course similar to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDR1/P-gp</ENAMEX>. The results
        suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> possibly acts as a reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ€.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> belongs to the superfamily of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>-binding cassette
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein transporters</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P-gp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> is located in the
        plasma membrane of resistant tumour cells; however, the
        mechanism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> might be fundamentally different from that
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P-gp</ENAMEX>. The extrusion of several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> requires
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glutathione</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRP</ENAMEX> might be identical to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GS-X</ENAMEX> pump [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>].
        MRP-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> was not reversed by classic reversal agents
        of P-gp such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VRP</ENAMEX> and cyclosporin A [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37, 38, 39</TIMEX>]. Our
        results suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> cannot modulate MRP gene
        expression either.
        TopoII, as a kind of nuclease, is important in the
        processes of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA metabolism</ENAMEX> such as transcription,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">replication</ENAMEX> and chromosome partitioning during cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">division</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> is present mainly in the S phase [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> in tumour cells is a target enzyme of some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anticancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> activity decreases or a
        TopoIIÎ± gene mutation develops, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> results
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41, 42</TIMEX>].
        Our results showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> expression in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR
        cells was weaker than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/WT cells. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> is
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> enzyme of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells might
        to some extent be related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX>. However, no change in
        TopoIIÎ± gene expression level was detected in NOM-treated
        MCF7/ADR cells, indicating that the reversal effect of NOM
        on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells cannot result from modulating the
        gene expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P-gp</ENAMEX> belongs to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATP</ENAMEX>-dependent transporters. It acts
        as a pump or hydrophobic vacuum cleaner, effectively
        increasing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">efflux</ENAMEX> and decreasing drug influx [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>].
        Many studies have demonstrated that progestogen compounds
        directly bind P-gp and block the function of the pump
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">efflux</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 44</TIMEX>]. We studied the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intracellular</ENAMEX> ADR accumulation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells by using
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCM</ENAMEX> assays. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> can emit fluorescence; its intensity
        represents its accumulation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> of treatment
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>, the intracellular fluorescence intensity of ADR
        was markedly enhanced, suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> directly
        inhibits the P-gp pump efflux function in the same way as
        other progestogen compounds do.
        It has been reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> induces dose-dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 M</ENAMEX> arrest and that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in this phase
        are particularly sensitive to chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>].
        Cell-cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> content assays by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCM</ENAMEX> suggest that NOM
        enhances the blocking activity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> on the cell cycle.
        This enhancement of blocking activity might be partly
        responsible for the reversal effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX>.
        In brief, our results indicate that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MCF7</TIMEX>/ADR cells
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> can significantly sensitize their chemosensitivity to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX>, down-regulate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MDR1/P-gp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ expression levels in
        time-dependent manner, markedly increase intracellular ADR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accumulation</ENAMEX> and enhance the cell cycle blocking activity
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX>. At present, although a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> inhibit
        the function of P-gp 
        in vitro , their clinical use is also
        limited by the toxicity associated with the doses required
        to reverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MDR</ENAMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> can be safely administered at
        high doses, it might be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for an MDR
        reversal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ADR</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adriamycin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DRO</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">droloxifen</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSTÏ</ENAMEX>€ = glutathione
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-transferase Pi; MDR</ENAMEX> = multidrug resistance; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MG</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">megestrol; MRP</ENAMEX> = MDR-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTT</ENAMEX> =
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-(<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4,5-dimethylthiazol-2-yl</NUMEX>)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">diphenyl</NUMEX>-2 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX> -tetrazolium bromide; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOM</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nomegestrol; PBS</ENAMEX> = phosphate-buffered saline; P-gp =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX>-glycoprotein; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> = reverse transcriptase polymerase
        chain reaction; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TAM</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tamoxifen</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TopoIIÎ±</ENAMEX> = topoisomerase
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIÎ±; VRP</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">verapamil</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
