
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, located north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, is distinguished among urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> by its relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX>
        residents), by a median per-capita income of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 200%</NUMEX>
        that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] , and by elevated rates of breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> that were first reported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] .
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> has since pronounced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> 'the breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> capital of the world' [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] , and heightened
        community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> has inspired grassroots and scientific
        efforts to investigate reasons for the high incidence.
        Initial studies have suggested that elevated rates in white
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco Bay Area</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX>) are generally explained by the higher prevalence of
        established breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors, including higher
        levels of education and income, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later age</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> birth,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nulliparity</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5</NUMEX> ] . Our previous assessment of breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> incidence trends in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> isolated the rate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elevation</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64 years</TIMEX> at diagnosis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX> and scientific concern over increasing incidence
        rates has nevertheless remained high, so detailed
        surveillance of incidence and mortality rates has
        continued.
        It has been estimated that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 45-55%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
        cases in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are explained by established
        risk factors such as income, reproductive factors, and
        family history [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Distinctive breast cancer</ENAMEX> incidence
        and mortality patterns in well-defined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> may
        therefore inform etiologic understanding. For this reason,
        and as part of ongoing regional <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> surveillance
        efforts, we analyzed the most recent breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>
        incidence and mortality data available for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> and
        compared these rates and trends with those from other areas
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer incidence</ENAMEX> and mortality data
          We obtained cancer incidence and mortality data for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Cancer Registry</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Office of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vital Statistics</ENAMEX>, respectively. Analyses were based on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diseases - Oncology</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2nd</TIMEX> edition, site codes
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50.0</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50.9</NUMEX> excluding histology codes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9590-9989</TIMEX>; invasive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Disease</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10th</TIMEX> edition, site codes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C50-C509</ENAMEX>) during
          the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1 January 1990-31 December 1999</TIMEX>. We excluded 
          in situ <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> from this analysis
          because of ongoing controversy over the diagnosis and
          malignant potential of these tumors [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . We
          additionally limited the analyses to white, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> because of the marked variation in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>
          incidence by race/ethnicity, and because of the small and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">unstable</ENAMEX> numbers of cases and deaths ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n <</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>) among
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian/Pacific Islander</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Rate calculation and statistical
          considerations
          Using <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> estimates obtained from the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Finance</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] , we calculated
          incidence and mortality rates for the individual years
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-1999</TIMEX> as well as for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 5-year</TIMEX> period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-1999</TIMEX> for
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> geographic areas: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, the rest of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alameda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Contra Costa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Mateo</ENAMEX>,
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Clara counties</ENAMEX>), and other urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>, which were defined as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX>-designated urban areas or as containing at
          least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, included
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Dorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fresno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madera</ENAMEX>,
          Merced, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monterey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Napa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Placer, Riverside</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Bernardino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Joaquin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Obispo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shasta, Solano</ENAMEX>,
          Sonoma, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanislaus, Sutter, Tulare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yolo</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yuba</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. We excluded rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> from the
          comparison because of the consistent association between
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> and breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEER*Stat</ENAMEX>
          software [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] was used to compute the rates, to age
          adjust them to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> standard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, to
          produce the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> confidence interval (CI), and to conduct
          weighted linear regression to estimate average annual
          percentage changes, which were evaluated for statistical
          significance with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-sided 
          P value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Joint</ENAMEX>
          Commission on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> rdedition staging was used to
          calculate stage-specific rates.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Incidence trends
          Incidence rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">invasive breast cancer</ENAMEX> among white
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> show a distinctly increasing trend
          over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linear</ENAMEX> regression showed
          that breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37%</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 1999</TIMEX>, but increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 3%</NUMEX> in the rest
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX> and other urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> rate of increase (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.6</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX>) was, on
          average, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times higher in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> than in
          comparison areas (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). In addition, there was a
          significant <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> increase in incidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>
          during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1-year</TIMEX> period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1998</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">191</NUMEX> cases per
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">167-219</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">230</NUMEX> cases per
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">203-261</ENAMEX>).
          Our previous study of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> incidence trends
          showed that, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1991 and 1997</TIMEX>, rates increased at a
          faster pace among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64 years</TIMEX> than among women
          of other ages [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . The present analyses confirm and
          update these observations, and show that the large rate
          increase <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 1999</TIMEX> was limited almost
          entirely to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64 years</TIMEX>, who represented about
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">one-half</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cases diagnosed in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Breast cancer</ENAMEX> incidence increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">79%</NUMEX> between
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 and 1999</TIMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64 years</TIMEX>,
          an average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> increase of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.7%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Trends were
          stable in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of similar age in other regions as well
          as in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><45 and â</NUMEX>‰¥ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years</TIMEX> regardless of
          region (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> rates in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64 years</TIMEX> approached the magnitude of
          those aged â‰¥ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years</TIMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Comparison of average annual incidence rates
          By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> rates
          continued to be substantially higher in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> than
          in other parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, including other parts of
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX>, age-adjusted <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> incidence
          rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> averaged over the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> most recent
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> for which we have data (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-1999</TIMEX>) exceeded, by at
          least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>, those from any single other urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, and they were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28%</NUMEX> higher than rates for other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SFBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> and were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38%</NUMEX> higher than rates for other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> combined (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, average incidence rates were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX> higher in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> than in the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX> and were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72%</NUMEX> higher
          than in other urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
          Nearly all of the excess in overall rates was for
          early-stage (stage I/<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stage II</ENAMEX>) disease, for which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> rates (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">175</NUMEX> cases per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">165-187</ENAMEX>)
          were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX> higher than those for the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">134</ENAMEX>
          cases per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">131-136</ENAMEX>) and were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48%</NUMEX> higher
          than those for other urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">119</NUMEX> cases
          per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">117-120</ENAMEX>). Rates of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>-stage
          (stage III/stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> were not significantly
          different in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> cases per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-19</NUMEX>) as compared with those in other areas (SFBA: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
          cases per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-14</NUMEX>; other urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> cases per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13-14</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Mortality trends
          Despite the excess in early-stage tumors, breast
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> mortality rates have been decreasing more slowly
          in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> than they have been in other parts of the
          state. Whereas breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> mortality declined
          significantly at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> per year in other parts of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> rates
          decreased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 1%</NUMEX> per year; this change was not
          statistically significantly different from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five-year</TIMEX> average (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-1999</TIMEX>) breast cancer death
          rates in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> higher than those
          rates observed for other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX> and urban
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 45-64</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, mortality rates increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.9%</NUMEX> per year in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> while decreasing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.5%</NUMEX> per year in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        Patterns of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer incidence</ENAMEX> and mortality in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, have deviated markedly from those
        observed in other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>.
        These findings demonstrate the public health burden of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, but also have the
        potential to serve as a source of hypothesis generation as
        regards the association between higher socioeconomic status
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer</ENAMEX> incidence patterns in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> have been informative in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>; the soaring
        incidence of endometrial cancer there in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1970s</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ]
        was ultimately linked to the utilization of estrogen
        therapy by postmenopausal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
        The higher breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> incidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> has
        been attributed to its unique and uniform sociodemographic
        characteristics [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] , which correspond to a higher
        prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with known breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors.
        With a relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> for an urban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> was one of the wealthiest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, with a median per-capita income of
        <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost US$58,000</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 200%</NUMEX> higher than the state and
        national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">medians</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> consistently ranks
        among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> with the most highly educated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">populations</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 44%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> having a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree, which is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">220%</NUMEX> higher than the national
        rate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ] . It also has a higher percentage of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">white</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX>) than surrounding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] .
        In accordance with its high socioeconomic status, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> has higher proportions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with other
        established breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors, including lower
        parity [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] and later age at childbearing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX> of
        the live births to white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, as compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . In addition, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69%</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55-64 years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47%</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> and over reported
        using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy as part of a community
        health survey conducted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RRE</ENAMEX>,
        unpublished data, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>) although comparable figures are not
        available for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prehn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>, using <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> census
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, calculated breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates for
        aggregations of census block <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> matched to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>
        on characteristics associated with higher breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>
        risk (percentage white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, urban status, average
        parity, median household income, percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with
        a college degree, percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> with a
        working-class occupation, and percentage of households
        living below the poverty line), and found rates in the
        matched areas to be comparable with those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ] . In another study using interview-based information,
        higher breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX> rates among white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX> were also fully explained by the distribution of
        parity, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> birth, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of breast-feeding, age
        at menarche, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at menopause [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . Other previous
        analyses of nationwide variation in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> incidence
        and mortality found most of it attributable to the
        distribution of known breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ]
        . It thus seems likely that a substantial part of the
        excess incidence observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> is explained by a
        higher concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with a higher breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>
        risk profile.
        The increasing incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> might be
        explained by changes in the composition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Census</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> show that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> had relatively high levels of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outmigration</ENAMEX> and had low levels of immigration during
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-1998</TIMEX> compared with other parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        Examination of the age-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> denominators
        used in this analysis [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] shows that the proportion of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64 years</TIMEX>, which includes the leading edge of
        the 'baby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomer</ENAMEX>' cohort, changed very little over the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, whereas this proportion increased
        substantially in comparison areas. This deviant pattern
        could be explained by the outmigration from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64 years</TIMEX> and by the immigration of younger
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. As realty data show that the median single family
        home price surged to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$530,000</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>, making
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> one of the least affordable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] , we speculate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age</TIMEX> group
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64 years</TIMEX> who may have had more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at younger ages
        left the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>, while younger, perhaps
        professional, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who did not have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or who
        delayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-bearing immigrated to or stayed in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX>. Some support for this phenomenon is provided by the
        widening difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> in
        the proportion of live births to white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years and older</TIMEX> as compared with those aged younger than 30
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (ratio: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.54</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.60</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . The
        numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> with a high breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>
        risk profile may thus have increased further over the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>.
        We consider it doubtful that the observed trends are
        strongly biased by inaccurate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> registry or population
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>. The trends observed in the rates were also observed
        in the case counts alone. Although some of the observed
        rate increases could be attributable to inaccuracy of the
        intercensal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> estimates, particularly in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45-64</NUMEX>
        age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, systematic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> undercounts would
        presumably have produced similar increases in the incidence
        of other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, which we did not observe. Furthermore,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Department of Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> estimate
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 1999</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">244,900</NUMEX>) was less than
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> lower than the actual count performed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Census</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">247,289</NUMEX>). Regardless of this, incidence trends
        will be reassessed when revised <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> estimates
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">benchmarked</ENAMEX> to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> census become available.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Breast cancer</ENAMEX> incidence has been positively associated
        with socioeconomic status across race/ethnicity, geography,
        and time [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 20 21 22 23</NUMEX> ] . Recent data from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
        show that rates for white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the highest
        socioeconomic quintile were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX> higher than the lowest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quintile</ENAMEX> and were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX> higher than the overall rate [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        However, understanding of the biologic factors mediating
        this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> remains incomplete. In a large, national,
        interview-based study conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, adjustment
        for reproductive patterns, menopausal characteristics,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> use, alcohol consumption, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> mass index, height,
        and family history did not entirely account for the
        relations of income and education to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> risk [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> ] . To achieve a more contemporary understanding of the
        contributions of established <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors, it
        would be helpful to reassess the roles of factors whose
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevalence</ENAMEX> has increased substantially over time, including
        delayed childbearing [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] and use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement
        therapy [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . In addition, there are ongoing efforts in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> to identify novel risk factors relevant to
        this socioeconomic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. These efforts include a
        case-control study of adolescent exposures and experiences
        for which data collection was recently completed, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> to identify environmental exposures unique to this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>.
        It is uncertain to what extent the socioeconomic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gradient</ENAMEX> in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and the patterns we have
        observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, might be explained by better
        awareness of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, by access to health care, or by
        utilization of screening programs. Screening mammography
        has been linked previously to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> incidence
        increases in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, most notably the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> annual
        increase after its widespread adoption in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ]
        . In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, mammography utilization accounted
        for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23%</NUMEX> of the geographic variation in overall breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-1993</TIMEX> and for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX> of the variation
        among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-64 years</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] .
        At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, our observations of incidence excesses
        limited to early-stage <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> would suggest some relation
        to regional differences in screening. However, these
        patterns do not demonstrate other hallmarks of differential
        'lead time bias'. There was no evidence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>
        deficit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>-stage <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, mortality rates remained
        stable despite distinct mortality declines observed in
        comparison regions, and disparate age-specific incidence
        trends were observed within the larger age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 40</TIMEX>+
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) targeted by screening programs [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] . In addition,
        mammography utilization data do not suggest substantially
        elevated rates of screening among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. A
        community health survey conducted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>
        found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>+ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> received a mammogram
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>; this proportion is comparable with or
        only slightly higher than those for other areas with lower
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> rates (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RRE</ENAMEX>, unpublished data, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). There
        are no data available to explore other aspects of
        mammographic screening in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, such as
        increased frequency or better sensitivity due to higher
        volume [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . The possibility of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a real</NUMEX> increase in small
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tumors</ENAMEX> is, however, underscored by reports of significant
        increases in small breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> among unscreened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">registries</ENAMEX> do not routinely collect
        information about patient income and education, making
        assessment of cancer trends by socioeconomic status very
        difficult [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ] . Our findings of rapidly increasing rates
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>,
        however, along with evidence that high rates there are
        explained by the sociodemography of the county [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] ,
        cause us to speculate whether breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates are
        increasing similarly in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of highly educated and
        affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> nationwide. While we can monitor incidence
        rates in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> because it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>, we cannot
        conduct ongoing annual <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> surveillance in
        sociodemographically similar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> living in
        sub<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">-county regions</ENAMEX> because of a lack of appropriate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> estimates. When detailed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> data are
        released for subcounty areas, we will re-examine the
        relations between sociodemographic characteristics and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographic</ENAMEX> variation in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer incidence</ENAMEX>. If our
        speculations are supported by these data, then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>
        statistics indeed serve as a 'canary in the gold mine' as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">regards breast cancer</ENAMEX> incidence in educated or affluent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, and they may also be prescient as regards breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> mortality. These observations should motivate us to
        intensify our efforts to learn more about the relationship
        between socioeconomic status and breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        The incidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">invasive breast cancer</ENAMEX> has increased
        significantly in the affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cali-fornia</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1990 and 1999</TIMEX>. This large increase has
        not been observed in other parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and appears
        to be limited to early-stage <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> among white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64 years</TIMEX> at diagnosis. Despite the preponderance of
        early-stage diagnoses in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
        mortality rates remain unchanged, declining somewhat
        overall and increasing slightly among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-64</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. These findings, coupled with our understanding of
        the unique sociodemographic characteristics of this region,
        have the potential to serve as a source of hypothesis
        generation as regards the association between higher
        socioeconomic status and breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX> = confidence interval; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFBA</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco Bay</ENAMEX>
        Area.
      
    
  
