
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">As many as 30%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> who have
        undergone curative surgery and show no evidence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">locoregional</ENAMEX> or distant disease still have recurrent
        disease <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 5-10 years</TIMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] . Some of these treatment
        failures may be attributed to residual disease in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX> or axillary lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . The limitation of
        routine histopathologic examination of the tumor margins
        and the dissected lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">node specimen</ENAMEX> is well known [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] .
        Contemporary methods of detection, including computed
        and flow cytometry, all have limited sensitivity and
        specificity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micrometastases</ENAMEX> can be found by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunohistochemistry</ENAMEX> or polymerase chain reaction in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> previously deemed free of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> by
        conventional histological methods [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7 8</NUMEX> ] . The prognostic
        importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">micrometastases</ENAMEX> found with these sensitive
        methods are now being evaluated [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10 11</ENAMEX> ] .
        Hepatocyte growth factor/scatter factor (HGF/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>) is a
        paracrine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor</ENAMEX> produced primarily by mesenchymal cells.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> induces mitogenic and morphogenic changes, including
        rapid membrane ruffling, formation of microspikes, and
        increased cellular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motility</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 13</NUMEX> ] . The diverse
        biological effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> are all mediated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>, which
        is preferentially expressed on epithelial cells [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> ] . 
        In vivo this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-ligand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> is
        essential for normal embryonic development [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15 16</NUMEX> ] .
        Whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> signaling clearly has a role in normal cellular
        processes, this signaling pathway has also been implicated
        in tumor development and progression. Met signaling can
        increase tumorigenicity, induce cell motility, and enhance
        invasiveness 
        in vitro and metastasis 
        in vivo [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 17 18 19 20</NUMEX> ] . In
        addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> signaling can increase the production of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protease</ENAMEX> and urokinase, which are associated with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">extracellular matrix</ENAMEX>/basal membrane degradation and are
        important for metastasis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14 19</NUMEX> ] .
        Operations for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> include either mastectomy
        or breast-conserving surgery, consisting of wide local
        excision of the tumor with margins of intact breast tissue
        ('lumpectomy') and axillary lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">node dissection</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Drains</ENAMEX>
        are inserted in the dissected axilla in most of these
        operations, to avoid the accumulation of lymphatic fluid.
        The goals of this study were to examine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> can be
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>) in the axillary drainage from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who have
        undergone conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, and to
        assess the correlations between the mRNA expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>
        in the collected fluid and prognostic factors of breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> and operations
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirty-one</ENAMEX> consecutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with invasive ductal
          carcinoma of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX>, who were suitable for
          breast-conserving treatment, were studied. We included
          only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who underwent conserving breast surgery so
          that we could evaluate the correlations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>-HGF/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>
          expression with both the tumor margins and the status of
          the axillary lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>. The diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> was
          established by needle core biopsy (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'Trucut'</ENAMEX>), which was
          performed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 weeks</TIMEX> before the operation. All patients
          underwent wide local excision and axillary lymph node
          dissection by the same team. Non-palpable tumors were
          localized by mammography before surgery by wire
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insertion</ENAMEX>. During operations a wide resection around the
          wire was performed, followed by mammographic confirmation
          of complete resection of the tumors. The axillary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissection</ENAMEX> was performed with a separate incision, and
          level <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">I and II</ENAMEX> axillary lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX> were removed. The
          breast incisions were closed without drainage, and all
          axillae were drained postoperatively by closed vacuum
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drains</ENAMEX> (ch-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biometrix</ENAMEX>). The output of the drain was
          collected and measured every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>; the drains were
          removed when the output was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than 25 ml per 24 h.</NUMEX> The
          presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>-HGF/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> and β-actin were assessed in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fluid</ENAMEX>, which was collected during the second
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">postoperative day</TIMEX> because during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 24 hours</TIMEX> it
          might contain many erythrocytes and debris.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathological</ENAMEX> examinations
          The resected specimen was covered circumferentially by
          black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> ink and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bouins</ENAMEX> solution and then was sliced
          into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> mm slices. Each slice was evaluated
          macroscopically for the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> and its
          distance from the margins of the specimen. All slices
          involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX> were paraffin embedded, sliced again
          into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> μm slides, and stained with hematoxylin-eosin.
          Microscopical evaluation was performed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologist</ENAMEX>
          for margin involvement, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor type</ENAMEX>, size, grade,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capillary</ENAMEX> or lymphatic invasion, and the distance from
          the margins. All axillary lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX> were paraffin
          embedded, sliced into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> μm slides and assessed for the
          presence of micrometastases.
        
        
          Receptor assays
          Estrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>)
          were assessed in the tumor by immunohistochemical assay
          with mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monoclonal antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NCL-ER-6F11</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NCL-PGR-312</ENAMEX>) in accordance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instruction</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novocastra Laboratories</ENAMEX>). We used the 'quick
          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">score'</ENAMEX>, a simple combination of the proportion of cells
          staining plus a measure of intensity of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">staining</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] .
          A cut-off value of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> or more was taken as negative for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>
          or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          RT-PCR assays
          Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted from axillary lymphatic fluid
          with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri Reagent</ENAMEX> procedure, in accordance with the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instruction (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). Reverse transcription
          was performed with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1-2 μg</NUMEX> of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>. The first strand
          of cDNA was generated with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.5 μg</NUMEX> of(dT) 
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 primer</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco-BRL</ENAMEX>) using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> units
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">subscripts II</ENAMEX> RNAse-H-reverse transcriptase
          (Gibco-BRL). This was incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">50 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42°C</TIMEX>,
          followed by inactivation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70°C</TIMEX>. To detect
          Met transcript, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 μl</NUMEX> of cDNA with
          MP1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">primer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGAATCGAGCTGCGAGA-3</ENAMEX>') and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MP2</ENAMEX> primer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TCCAACATGCAGTTTCTTGC-3</ENAMEX>'). To detect β-actin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transcript</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> was performed on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3 μl</NUMEX> of cDNA with MP1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CTCTTCCAGCCTTCCTTCCT-3</ENAMEX>') and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MP2</ENAMEX> primer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>'-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AGCACTGTGTTGGCGTACAG-3</ENAMEX>'). Cycling conditions
          consisted of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cycles</ENAMEX> with denaturation steps at 94°C
          for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> s, hybridization steps at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> s and an
          extension step at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72°C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> min. The β-actin and c-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCRs</ENAMEX> were performed simultaneously, under the same
          conditions. The limit of sensitivity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> system
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 pg</NUMEX> of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Immunohistochemical analyses
          Staining was performed with an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> against
          hepatocyte growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">factor-α receptor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGFα-R; H-145; Santa</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruz Biotechnology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sections</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5 μm</ENAMEX>) mounted on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Frost</ENAMEX>/plus <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> (Menzel
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claser</ENAMEX>, both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Braunschweig</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>), were
          processed by a labelled streptavidin-biotin method with a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Histostain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plus</ENAMEX> kit (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zymed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Heat-induced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen retrieval</ENAMEX> was performed by
          temperature-controlled microwave treatment with an H2800
          model processor (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Beam Sciences Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Agawan</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 min</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> mM citrate buffer,
          pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.0</NUMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">97°C</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were treated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 min</TIMEX> with
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> H 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , followed by a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 min</NUMEX> incubation
          with the universal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blocker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cas</ENAMEX>-block (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zymed</ENAMEX>). The
          sections were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX> min with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:20</TIMEX> diluted
          HGFα-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>. A biotinylated second <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 min</TIMEX>, followed by incubation with
          horseradish peroxidase-conjugated streptavidin for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          min. The slides were washed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Optimax</ENAMEX> wash buffer
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioGenex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Ramon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) after each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incubation</ENAMEX>. The immunoreaction was revealed by a
          horseradish peroxidase-based chromogen. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX> were
          then counterstained and cleared in xylene. Controlled
          staining was performed with human liver tissue. The
          presence of brown (diaminobenzidine) staining of the cell
          membranes of tumor cells was interpreted as positive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reactivity</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> group
          To verify that in normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> there is no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in
          the axilla we examined the axillary drainage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with malignant <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">melanoma</ENAMEX> who were found to have
          negative axillary sentinel lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">node</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> were
          located in the upper limbs, and the lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">node</ENAMEX> basins
          were found to be in the axilla. Sentinel lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX> were
          found in all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and none was involved with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">melanoma</ENAMEX> in frozen sections or in paraffin-embedded and
          stained slices.
        
        
          Statistical evaluation
          Correlations between the various clinicopathological
          parameters and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> assays in lymphatic fluid were
          analyzed by the χ 2test ( 
          P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Results
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirty-one</ENAMEX> consecutive female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who underwent
        breast-conserving surgery for operable invasive duct
        carcinoma of the breast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1 January and 30 June 2000</TIMEX>
        were included. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with tumors that invaded the chest
        wall or skin, or with inflammatory carcinoma, were
        excluded. The mean age was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-three</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74.2%</NUMEX>) underwent lumpectomy for palpable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>,
        and in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25.8%</NUMEX>) wire-guided excision of
        non-palpable tumors was performed. The tumor size was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>-1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cm</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32.2%</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cm</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29.0%</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-5</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cm</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35.4%</NUMEX>), and larger than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> cm in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.2%</NUMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.9%</NUMEX>) had grade I tumors, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61.3%</NUMEX>) had grade II
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lesions</ENAMEX>, and grade III tumors were found in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25.8%</NUMEX>).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lymphatic</ENAMEX> and capillary invasion were noted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32.2%</NUMEX>)
        and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35.4%</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, respectively. While attempting to
        achieve free margins, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16.1%</NUMEX>) had to undergo
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-excision owing to incomplete resections. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had wire-guided excisions.
        The collected axillary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> were assessed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT</ENAMEX>-PCR
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> and β-actin. The β-actin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> served as positive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and gave strong signals in all cases, indicating
        that both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA preparation</ENAMEX> and cDNA synthesis were
        successful. The RT-PCR assays were positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74.2%</NUMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). In all of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> gave positive
        results for β-actin but was negative for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>.
        The correlations between tumor size and the presence of
        Met in the axillary fluid are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. Positive
        RT-PCR assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the lymphatic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> were
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with increasing tumor size. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57.9%</NUMEX>) with T1 tumors (tumor size <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cm</ENAMEX>) had
        positive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the axillary fluid (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50% and 66%</NUMEX> for tumors
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cm</ENAMEX> in size respectively), compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>) with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">T2 and T3</TIMEX> tumors ( 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>).
        The average number (± SD) of axillary lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">± 4</ENAMEX>, and all dissected nodes were examined for the presence
        of metastases. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">38.7%</NUMEX>) had axillary lymph
        node metastases as revealed by hematoxylin-eosin staining.
        The correlation between metastatic axillary lymph node
        involvement and the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the lymphatic fluid
        is shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with axillary lymph
        node metastases had positive RT-PCR assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>,
        compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57.9%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>) positive assays for women
        without lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">node metastases</ENAMEX> ( 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.01</NUMEX>).
        All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with tumor involvement in the margins
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resection</ENAMEX> had positive RT-PCR assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in
        their lymphatic fluid, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> positive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assays</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69.2%</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> without involved margins ( 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.04</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>
        between tumor grade, capillary and lymphatic invasion, and
        the presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the axillary fluid are presented in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with lymphatic invasion of the tumor were
        all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>-positive (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> without lymphatic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invasion</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61.9%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX>) positive assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> ( 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.02</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Capillary</ENAMEX> invasion of
        the tumor was also found to be in correlation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>;
        although all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with capillary invasion had
        positive RT-PCR assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in their axillary fluid, the
        assays were positive in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 60%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>) patients
        without capillary invasion ( 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.02</NUMEX>). The presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in
        the axillary drainage was also correlated with higher tumor
        grade: it was found in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of grade I tumors, compared with
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87.5%</NUMEX> of grade III <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> ( 
        P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>).
        The correlations between the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> status and RT-PCR
        assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the axillary fluid are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seventeen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>-negative tumors, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94.1%</NUMEX>)
        of these had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>-positive assays in the axillary fluid. In
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87.5%</NUMEX>) of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>-negative
        assays the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> were positive. Similarly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>-negative tumors, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95.2%</NUMEX>) of these were positive
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>-positive tumors were found in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87.5%</NUMEX>) in whom assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the axillary
        drainage were negative.
        All the paraffin-embedded sections of the resected
        primary breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> were assessed by
        immunohistochemistry staining for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90.3%</NUMEX>) the primary tumor stained positively for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> and
        none of the tumors that had negative staining had a
        positive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> RT-PCR assay in the axillary drainage. In
        addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with negative staining had no
        involvement of lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Discussion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> is synthesized as a pro-HGF, and once activated
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX> activator (HGFA), the complex HGF/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> affects
        numerous normal cellular processes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> is
        also involved in malignant transformation, presumably as a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> in interaction between tumor and stroma, which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">enhances tumor progression</ENAMEX>, and also angiogenesis [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23 34</NUMEX> ]
        . In invasive ductal carcinoma, stronger expression of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> seems to be associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tubule</ENAMEX> formation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ]
        . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> is overexpressed in breast carcinoma 
        in situ and invasive ductal carcinoma
        in comparison with normal breast tissue. Normal mammary
        ducts within infiltrating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> showed intermediate levels
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>. This finding suggests that the expression of
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> is regulated by soluble
        factors produced by the tumor cells [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26 27</NUMEX> ] . High levels
        of expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> are associated with invasive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, and might be causally linked to early
        recurrences, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">metastatic disease</ENAMEX> and shortened survival of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29</NUMEX> ] . High levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>
        detected within breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor extracts</ENAMEX> are correlated with
        larger tumor size and shorter relapse-free and overall
        survival compared with tumors with low HGF/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> concentration
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] .
        The activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGFA</ENAMEX> might be modified by
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HGFA inhibitors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HAI-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HAI-2</ENAMEX>. Highly invasive
        breast cancer cells express large amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>,
        and no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HAI-1</ENAMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cells with low invasive
        potential have low levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>, and high levels
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HAI-1</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> model system HGF antagonists
        suppressed the conversion of pancreatic tumors from
        carcinoma 
        in situ into invasive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        It seems that regulation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> stimulation and
        inhibition activities is associated with the metastatic
        potential of tumor cells, and knowing the status of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGFA</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HAI-1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HAI-2</ENAMEX>, in addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>, might provide useful
        information.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> have been found in a variety of tumors [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31 32 33</NUMEX> ] , and in lymph nodes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with no tumor [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> ] , but never in the fluid drained from the tumor bed or
        the lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">node</ENAMEX> basin. In this study we evaluated whether
        Met can be detected in the axillary drainage of breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and the significance of its expression in
        the lymphatic fluid. Studying the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the
        axillary fluid is a simple, non-invasive procedure because
        drains are routinely inserted during axillary lymph node
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dissections</ENAMEX>. The collected fluid is readily available, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> is a routine, short assay with minimum
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">artefacts</ENAMEX>.
        The axillary fluid after breast and axillary lymph node
        operations includes erythrocytes, lymphocytes, epithelial
        cells and tumor cells. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the goals of this work was to
        examine whether tumor cells can be detected in the axillary
        drainage by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>. To determine the source
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the axillary fluid in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and
        to exclude the possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> was related to
        surgical trauma, we evaluated a control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of melanoma
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with negative axillary sentinel lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>. In
        none of the control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was the axillary drainage
        Met-positive. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> the primary tumor stained
        positively for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> and none of the tumors that had negative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immunostaining</ENAMEX> had a positive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> RT-PCR assay in the
        axillary drainage. Thus, it seems likely that the source of
        Met in the axillary fluid in node-negative breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> is the tumor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX>.
        The results show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> can be detected in the
        axillary drainage, and although the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was
        not high, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> is associated with unfavorable prognostic
        factors. Positive assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> are correlated with tumor
        size, grade, lymphatic invasion, tumor involvement of the
        margins of the resected specimen, the existence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">metastases</ENAMEX> in the lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nodes</ENAMEX>, and the numbers of lymph
        nodes with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX>. Met was associated with larger tumors,
        and in none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with tumors larger than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> cm
        was the assay negative. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> was never negative in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with metastatic carcinoma in the lymph <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">node</ENAMEX>.
        Negative staining for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> is associated with
        unfavorable prognosis, and the assays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the
        axillary fluid were positive in most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>-negative
        tumors.
        One could postulate that because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> was highly
        correlated with tumor size, its expression implies
        aggressive behavior of the malignant processes. The
        significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> as a marker of poor prognosis might
        also be associated with its effects on acquired resistance
        to anti-cancer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35 36</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> protects cancer
        cells from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA-</ENAMEX>damaging chemotherapy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> through
        pathways involving signaling from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> to phosphoinositide
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-kinase and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">c-Akt</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] . Human breast cancer cells,
        preincubated with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> and then exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adriamycin</ENAMEX>,
        exhibit an altered pattern of gene expression compared with
        cells treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adriamycin</ENAMEX> alone. Cells treated with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adriamycin</ENAMEX> also had modified cell line
        regulation and signal transduction that might suggest
        mechanisms by which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> exerts its protective activity [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> ] .
        expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the axillary drainage in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who
        have undergone operations for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>. The results
        suggest that the expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the axillary drainage
        might have prognostic significance. More importantly, its
        expression in histologically node-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> point
        to the need to search for node micrometastasis or
        involvement of the excision margins by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tumor</ENAMEX>. Therefore,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> in the axillary fluid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who
        undergo breast-conserving surgery for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> could
        influence therapy. The results of this study justify
        prospective investigation on a larger scale, and the
        clinical significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> positivity in the axillary
        drainage fluid in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> should be defined
        by an extended follow-up study.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        Abbreivations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">estrogen receptor</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HGFA</ENAMEX> = hepatocyte growth factor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activator; HGF</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX> = hepatocyte growth factor/scatter
      
    
  
