
  
    
      
        Introduction
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco Bay Area</ENAMEX> reports some of the highest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> rates in the world [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX> ] . Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this</TIMEX>
        region, appropriately adjusted <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer incidence</ENAMEX> and
        mortality rates are highest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, a small, urban
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">county</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> predominantly white, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX>
        residents located immediately north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>. Averaged over the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-99</TIMEX>, age-adjusted
        invasive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> rates per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> white,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">155</NUMEX> in the
        rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco Bay Area</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">144</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> as a whole [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Pronounced international and
        national geographic variation in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates has
        been studied extensively [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4 5 6 7 8</NUMEX> ] and has been
        attributed variously to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> differences in the use
        of mammographic screening, diet, physical activity, body
        size, alcohol consumption, and socioeconomic and
        reproductive factors [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6 7 9 10</NUMEX> ] . However, studies of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer incidence</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">migrants</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> have noted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> with age at migration,
        suggesting additional important influences of childhood or
        adolescent exposures or experiences [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5 6</NUMEX> ] . With regard
        to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, an earlier study by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Cancer Center</ENAMEX> (NCCC) using census data suggested
        that the high incidence was associated with the
        sociodemographic characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> and not with
        a geographically specific exposure [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ] and that women
        living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> have a higher prevalence of some
        recognized breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors, such as high
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and income as well as low and late parity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX>
        ] .
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marin Breast Cancer Watch</ENAMEX>, a
        grassroots non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to help them
        to investigate causes of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> more
        thoroughly; these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community members</ENAMEX> actively participated
        in all aspects of conducting this study.
        In this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>-based case-control study of women
        residing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, we asked about generally
        recognized risk factors [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5 12</ENAMEX> ] and a variety of
        adolescent physical, psychological, and social factors. The
        main purpose in this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> report is to compare generally
        recognized breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors, as well as childhood
        and adolescent socioeconomic factors and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of residence
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with and without breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
        Although it was not the purpose of this study to explain
        the high rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, one
        hypothesis of the study was that if exposures specific to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> were to some degree responsible for the high
        rates there, one would expect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> to
        have lived longer in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> than control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> after
        adjustment for generally recognized breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk
        factors. The thought was that finding such a difference
        would provide justification for a more detailed exploration
        of exposures specific to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, whereas no
        difference would motivate research into other explanations.
        Thus, this initial report provides important information
        for planning future studies in this and other high-risk
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Case-control ascertainment
          Eligible cases included any female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> with a diagnosis of primary breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> between
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1997 and June 1999</TIMEX> if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 50 years of age</TIMEX>, and
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between July 1997 and March 1999</TIMEX> if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years old</TIMEX> or older
          at diagnosis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Dates were chosen to yield about
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> overall, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 50 years of age</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> aged
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> and over. The sample size was planned with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX>
          statistical power to detect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX>-fold odds ratios (ORs)
          between the highest and lowest quartiles of any
          continuous variable, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.9</NUMEX>-fold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> for quartile trend, a
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.25-year</TIMEX> case-control difference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at menarche, and
          a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3.5-year</TIMEX> case-control difference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> lived in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>. Names and addresses of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and their
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> were obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> registry
          operated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCCC</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> in the National
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer Institute</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI's</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surveillance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epidemiology</ENAMEX>,
          and End Results program. After receiving an introductory
          letter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who did not refuse by postcard were
          telephoned by a study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> to arrange a time and
          place for the in-person interview.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> without breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> were ascertained
          through random digit dialing (RDD) by using a
          modification of the method of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waksberg</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13 14</NUMEX> ] and were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">frequency-</ENAMEX>matched to cases by age at diagnosis (within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) and ethnicity. To maximize the chances of reaching
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">residential</ENAMEX> numbers, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> numbers used for dialing
          included the area code plus the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> digits of the
          study's cases and all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases diagnosed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. All possible numbers other than the
          cases' numbers were generated and randomly sorted. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RDD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> also generated a batch of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 300</NUMEX> random
          numbers from marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to increase the number of
          calls to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 years and older</TIMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Randomly sorted</ENAMEX> numbers were called sequentially. Two
          survey research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Survey Methods</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Field</ENAMEX>
          Research Corporation, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>)
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conducted RDD</ENAMEX> and preliminary eligibility screening of
          controls. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RDD</ENAMEX> was conducted from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2000</TIMEX> to August
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
          on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Research</ENAMEX> approved the study methods, and
          informed consent was obtained from all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Interviews
          The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 2-hour</TIMEX> in-person interviews were
          conducted at a place of each subject's choosing. Because
          many questions required the recall of adolescent factors,
          the interview used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> memory tools developed during
          the pilot phase of this study: a visualization exercise,
          a magnetic memory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, and photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> at
          various stages of development in a variety of social
          settings. The magnetic memory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> consisted of a sheet
          with rows showing the subject's age (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0-20 years</TIMEX>), the
          corresponding year, and memorable historic events that
          occurred during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> went through the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">questionnaire</ENAMEX>, magnets with major life events (such as
          moves, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> changes, births and deaths in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>)
          were placed in the appropriate row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age or year</TIMEX> in
          which the events occurred. All contemporary factors were
          asked of cases up to or around diagnosis date and of
          controls, up to the date of interview. The questionnaire
          included factors that have been summarized elsewhere [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> ] as being either established or strongly suspected
          risk factors for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> who did not wish to
          participate in the full interview were asked to complete
          a brief telephone interview that included a subset of the
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> interview questions.
          Questionnaire items pertinent to this report included
          detailed residential and school histories before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21</TIMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (such as location, ownership or rental, and dates
          in and out), highest level of schooling; total time of
          residence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX> and other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX> throughout the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX>; ethnicity; childhood
          religion; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' highest level of education and
          occupational characteristics at subject's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 5, 12</TIMEX>, and
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX>; other measures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s socioeconomic
          conditions including self-assessed socioeconomic status
          currently and before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX>; ages at menarche and
          menopause, and menopausal status; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> use and tobacco
          use and exposures; reproductive and breastfeeding
          history; family history of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>; type and ages
          of use of female <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>; previous non-breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>;
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cervical cancer</ENAMEX> screening practices; breast
          procedures; radiation treatments before breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>;
          and body weight and height at various times in life not
          including the times that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was pregnant or
          nursing or during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 6 months</TIMEX> after pregnancy.
          Case interviews were conducted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from December 1999</TIMEX> to
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2001</TIMEX> and control interviews were conducted from
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2000 to September 2001</TIMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> analysis methods
          We computed frequencies of categorical variables and
          means, standard errors, and medians of continuous
          variables separately for cases and controls. Continuous
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> also were categorized into quartiles determined by
          the control group distributions. Analysis of variance was
          used to compare unadjusted means and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilcoxon</ENAMEX> tests were
          used to compare medians of continuous variables for cases
          and controls. Case-control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIs</ENAMEX> were estimated
          for categorical and quartiled data by using logistic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regression</ENAMEX>. Preliminary analyses made adjustments for
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year</TIMEX> age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>; these analyses included telephone
          interview <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> for variables asked in both the
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> and abbreviated interviews. After a review of
          results of the preliminary age-adjusted analyses, a
          subset of the many variables was selected for inclusion
          in a multivariate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>; these included variables that
          are established or strongly suspected risk factors for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> that might confound other results and those
          that were statistically significant in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age-</TIMEX>adjusted
          comparisons. Age was included in all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX>. In addition,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> for residential history variables were adjusted for
          other variables included in the multivariate model, but
          not for each other, because the various residential
          variables were not mutually exclusive. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Multivariate</ENAMEX> ORs
          were estimated with logistic regression and included only
          those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> with in-person interviews and non-missing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> for all the variables in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.
          Analyses were conducted across all age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> as well
          as separately for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 50 years of age</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years of age and older</TIMEX>. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were chosen
          for separate analyses before any data collection, because
          the direction and magnitude of several important breast
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors seem to vary by age [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] .
          Furthermore, we specifically chose not to analyze women
          separately by premenopausal and postmenopausal status,
          because the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perimenopausal women</ENAMEX> do not readily fit
          into either category. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 1</NUMEX> are given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
          decimal places; those greater than or equal to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> are
          given <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> decimal place to achieve comparable
          accuracy.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Residences</ENAMEX> at birth and before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX> were
          grouped into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> broad geographic regions based on the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographic</ENAMEX> variation of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> mortality as shown
          in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlas of Cancer Mortality</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] . These
          regions were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Lakes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plains</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>);
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">West</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>);
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>;
          and not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Subject ascertainment and interviews
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1shows</ENAMEX> participation rates for cases and
          controls, and the footnote gives details on the numbers
          and disposition of calls made through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RDD</ENAMEX>. Ages and
          ethnicities of cases and controls that completed the full
          interview were very similar by study design (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
          Because only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 4%</NUMEX>) had died by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of the study, we did not conduct proxy interviews.
          Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">305</NUMEX> cases and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> controls completing the
          in-person interview, complete data for all variables
          considered in the multivariate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> were available for
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">285</NUMEX> cases and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">286</NUMEX> controls.
        
        
          Risk factors
          
            Personal and family health history
            As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, there were no substantial or
            frequencies of cases and controls reporting a
            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree relative with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> or a history
            of benign breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">biopsy</ENAMEX>. Cases were somewhat more
            likely than controls to report previous radiation
            treatments for conditions other than breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and
            the OR was significantly elevated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the
            age of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). However, on closer
            inspection <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cases and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the controls reported
            radiation treatments to the upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, whereas two
            cases and no controls reported radiation treatment for
            plantar <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">warts</ENAMEX>.
            There were no differences in average or median age
            at menarche for cases and controls (average was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.6</NUMEX> ±
            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.1</NUMEX> for cases and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.5 ± 0.1</NUMEX> for controls) and no
            statistically significant trends with age at menarche
            in either age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the
            age of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>, cases were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> as likely as
            controls to have begun menarche at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 15 years</TIMEX> or
            older, but the results were not significant (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
            In both age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, cases were more likely to be
            premenopausal at diagnosis than controls at a similar
            age (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Similar proportions of cases (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.7%</NUMEX>) and
            controls (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.3%</NUMEX>) reported having had both ovaries
            removed; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> of controls had both
            ovaries removed before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 40 years</TIMEX>. Cases were more
            likely than controls to have had a history of uterine
            or ovarian <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> (OR = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.60</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15.1</NUMEX>), but
            the result was not statistically significant.
            Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> of reproductive factors
            differed by age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> and
            older, compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had never been pregnant,
            cases were more than twice as likely as controls to
            have been pregnant or parous, without breastfeeding
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). However, there were no differences between
            these cases and controls in average age at first
            pregnancy (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25.1</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.4 years</TIMEX> for cases and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24.7</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> for controls) or at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> birth (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">26.0 ± 0.4</NUMEX> years
            for cases and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25.9</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.4 years</TIMEX> for controls) and no
            suggestions of trends with numbers of births (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
            Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who breastfed, there was no difference
            between cases and controls in duration of breastfeeding
            (mean durations: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.2</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1.2 months</TIMEX> for cases, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.8</NUMEX> ±
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1.3 months</TIMEX> for controls; categorized data presented in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 50 years</TIMEX>, cases
            were more likely than controls to have never been
            significant (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). In categorized data, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or more births, or more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> of
            breastfeeding, had significantly reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> compared
            with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who were never pregnant (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). As with
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 and older</TIMEX>, there were no trends evident
            for and no differences in average ages at first
            pregnancy (cases <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25.4</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.8 years</TIMEX>; controls <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26.3</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.7</NUMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> birth (cases <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30.1</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.9 years</TIMEX>; controls
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30.4</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.7 years</TIMEX>).
            Significantly fewer cases than controls had ever
            used birth control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> in both age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
            There were no apparent trends with total time used;
            compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who never used birth control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>,
            the use of birth control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 2 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-6</ENAMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years, 6-10 years</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 10 years</TIMEX> had ORs of
            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.55</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.33</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.93</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.52</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.30</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.89</NUMEX>),
            <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.57</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.32</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.47</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.27</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.82</NUMEX>),
            respectively. There was also no difference with current
            use versus past use.
            About equal percentages of cases (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54.7%</NUMEX>) and
            controls (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55.9%</NUMEX>) had ever taken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement
            therapy and there were similar percentages who had
            taken combination therapy (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
            Cases and controls had similar average and median
            maximum lifetime heights of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 65 inches</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">165 cm</NUMEX>).
            There were no notable differences in highest or lowest
            postpubertal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> mass index before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX> (the
            median highest body mass index for both cases and
            controls was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20.6 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2</ENAMEX>, and the median lowest body
            mass index was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18.5 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2for</ENAMEX> cases and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18.6 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m</ENAMEX> 2for
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">controls</ENAMEX>) or in lowest body mass index after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21</TIMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. However, in both age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, the highest body
            mass index after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX> was lower in cases than
            in controls (the median highest body mass index was
            <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">23.9 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2for</ENAMEX> cases and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25.0 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2for</ENAMEX> controls);
            categorized data are presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. A similar
            result was found by using body mass index <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> before
            diagnosis for cases and before interview for
            controls.
            We also conducted an analysis of perimenopausal and
            postmenopausal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that stratified body mass index by
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy use, adjusting for other
            variables in the multivariate model: in comparison with
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had not used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy and
            had a body mass index of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than 25 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2</ENAMEX>, cases
            were significantly less likely than controls to report
            a highest body mass index of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 30</NUMEX>, regardless
            of whether they had used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy
            (OR = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.36</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.14</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.89</NUMEX>) or not (OR = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.24</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.08</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.75</NUMEX>).
            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all</TIMEX> and in both age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, cases were more
            than twice as likely as controls to have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or
            more mammograms during the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-94</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
            Regarding other factors related to health care access
            and use, all but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> of controls had
            health insurance. For the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-94</TIMEX>, among women
            under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 50 years</TIMEX>, cases were somewhat less
            likely than controls (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92%</NUMEX>) to have clinical
            breast exams <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> or more often, whereas cases and
            controls were about equally likely (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89%</NUMEX> of cases and
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94%</NUMEX> of controls) to have an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> or more frequent
            pelvic exam. During this same period, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years and older</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 92%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83%</NUMEX> of controls
            reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> or more frequent clinical breast exams,
            and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">93%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87%</NUMEX> of controls reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> or
            more frequent pelvic exams and pap tests.
          
          
            Socioeconomic factors
            Over all ages, there were no meaningful or
            controls for current or past socioeconomic indicators,
            except that cases were more likely than controls to
            report their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s socioeconomic strata before age
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years</TIMEX> as 'upper' (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). However, no difference
            was noted when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in this small category of women
            (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.9%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.7%</NUMEX> of controls) were combined with
            the 'upper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middle</ENAMEX>' category (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). The
            self-reported socioeconomic status at the time of
            diagnosis for cases and interview for controls was very
            similar for cases and controls: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX> of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">controls</ENAMEX> reported their status as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'poor'</ENAMEX>, 'working
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>' or 'lower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middle</ENAMEX>', <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX> of both cases and
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">controls</ENAMEX> reported 'middle' and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX> of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">controls</ENAMEX> reported 'upper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middle</ENAMEX>' or 'upper'. Both cases
            and controls had a median of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX> of education.
            There was some indication that case-control
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> of socioeconomic factors differed between
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years and older</TIMEX> and those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 50 years</TIMEX>. For
            example, among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> and older, cases
            were more likely than controls to report their family
            socioeconomic status as 'upper or upper middle' before
            age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Although this finding was
            largely due to the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> classifying
            themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">'upper'</ENAMEX>, consistent with this was the
            observation that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX> of cases versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> of controls
            reported their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> to have been self-employed or
            business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 years old</TIMEX> ( 
            P <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 0.05</NUMEX>). In contrast, among
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 50 years old</TIMEX> there was a non-significant
            inverse association with increasing self-reported
            family socioeconomic status before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Consistent with this was the observation that case
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> spent significantly more time on average than
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in rental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21</TIMEX>
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.2</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.7 years</TIMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.4</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0.5 years</TIMEX>; 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.03</NUMEX>) and cases were less
            likely than controls to report that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> had a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> degree (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54%</NUMEX>; 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>) or that their father
            held a supervisory position (for example, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> versus
            <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX> at subject's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 5</TIMEX>; 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX>).
          
          
            Religion
            Over all ages, significantly fewer cases than
            controls were raised with no specific religion, and
            among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> and over cases were less likely
            than controls to report having been raised in religions
            other than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> consumption
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> were significantly less
            likely than control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to report having drunk
            alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverages</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
            Consistent with this finding was the fact that cases
            also reported significantly fewer average or median
            numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> than controls before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX>
            (median <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX>; 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.01</NUMEX>). However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> reported a higher frequency of drinking
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX> than controls, and there was
            a trend with increasing average frequency of drinking
            irrespective of age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>) that was
            statistically significant among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> less than 50
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX>.
          
          
            Tobacco exposures
            Although equivalent percentages of cases and
            controls had ever smoked cigarettes (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59% and 55%</NUMEX>,
            respectively), cases were more likely than controls to
            report <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 28.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack-years</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28.5 years</TIMEX>
            was the cutoff point for the upper quartile of
            pack-years smoked among controls). This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> was
            also significant for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> and over, but there
            was no trend with increasing pack-years smoked below
            the highest quartile (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). With regard to passive
            exposure to tobacco smoke, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">79%</NUMEX> of
            controls had ever lived in a household with a smoker
            before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62%</NUMEX> of
            controls had ever lived in a household with a smoker
            after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX>, with no trend for duration of
            exposure in either age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            Residence history
            As shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>, there were no substantial
            differences in geographic area of birth or places ever
            lived before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> overall or women
            over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 50 years</TIMEX>. However, among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the age
            of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX>, a significantly higher percentage of cases
            than controls reported having been born in or having
            ever lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Lakes</ENAMEX> areas before
            age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years</TIMEX> (only geographic areas with noteworthy
            differences are included in the table).
            Over all ages and among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> and
            over, there were no notable case-control differences in
            the age of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before
            the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 21 or lifetime years</TIMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>
            or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime years</TIMEX> lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco Bay Area</ENAMEX>
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>). Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 50 years</TIMEX>, cases
            had lived significantly fewer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> than controls in
            other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco Bay Area</ENAMEX>, but had
            similar durations of living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
          
        
      
      
        Discussion
        In this article we have focused on comparisons of
        generally accepted or suspected risk factors for breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, including some characteristics measured both for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adulthood</ENAMEX> and adolescence. Interestingly, cases and
        controls were strikingly similar for several factors known
        to influence breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk (such as family history of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, contemporary socioeconomic status, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> birth, or use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy). For
        instance, although the overall rate of positive
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree family history (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX>) among cases is similar to
        that reported in other recent series [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ] , the
        controls in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> had rates of family history
        comparable to those of the cases. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possible explanation
        for the homogeneity of cases with regard to these factors
        could be our focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of a small, relatively
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">homogenous</ENAMEX>, and affluent area, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>. The
        homogeneity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is supported by
        recent maps showing little variation in standardized
        incidence rate ratios for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> among the census
        tracts within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] .
        Another explanation could involve preferential
        participation in the study by controls with these
        recognized breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors over those without
        these factors. This seems unlikely given the high
        participation rates among those found to be eligible on the
        basis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RDD</ENAMEX>, but it is possible that there was some
        selection bias in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> who were willing to
        answer the telephone call screening for eligibility.
        Further studies with alternative control ascertainment
        methods would be necessary to resolve this issue. In
        addition, appropriately adjusted comparisons of these
        factors in this high-risk area versus geographic areas with
        lower breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates would be needed to answer the
        question of how much of the excess of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
        incidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> might be due to patterns of these
        risk factors. Such a study is currently underway. A study
        that uses risk factor prevalence data from this study and
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> is also underway to estimate the attributable
        proportions of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> due to specific risk
        factors.
        As mentioned above, selection bias due to differential
        participation by cases or controls with some risk factor of
        interest is always a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> in case-control
        studies. In attempts to minimize this problem, we sought an
        abbreviated interview for those cases and controls not able
        or willing to participate in the full interview. The
        preliminary age-adjusted analyses of individual risk
        factors used all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for whom information was available.
        There were not any notable differences in magnitude of the
        age-adjusted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> that used all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">657</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> and the
        multivariate results based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">571</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> with complete
        information.
        Despite homogeneity in current socioeconomic status, our
        study suggests that among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> and older,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> cases might have been more likely than
        controls to have grown up in more affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>,
        although the results are largely due to the small
        proportion of subjects reporting their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s
        socioeconomic status as 'upper' before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX>. In
        contrast, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 50 years</TIMEX>, breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> cases were somewhat less likely than controls to
        have grown up in more affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. That an effect of
        pre-adult socioeconomic status existed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>
        and over that was independent of contemporary socioeconomic
        status as well as established reproductive, menstrual, and
        other factors such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> size and alcohol consumption
        suggests that further attention is needed to understand the
        relationship of childhood or adolescent socioeconomic
        factors and breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
        Almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in this study had health insurance, and
        whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> were more likely than
        controls to report having had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or more mammograms in
        the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-94</TIMEX>, they were about equally likely to
        report obtaining pelvic exams over the same period. This
        suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who subsequently developed breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> might have had more mammograms than controls because
        they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> breast problems rather than because they
        were, in general, more regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of cancer screening
        services than controls.
        Interestingly, in both age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had given
        birth but had not breastfed had a higher risk for breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had never been pregnant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
        had been pregnant but not parous, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parous</ENAMEX> and breastfed, although the result was statistically
        significant only in those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 50 years and older</TIMEX>. In
        addition, among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 50 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
        breastfed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> or more had significantly reduced
        odds of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>. This finding is consistent with a
        large collaborative study [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] showing breastfeeding to
        be protective for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> through hormonal or other
        mechanisms. That report suggested an urgent need to fully
        understand the mechanisms of the protective effect of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breastfeeding</ENAMEX> so that some intervention mimicking
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">breastfeeding</ENAMEX> could be developed and offered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
        have not breastfed.
        It is also possible that inability to lactate or
        suppressing lactation after giving birth might have a
        deleterious effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast physiology</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] , but we did
        not request this information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Given the
        relatively late ages of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> birth in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, one
        might not expect to see a protective effect of having ever
        given birth, because the well-established protective
        effects of pregnancy seem to be reversed for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> births
        at about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 30 years</TIMEX> or later [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22</NUMEX> ] . This study had a
        higher percentage of nulliparous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of cases and
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26%</NUMEX> of controls) than a recent study conducted in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> area (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX> of cases and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> of controls) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Teachers Study</ENAMEX> cohort, with a
        similarly elevated rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">invasive breast cancer</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">151</NUMEX>
        per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> years among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> white women
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1995 and 1998</TIMEX>, reported a similar percentage of
        nulliparous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX>) among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> without breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        Consistent with previous findings [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] was our
        observation that cases were more likely to be premenopausal
        than controls, suggesting a later age at menopause. Despite
        the absence of a strong difference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at menarche
        between cases and controls in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
        developed breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> had relatively later menopause,
        indicating a greater number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of active
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">menstruation</ENAMEX>. Starting menarche at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 11 years</TIMEX> or earlier
        is considered an established <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> risk factor, and
        starting menarche at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 15 years or older</TIMEX> is considered an
        established protective factor [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . In the present
        study, cases were somewhat less likely than controls to
        start menarche at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 15 years or older</TIMEX>, but cases were not
        more likely than controls to have early menarche. A similar
        lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of age at menarche with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>
        status was apparent in the large recent study by
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] . The distribution of age
        at menarche reported by control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX> was
        similar to that observed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teachers Study</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohort</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        Disagreement remains in the literature on the direction
        and magnitude of effect, if any, of oral contraceptives on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> risk [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 16 24</NUMEX> ] . Despite large studies
        designed to address such differences, chance, selection
        factors, changes in formulations, patterns of use, and
        different background risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> might account
        for some of the variation in findings. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>
        study, we found a rather strong and significant inverse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> of oral contraceptive use and breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
        However, the lack of case-control differences by duration
        or latency of use argues against a causal connection and
        suggests that oral contraceptive use might be a surrogate
        for some other protective behavior or exposure. Given the
        very high rate of use of oral contraceptives in this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, an alternative explanation could be that
        factors or conditions contraindicating the use of oral
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contraceptives</ENAMEX> might increase the risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>.
        In future studies it might be worthwhile to assess why
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> chose to use, or not to use, oral contraceptives.
        In addition, there was no indication of large
        differences in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy use among cases
        and controls, which was similar to a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
        case-control study [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] , although any use of hormone
        replacement therapy was somewhat higher in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55-56%</NUMEX>) than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> study
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49-51%</NUMEX>). In addition, the specificity of questions about
        types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy used and the sample
        size of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX> study is insufficient to rule out the
        small increased risk (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25-30%</NUMEX>) observed in larger studies [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 26</NUMEX> ] or to examine in detail different hormone
        replacement therapy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regimens</ENAMEX>, duration, or age of use.
        Appropriately adjusted comparisons of rates of hormone
        replacement therapy use in this area and geographic areas
        with lower breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates would be informative
        regarding the relationship of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy
        use to the elevated <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> incidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX>.
        Many studies have examined <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> in relation to
        body weight, height, and overall body size (as measured by
        body mass index). The general consensus has been that
        increased height might be associated with increased risk
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, and that obesity might increase risk in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> or over or who are post-menopausal but
        might decrease risk in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 50 years</TIMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28 29 30</NUMEX> ] . Highest adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> mass index was strongly
        inversely related to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> status both in women
        under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 50 years</TIMEX> and, unexpectedly, in those aged
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years and older</TIMEX>. The average highest body mass indexes
        reported in this study (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24.9 and 26.5 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2for</ENAMEX> cases and
        controls, respectively) were in the same range reported for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> mass index <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> previously in a recent
        large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> study (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25.5 and 25.8 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2for</ENAMEX> cases and controls,
        respectively) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teachers Study</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">24.8 kg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/m 2</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX> ] .
        One explanation for the finding could be that mechanisms
        of weight maintenance might have contributed to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX>. Because we did not ask about adult or recent
        physical activity in the interview, we cannot assess the
        impact of these factors on the body size results. In the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nurses</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Study</ENAMEX> cohort, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX> ]
        reported that among postmenopausal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, weight gain was
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> only among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had not used hormone
        replacement therapy. We found that cases had lower highest
        body mass index than controls both among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had used
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy and among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who had not. It
        is possible in this affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that perimenopausal
        and postmenopausal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are not taking prescribed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy could be eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> or taking
        herbal or other non-prescribed supplements to ameliorate
        menopausal symptoms that might simulate the effects of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> replacement therapy. Unfortunately we did not
        collect the data to test this possibility, but such
        questions should be included in future studies.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Alcohol</ENAMEX> use has been increasingly associated with both
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">premenopausal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">postmenopausal breast cancer</ENAMEX> risk [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32 33</NUMEX>
        ] , including a report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Teachers Study</ENAMEX>,
        showing that recent alcohol consumption increases risk for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] . We found that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> were less likely than controls to have begun
        drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX>, they were much more
        likely than controls to consume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> per day
        on average as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. That the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORs</ENAMEX> for alcohol consumption
        in this study were generally higher than those reported in
        other studies suggests a possible interaction of alcohol
        consumption with other factors that have a high prevalence
        in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
        Cigarette smoking has not been consistently associated
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> risk [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> ] . The elevated OR observed
        in this study for the highest quartile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX>-years smoked
        might be due to differential participation by controls with
        a lower pack<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year</TIMEX> history or differential reporting of
        smoking history by cases and controls. It is also possible
        that smoking history was confounded by factors not measured
        in this study, such as physical activity.
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 50 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> were much more likely than controls to have been
        born or lived before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Northeastern</ENAMEX> or
        Great <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lakes</ENAMEX> regions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>, regions that were in the
        upper deciles of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> mortality both for the
        period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950-69</TIMEX> and for the period <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970-94</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] .
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geocoding</ENAMEX> and other refinements of residence information
        might help to clarify which areas of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or early life
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">residences</ENAMEX> might be associated with later risk for breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
        The similar average ages of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> and total
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin</ENAMEX> for cases and controls do not support
        (but cannot completely rule out) the hypothesis that there
        is some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> specific to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, such as a
        particular water <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, that might increase the risk for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>. These findings do not imply that
        environmental factors are unimportant in breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">causation</ENAMEX>. On the contrary, our and others' findings of
        increased risk with frequency of alcohol consumption show
        that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s personal environment can strongly influence
        her breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk. In addition, our result of higher
        risk among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 50 years</TIMEX> who lived in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northeast</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Lakes</ENAMEX> regions before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 21 years</TIMEX> might
        suggest a role of early environmental factors.
        Because control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in this study had such high rates
        of health insurance and use of basic screening services, it
        seems likely that they truly did not have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> at
        the time of interview. This was despite a higher proportion
        of controls with established <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors
        such as family history and nulliparity than observed in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject groups</ENAMEX> in other recent studies. Given this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observation</ENAMEX>, a further intensive study of this or other
        similarly high-incidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> might reveal factors
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proximate</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> diagnosis that could enrich our
        understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> etiology in a high-incidence
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Some provocative clues from this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> analysis
        suggest that some as yet unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correlate</ENAMEX> of oral
        contraceptive use might be protective and that consuming
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or more alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> per day might be deleterious
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in this high-incidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. We were unable
        to examine the effects of other provocative exposures
        previously proposed by others, including exposures to light
        at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ]
        . The observed early socioeconomic differences combined
        with a lack of differences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> at menarche or early body
        size also suggest that attention might be turned to
        patterns of early infection (or lack of infection) and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> response [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] .
        This study is among the first reported in which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community advocates</ENAMEX> took part in all aspects of the
        research process, from formulating questions of interest
        and questionnaire design to monitoring progress of subject
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recruitment</ENAMEX> and data analysis and interpretation at regular
        meetings. This study provides important information for
        planning additional studies to understand reasons for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> in this or other high-risk geographic areas
        characterized by a socioeconomically affluent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> and controls had very similar
        distributions of age of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> living and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> lived in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>, suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">County</ENAMEX>'s high breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> rates are probably not due to geographically
        specific exposures. Despite similar distributions for
        several known breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk factors, case-control
        differences in alcohol consumption suggest that breast
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> risk in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> might be modifiable. This
        study might be useful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        concerned with understanding the basis of, and means of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mitigating</ENAMEX>, high local or regional rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>.
        Intensive study of high-incidence areas might reveal other
        important risk factors proximate to diagnosis.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CI</ENAMEX> = confidence interval; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCCC</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern California</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer Center; NCI</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Cancer Institute</ENAMEX>; OR = odds
        ratio; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RDD</ENAMEX> = random digit dialing.
      
    
  
