
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Transport of critically ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>, and
        within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> can be associated with potentially adverse
        events [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 3</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> have shown that increased
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vigilance</ENAMEX>, appropriate equipment, and well-trained
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> can lead to improved safety while critically ill
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are being transported [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 5</ENAMEX>]. Prior work
        evaluating the potential problems associated with transport
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to intensive care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> has led to the
        establishment of guidelines for the transport of the
        critically ill [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6, 7</ENAMEX>].
        The need for safe and effective patient care en route
        has also been a goal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> military. Because
        initial emergency life-saving surgery and prompt,
        aggressive resuscitation may have to be performed under
        austere field conditions to render a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> transportable
        and since resource limitations or adverse conditions may
        lead to delayed evacuation or prolonged evacuation times,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Army</ENAMEX> has developed a new critical care
        transport <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Support for Trauma and</ENAMEX>
        Transport (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT™</ENAMEX>).
        Design goals for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> were solicited from medical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who have been deployed to combat zones, military
        and civilian medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who transport and care for
        critically ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> in military logistics
        with regard to medical equipment. Design goals included the
        following: weight limit of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">120 pounds</NUMEX>, volume not to exceed
        <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22 × 72 × 13 inches</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">56 × 183 × 20 cm</NUMEX>), battery power for
        up to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 minutes</TIMEX>, computer linkage of all the diagnostic
        and therapeutic equipment, capability of sending
        physiologic data to remote sites, and ability to generate
        pressurized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX> for the ventilator. To meet these design
        constraints, the diagnostic and therapeutic equipment
        contained within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> had to be significantly
        The purpose of this study was to evaluate how modified
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>, configured to fit within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>, may affect
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the identification and management of life-threatening
        physiologic derangements, using a patient <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulator</ENAMEX>, and
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) ongoing monitoring of vital signs in a recovery room
        setting.
      
      
        Methods
        
          Equipment
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> (model number <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9602</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated Medical</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems, Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signal Hill</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) consists of a pan and
          a stretcher. The pan contains commercially available
          equipment that has been reconfigured to fit in the
          <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5-inch-</NUMEX>deep (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">13-cm-</NUMEX>deep) pan (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The pan fits
          beneath and is attached to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> stretcher and has a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> fairing that extends <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7 inches</NUMEX> above the stretcher
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). This equipment includes a transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ventilator</ENAMEX>,
          a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">480-liter</NUMEX> oxygen tank, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-channel infusion pump, a
          defibrillator, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood gas</ENAMEX> and blood chemistry analyzer,
          a suction device, a vital signs monitor, a computer, a
          power converter, and a battery power supply. The computer
          within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> continuously transmits physiologic data
          over a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wireless network</ENAMEX> to a fixed large display called
          the clinical display and to a handheld
          notebook-computer-based display called the secondary
          display.
        
        
          Phase I: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evaluation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> by clinicians
          using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> simulator
          After internal review board approval at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Surgeons Human Subjects Research</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Board</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> anesthesiologists and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> recovery room
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nurses</ENAMEX> served as consenting volunteer clinicians to
          compare the clinical utility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> with
          conventional monitoring systems, using a patient
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">simulator</ENAMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer clinician</ENAMEX> was presented with a
          scripted description of the study methods and equipment
          to be used. The study description was read verbatim by
          the study proctor. The study proctor was the same person
          for all study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. Equipment included the LSTAT
          standard equipment used for physiologic monitoring
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protocol Systems Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model Propaq Encore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beaverton</ENAMEX>,
          OR, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), an E cylinder filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> (holding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">660</NUMEX> l
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2200</TIMEX> psi), a semiopen ventilation circuit
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vital Signs Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resuscitation Circuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX> No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5105</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">RV</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Totowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), an anesthesia machine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Drager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model Narkomed AV2</ENAMEX>+, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Telford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>),
          and a defibrillator (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX>, model number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43110</NUMEX>
          A, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">McMinnville</ENAMEX>, OR, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The anesthesia machine
          contained a ventilator and a suction device.
          After reading the scripted instructions, each
          volunteer clinician was allowed to ask questions about
          the use of each piece of equipment. The study did not
          proceed until sufficient answers to all questions were
          given as determined by the volunteer clinician. A
          comparison was made of the training time required for
          volunteer clinicians to feel ready to use the LSTAT
          versus conventional monitors. The training time was
          defined as the time required by the study proctor to read
          the instructions plus the time required for each
          volunteer clinician to ask questions about its use.
          After having been trained, each volunteer clinician
          was presented with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> scenarios in turn (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>),
          using a patient <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulator</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Education Technologies</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarasota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). During <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> scenarios, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinicians</ENAMEX> used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> and during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other two</TIMEX>
          scenarios they used conventional equipment. The
          clinicians were randomly assigned to one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group A</ENAMEX> used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> with scenarios <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 2</NUMEX> and
          conventional equipment with scenarios <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 and 4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group B</ENAMEX>
          did the opposite.
          Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer clinician</ENAMEX> was required to state the
          diagnosis and the treatment needed during each scenario.
          Incorrect answers were ignored. If a clinician required
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to state the correct diagnosis or
          treatment, the scenario was stopped and recorded as
          incorrect. When the correct diagnosis was stated, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> was recorded. The time to treatment was recorded
          when the volunteer clinician stated the appropriate
          treatment and demonstrated the appropriate use of the
          equipment needed to implement it. The times to diagnosis
          and treatment with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> monitoring systems were
          compared using the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mann-Whitney</ENAMEX> test.
          After the simulations were over, each volunteer
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinician</ENAMEX> completed a survey about use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. The
          survey asked about the alarm systems, ability to detect
          critical changes in vital signs, and utility of the LSTAT
          to manage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> if no other equipment were
          available.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phase II</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evaluation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> in a routine
          postoperative setting
          Nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> received a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45-minute</TIMEX> training seminar in
          the use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>, in which the system was placed on a
          modified wheel system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stryker Medical</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Wheel No.</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kalamazoo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> consenting adult patients
          were each placed on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> in the operating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> after
          surgery. A pulse oximeter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, electrocardiogram leads,
          and blood pressure cuff were attached to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. Each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> received supplemental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> via facemask.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> were then transported to the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> in the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was noted for all
          events requiring intervention (e.g. deteriorating
          respiratory function requiring acute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">airway</ENAMEX>, episodes of hypotension, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>,
          arrhythmias, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">postoperative nausea</ENAMEX> and vomiting, and
          inadequate pain control) as detected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>.
          Measures of performance included both the number of
          postoperative events requiring intervention that were
          detected using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>'s physiologic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> and a
          survey of its utility taken from recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> nursing
          staff, reviewing functionality, problems, and potential
          problems observed during clinical use.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Phase I: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evaluation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> by clinicians
          using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> simulator
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirty-one</ENAMEX> volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> participated in the
          simulator evaluation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. All of them had been
          trained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Cardiac Life Support</ENAMEX> (ACLS), <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71%</NUMEX> had
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">up-to-date ACLS</ENAMEX> certification (recertification within the
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">preceding 2 years</TIMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29%</NUMEX> had been trained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trauma Life Support</ENAMEX> (ATLS).
          The time required to provide instruction to each
          volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clinician</ENAMEX> ranged from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 to 7 minutes</TIMEX>. They
          required <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 1 to 2 minutes</TIMEX> more to learn how to use
          the LSTAT than to use conventional monitors.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2compares</ENAMEX> conventional monitoring equipment and
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> with regard to the time required to reach a
          diagnosis and the time required to choose an appropriate
          treatment for anesthesiologists. The size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
          recovery room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> was not large enough to merit
          statistical analysis and therefore only the results from
          the survey are reported.
          In scenarios <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, there was no significant
          difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> and conventional monitors in
          the time required to reach a diagnosis or treatment. In
          scenario <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pulseless ventricular tachycardia</ENAMEX>), the time
          required to make the diagnosis and treatment was shorter
          than with the other scenarios regardless of which
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX> (LSTAT or conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> and equipment)
          was used; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> anesthesiologists made the
          diagnosis in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">less than 1 minute</TIMEX>. The time required to
          treat the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pulseless ventricular tachycardia</ENAMEX> was less with
          the conventional monitors than with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. In
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">scenarios 1, 2</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, the number of anesthesiologists
          unable to provide a correct diagnosis or treatment within
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX> was evenly distributed between the conventional
          monitor and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. In scenario <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, all
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anesthesiologists</ENAMEX> provided the correct diagnosis and
          treatment within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3shows</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX>' response to the survey
          regarding the clinical usefulness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> after
          completing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> simulations. All the participating
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinicians</ENAMEX> reported that they were able to properly
          manage the simulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. All
          participating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> except one who abstained
          reported that if no other medical equipment were
          available in a remote setting, they would be able to
          provide appropriate care using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. All of the
          survey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> indicated that it was safe to proceed
          to the next phase of the study, in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> would
          be used in a clinical setting.
          Survey questions aimed at exploring how useful the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> was in managing critical events revealed that all
          of the participating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> were able to properly
          manage the simulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> reported that they
          were able to detect critical changes in vital signs in a
          timely manner. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> clinicians, however, reported that
          they were not able to detect critical changes in vital
          signs because of difficulty seeing physiologic data on
          the display screens and the location of the displays.
          Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> indicated that they would have liked
          more time to become familiar with the equipment before
          assuming patient care.
          A majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> reported that suction and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">capnography</ENAMEX> would be useful during transport and that the
          controls on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> were easy to operate. In addition,
          the survey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> reported that the configuration of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>, as an intrinsic part of the stretcher, did not
          obstruct access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. Features that were noted
          to be useful by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> were the compactness of all
          the equipment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> and the integration of a
          ventilator into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> to facilitate transport of
          ventilator-dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phase II</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evaluation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> in a routine
          postoperative setting
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were monitored on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> during their
          recovery from surgery. Complications experienced by this
          patient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> associated with recovery from surgery
          included postoperative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nausea</ENAMEX> and vomiting, inadequate
          pain control, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>, hypoxia, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tachycardia</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> who cared for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> in the
          recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> completed surveys and the results are
          presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4</ENAMEX>.
          All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> of the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> reported
          that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> provided adequate equipment to properly
          care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> recovering from surgery. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> of the
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> reported that it was easy to operate. The remaining
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> reported that they would have liked a more extensive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">in-service</ENAMEX> training before using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>.
          All those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> who responded reported that all
          critical changes in vital signs were detected and
          addressed in a timely manner using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. Limitations
          cited by the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> included
          difficulty reading displays of vital signs on the
          secondary display and muted audible alarms that were
          difficult to hear in a recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> environment. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
          of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> reported that the large clinical
          display improved their ability to detect changes in vital
          signs and all but one reported that if no other equipment
          were available in a remote setting, they would be able to
          resuscitate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>.
          During transport of recovery room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, no
          critical events were reported. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> reported
          that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> provided an advantage during transport
          within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and most reported that the secondary
          display was useful for monitoring vital signs during
          transport. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> reported that if the secondary display
          was not available, it would be difficult to monitor vital
          signs during transport if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was placed on the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> so that the head fairing containing the physiologic
          monitoring and ventilator displays were at the foot of
          the bed. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> that responded reported that the
          maneuverability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> was adequate to
          enhanced.
          Overall comments by recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> nursing staff
          suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> would be helpful in patients
          with more highly acute conditions (e.g. in the intensive
          care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, trauma bay, and prehospital settings) and that
          features that set the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> apart from conventional
          equipment include compactness, readily available suction,
          capnography, defibrillator, and on-board oxygen tank.
          Finally, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22%</NUMEX> of the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> found the
          integration of the monitoring and therapeutic equipment
          into a stretcher for transport very useful, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> found it
          to be useful, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX> found it to be somewhat useful.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
          Phase I: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evaluation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> by clinicians
          using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> simulator
          In this simulation phase of the study, the time
          required for clinicians to detect and treat
          life-threatening physiologic derangements was nearly
          identical using conventional equipment versus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>.
          In the simulations of tension pneumothorax, severe adult
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">respiratory distress syndrome</ENAMEX>, and cardiac tamponade, the
          number of anesthesiologists unable to make a correct
          diagnosis or provide the correct treatment within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> was evenly divided between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> study
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
          In the simulation of pulseless ventricular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tachycardia</ENAMEX>, the median time to diagnosis and treatment
          was significantly shorter using conventional monitors
          than using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. Although pulseless ventricular
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tachycardia</ENAMEX> is a life-threatening arrhythmia and merits
          immediate attention, the differences between the LSTAT
          and conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> are subtle and may not be
          clinically important (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> versus <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">41 seconds</TIMEX> in the time to
          diagnosis and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> versus <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">44 seconds</TIMEX> in the time to
          treatment). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> potential source of delay for the time to
          treatment was that the defibrillator used in the
          conventional monitoring simulation was similar to one
          currently used in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> operating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, whereas
          the defibrillator incorporated into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> is not. It
          is important to point out that if a defibrillator is not
          readily available (the defibrillator was readily
          available in our simulations), the time required to
          locate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and treat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> could be much longer
          than that reported in our simulation.
          In the tension pneumothorax and the adult respiratory
          distress scenarios, the simulated patient required
          mechanical ventilation. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, ventilation
          was accomplished using the transport ventilator contained
          within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> using conventional
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monitors</ENAMEX>, ventilation was accomplished using a semiopen
          ventilation circuit that required manual operation. One
          difference reported by the volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> was that
          they wanted to take the patient off the ventilator to
          hand ventilate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in order to validate their
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diagnosis</ENAMEX>, despite already having the peak airway
          pressures, delivered tidal volumes, and end tidal carbon
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dioxide</ENAMEX> levels readily available. This issue is not
          unique to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> ventilator. None of the commercially
          available transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ventilators</ENAMEX> has an auxiliary
          ventilator circuit that allows manual ventilation.
          Mechanical ventilation during transport of critically ill
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> has been found to be advantageous over hand
          ventilation in meeting oxygenation and ventilation goals
          and in minimizing the acid-base disturbances that may
          lead to hemodynamic instability [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 3</ENAMEX>]. In addition,
          even though hand ventilation was not available during
          simulated transports with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> ventilator, there was
          no difference in the time to diagnosis or treatment for
          either the tension pneumothorax or the severe adult
          respiratory distress scenarios.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> potential criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> is that it is too
          sophisticated and will require excessive training to
          teach clinicians how to use it. Our results did not
          validate this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. Both recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> nursing staff
          and the anesthesiologists required <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 2</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> more training time with the LSTAT than with
          conventional monitors. The overall training time never
          exceeded <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 minutes</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. These results may be
          influenced by several factors. Because the patient
          transports were simulated, the volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> may
          not have felt that they needed to pursue all the nuances
          about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>'s equipment that they otherwise would
          have if they had been caring for a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Secondly</NUMEX>, the volunteer clinician <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> studied has
          significant experience with various types of patient
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monitors</ENAMEX>, ventilators, and defibrillators and may not
          have required as much teaching time as would other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> who are not as routinely involved with these
          items.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phase II</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evaluation</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> in a routine
          postoperative setting
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> was judged by nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to be adequate
          for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> recovering from surgery.
          Complications experienced by the patient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> were
          typical of complications associated with recovery from
          surgery. Features that set the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> apart from routine
          monitoring of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> included the
          readily available defibrillator, availability of suction
          and capnography for transport, a built-in oxygen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>,
          the fixed large clinical display of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s vital
          signs in the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and the mobile secondary
          display which reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s vital signs for use
          during transport.
          After having used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> in the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, the
          nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> was asked to critique the use of the LSTAT
          in managing critical events. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> visualization and
          visual and auditory alarms were of primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> both
          with the physiologic monitor and the ventilator. Some
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> were concerned that they would not be able to
          detect critical changes in vital signs because of these
          limitations. This problem may be the result of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
          conflicting design goals: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> needs (low sound
          and low light <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX>) and the needs of the intensive
          care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> (visual physiologic data presentation and loud
          auditory signals and alarms). The screens contained
          within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> were selected to reduce power
          consumption and minimize light emission. Potential
          solutions to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> include enhanced training with
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> to improve clinicians' comfort with the
          existing data displays and alarm systems as well as
          exploration of alternatives for data and alarm
          presentation to improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinician</ENAMEX>'s awareness of a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s status.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX> recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> reported that they
          did not notice any particular advantage of the LSTAT
          during transports within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. In this phase of
          the study, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> was used to transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> from
          the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to the ambulatory surgery discharge
          area or to a hospital bed, a transport routinely done
          without any patient monitoring. Thus in less acute
          transport settings, it is reasonable that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> would
          not provide any significant advantage.
          An expressed concern of some of the military product
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX> was that the weight of the LSTAT pan and the
          configuration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> as dictated by the size
          constraints to fit in military aircraft would make the
          LSTAT awkward to use during patient care. The survey
          results did not support this potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. For
          example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> was easy to
          operate, access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> was not obstructed, and
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> was easy to maneuver. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> reported
          that consolidation of all the physiologic monitoring
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX> and incorporation of a transport ventilator
          were all advantages for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> transport. After the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">simulator</ENAMEX> study, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> indicated that it was
          safe to proceed to the next phase of the study, in which
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> would be used in a clinical setting.
          Furthermore, volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinicians</ENAMEX> reported through their
          surveys that they were able to properly manage the
          simulated and real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>. All but one
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinician</ENAMEX> reported that if no other equipment were
          available in a remote setting, they would be able to
          resuscitate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX>.
          This report represents a preliminary evaluation of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> in a clinical setting. The goal was to validate the
          functionality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> before its evaluation in more
          acute settings such as intensive care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, emergency
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>, transports within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, within medical
          evacuation <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> during transport between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>,
          and eventually in remote areas where medical resources
          are limited or unavailable. A logical next step is to
          evaluate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> during the initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of
          critically injured trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> as they present for
          evaluation in an emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> trauma bay. This might be
          best accomplished in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> designed for and staffed
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> trained in trauma patient care. The same
          study hypothesis might be: does equipment typically found
          in an intensive care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, condensed to fit in a small
          space underneath a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> stretcher, serve as an
          equivalent tool to conventional equipment in detecting
          and treating life-threatening problems?
          Additional questions may incoude the following: Does
          the LSTAT reduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and resources needed for
          intra-hospital transport for emergency imaging (e.g.
          computer tomography scans or angiography studies), rapid
          transfer to the operating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, or transfer to the
          intensive care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>? Does remote monitoring of a patient
          during intrahospital transport improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinician</ENAMEX>'s
          vigilance in detecting life-threatening problems that may
          develop during transport? Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> other than
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anesthesiologists</ENAMEX> and recovery room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> learn to use
          the medical devices contained within the LSTAT
          effectively? And finally, does the integration of
          physiologic data, ventilator data, arterial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood gas</ENAMEX> and
          chemistry data, and clinical data into an optimized
          computer-based display help clinicians evaluate patients
          more efficiently and make more informed decisions when
          caring for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with multiple life-threatening
          injuries [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8, 9, 10</ENAMEX>]?
          The clinical relevance of this line of investigation
          is a function of the prevalence of trauma in our world
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and the need to provide life-saving intervention
          quickly after injury. Experience in major metropolitan
          <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> where evacuation times are quick and
          state-of-the-art surgical and resuscitative resources and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">well-trained</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> are readily available has
          established the benefit of early surgical intervention
          and resuscitation on survival [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11, 12</TIMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> was
          designed to provide equipment for underserved areas where
          conventional intensive care resources may be unavailable.
          Thus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> may serve as a critical resource to a
          highly mobile surgical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> because it can be placed very
          near the site of injury in an effort to reduce the time
          from injury to life-saving intervention. The LSTAT
          provides the equipment necessary for appropriate
          postoperative care of a critically injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, for
          transport to tertiary care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, or for holding
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> until evacuation is feasible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> can also
          serve as a resource to resuscitate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who do not
          require surgery but who do require intensive care.
        
      
      
        Key messages
        Medical equipment reconfigured and miniaturized into a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">stretcher</ENAMEX>-based portable intensive care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> (called the
        Life Support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trauma and Transport</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT TM</ENAMEX>]) was
        evaluated using a patient <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">simulator</ENAMEX> and during patient care
        in a recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> setting
        In the simulation phase of the study, volunteer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinicians</ENAMEX> compared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> with conventional monitors
        while managing critical events
        In the recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> phase of the study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>
        critiqued the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> while caring for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> after
        surgery
        In both the simulated and postoperative environments,
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> provided appropriate equipment to detect and
        manage critical events in patient care
      
      
        Competing interests
        This study was supported in part by a grant from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Army Medical Research and Material Command</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSTAT</ENAMEX> is a trademark of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Army</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LSTAT™ = Life Support for Trauma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transport</ENAMEX>
        = <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">pounds per square inch</NUMEX>.
      
    
  
