
  
    
      
        Introduction
        The term 'sepsis' is used to define the systemic
        inflammatory response to an infectious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> (i.e.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bacterial</ENAMEX>, viral, fungal or parasitic). Despite the use of
        new treatment modalities, improvements in technology and
        increased experience, mortality rates in sepsis remain high
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2</ENAMEX>]. Critical care <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> have at their disposal a
        variety of data to serve as a guide in discriminating
        infectious from noninfectious conditions in newly admitted
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. In a number of newly admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> the
        diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> becomes clear after taking the medical
        history and completing the physical examination [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. In
        other cases, in which noninfectious insults are responsible
        for systemic inflammatory response syndrome (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX>; e.g.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trauma</ENAMEX>, burns, haemorrhages, hypothermia, pancreatitis and
        surgery) or in comatose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, the diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>
        remains difficult.
        Prompt diagnosis and treatment with appropriate
        antimicrobial chemotherapy is of the utmost importance in
        reducing the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">morbidity</ENAMEX> and mortality associated with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. The lack of specific early markers of infection may
        be responsible in part for withholding, delaying or
        unnecessary antimicrobial treatment in critically ill
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. Thus, there is an unmet need for clinical or
        laboratory tools that can distinguish between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. Various markers of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>reactive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (CRP), tumour necrosis factor (TNF)-α, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-1β, IL-6</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, have all been studied for their ability to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiate SIRS</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 5, 6, 7</ENAMEX>]. Several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have questioned the diagnostic accuracy of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">procalcitonin</ENAMEX> (PCT) measurement, results with which have
        been inconsistent and variable [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10</ENAMEX>]. Thus,
        it may not be easy to discriminate between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>,
        even with the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">procalcitonin</ENAMEX> level at early diagnosis (and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX>) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with systemic inflammatory
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">response syndrome</ENAMEX> (SIRS) and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>, in comparison with
        C-reactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> and tumour necrosis
        factor-α in an unselected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> suffering
        from a broad range of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> in an intensive care unit
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICU</ENAMEX>).
      
      
        Methods
        
          Laboratory measurements
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX> was measured using a routine turbidimetry assay
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILAD-900; Instrumentation Laboratory</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>); a
          value greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/l was considered to be
          abnormally elevated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> were
          measured using commercially available cheluminesan kits
          (Immulite-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). All cytokine
          samples were analyzed in duplicate. PCT levels (normal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">range 0-0.5 ng/l</ENAMEX>) were determined by means of a specific
          and ultrasensitive immunoluminometric assay (LUMI test
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT; Brahms Ag</ENAMEX>, Hennigsdorf/ <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          For multiple group comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ILs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX>,
          one-way analysis of variance was applied, with least
          squares difference for 
          post hoc comparison. The best
          cutoff value of parameters for the diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>
          was determined according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youden</ENAMEX>'s index method.
          The ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> to predict <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> was evaluated by
          performing receiver operative characteristic analyses to
          compare SIRS versus <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>]. Furthermore,
          the areas under the receiver operative characteristic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curve</ENAMEX> (AUCs) were determined, as well as the
          positive/negative predictive values. Positive predictive
          values and negative predictive values indicate the
          proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with a cytokine level greater than
          or below the chosen cutoff point. Test effectiveness is
          the sum of the positive predictive values and negative
          predictive values. Thus, the maximum score is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, which
          represents perfect prediction, both positive and negative
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. The septic shock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was not included in this
          analysis because of insufficient data. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical</ENAMEX>
          analyses were conducted using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Program</ENAMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Science</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPSS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P < 0.05</ENAMEX> was considered
          statistically significant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> in the text are shown as
          mean ± standard error, or as median and percentiles
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%/25%/75%/90%</NUMEX>).
        
      
      
        Results
        A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>) were
        included in the study. The median age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> was
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">58 ±</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX>. The duration of stay of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICU</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX> ± <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6.78 days</TIMEX>. The final, retrospectively
        confirmed diagnoses of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are shown in Table
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
        For each of the time points assessed in the present
        study, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were categorized into the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">namely SIRS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and septic shock. No severely septic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were identified. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> died on the second
        day following admission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICU</ENAMEX>, and those patients
        underwent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> assessments. Thus, a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX>
        assessments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' clinical status were conducted
        (referred to hereafter as 'conditions'), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> of which
        indicated SIRS (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">35 sepsis</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX> of all
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> septic shock (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7%</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>).
        Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> conditions of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and septic shock, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX>) involved <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>) urogenital infection, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>) intraperitoneal abscess and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX>) wound infection.
        In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> no infectious focus could be found, but
        blood cultures were positive. Infections were
        microbiologically proven in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88%</NUMEX>) conditions, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51%</NUMEX>
        being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gram</ENAMEX>-negative, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gram</ENAMEX>-positive and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> mixed
        infections. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> conditions with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX>, tracheal
        cultures were positive but did not exhibit any host
        response; they were therefore considered colonization.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> did not receive antimicrobial treatment in
        any of the study periods. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who died
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5/6</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83%</NUMEX>]) were in septic shock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who died (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5/35</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX>]) were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APACHE-II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> did not differ between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. No
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correlation</ENAMEX> was found between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> concentrations and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APACHE-II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> ( 
        r = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.23</NUMEX>). Serum concentrations of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> were not statistically different
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">septic shock groups</ENAMEX>. IL-2, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> levels were different between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Septic shock
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had the highest level of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> and PCT
        concentrations. Median and percentiles (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10/25/75/90%</NUMEX>) for
        all parameters and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">APACHE-II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and septic shock are presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>.
        Because we only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> septic shock conditions were
        identified, we employed only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> conditions for
        statistical analysis of diagnostic reliability of serum PCT
        and cytokines. Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youden</ENAMEX>'s Index, the best cutoff value
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.415</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml. The best cut-off value and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUC</ENAMEX> for
        all markers are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUC</ENAMEX> was highest for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4summarizes</ENAMEX> the predictive accuracy of the
        laboratory variables for the specific diagnoses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. With a cutoff point of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.415</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml, serum PCT
        concentration was found to be the most discriminatory
        laboratory variable, the predictive accuracy of which
        exceeded those of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>. With
        regard to positive and negative predictive values, we found
        that PCT markedly exceeds the values calculated for other
        variables. The test effectiveness was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.84</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">predicting sepsis</ENAMEX>, whereas the other variables reached
        values between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.96</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.22</NUMEX>.
      
      
        Discussion
        We analyzed the plasma concentrations of various
        biochemical markers with respect to their potential use in
        differentiating between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. This assessment is of potential interest
        because systemic inflammation is a common problem in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICU</ENAMEX>, which often leads to shock and death. The diagnostic
        repertoire for identifying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> is poor. Verification of
        infection site, and even the presence of infection, remains
        problematic in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, the infection
        site is never identified. Neither imaging studies nor blood
        culture analysis can rule out the presence of infection [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>]. Moreover, there are classes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
        unconfirmed infection, or for whom cultures are negative
        yet who develop similar symptoms, rates of organ failure
        and survival outcomes as do those in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in whom
        infection is confirmed. The availability of laboratory
        tests for accurate and rapid identification of septic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> by isolation of micro-organisms from body fluid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specimens</ENAMEX> would be of considerable value. Thus, there is a
        clear need for a reliable diagnostic procedure that allows
        early discrimination between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> suffering from SIRS
        and those with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. A relatively new marker that has
        been associated with inflammation and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX>, a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">116</NUMEX>-amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid protein</ENAMEX> that is the precursor to calcitonin.
        The PCT plasma level in healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> is low, usually
        below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. That PCT concentration is
        significantly elevated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with organ dysfunction
        is undoubted. However, the difference in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and those with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> may be small.
        Reports of the usefulness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> for discriminating between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> are conflicting [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10</ENAMEX>].
        Therefore, we selected several cytokines as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> for
        early diagnosis (and differentiation) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with SIRS
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>.
        High serum PCT concentrations were first described by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assicot</ENAMEX> and coworkers [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>] in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with severe
        bacterial infections, and were suggested to be a specific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marker</ENAMEX> for bacterial infection. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Nawas</ENAMEX> and coworkers [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>] reported higher PCT levels in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with clinically
        documented infection than in those fulfilling the criteria
        for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> studies compared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and
        found that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> had poorer sensitivity, specificity and AUC
        than did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX> as a marker of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8, 10</ENAMEX>]. In order to
        assess the diagnostic utility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX> in a medical
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICU</ENAMEX>, prospective measurements were conducted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX>
        consecutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with acute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> did not
        clearly discriminate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. Another group
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> reported average PCT concentrations of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> ±
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> ± <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.9</NUMEX> ±
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml for severe <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. On the basis of their
        findings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX>, white
        blood cell and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> temperature does not discriminate SIRS
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> was the only parameter to discriminate
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and severe <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>] investigated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
        admitted to a medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICU</ENAMEX> and suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> is a more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reliable marker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> than is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> and lactate
        levels. To assess the diagnostic value of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-6, IL-8</ENAMEX>
        and standard measures for identifying critically ill
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>, prospective
        measurements were taken in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX> consecutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> admitted
        with acute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and suspected infection. PCT yielded the
        highest discriminative value for differentiating patients
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> from those with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-6 and IL-8</ENAMEX>
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selberg</ENAMEX> and coworkers [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>] studied discrimination of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of circulating plasma
        concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C3a</ENAMEX> in a medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICU</ENAMEX>. Their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> indicated that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C3a</ENAMEX> concentrations are
        more reliable parameter for differentiating between septic
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> than are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX> and elastase.
        Mechanical trauma causes elevated PCT levels, the degree
        of which depends on the severity of the injury. Levels peak
        on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days 1-3</TIMEX> and fall thereafter. High concentrations of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">circulating PCT</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first 3 days</TIMEX> after injury
        discriminate between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> at risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> and
        multiple organ dysfunctions in the early and late
        post-traumatic course [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>].
        Previous studies compared <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-α and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> separately for differentiating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>; in the
        present study, all of the available biochemical markers
        were measured at the same time [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 7, 8, 9, 10</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> had
        the highest sensitivity and specificity for differentiating
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>, followed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">IL-2</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>. Thus, in
        agreement with previous studies [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6, 7</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> was a more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reliable marker</ENAMEX> in the diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> than other
        measures.
        The present study included consecutive unselected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who were representative of an ICU <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, with
        baseline characteristics similar those reported in the
        literature, and strict objective criteria for the diagnosis
        of infection were employed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. However, several
        criticisms of the study should be addressed. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> was
        not monitored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, and a shorter monitoring interval
        may improve its performance as an aid for diagnosis and
        follow up of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, with the use of clinical
        criteria and microbiological evidence, it might have been
        difficult to ascertain the exact aetiology of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> in all
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. This may have introduced some misclassification
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> who were blinded to the
        cytokine results performed the case ascertainment; however,
        we do not believe this lack of an important standard
        compromised our study conclusions. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, antimicrobial
        therapy may have an impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> values. Our study design
        does not allow us to explain the exact relationship between
        antimicrobial therapy and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> values. The temporal
        relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX> treatment should be
        assessed in further studies.
      
      
        Conclusion
        In the present study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> appeared to be a more accurate
        diagnostic parameter for differentiating between patients
        suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and those with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>. Routine
        determination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> may improve management of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,
        for example by preventing the use of unnecessary
        antibiotics that are known to select resistance strains.
        Further studies of the early phases of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX> are necessary
        to define the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> in possible therapeutic
        strategies, such as antimicrobial and immunological
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">therapies</ENAMEX>, and cost implcations.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        Key message
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• PCT</ENAMEX> appears to be a useful early marker for
        discriminating between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">sepsis</ENAMEX>
      
      
        Abbreviations
        curve; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CRP</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">reactive protein</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICU</ENAMEX> = intensive care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interleukin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCT</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">procalcitonin</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIRS</ENAMEX> = systemic
        inflammatory response syndrome; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX> = tumour necrosis
        factor.
      
    
  
