
  
    
      
        Introduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> is a potentially catastrophic event in patients
        presenting with acute coronary syndromes. In recent trials
        of antiplatelet and antithrombotic therapies for such
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, prevention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> was the primary treatment effect
        assessed [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 2, 3, 4</ENAMEX>]. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> has been considered a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'hard</ENAMEX>' end-point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of MI end-points in
        clinical trials can be difficult, just as in clinical
        practice. Because of conflicting clinical, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrocardiography</ENAMEX> (ECG) data, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> often disagree
        whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> has suffered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>. The importance of
        low-level enzyme elevations also has been controversial,
        particularly in asymptomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and in those
        undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
        Although such enzyme elevations are defined as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX> in many
        trial protocols, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> in clinical practice do not
        consistently consider them as such. The MI rates reported
        by site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> in recent cardiovascular trials have
        differed from rates adjudicated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6, 7, 8, 9</ENAMEX>]. The
        reasons for these differences are unclear.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CECs</ENAMEX> are widely accepted to adjudicate suspected
        endpoint events in trials, but only limited information has
        been published regarding end-point adjudication [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11</TIMEX>,
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 13, 14, 15</TIMEX>]. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PURSUIT</ENAMEX> trial [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>], a central,
        independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEC</ENAMEX> systematically identified and adjudicated
        all suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIs</ENAMEX> that occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 30 days</TIMEX> after
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enrolment</ENAMEX>. The rationale for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> adjudication was the need
        for a systematic, unbiased, independent, and standard
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment of MIs</ENAMEX> in a large international trial. In a
        previous analysis of the CEC process in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">PURSUIT trial</ENAMEX>,
        we found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> and site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> assessments of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">end-point MI</ENAMEX> disagreed in ~<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. We
        retrospectively reviewed these cases, to identify reasons
        for them and to understand their potential effect on the
        trial results.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PURSUIT</ENAMEX> trial
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PURSUIT</ENAMEX> trial examined the role of eptifibatide, a
          platelet glycoprotein <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIb/IIIa</ENAMEX> antagonist, in patients
          presenting with acute coronary syndromes without
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">persistent ST</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> elevation. The trial enrolled
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,948</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">726</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, using previously reported inclusion and exclusion
          criteria and treatment regimens [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. The primary
          end-point was a composite of death or post-enrolment MI
          (or reinfarction if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> at enrolment) by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> as adjudicated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX>. The composite end-point was
          also constructed using the site investigator
          determination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Definitions
          The protocol defined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> as an end-point event based on
          clinical, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX>, and laboratory criteria (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appendix</ENAMEX>);
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX> that occurred before or at enrolment were not
          included in the primary end-point. The site investigators
          and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> used the same MI criteria. These criteria
          were presented in the protocol, at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> meetings,
          and in trial materials and newsletters.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> collection
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> were captured on standard case report forms.
          Information collected for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> included cardiac
          enzymes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECGs</ENAMEX> (at the time of the qualifying episode, at
          enrolment, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>, at initial discharge, and at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>), revascu-larisation procedure reports, details of
          ischemic episodes, clinical complications, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX>,
          and readmission records. All enzyme values for each
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> were to be reported, and study monitors verified
          them against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> documents. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suspected MI</ENAMEX>, site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> were to submit
          supporting documents and to include discharge summaries
          and additional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECGs</ENAMEX> during the suspected event. An
          independent, blinded, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG Core Laboratory</ENAMEX> read the ECGs
          and identified suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIs</ENAMEX>, defined as new Q waves â‰¥
          0.04 s in two contiguous leads.
        
        
          Clinical events classification process
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> and the event adjudication
          process have been reported in detail elsewhere [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>].
          Computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">algorithms</ENAMEX> systematically identified key
          clinical, enzymatic, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX> data from the database that
          could indicate the occurrence of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>. Each case of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suspected MI</ENAMEX> was reviewed independently by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blinded</ENAMEX> to treatment. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> agreed that a MI
          had or had not occurred, the case was classified as
          resolved. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> cardiologists reviewed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> about which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> disagreed, for
          adjudication by consensus.
        
        
          Disagreements between the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and
          CEC
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> cardiologist (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KWM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSC</ENAMEX>) re-reviewed
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with disagreement between the site investigator
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> adjudication of end-point <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>, to
          determine reasons for the disagreement. This review
          occurred after the main trial results were presented, but
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> were blinded to patient treatment
          assignment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> were categorised during the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-review in clinically meaningful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enrolment</ENAMEX> (versus post-enrolment MI), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> related to the
          revascularisation procedure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> related to clinically
          evident ischemia, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asymptomatic cardiac enzyme</ENAMEX> elevation
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-enrolment</ENAMEX>, and clinically significant cardiac event
          resulting in death (versus sudden death without evidence
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>).
          Despite rigorous criteria to define <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>, some patients
          required a subjective assessment by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> if
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac enzyme</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX>, and clinical information conflicted.
          For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> identified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> but not by the
          site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> (excluding events after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> or bypass
          surgery), we therefore assigned a level of clinical
          certainty. A high clinical certainty was assigned when
          all clinicians agreed that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> had occurred; a low
          clinical certainty was assigned when only some clinicians
          would agree that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> had occurred.
        
        
          Statistical analysis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> regarding the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with suspected
          events and those with disagreements between the site
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> were obtained from the entire
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PURSUIT</ENAMEX> study <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, so the data included patients
          assigned high-dose eptifibatide, low-dose eptifibatide,
          or placebo. Comparisons by treatment assignments included
          only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> assigned to high-dose eptifibatide or
          placebo to maintain consistency with the primary efficacy
          analysis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PURSUIT</ENAMEX> trial [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> values were calculated using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î§ 2test.</ENAMEX>
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Incidence of disagreement
          Overall, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5005</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with possible or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suspected MI</ENAMEX> were identified and adjudicated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX>.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> identified more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with end-point events
          than did the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13.6%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.7%</NUMEX> for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">placebo</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.6%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.2%</NUMEX> for eptifibatide). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> and
          site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> assessments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> disagreed for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9%</NUMEX> of
          all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> enrolled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PURSUIT</ENAMEX> trial. The CEC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">identified MIs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1415</TIMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5005</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suspected MI</ENAMEX>. The site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> and the CEC
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assessments</ENAMEX> disagreed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">983</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX>) of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5005</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
          Of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">983</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with disagreements, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">816</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
          had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> identified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> but not the site
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">167</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> identified by
          site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX>. The proportion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with disagreement was similar among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Reasons for disagreement
          Most often, when the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> had identified
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> had not, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> had
          misclassified a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> at enrolment as an end-point <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>,
          although by protocol these were not end-point events
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Recurrent ischemic events without elevated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac enzymes</ENAMEX> or ECG evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> were also
          incorrectly identified by site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). In cases where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> had identified a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> and
          the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> had not, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of those
          identified were MIs defined by enzyme elevations without
          clinical or ECG evidence of ischemia or infarction (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Enzyme elevations after bypass surgery accounted for
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> of these cases. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX> with clinically evident
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ischemia</ENAMEX> reported by the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> and associated
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac enzyme elevations</ENAMEX> were not reported as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX>
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27%</NUMEX> of the cases of disagreement
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). Few infarctions based on new Q waves without
          clinical evidence of reinfarction were identified by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> and not by site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3presents</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac enzyme</ENAMEX> elevation for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX>
          that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> identified and the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> did
          not. These data exclude MIs associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> or bypass
          surgery; by definition, those types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> required enzyme
          elevations greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or five</NUMEX> times the upper
          limit of normal (ULN), respectively. The ratio of
          creatine kinase-myocardial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX>) to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULN</ENAMEX> was
          highest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> (median [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>] 1.6 [<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.9</NUMEX>]). Enzymes were similarly elevated between patients
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX> defined only by enzyme elevations (without
          symptoms or ECG changes) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with elevations
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX> or clinical evidence of ischemia.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4presents</ENAMEX> the level of clinical certainty for
          MIs not associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> or bypass surgery, as
          identified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> but not the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>.
          Overall, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">98</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX>) of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were assigned a low
          level of clinical certainty. The proportion of patients
          assigned a low level of clinical certainty varied among
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>, with the lowest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Effect of disagreement on outcomes
          The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-day</TIMEX> CEC rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> and death or MI overall are
          presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 5by</ENAMEX> geographic region. The event rates
          are also shown for the analyses in which the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
          assigned a low level of certainty were reclassified as no
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infarction</ENAMEX>.
          The lowest mortality rates were in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for whom
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> and site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> agreed that no MI had
          occurred by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 days</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>). The highest rates were in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> for whom there was agreement that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> had
          occurred. Mortality was high in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with MI
          identified by the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX>;
          however, many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> had suspected sudden
          cardiac death as the event identified as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">investigator</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). The absolute increase in
          mortality <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 30 days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 months</TIMEX> was greater in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with CEC-determined MIs not identified by the
          site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> than in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> identified by
          the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
          Event rates
          The MI rates adjudicated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> in the PURSUIT
          trial were higher than those reported in trials of
          similar patient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 17, 18, 19</TIMEX>]. The reasons
          for these higher rates have been detailed previously [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>], and include the review of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 50%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicians</ENAMEX> to identify suspected events, more liberal MI
          criteria, and rigorous measurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac enzymes</ENAMEX> in
          all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Studies that have used only
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">investigator</ENAMEX>-reported events probably underestimate the
          true MI rate.
        
        
          Lack of concordance between site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> event rates
          Site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> underreported <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIs</ENAMEX>. A similar lack
          of concordance between events adjudicated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> and
          those identified by clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> has been
          observed in trials in which a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> group
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adjudicated MIs</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 8</ENAMEX>] and in other trials [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7, 9</ENAMEX>].
          The MI definitions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">PURSUIT trial</ENAMEX> were
          formulated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Steering Committee</ENAMEX> based
          on experience and clinical expertise. Because of the
          broad geographic enrolment planned for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">PURSUIT trial</ENAMEX>,
          definitions were designed to be applicable in an array of
          clinical practice situations. The definitions were
          detailed in the study protocol, in study newsletters, and
          in study materials so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> and site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> had
          the same set of criteria to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">classify MIs</ENAMEX>.
          The reasons for disagreements in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MI</ENAMEX> assessment between
          the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PURSUIT</ENAMEX> trial
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tables 1and 2</ENAMEX>) are similar to those seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global</ENAMEX>
          Use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategies</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open Occluded Arteries in Acute</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coronary Syndromes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GUSTO-IIb</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrilin</ENAMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minimize Platelet Aggregation</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coronary Thrombosis</ENAMEX>
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IMPACT-II</ENAMEX>) trials (unpublished personal data). Many of
          the disagreements reflect physician reluctance to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diagnose MI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> they are treating, particularly
          when the definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> includes events with low-level
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac enzyme elevations</ENAMEX> (often called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'enzyme leaks' in</ENAMEX>
          clinical practice). This reluctance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diagnose MI</ENAMEX> is also apparent for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> undergoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX>,
          in which the clinical significance of postprocedural
          enzyme elevations is controversial, even though such
          elevations correlate with worse outcome [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>].
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">disagreements</ENAMEX> also may partly reflect the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">definitions</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appendix</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> themselves. These
          definitions were designed to be applied to a broad set of
          clinical scenarios, including events after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> or bypass
          surgery, and to events occurring early after enrolment,
          which needed to be differentiated from pre-enrolment or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enrolment MIs</ENAMEX>. Site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> may have had difficulty
          applying these criteria, particularly with conflicting
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac enzyme</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX>, and clinical information. In
          addition, the enzyme criteria in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PURSUIT</ENAMEX> trial
          required only one cardiac enzyme value above normal to
          provide supportive evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>. Substantial clinical
          uncertainty exists regarding the need for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
          elevated enzyme value and whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> criteria
          should specify elevations greater than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> Ã— ULN or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã—
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULN</ENAMEX>.
          The strategy used by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> to adjudicate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIs</ENAMEX> can
          dramatically influence event rates and the proportion of
          events with disagreements between site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX>. Some trials have confirmed only events reported by
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21</TIMEX>], while other
          trials have adjudicated all suspected events identified
          by systematic screening of patient data [ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2, 3, 7, 8,</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>]. When only events reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are
          reviewed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX>, the reported event rates will be
          identical to or lower than the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> rates.
          When events are identified independently by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX>, the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> event rates may be higher, lower, or the same as the
          site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>-reported rates.
        
        
          Difference in treatment effect
          The absolute difference in the MI rates was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.6%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.2%</NUMEX>
          for eptifibatide versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.8%</NUMEX> for placebo) as assessed by
          the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.6%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13.6%</NUMEX>) as
          adjudicated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX>. The higher event rates in both
          treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> data, despite the similar
          absolute difference, reduced the relative treatment
          effect (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.4%</NUMEX> versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20.5%</NUMEX> reduction) as expected. A
          similar decrease in relative treatment effect has been
          noted in some trials [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1, 8</ENAMEX>] but not others [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 18</TIMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>].
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX> determined by <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac enzyme</ENAMEX> elevations
          without clinical symptoms or ECG changes accounted for
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX> of the disagreements in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> identified a MI
          and the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> did not. The median <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elevation</ENAMEX> in these events was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.6 Ã—</NUMEX> ULN. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 50%</NUMEX> of
          these events were thus defined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> values between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ã— ULN</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX> Ã— <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULN</ENAMEX>, with normal median <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CK</ENAMEX> values (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.9</NUMEX> Ã—
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULN</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>).
          A retrospective but blinded review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX> identified
          by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> but not the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">98/540</NUMEX>) of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> were assigned a low level of
          clinical certainty. This was because, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CK</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> elevations met the end-point criteria, the cardiac
          enzyme data were considered inconsistent or unreliable,
          or were associated with conflicting clinical and ECG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>.
          We noted regional differences in the proportion of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with low clinical certainty. The highest
          proportions were in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>,
          where the observed treatment effect using the CEC
          definition was negligible. Furthermore, the magnitude of
          the enzyme elevations (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>) parallels discrepancies
          in the assigned level of certainty. The highest enzyme
          elevations were observed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> (median <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX>
          elevation, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.9</NUMEX> Ã— <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULN</ENAMEX>; median <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CK</ENAMEX> elevation, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.6 Ã—</NUMEX> ULN),
          where the treatment effect was mostpronounced. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX>
          elevations in other regions were less striking (median
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> elevation, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.4 Ã—</NUMEX> ULN-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.0</NUMEX> Ã— ULN). The regional
          differences in treatment effect are, however, complex and
          include differences in patient demographics, the use of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cardiac</ENAMEX> procedures, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> and revascularisation,
          and the reliability of laboratory data [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. These
          findings support the hypothesis that including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>
          end-points defined by low-level cardiac enzyme elevations
          or events associated with conflicting clinical and ECG
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> may dilute the actual treatment effect.
        
        
          Predictive value of CEC-identified events
          The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-day</TIMEX> treatment effect was reduced using
          CEC-adjudicated end-points versus site investigator
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assessments</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with events adjudicated by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> (but not identified by the site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>) had
          greater mortality <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 30 days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 months</TIMEX> than did
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> reported only by the site investigators
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 6</ENAMEX>). In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX> identified by a similar CEC
          process have been associated with worse long-term
          outcomes at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year</TIMEX> follow-up [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. These data suggest
          that events identified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> alone are of prognostic
          importance.
        
      
      
        Implications
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> adjudication of suspected nonfatal MI end-point
        events is important to provide independent, unbiased,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard</ENAMEX>, systematic assessment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> adjudication does
        have certain limitations. The criteria used to define MI
        must be evaluated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> may require more
        clinical judgment in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with inconsistent clinical
        history, cardiac enzyme data, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX> information, or
        suspect cardiac enzyme data. We recognise that this may
        decrease the objectivity that is important for event
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classification</ENAMEX>, particularly in trials across geographic
        regions and clinical practice settings. At a minimum,
        events characterised by a low level of clinical certainty
        should not be classified as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIs</ENAMEX>.
        Although the absolute difference in infarction rates
        determined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> versus site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> was small,
        the relative difference was more substantial. This caused a
        substantial impact on the statistical outcome of the trial.
        This phenomenon must be considered in calculations of
        sample size and power during design of future trials, and
        also may influence how clinical and regulatory bodies
        interpret trial results. In addition, the CEC process used
        must be considered, among other factors, when performing
        comparisons of event rates between trials.
      
      
        Conclusions
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonfatal MI</ENAMEX> is an important clinical outcome, and its
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prevention</ENAMEX> is a key measure of efficacy in evaluating new
        therapies for acute coronary syndromes. The determination
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> can be difficult in clinical practice due to
        conflicting clinical, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac enzyme</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX> data. The CEC
        adjudication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> provides a standard, systematic,
        independent, and unbiased assessment of this end-point in
        clinical investigations. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">PURSUIT trial</ENAMEX>, the
        assessments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> by site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> and a central CEC
        disagreed; more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MIs</ENAMEX> were identified by the CEC than by site
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disagreements</ENAMEX> reflected underreporting
        of procedure-related events and misclassification of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enrolment MIs</ENAMEX> as post-enrolment (end-point) MIs.
        Understanding the CEC process used in a trial is important
        in interpreting event rates, particularly when comparing
        rates between trials. The type of CEC process also has
        implications in calculations of sample size and power. Our
        review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">PURSUIT trial</ENAMEX> CEC experience has highlighted
        some of these important issues and the need to further
        evaluate the strategies used for event adjudication.
      
      
        Competing interests
        None declared.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CEC</ENAMEX> = clinical events <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB =</ENAMEX> creatine
        kinase-myocardial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electrocardiography</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX> =
        myocardial infarction; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> = percutaneous coronary
        intervention; PURSUIT = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Platelet Glycoprotein IIb/IIIa</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unstable Angina: Receptor Suppression Using</ENAMEX> Integrilin
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eptifibatide</ENAMEX>) Therapy; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULN</ENAMEX> = upper limit of normal.
      
      
        Appendix: definition for post-enrolment myocardial
        infarction
        
          Enzyme criteria
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Myocardial infarction (events without documentation
          of previous infarction during the admission): creatine
          kinase-myocardial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX>) level above the upper
          limit of normal (ULN) and â‰¥ <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> of total CK. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> was
          unavailable, then total CK ><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Ã— <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULN</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Myocardial reinfarction (events with documentation
          of an infarction before or at enrolment):
          If <<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 hours</TIMEX> since previous infarction. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Recurrent,</ENAMEX>
          severe ischemic discomfort and new, recurrent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ST</ENAMEX>-segment
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">elevation â‰¥ 0.1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mV</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> contiguous leads,
          either persisting <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">â‰¥ 30</ENAMEX> min.
          If â‰¥ <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18 hours</TIMEX> since previous infarction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>-elevation
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> to above the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ULN</ENAMEX> (if prior <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> was within
          normal range) or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">>50%</NUMEX> above <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the prior</TIMEX> level (if prior
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> was above normal). If <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> was unavailable: either
          total <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK â‰¥ 2 Ã— ULN</ENAMEX> and increased by â‰¥ <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX>; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">â‰¥ 1.5</NUMEX> Ã— ULN
          and increased by â‰¥ <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 IU</NUMEX> above prior value.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Periprocedural infarction (events occurring during
          or within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX> of percutaneous coronary
          intervention): <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB level â‰¥ 3 Ã— ULN</ENAMEX> and ><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> above
          prior nadir value. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX> was unavailable, total CK <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">â‰¥ 3</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ã— ULN</ENAMEX>.
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Perioperative infarction (events occurring during
          or within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">36 hours</TIMEX> of bypass surgery): <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB â‰¥ 5 Ã—</ENAMEX> ULN
          (or CK, in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CK-MB</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ECG</ENAMEX> criteria
          New, significant Q waves or equivalents â‰<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¥ 0.04</NUMEX> s in at
          least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> contiguous leads. When enzyme or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrocardiographic</ENAMEX> (ECG) data were unavailable, an
          infarction was identified when the bulk of clinical
          evidence (patient signs, symptoms, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ECG</ENAMEX> changes, and
          pathological findings) so indicated.
        
      
    
  
