
  
    
      
        Background
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA arrays</ENAMEX>, variously called microarrays, complementary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DNA (</ENAMEX>cDNA) arrays, gene arrays and gene expression arrays,
        have been widely heralded and are becoming increasingly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> into the current research and future plans of
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. The main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA arrays</ENAMEX> lies
        in their ability to report the expression level of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of genes simultaneously, although other uses are
        being continually introduced. There are an increasing
        number of different commercially available <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> array
        formats. These include: the glass-slide based
        oligonucleotide array system [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2, 3, 4</ENAMEX>] developed by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affymetrix</ENAMEX>; the glass-slide-based cDNA clone <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Expression Microarray</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GEM</ENAMEX>) line from Incyte Genomics
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGI</ENAMEX>); the filter and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>-slide-based 'Atlas' arrays
        developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech Laboratories</ENAMEX>, composed of selected
        regions of PCR-amplified gene sequences; filter-based
        GeneFilters from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Genetics</ENAMEX> (RGI) which, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGI</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GEMs</ENAMEX>, utilize partial or full-length cDNA clones. Many
        research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> are also investing in core facilities
        that, after the fashion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> laboratory [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5, 6</ENAMEX>],
        are producing their own filter and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass arrays</ENAMEX> from PCR
        products of clones from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated Molecular Analysis</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genomes</ENAMEX> and their Expression (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMAGE</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX>, or
        other clones. A detailed explanation of the differences
        between these various array formats and other aspects of
        current DNA array technology can be found in the review by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dix</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>].
        The efficiency, sensitivity and reproducibility of
        commercially available arrays is good and improving, but
        they are limited in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> main areas: their cost is still
        somewhat prohibitive for some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>; the number of species
        for which arrays are available is small; the genes
        available are limited in scope and number. Although many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> offer a custom service for producing arrays, the
        process is expensive and cumbersome, and does not lend
        itself well to the commonly changing needs of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>. Most commercially available off-the-shelf
        arrays contain a cosmopolitan series of well characterized
        genes expressed across many cell types. As most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        focus on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or two tissues only, this global approach to
        array production is somewhat wasteful. In many cases, it
        would be far more useful to report on the expression of
        only those genes that are part of the transcriptome of the
        tissue of interest. Thus, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> interested in the liver
        may be better served by a chip containing only those genes
        expressed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, such as our own,
        interested in the testis, should find more value in a
        testis expression chip. We are interested in the effects of
        environmentally induced male infertility, with a focus on
        using components of the stress response as a means to
        indicate, qualitate or even quantitate the degree of
        harmful exposure. It may also be possible to use this gene
        expression data to elucidate the mechanisms of action of
        toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">agents</ENAMEX> and identify the causative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, thus
        facilitating better preventive or palliative action. The
        development of an in-house array is a complex process,
        however, which must overcome a number of logistical
        problems.
        We describe here our approach to developing a testis
        expression array, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> selection and printing
        procedures. We have assembled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lists of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (one of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">950</NUMEX> mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, and one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">960</NUMEX> human genes) that are
        expressed in either mouse testis or human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">testis</ENAMEX> or both.
        These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct sets of testis-expressed genes,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">containing 764</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">homologs</ENAMEX>, have enabled us to focus our
        resources more efficiently and begin to develop a picture
        of gene expression patterns in environmentally and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genetically</ENAMEX> challenged mouse models. It is anticipated that
        the production of human testis expression arrays will
        follow, thus permitting the direct comparison of gene
        expression <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> in mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and human clinical
        samples. This may aid in the elucidation of the molecular
        mechanisms underlying genetically and environmentally
        induced male infertility.
      
      
        Results and discussion
        
          Availability of a publicly accessible clone
          Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clontech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGI</ENAMEX> and the IMAGE
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consortium</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>] provide public access to a vast number
          of full-length and partial clones from a number of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX>, not all genes are represented by a publicly
          accessible clone of the gene or gene fragment. This
          problem is most often encountered when newly discovered
          or characterized genes have been selected from the
          literature.
        
        
          Availability of a sequence-verified clone
          It is important to select sequence-verified clones
          where possible to ensure that correct sequences are
          obtained. For example, clones provided by IMAGE (by far
          the largest selection of publicly available clones) can
          be mislabeled (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 7 and 13%</NUMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'-end clones
          When the choice is available (with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UniGene</ENAMEX> database [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>] verification), selection of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 3</TIMEX>'-end clone is
          desirable, as the inclusion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTR</ENAMEX> will, in most
          cases, enhance the specificity of the gene fragment for
          its gene in the hybridization process.
        
        
          Length of clone
          Selected clones should be checked to confirm that they
          are not so small that they allow a high degree of
          non-specific hybridization, and not so long as to
          introduce concerns about being able to amplify the insert
          by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> for printing on the array. Gene fragments in the
          range of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> pairs (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bp</ENAMEX>) are optimal.
          It should also be recognized that IMAGE and other
          clones are frequently reassigned to different gene
          clusters in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UniGene</ENAMEX> database, and that UniGene
          numbers and the genes/clones they represent can be
          removed at any point as new information becomes
          available. Consequently, the tracking and naming of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clones</ENAMEX> is of central importance in projects such as this,
          and gene lists should be constructed to provide as much
          detail as possible. Thus, it is prudent to include for
          each gene such details as: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UniGene</ENAMEX> number (and note
          the build from which it was taken); the IMAGE or other
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">clone</ENAMEX> number; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> accession number [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]; the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">SwissProt</ENAMEX> number [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]; the source of selection, which
          may be of value if questions subsequently arise
          concerning specific clones.
          Selected details (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UniGene</ENAMEX> number, IMAGE number and
          gene name) of the final gene lists for our mouse and
          human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA arrays</ENAMEX> are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tables 2</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>,
          respectively, available with the complete version of this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article online</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">764</NUMEX> homologous clones are shown in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, available with the complete version of this

          <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, online. More detailed lists have been posted on
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consortium</ENAMEX> (EPAMAC) website [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>], where they are freely
          accessible as a public resource.
          Assembling the list of genes to be included in a
          tissue-specific array is perhaps the most challenging
          part of the process. The subsequent acquisition of clones
          can be as simple as ordering the entire set from a sole
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">supplier</ENAMEX>. In this case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> of the gene list
          will be limited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. However,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distributors of IMAGE</ENAMEX> clones clearly have a very large
          selection and are continuously sequence-verifying and
          purging this vast resource of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">phage</ENAMEX> contamination.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proprietary</ENAMEX> clones are also available from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> such
          as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGI</ENAMEX>. Although these tend to be a little
          more costly than IMAGE clones, they include genes that
          are not available through IMAGE.
          To prepare <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA arrays</ENAMEX>, clones of the genes to be
          printed are grown, the plasmids containing the gene
          fragments isolated, and the gene fragments amplified
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> (see [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>] for detailed protocols). This can be
          done in-house or, as in this case, provided as a contract
          service by the clone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>. In preparing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products
          of a clone set for printing, it is prudent to note that
          clone growth may not occur in some cases. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> of our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">963</NUMEX>
          requested clones (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.6%</NUMEX>) were scored as 'no grows'.
          However, spots representing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these clones produced
          positive results in our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">TestisFilter</ENAMEX> hybridizations. This
          suggests that, in these cases, limited bacterial growth
          did actually occur, permitting the isolation of small
          amounts of plasmid and subsequent production of small
          amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> product, whose levels were below the
          detection limit of the gels used to check them.
          Hybridization signals from such spots should be treated
          with caution, as it is not known whether enough PCR
          product was deposited onto the membrane to be in excess
          of the target cDNA in the test sample. In addition, PCR
          amplification of IMAGE (and other) clones can be expected
          to fail at a small rate. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">963</NUMEX> original
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amplifications</ENAMEX> (carried out by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGI</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.7%</NUMEX>) did fail
          and had to be repeated under more carefully controlled
          conditions to obtain product. Furthermore, a small number
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products can be expected to produce multiple bands
          or smearing. Such results are most likely the result of
          mispriming events in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reaction, although it is
          possible that the original stocks may be contaminated
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or more</NUMEX> additional clones. In fact we observed
          that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.5%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">53/963</NUMEX>) of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products contained a double
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.0%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">29/963</NUMEX>) contained a triple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.3%</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3/963</NUMEX>) contained a quadruple <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/963</NUMEX>)
          produced a smear. Despite these anomalous amplifications,
          we printed from all <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> without re-racking to eliminate
          the anomalous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products. Although this saved time and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>, the caveat is that significant results from
          all subsequent array hybridizations must be checked
          against this list of potentially spurious clones. If
          hybridizations with the spots containing multiple-band
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products repeatedly give statistically significant
          changes, it should be possible to isolate and sequence
          the different PCR products, and use this information for
          Genes from the mouse testis-expressed gene list were
          procured as both clones and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products from a single
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supplier</ENAMEX> (RGI). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> additional reactions were added from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> amplifications of heat-shock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> clones available
          in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>. This final set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products was
          prepared for printing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were then printed as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filter</ENAMEX> arrays by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radius Biosciences</ENAMEX>).
          Relatively small amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> were required to produce
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple arrays</ENAMEX>. We obtained <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">84 arrays</NUMEX>, with each spot
          printed in duplicate, from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately 3 Î¼g</NUMEX> of PCR
          product resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12 Î¼l</NUMEX> 3x <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>.
          Preliminary hybridizations were carried out on the
          arrays with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">testicular RNA</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">C57BL/6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>
          (Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2a</TIMEX>,b). Bromochloroacetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">216</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">mg/kg/</ENAMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day</TIMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was administered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> by gavage for
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> extracted from these testes and hybridized
          against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisFilters</ENAMEX> produced measurable signal in
          the duplicate spots of virtually all the arrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>,
          confirming the expression of the genes we selected. At
          the time of writing, there were a small number of genes
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14</NUMEX>) that did not appear to be expressed in the testis of
          either this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> or a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, metallothionein
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">knockout</ENAMEX> (129SvPCJ background [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]), model which was
          also investigated. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> of these genes were 'no grows'.
          The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> may have represented genes that were not
          expressed in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> we tested, although they
          could also represent clones that had been
          UniGene-clustered with the wrong gene. As described
          earlier, the selection of some of the genes on this mouse
          testis array was based on results with human expression
          arrays, showing that our cross-species approach to gene
          selection is a viable means of identifying candidate
          genes for such tissue-specific arrays.
          We also produced slide-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> arrays of our
          testis-expressed clone set at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Molecular</ENAMEX>
          Medicine and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MI</ENAMEX>). A picture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such array, stained with POPO-3
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iodide</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>), is shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
          Experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> had not been applied to this array
          at the time of writing, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">POPO-3</ENAMEX> stain clearly
          shows the quality of printing and the configuration of
          the sub-grid of spots within the array. The TestisSlides
          were printed on bar-coded slides, the numbers being
          visible to both the naked eye and in the
          fluorescence-scanned image. The use of such slides is
          highly recommended, as it ensures that hybridizations
          with different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> can be identified quickly
          and linked unambiguously to subsequent image and data
          analysis.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> acquisition from both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisFilter</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisSlide</ENAMEX> requires that the identity of the cDNA spots
          be related to their respective positions on filter or
          glass slide. This information can be embedded in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">appropriate Excel</ENAMEX> spreadsheets. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisFilters</ENAMEX>, we
          are currently testing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> approaches for acquiring
          intensify values from digital phosphorimages of the
          hybridized arrays. In the first approach, we designed
          templates matching the arrangement of cDNA spots on the
          filters using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ImageQuant</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamics</ENAMEX>). These templates were used for volume
          integration as a measure of signal intensify. Our second
          approach utilizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Phoretix Array v2.0</ENAMEX> software (Nonlinear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) to automatically generate an acquisition template
          and perform volume integrations for the cDNA spots. Both
          these software packages accommodate background
          determination and subtraction, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nonlinear</ENAMEX> software
          also supports data normalization. TestisSlides are being
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imaged</ENAMEX> using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ScanArray 4000</ENAMEX> confocal laser scanner
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packard Biochip Technologies</ENAMEX>) and data acquisition
          accomplished using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">QuantArray</ENAMEX> software from the same
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX>.
          Although it is widely acknowledged that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA arrays</ENAMEX> are
          most powerful when they contain as many different gene
          probes as possible, the cost of purchasing or producing
          such large arrays is prohibitive for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>.
          Thus, the primary advantage of developing a relatively
          small tissue-specific array is its economy, whereby the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> is not obliged to obtain prefabricated arrays
          or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> that are uninformative for
          their favorite tissue and/or genomic interests. Another
          advantage is that the clone set is also retained by the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> and can be reused at will to prepare nucleic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> for further array printing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX> clones can also be
          added to the set as they become available. Such a set
          also allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> to be more or less focused in
          their choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> for expression analysis, permitting
          use of the full set or subsets. This approach enables the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> to select genes that are of specific, probable
          or possible interest in a particular context, and thus to
          tailor the final array exclusively to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>(s) of
          interest. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> may wish to examine
          the effects of a chemical treatment on a particular gene
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> (for example, glycolysis) or family of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (for
          example, heat-shock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, cytochrome <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P450s</ENAMEX>) in a
          particular tissue. Relatively small targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arrays</ENAMEX> can
          be used in this context to provide a focused platform to
          generate leads for the new kind of data-driven research
          that is gradually supplanting hypothesis-driven
          experimentation in genomics.
          Despite these advantages, it should nevertheless be
          recognized that, like commercially available arrays, the
          final list of genes selected for this array is arbitrary
          in that they were selected on the basis of the somewhat
          restrictive combination of individual judgment and the
          limited availability of sequence-verified clones, and
          therefore may not reflect 
          a priori the most versatile or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">optimal</ENAMEX> set of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> for such an array. For example, at
          the time of purchase we were unable to acquire
          sequence-verified IMAGE clones of 
          Prm1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dmc1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Msh4</ENAMEX> and a number of
          important cyclins, all of which have key roles in
          testicular function. Fortunately, the number of available
          sequence-verified IMAGE clones is increasing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>, as is
          the understanding of molecular mechanisms underlying cell
          function. Thus, arrays developed in future will benefit
          from this increased resource and knowledge base, and will
          therefore be less arbitrary than current versions,
          permitting an even more efficient use of resources.
          In an ideal situation, one would perhaps like to array
          whole tissue transcriptomes so that all possible
          transcription profiles can be accounted for. It should be
          noted, however, that a complete 'normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> mouse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testis</ENAMEX>' transcriptome (or that of any other tissue or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organ</ENAMEX>) will be extremely difficult to assemble, given
          that expression differences undoubtedly exist between
          strains and even between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> of the same inbred
          strain. Migrating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> such as immune cells can also
          complicate the issue. Completion of the sequencing of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and other laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal genomes</ENAMEX> will facilitate
          the production of more directed arrays, but until the
          alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">splicing</ENAMEX>) repertoire of every cell type in
          every condition in every strain at every age is mapped
          out, developing a fully representative array is
          unrealistic. Nevertheless, we have described the first
          steps, and the caveats to consider, for those wishing to
          begin developing the kind of tissue- or cell-specific
          arrays that will, we believe, be used with increasing
          frequency by the array community.
        
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Obtaining a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> testis transcriptome
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>
            Male <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">C57BL/6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Charles River</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breeding Laboratories</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks old</TIMEX>, and maintained in
            a temperature- and humidity-controlled room on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> h
            light/dark cycle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> were housed singly in
            polycarbonate cages with pine shavings bedding and free
            access to food and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            Heat-shock treatment
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">At 10 weeks of age</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> were sedated by an
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intraperitoneal</ENAMEX> injection of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 Î¼l</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> g body
            weight of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> ketamine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Dodge Laboratories</ENAMEX>) in
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX>-buffered saline (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>). The lower <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of
            the torso of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> was submerged in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">43Â°C</NUMEX> water
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bath</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX>, after which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> were dried off
            and returned to their cages. The testes from these
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> were harvested <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 h later</TIMEX>. The testes of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">untreated</ENAMEX>, adult male <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">C57BL/6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were harvested
            concurrently.
          
          
            Arrays
            Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted individually from the testes
            of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> extractions through Tri
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>). The control and heat-shocked total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
            samples were then pooled and passed twice through the
            Oligotexâ„¢ mRNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purification System</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>) to produce
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poly</ENAMEX>(A) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> microgram each of normal and
            heat-shocked testicular poly(A) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was submitted to
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genome Systems</ENAMEX> (now part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGI</ENAMEX>) for contract
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hybridization</ENAMEX> against their mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Expression</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Microarray I</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GEM 1</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]). Hybridization of the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> and analysis of the gene expression changes was
            carried out by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GSI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and the data returned
            electronically. All named expressed genes were added to
            the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> testis transcriptome gene list. The same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
            samples were used to probe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX> mouse cDNA expression
            array (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">588</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Stress</ENAMEX>/Tox array (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">149</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>)
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech Laboratories</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32P</NUMEX>-labeled cDNAs were
            produced from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Î¼g</NUMEX> of each pooled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>, using the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reagents</ENAMEX> supplied with the membrane array kits.
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hybridization</ENAMEX> to the membrane arrays was carried out
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and heat-shock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> were each hybridized
            against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different membranes of each membrane type.
            During exposures, the arrays were kept moist with 2x
            SSC saturated filter paper wrapped in plastic wrap.
            Images were developed using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phosphorlmager</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamics</ENAMEX>). Images were analyzed using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlas Image</ENAMEX> v1.01
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>). Genes whose adjusted signal intensity
            (average intensity minus background) were not at least
            twice their respective background value on both
            membranes were not considered genuine signals and
            discarded, as were those which were expressed on only
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> membrane. The remaining 'expressed' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> were
            added to the mouse testis transcriptome gene list.
          
          
            Homolog search
            In addition to the mouse array expression data, a
            search for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> homologs of genes expressed in human
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testes</ENAMEX> (according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGI</ENAMEX> arrays),
            which were not represented in the mouse arrays, was
            carried out using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UniGene</ENAMEX> and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneCards</ENAMEX>. Genes from
            successful searches were added to the mouse testis
            transcriptome gene list.
          
          
            Database search for testicular transcriptome
            genes
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI UniGene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Laboratories Mouse Gene</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Expression</ENAMEX> (GXD), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Library of Medicine</ENAMEX>
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEDLINE</ENAMEX>) databases were searched to identify genes
            expressed in mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">testis</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21, 22</TIMEX>]. Genes that were
            not already present in the mouse testis transcriptome
            gene list were added.
          
          
            Literature search for testicular transcriptome
            genes
            An extensive literature survey was conducted to find
            murine testis-expressed genes. Genes that were not
            already present in the mouse testis transcriptome gene
            list were added.
          
          
            Collaborator contributions for testicular
            transcriptome genes
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPAMAC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX> contributed the names of murine
            testis-expressed genes not present on the master
            list.
          
        
        
          Obtaining a human testis transcriptome
          
            Genes expressed in human testis
            Adult human testicular total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was purchased from
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>. This pooled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> originated from samples taken
            from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Caucasian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> (trauma <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>) ranging from
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 to 54 years of age</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas</ENAMEX> human filter
            arrays were used: the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">588</NUMEX>-gene cDNA Expression v1.1
            array and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">234</NUMEX>-gene Stress/Toxicology array. Two
            micrograms of total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was reverse transcribed with
            32P-dATP, and the labeled fractions collected using
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ChromaSpin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX>) columns. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> microgram of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was
            also hybridized against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,184</NUMEX>-element human GeneFilter
            membrane arrays (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGI; GeneFilters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>, and
            Named-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genes</ENAMEX>) following purification of the [
            33P]<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">dCTP-labeled probe</ENAMEX> with BioSpin6 columns (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX>).
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hybridization</ENAMEX> to all the membrane arrays was carried
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">washing</ENAMEX>, the arrays were exposed to phosphorimaging
            screens for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-7 days</TIMEX> and images developed using a
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phosphorlmager</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics</ENAMEX>) or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imager FX</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX>). Clontech array images were analyzed
            using <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Atlas Image v1.01</ENAMEX>. RGI array images were analyzed
            using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathways</ENAMEX> v.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.01</NUMEX> software, and all expressed genes
            added to the human testis transcriptome gene list.
          
          
            Homolog search
            In addition to the human array expression data, a
            search for human homologs of genes expressed in mouse
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">testes</ENAMEX> (according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGI</ENAMEX> arrays and
            the database search), which were not represented in the
            human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arrays</ENAMEX>, was carried out using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UniGene</ENAMEX> and/or
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeneCards</ENAMEX>. Genes from successful searches were added to
            the human testis transcriptome gene list.
          
          
            Literature search for testicular transcriptome
            genes
            An extensive literature survey was conducted to find
            human testis-expressed genes. Genes that were not
            already present in the human testis transcriptome gene
            list were added.
          
          
            Collaborator contributions for testicular
            transcriptome genes
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPAMAC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX> contributed the names of human
            testis-expressed genes not present on the master
            list.
          
        
        
          Assembly of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> mouse-human testis
          transcriptome gene list
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and human testis transcriptome gene lists
          were brought together for comparison. Paring of the lists
          down to the final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">960</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> was carried out sequentially
          according to the following criteria: all genes which did
          not have a sequence-verified mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IMAGE clone</ENAMEX> available
          were removed (assessed by checking against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGI</ENAMEX> inventory
          of svIMAGE clones);
          All genes present in both lists were retained; all
          genes of specific interest to ourselves and our
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX> were retained, as were those with proven or
          suspected toxicological relevance; genes shown to be
          expressed in the array experiments were selectively
          retained over those obtained from the literature, which
          were in turn selectively retained over those obtained
          from database searching, which were in turn selectively
          retained over those obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homolog</ENAMEX> searches.
          In this way we were able to produce <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> final master
          lists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">960</NUMEX> testis-expressed genes for both human and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>, all of which, except <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, were obtainable from a
          single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> (RGI).
        
        
          Procurement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> clones and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products
          Sequence-verified mouse IMAGE clones of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">963</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>
          on the final testicular transcriptome gene list were
          obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGI</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products of the same
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3-5 Î¼g</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> per gene. Owing to undetected
          IMAGE or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unigene</ENAMEX> number duplications on the submitted
          list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">955</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 945</NUMEX> unique clones were received.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> heat-shock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">HSP70-1,</ENAMEX>
          HSP70-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HSP70-3</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Hsc70 and HSC70t</TIMEX>) were produced
          in-house and added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, to produce a final
          total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">950</NUMEX> unique gene <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products.
        
        
          Array printing
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were precipitated, washed, dried and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuspended</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12 Î¼l</NUMEX> 3x <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX> in V-bottomed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>-well
          microtiter plates. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> were used by Radius
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioSciences</ENAMEX> to print <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">84 12 cm Ã— 8 cm</NUMEX> filters. Each gene
          was printed in duplicate on each filter. Slide-based
          arrays were prepared by the array <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Medicine and Genetics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wayne State</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>) directly from the clone set. Arrays were
          printed using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flexys</ENAMEX> robot (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genomic Solutions</ENAMEX>) on a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> Ã—
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> double-spotted grid with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">400 Î¼m</NUMEX> spacing between spots.
          Bar-coded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CMT-GAPS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma amino propyl silane</ENAMEX>) coated
          slides (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corning</ENAMEX>) were used.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hybridization of TestisFilter</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> mouse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eight-week-old</TIMEX> male <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">C57BL/6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were dosed via gavage
          with either <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">216 mg/kg BCA</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 days</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> after the final dose, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> were sacrificed and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">testes</ENAMEX> harvested. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was extracted from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a
          testis by homogenization in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tri Reagent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>) and
          treated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> units of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ambion</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> microgram
          of the total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> from a single animal was primed with
          oligo dT and incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> min followed by a
          brief chill on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> microliters of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">5x first</NUMEX>-strand
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX> (RGI) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼l 100</ENAMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTT</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.5 Î¼l</NUMEX> dNTPs (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 mM</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼l</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33P</TIMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dCTP</ENAMEX> (ICN)) were then added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">primed RNA</ENAMEX>.
          Elongation was carried out at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">90 min</TIMEX>, after
          which <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70 Î¼l</NUMEX> water was added. Unincorporated isotope was
          separated using BioSpin6 columns (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX>). Filters were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prehybridized</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> ml Microhyb
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RGI</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î</NUMEX>¼l mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cot-1 DNA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 Î¼l</NUMEX> poly(A) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 h</TIMEX> at
          42Â°C. The probe was added and incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at
          42Â°C. Filters were washed twice with 2x <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> at
          50Â°C for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, and once with 0.5x <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> at room
          temperature for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> min. The filters were then exposed to
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> phosphorimaging screen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> and
          visualized with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Imager FX</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BioRad</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> acquisition from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisFilter</ENAMEX> and
          TestisSlide
          An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ImageQuant</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molecular Dynamics</ENAMEX>)
          template matching the arrangement of cDNA spots on the
          TestisFilter was used for volume integration as a measure
          of signal intensity. Alternatively, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Phoretix Array</ENAMEX> v2.0
          automatically generated an acquisition template and
          performed volume integrations. TestisSlides are imaged
          using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ScanArray 4000</ENAMEX> confocal laser scanner (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packard</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biochip Technologies</ENAMEX>) and data acquired with QuantArray
          software from the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Additional data files
        The following additional data files are included with
        the online version of this article: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>, The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">764</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">homologous mouse</ENAMEX> and human genes present in
        testis-expression gene lists; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">950</NUMEX> testis-expressed
        genes included in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse TestisFilter</ENAMEX> and TestisSlide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arrays</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">960</NUMEX> human testis-expressed genes
        selected for producing a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TestisFilter</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisSlide</ENAMEX>.
        Additional data file 1
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">764</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">homologous mouse</ENAMEX> and human genes present in
        testis-expression gene lists
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">764</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">homologous mouse</ENAMEX> and human genes present in
        testis-expression gene lists.
        Click here for file
        Additional data file 2
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">950</NUMEX> testis-expressed genes included in mouse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisFilter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisSlide</ENAMEX> arrays
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">950</NUMEX> testis-expressed genes included in mouse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisFilter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisSlide</ENAMEX> arrays.
        Click here for file
        Additional data file 3
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">960</NUMEX> human testis-expressed genes selected for
        producing a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TestisFilter</ENAMEX> and TestisSlide
        The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">960</NUMEX> human testis-expressed genes selected for
        producing a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TestisFilter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TestisSlide</ENAMEX>.
        Click here for file
      
    
  
