
  
    
      
        Background
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2002</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse genome assemblies</ENAMEX> were
        released. One was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> version of the mouse genome
        assembly from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera Genomics</ENAMEX>, created by using both
        private and public sequence information (denoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cel2</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>]), and the other was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> version of the assembly
        from the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mouse Genome Sequencing Consortium</ENAMEX> (denoted
        MGSCv3 [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]). Both these draft mouse genomes were obtained
        using a whole-genome <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> (WGS) strategy, but using
        different mouse strains and distinct sequence-assembly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">algorithms</ENAMEX>.
        Assembled by direct overlapping sequence fragments, Cel2
        has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 260,000</NUMEX> contigs with a total size of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.51</NUMEX> × <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        9base-pairs (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.51 gigabases</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gb</ENAMEX>)), whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGSCv3</ENAMEX> has about
        220,000 contigs and covers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.475</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gb</ENAMEX> of the mouse genome. By
        incorporating pair-end sequence information, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cel2</ENAMEX> and
        MGSCv3 contain <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around 47,000 scaffolds</NUMEX> and around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43,000</NUMEX>
        supercontigs, respectively. After using physical map
        information, such as sequence-tagged sites (STSs), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mouse
        chromosomes were constructed together with an 'unassigned'
        chromosome called chromosome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX> and chromosome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Un</ENAMEX>
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3</TIMEX>. The total sizes of these chromosomes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX> and
        MGSCv3 are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2.62</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gb</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.59</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gb</ENAMEX>, respectively. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gaps</ENAMEX> in these chromosomes occupy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.1%</NUMEX> of genome in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX> and
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.5%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3</TIMEX>. The average size of the contigs, gaps and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">scaffolds/supercontigs</ENAMEX> of both the genome assemblies are
        comparable (data not shown).
      
      
        Results
        
          Comparison of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mouse assemblies
          To compare the coverage and accuracy of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cel2</ENAMEX> and
          MGSCv3, we used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BLAT</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>] to compare <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,434</NUMEX> mouse mRNA
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RefSeq</ENAMEX> database of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center</ENAMEX>
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnology Information</ENAMEX> (NCBI) ([ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>], <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 April</TIMEX>,
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>) with these assemblies. As a basis for comparison,
          we determined the numbers of mRNAs that have more than
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90% and 97%</NUMEX> of base-pairs that match in both
          Cel2 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MGSCv3</ENAMEX>, in one assembly only, or in neither
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assembly</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Although most mRNAs could be matched
          with both assemblies, there were some mRNAs that could be
          matched well in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>. We also found that
          more mRNAs had higher percentage matches in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX> than in
          MGSCv3 (that is, > <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97%</NUMEX>). As a further test, we
          especially investigated how well long mRNAs can be
          matched to each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> longest mRNA sequences
          are all matched well with both assemblies, except for the
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">piccolo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pico</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> (coding for a
          presynaptic cytomatrix <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>): paradoxically, it is
          matched in chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX> and in chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> in
          MGSCv3.
          mRNA sequences can only be used to check the quality
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> in the gene regions, and, for this, the
          accuracy can be determined only within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">exons</TIMEX>. Therefore,
          we also used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> newly finished mouse bacterial artificial
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chromosomes</ENAMEX> (BACs) with known chromosome locations (data
          from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 May to 23 May 2002</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX> daily updates) to test
          the coverage and accuracy of long continuous regions.
          Although all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BACs</ENAMEX> matched at the correct chromosomal
          locations in both assemblies, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3</TIMEX> exhibited higher
          matching quality in these BAC regions. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3</TIMEX>, only
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BACs</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 90%</NUMEX> coverage: AC087780 (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74%</NUMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">chromosome 1</ENAMEX>) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AC099773</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84%</NUMEX> in chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) while
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BACs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 90%</NUMEX> coverage: AC090479
          (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11%</NUMEX> in chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AC023789</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX> in chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>),
          AC021063 (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86%</NUMEX> in chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AC087115</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89%</NUMEX> in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">chromosome 8</ENAMEX>). For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AC090479</ENAMEX>, which has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 11%</NUMEX>
          coverage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX>, many of the matching genomic DNA
          fragments are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UA</ENAMEX> chromosome at present. This is
          probably due to the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> sequencing
          information that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cel2</ENAMEX> used was released before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2001</TIMEX>.
          Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MGSCv3</ENAMEX> could have a better assembly in those
          regions where newer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> information had been
          incorporated. Interestingly, these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> assemblies show
          some complementary features. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> AC090479
          was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 11%</NUMEX> covered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99%</NUMEX> covered by
          chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3</TIMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AC087780</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74%</NUMEX>
          coverage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3</TIMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94%</NUMEX> coverage in chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in
          Cel2.
          As well as using different assembly methods, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cel2</ENAMEX> and
          MGSCv3 also used different mouse strains. This may also
          cause some slight differences when comparing mRNAs or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BACs</ENAMEX> from different strains with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2 and MGSCv3</TIMEX>.
          From the above analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse mRNAs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BACs</ENAMEX>, we
          find some features that are complementary between MGSCv3
          and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX>. This complementarity partly originates from the
          fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGSCv3</ENAMEX> used more BAC sequencing information,
          which produced higher sequence quality and coverage in
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> covered by sequenced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BACs</ENAMEX>. However, the mRNA
          test indicates that the sequences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX> are more
          accurate than sequences in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3</TIMEX> in gene regions. Thus,
          it is highly recommended that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> genome
          assemblies be used in an integrated fashion rather than
          separately.
        
        
          Comparison between the human genome golden path and
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mouse assemblies
          The human genome project is well into the finishing
          stage [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>], providing the opportunity to compare the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> and human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genomes</ENAMEX>. Comparing the human genome with
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> genome can greatly help our understanding of
          both genomes. We used the BLASTN program [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>] to compare
          the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2001</TIMEX> golden path freeze of the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX>,
          which is also NCBI build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>, with each <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> assembly. We
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> used RepeatMasker (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Smit</ENAMEX>, unpublished work, and [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>]), to mask the repeats in all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> genomes. With a
          fixed expect value (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-</ENAMEX>value) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1.0e-1</ENAMEX> we found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,860,560</NUMEX>
          conserved sequence elements (CSEs) between the human and
          MGSCv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genome</ENAMEX> assemblies and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,737,297</NUMEX> CSEs between the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> human genome
          segment and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> matched mouse genome segment. The
          simplest cases, which we call 'univalent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>', are
          matches between unique human and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> regions. However,
          there are some cases, which we call 'multivalent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>',
          where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> mouse region matches the same human
          region, or conversely, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> human region matches
          a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> region. For all multivalent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>, we chose the
          longest matches, and added them to univalent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> to make
          a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">set</ENAMEX>, called 'primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> set'.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1shows</ENAMEX> the numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and the base-pairs
          covered in the human or mouse genomes in the following
          categories: all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>; human primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> primary
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>; and univalent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>. We can see that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> from
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Celera mouse</ENAMEX> assembly cover slightly more of the
          human genome than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> from MGSCv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>. Although the
          numbers of univalent CSEs from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse assemblies</ENAMEX> are
          almost the same (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 415,000</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">31,000 univalent</NUMEX> CSEs
          could be identified in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX> from MGSCv3
          alone, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31,194</NUMEX> were identified from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2</TIMEX>. This
          indicates again that the majority of univalent CSEs are
          common <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between Cel2 and MGSCv3</TIMEX>, yet some differences
          remain between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> assemblies. We then constructed
          an overall CSE set, which includes all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> found from
          both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3 and Cel2</TIMEX> (named as aCSE) and its human
          primary set (named as aCSE-hp). Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2aillustrates</NUMEX> the
          length distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in set aCSE and aCSE-hp, and
          Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2bshows</NUMEX> the plot of the percentage identity versus
          length of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in set aCSE. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> show <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80-95%</NUMEX>
          identity between the human and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse genomes</ENAMEX>. Very short
          CSEs overlap each other more frequently in the human or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse genomes</ENAMEX> than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long CSEs</TIMEX> because they are more likely
          to happen by chance. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E < 1.0e-1</ENAMEX> level, the
          average length of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">109 bp</NUMEX> in the aCSE set and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">151</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bp</ENAMEX> in the aCSE-hp set. The shortest one is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 26 bp</NUMEX>,
          and the longest one is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6,735 bp</NUMEX>, which covers the human
          spastic ataxia of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlevoix-Saguenay</ENAMEX> (sacsin) gene.
          We compared the human genome <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> covered by CSEs
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from Cel2 and MGSCv3</TIMEX> and found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 90</NUMEX> megabases
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mb</ENAMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 3%</NUMEX> of the whole human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX>) are
          covered by all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cel2 and MGSCv3</TIMEX> covered
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97% and 95%</NUMEX> of this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mb</ENAMEX> region, respectively. Among
          them, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">92%</NUMEX> of the base-pairs were covered by both CSE
          sets. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3shows</NUMEX> the distribution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> locations in
          each human chromosome. These results also suggest that
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> has slightly higher coverage
          than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3</TIMEX> in the whole mouse genome.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX>-species sequence conservation information is
          widely used in current gene-prediction tools, such as
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TwinScan</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SGP-1</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SLAM</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L. Pachter</ENAMEX>, personal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>). Lack of conservation information may
          decrease the prediction accuracy of these methods. The
          inconsistency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> locations in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX> from
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different mouse assemblies suggests that, for
          reliability, it is advisable to use both assemblies to
          search genes and to perform other functional
          analyses.
        
        
          Functional analysis of CSEs
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RefSeq genes</ENAMEX>
            We used the human RefSeq gene annotation from golden
            path <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2001</TIMEX> database to explore further the
            possible functional implications of these CSEs. The
            locations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genome</ENAMEX> were compared
            with a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,653</NUMEX> RefSeq gene structures. We found
            that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94.9%</NUMEX> of these genes and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX> of all exons
            (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">139,694</NUMEX>) are covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in aCSE-hp (data not
            shown). These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> also cover <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57.2%</NUMEX> of the base-pairs
            in the exon regions. Coding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> (CDS) have a higher
            degree of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> coverage (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77.7%</NUMEX> at the nucleotide level)
            than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>' untranslated regions (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTRs</ENAMEX>) (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24%</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTRs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18%</NUMEX>). In addition, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35.3%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> are located
            within RefSeq gene regions. Of these, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19.3%</NUMEX> are
            exon-related, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.8%</NUMEX> are intron-related, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.2%</NUMEX> are
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'alternative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exon</ENAMEX>'-related (that is, the location of
            the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX> is in an intron region
            according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> mRNA transcript, but in an exon region
            according to another mRNA transcript). Here, the
            relationship between a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> and an exon or an intron is
            defined by the location of the middle point of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX>.
            Clearly, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RefSeq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> CSE
            hit.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in the known and predicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ETS-domain protein</ENAMEX> family
            To determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> are found within regions
            encoding conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein motifs</ENAMEX>, we examined the
            relationship of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> locations and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-domain of
            a large gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> (the ETS-domain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>) found by
            our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GeneFamilyScan</ENAMEX> software (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GFScan</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
            For all known human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in this gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, only
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TEL2</NUMEX>) has no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> hit. Additionally, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> newly
            identified potential human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ETS-domain genes</ENAMEX> have CSE
            hits in the corresponding motif regions. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Remarkably,</ENAMEX>
            for the novel gene corresponding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ensembl</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]
            predicted transcript <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ENST00000299272</TIMEX>, we found a mouse
            ETS-domain gene ( 
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spi-C</ENAMEX> ), which shares <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67%</NUMEX> protein
            sequence identity with the human predicted transcript.
            Hence, the existence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> within a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-domain
            region can help to find other related novel genes.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in intronic regions of known genes
            To investigate the possible function of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in
            intronic regions, we examined a subset of intronic
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> longest intronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> (see Supplementary
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX> in the additional data file) within known human
            genes, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RefSeq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and other genes with
            known mRNA sequences, were further examined and
            compared with the human golden path annotation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>].
            Our analysis indicates that many long intron-related
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> may actually be alternative exons. For example, we
            found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> CSEs have spliced or
            unspliced human expressed sequence tag (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>) matches.
            Some of them also shared similarity with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse mRNAs</ENAMEX>.
            There was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> for which we could not get any
            functional information (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE ID</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">chr1c</TIMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0024330</ENAMEX>, it is
            located at human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chr1</ENAMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">246028930-246030945</ENAMEX> in an intron
            region of a novel gene with mRNA accession number
            AL122093.)
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and transcriptional activity in human
            chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
            To investigate whether the density of CSEs
            correlates with gene density and resulting
            transcriptional activity, we chose to examine
            chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>, a well-finished and annotated
            chromosome, more closely. We calculated the density of
            base-pairs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sanger Center</ENAMEX> annotated
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exons</ENAMEX> in chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> separately. The distributions of
            these densities are consistent across the length of the
            whole chromosome (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>), except <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> around
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">21-22 Mb</ENAMEX>. The average length of the exons in this <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-Mb</ENAMEX>
            region is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">247 bp</NUMEX>, which is shorter than the average
            length of all exons in chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">302 bp</ENAMEX>). Although
            the average CSE length is shorter than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">247 bp</TIMEX>, some
            very short conserved regions still cannot be covered by
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>, which causes the difference of the base-pair
            densities between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and exons in this region. To
            further investigate this discrepancy, we used data
            collected by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affymetrix</ENAMEX>. From Affymetrix
            oligonucleotide array data [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>], we obtained the
            density of the base-pairs around all positive probes in
            this chromosome. The density distribution of base-pairs
            in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> is more consistent with that in exons than that
            in oligonucleotide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> regions for this chromosome.
            This indicates that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affymetrix</ENAMEX> oligonucleotide
            array detected more transcripts that are less conserved
            compared to the known exons, especially those
            transcripts toward the end of the chromosome.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> between known genes
            Many long <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> that are located in the intergenic
            regions between the known human genes were also
            scrutinized against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESTs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>.
            Although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> longest intergenic region CSEs
            were determined to be pseudogenes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others appeared
            to be gene-related. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">chr9p</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0053719</ENAMEX> is located in the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">17707984-17709816</ENAMEX> region of human chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. In the
            corresponding mouse region, transcript mCT3199 was
            predicted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> database and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc</ENAMEX>-finger
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein basonuclin</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">143875</ENAMEX>) was also
            annotated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">chr6p</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0056662</ENAMEX> (human location:
            chr6: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">51140014-51141656</ENAMEX>) also overlaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> annotated
            novel gene, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">dJ402H5.2</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX>. Of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>, only
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">chr6p</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">0077382</ENAMEX> does not have any annotation
            information. However, we found a genomic region in the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat genome</ENAMEX> that matches the human location
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">chr6:105053471-105055327</ENAMEX>) with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94%</NUMEX> identity, which is
            not much lower than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this CSE</TIMEX>. Even in the
            well-finished and annotated human chromosomes, such as
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 and 22</TIMEX>, some long intergenic region <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> can still
            be found. Some of them are pseudogenes, while others
            appear to be related to novel genes. For example, in
            the human genomic region around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">chr20p</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0001494</ENAMEX>, a
            novel gene is predicted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenomeScan</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>] in NCBI
            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XM</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">104356</ENAMEX>), but is not otherwise confirmed. In the
            whole human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genome</ENAMEX>, we found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,259</NUMEX> NCBI-annotated novel
            human gene models that are covered by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX>.
            Although we do not know the clear functions for these
            novel gene-related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>, they obviously deserve
            immediate experimental verification.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in promoter regions
            It is probable that many CSEs located in promoter
            regions contain 
            cis -regulatory elements. For
            example, transcription factor 8 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TCF8</NUMEX>) can repress
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interleukin</ENAMEX> 2 (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">IL2</NUMEX>) expression by binding to a negative
            regulatory element <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 bp</NUMEX> upstream of the IL2
            transcription start site [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. We found that this
            promoter region is hit by our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">chr4p</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0043880</ENAMEX> (its
            human location is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">chr4</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">124039778-124040406</ENAMEX>). In a
            separate study, we are systematically investigating how
            to incorporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> information into promoter
            analysis.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA genes</ENAMEX>
            We found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">439</NUMEX> CSEs are related to non-translated
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA genes</ENAMEX> (from golden path <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX> human genome
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">annotation</ENAMEX>), such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ribosomal RNA</ENAMEX>, microRNA, small
            nucleolar <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (snoRNA), and the like. For example, Z30
            small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nucleolar RNA</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>] (accession number: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">AJ007733</ENAMEX>),
            located at human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chr17</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">34803858-34803954</ENAMEX>, is a
            methylation guide molecule for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U6</TIMEX> snRNA. The whole
            genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> region of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Z30</ENAMEX> is hit by our CSE
            chr17p_<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0010358</ENAMEX> (human location: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">chr17:</ENAMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">34803845-34803959</ENAMEX>). By checking the corresponding mouse
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">genome</ENAMEX> location of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX>, we discovered the
            corresponding mouse Z30 gene (accession number:
            AJ007734). Therefore, genomic sequence conservation
            between different species can effectively facilitate
            the discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA genes</ENAMEX>.
          
          
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and human genomic segment duplication
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Multivalent CSEs</ENAMEX> can be used to find genomic segment
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">duplication</ENAMEX> because these CSEs that hit once in one
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genome</ENAMEX> hit multiple times in the other genome. We used
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> of length greater than 100 bp found by BLAST with
            E value < <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1.0e-10</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">MGSCv3</TIMEX> to analyze human
            genomic sequence duplication. As an example, we used
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of multivalent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>, in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> region
            can match <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate human regions, to find doublet
            duplications in the human genome relative to the mouse
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genome</ENAMEX>. The human and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> regions in some of these
            type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> are located in the genomes with the same
            order. In this case, we can link them together and
            collect a pair of human genome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> mouse
            genome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX>. With length constraint of these
            segments (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">> 10 kb</NUMEX>), we found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">451</NUMEX> pairs of human
            segments and their corresponding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">451</NUMEX> segments in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse autosomal chromosomes</ENAMEX>. We defined a pair of human
            segments as doublet duplication when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> length
            difference is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 10%</NUMEX> of the shorter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. For all
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">451</NUMEX> doublet duplications, the identity between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
            human segments varies from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37% to 100%</NUMEX>, whereas the
            length of segments varies from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kb</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">257</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kb</ENAMEX> (the
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> are available in our ftp server [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>] and
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX> in the additional data file).
            Because there may have been much artificial duplication
            in the human working draft sequences due to
            misassembly, we checked those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">451</NUMEX> human duplication
            segments against the newest human genome assembly (NCBI
            human build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>), which has only become available very
            recently. We found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 79</NUMEX> duplications exist
            according to this updated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>, as shown in Figure
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. As the known repeats in both genomes were masked
            before we constructed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>, these doublet duplications
            in the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genome</ENAMEX> may point to either true expansion
            regions or further assembly errors. As we have limited
            the length of the duplication regions to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer than 10</TIMEX>
            kb, and the length difference between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> duplicated
            regions to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 10%</NUMEX>, these pairs of human regions
            look more like direct duplications of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genomic DNA</ENAMEX> than
            a pseudogene. But their true identity may require
            experimental verification. We are trying to use CSEs to
            find more expansion or contraction regions in the human
            and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse genomes</ENAMEX>.
            Although many CSEs are related to different
            functional regions in the genome, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of all
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> are still mysterious. Experimental approaches and
            further theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characterizations</ENAMEX> are needed to
            discover the function of these conserved elements. All
            the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and their available functional information are
            accessible and searchable in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEdb</ENAMEX>, which may be
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accessed</ENAMEX> through the genome browser link at [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>].
          
          
            Human gene number estimation by human-mouse
            comparison
            We analyzed the correlation between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> number and
            chromosome length. We found that they are not
            correlated very well (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Supplementary</ENAMEX> Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in the
            additional data file). From Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, we found that
            most human regions with high Ensembl gene density also
            have high CSE density, although some regions may lack
            this kind of correlation, probably because of the
            divergence between the human and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>. Together with
            the statistics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RefSeq</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, in which most
            RefSeq <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> hit (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RefSeq</ENAMEX> data
            above), we believe that it is more meaningful and
            accurate to estimate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-coding gene number from
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> instead of from chromosome length. Because human
            chromosomes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 21 and 22</TIMEX> have been finished and
            annotated, we used the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coding genes</ENAMEX> in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> chromosomes and the
            number of total CSEs to estimate: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, the number of
            the human and mouse homologous genes that share at
            least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, the total number of the
            human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. By our estimates, the total number of
            human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein-coding genes</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37,000</NUMEX>, of which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX>
            are related to mouse through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX>. The estimated
            number of all human genes at different E-values is
            almost constant. The estimated homologous gene numbers
            increased with increasing E-value as expected (Figure
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>).
          
        
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLAT</ENAMEX> search
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLAT</ENAMEX> was used to match all mouse mRNA sequences and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> sequences to both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse assemblies</ENAMEX> with the default
          parameter setting. As the chromosome information is known
          for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX>, we only calculated the coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAC</ENAMEX> by
          the corresponding chromosome in order to check the
          accuracy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          BLAST search
          The BLAST comparison of the human golden path with
          Cel2 and MGSCv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse genome assemblies</ENAMEX> were finished on
          an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPU LINUX</ENAMEX> cluster in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 days</TIMEX>. NCBI BLAST was used
          with different E-values as the threshold (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1.0e-10</ENAMEX>,
          1.0e-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1.0e-1</ENAMEX>) in this project. We found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0e</NUMEX>-1
          appeared to be the best parameter for covering both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>-related and non-coding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX>, because the average
          length of exons is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 150 bp</NUMEX> and that of regulatory
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> is much shorter. Another reason to choose 1.0e-1
          is that we can use only those more highly significant
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> if needed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> number is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-exponentially</ENAMEX>
          decreased when increasing the significance from 1.0e-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to
          1.0e-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>. The other options of BLAST use -b <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">50000 -v 50000</ENAMEX>
          - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U T.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Density of base-pairs in CSEs
          The density of base-pairs in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanger Center</ENAMEX>
          annotated exons is calculated by counting the number of
          base-pairs in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> or exons within every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.7</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mb</ENAMEX> window.
          This <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.7</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mb</ENAMEX> window is slided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> kb in each step.
          Oligonucleotide array data was downloaded from the
          The probe whose score is higher than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX>
          cell line is regarded as the positive probe. The
          following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> base-pairs of the positive probes are
          counted to calculate the base-pair density in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX>-kb
          window [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>].
        
        
          Pseudogene test
          To test whether a human region in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> encoded a
          pseudogene, we used the human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genomic DNA</ENAMEX> region of this
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSE</ENAMEX> to search the whole human genome with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLAT</ENAMEX>. If this
          continuous human region contained internal splice sites
          like a cDNA, we regarded this region as a potential
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">pseudogene</ENAMEX> location.
        
        
          Gene number estimation
          Estimation of the number of human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-coding genes
          and of human-mouse homologs is based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> assumptions.
          As the only training data at present are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> finished
          human chromosomes, (chromosomes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 21 and 22</TIMEX>), the first
          assumption is that the percentage of the gene-related
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> finished chromosomes is approximately the
          same as the percentage in the whole genome. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
          assumption is that the average CSE number per gene
          calculated in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> finished chromosomes is
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> the same as in the whole genome. Under
          these assumptions, we could estimate the total number of
          human-mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">homologous genes</ENAMEX> ( 
          nGENE 
          
            hm 
           ) from the total number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CSE-hp</ENAMEX> ( 
          nCSE 
          
            a-hp 
           ) set, the number of human primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
          finished chromosomes ( 
          nCSE 
          
            3chr-hp 
           ) and the total genes in these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> chromosomes
          covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> ( 
          nGENE 
          
            c 
           ):
          
          And the total number of human genes ( ) could be
          estimated by:
          
          where 
          nGENE 
          
            3chr 
           is the total number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">annotated genes</ENAMEX> in
          chromosomes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20, 21 and 22</TIMEX>, which is equal to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,595</NUMEX> (the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">overlapping genes</ENAMEX> were only counted once and non-coding
          genes are not counted) from the present data. Of these,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,291</NUMEX> are covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and the total number of human
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primary CSEs</ENAMEX> within these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> chromosomes is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,578</NUMEX>.
          Thus, we obtain the total number of human-mouse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">homologous genes</ENAMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">590,632 ×</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,291/25,578</NUMEX>) = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,811</NUMEX> at
          E-values less than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1.0e-1</ENAMEX>, and the total number of human
          genes is therefore estimated <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as 590,632 ×</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,595/25,578</NUMEX>)
          = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36,830</NUMEX>.
          We also tried to use information from these three
          chromosomes to estimate gene number separately, and got
          the mean number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,322</NUMEX> with a standard deviation of
          9,705.
        
        
          Availability
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> concerning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,259</NUMEX> novel genes are available from [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>] and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEdb</ENAMEX> browser at [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. The human
          duplicated segments data is available from [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>].
        
      
      
        Additional data files
        Supplementary tables listing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> longest
        intron-region <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">451</NUMEX> mouse genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> and their
        matched human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> pairs, and a figure showing the
        correlation between portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and chromosome length
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chromosome in the whole genome are available as
        additional data filewith the online version of this
        paper.
        Additional data file 1
        Additional tables and figure
        Supplementary tables listing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> longest
        intron-region <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">451</NUMEX> mouse genomic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> and their
        matched human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> pairs, and a figure showing the
        correlation between portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSEs</ENAMEX> and chromosome length
        of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chromosome in the whole genome
        Click here for additional data file
      
    
  
