
  
    
      
        Background
        The discovery of genes underlying multigenic diseases
        currently facing genetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>. This effort has been
        aided by quantitative trait locus (QTL) mapping methods,
        which have now been applied to numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> phenotypes
        in a range of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, including many behavioral phenotypes
        of high interest. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> is a chromosomal region that
        contains a gene or genes that influence a quantitative
        trait. The power of this approach was first demonstrated in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>] and later in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>], flies [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>], livestock
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4, 5</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6, 7, 8, 9</ENAMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>].
        Historically, a typical approach to going from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX> has been to select one or a few of the best biological
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candidate genes</ENAMEX> from within the QTL interval and search for
        sequence differences that predict differential expression
        and/or structure of the gene product. An alternative
        strategy is to carry out comparative sequencing of large
        numbers of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> genes located within the QTL
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interval</ENAMEX>, which is feasible given the automated sequencing
        methods now available [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. However, these approaches are
        limited because the gene underlying a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> may not be
        recognized as a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> gene if little is known
        about the gene's function and/or if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> region is large,
        in which case sequencing every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">QTL</ENAMEX> requires
        considerable time, cost and labor to complete.
        The recent development of murine whole-genome draft
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>] should speed the process of identifying
        disease genes underlying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX> because several of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> used for genome sequencing are the same as those
        that have been used to develop the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> QTLs
        so far identified. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> mouse genome sequencing
        effort used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C57BL/6J</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">B6</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, while the private effort by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> has sequenced the mouse genome in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> strains:
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBA</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/2J</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">D2</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A/J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">129X1/SvJ</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">129S1/SvImJ</ENAMEX>. Combinations
        of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX>, for example <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B6xD2</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B6xA/J</ENAMEX>, have been
        used for the identification of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 250 murine</NUMEX> QTLs.
        Because of these resources, we reasoned that sequence
        variations in QTL <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> might now be identified simply by
        direct 
        in silico alignment of the sequences
        obtained directly from the databases of the two relevant
        strains, obviating much of the need for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">de novo</ENAMEX> sequencing. We show that,
        once several factors were addressed, such as sequencing
        error detection and discrimination between closely related
        genes, a high-throughput <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipeline</ENAMEX> could be developed that
        allows large numbers of gene-coding regions from QTL
        intervals to be rapidly compared 
        in silico and interstrain allelic
        sequence differences quickly identified and targeted for
        further hypothesis-driven analyses. We also believe that
        this strategy has considerable general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>, and should
        be applicable to any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> used are
        those for which relatively complete genome sequences are
        available.
        While our work was in progress, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> incorporated the
        public B6 sequence into its mouse genome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> and
        developed a searchable database of mouse single nucleotide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polymorphisms</ENAMEX> (SNPs) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>]. Comparison of the gene variants
        identified by our approach to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> identified by a
        search of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>'s SNP database indicates that the latter
        significantly underestimates the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> present and
        that the method described here provides the most complete
        and accurate compilation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> gene variants.
        We tested this approach on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX> involved in physical
        dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>; these are located on murine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">chromosomes 1</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> and were identified using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mapping
        populations derived from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B6 and D2</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">progenitor strains</ENAMEX>.
        The well documented difference in susceptibility to
        withdrawal after chronic ethanol exposure between the B6
        and D2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inbred</ENAMEX> mouse strains provided an excellent starting
        point for dissecting genetic influences involved in
        physical dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> and to study how common
        allele variants influence genetic predisposition to
        physical dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>. Genome-wide evaluations of
        chronic ethanol withdrawal convulsions identified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX> on
        murine chromosomes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1, 13, 19 and 4</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX> on
        chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> (a sex-limited QTL) were
        detected in two mapping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, that is, the BXD
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">recombinant inbred strains</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">B6D2 F2</NUMEX> intercross [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>].
      
      
        Results
        A flow chart showing the steps involved in the 
        in silico comparison of the coding
        region of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> within the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> withdrawal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX> is
        shown in Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for Biotechnology</ENAMEX>
        Information (NCBI)/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouse Genome Database</ENAMEX> (MGD) human<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">/</ENAMEX>mouse
        homology map and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> mouse genome <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> were
        searched to obtain a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and predicted genes
        within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each QTL</TIMEX>. The selected genes included plausible
        candidate genes that have been implicated in functions
        relevant to alcohol action, as well as genes whose
        functions are not well understood or were not previously
        suspected to be related to alcohol action. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> on
        chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> was selected, most of
        which are within <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4 million</NUMEX> bases (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mb</ENAMEX>) upstream or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4 Mb</ENAMEX>
        downstream of the peak log of odds (LOD) score
        (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">approximately 18-24 centimorgans</TIMEX> (cM) from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centromere</ENAMEX>). For chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>, a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> was
        selected, most of which are within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 Mb</NUMEX> upstream or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 Mb</ENAMEX>
        downstream of the peak LOD score (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately 37 cM</NUMEX> from
        the centromere). The complete coding region of each gene,
        as available, was retrieved either from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celera</ENAMEX> or NCBI to
        be used as the query for subsequent strain-specific BLAST
        searches [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. B6 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX> were retrieved from the
        mmtrace database at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX> using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MegaBLAST</ENAMEX> search, and D2
        sequences were retrieved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celera</ENAMEX> by BLAST search of the
        All <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse Fragments</ENAMEX> (masked) database. All data were
        retrieved from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between August 2001</TIMEX> and
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2002</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> in-house programs were used to parse the
        BLAST results and remove any hits with low
        nucleotide-similarity scores or an insignificant e-value.
        The filtered BLAST results from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B6 and D2</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> were
        then aligned using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AutoAssembler</ENAMEX> and allelic sequence
        variations were detected.
        On proximal chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125,385</NUMEX>
        base-pairs (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bp</ENAMEX>) were selected and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX> aligned,
        and for chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84,635</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bp</ENAMEX> were
        selected and aligned. Altogether, the alignment encompassed
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> spanning <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">210,020 bp</NUMEX>. Because of some gaps that
        remain in the available genome sequences for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B6</TIMEX> and D2
        strains, complete coding regions were sometimes not
        available and in such cases the coverage was therefore
        incomplete. Our calculations indicate that the 
        in silico coverage of the coding
        region of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B6</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">D2</NUMEX> strains was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86%</NUMEX>
        and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69%</NUMEX>, respectively. The lower percent coverage of the D2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genome</ENAMEX> is likely to be due to the fact that it is only one
        out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> used to generate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>'s 5.2x
        coverage of the mouse genome. When the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">B6</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">D2</ENAMEX> data are
        combined, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61%</NUMEX> of the length of the coding regions was
        covered by both genome sequences (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>).
        Previous efforts to identify human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SNPs</ENAMEX> by database
        mining found it important to filter results in order to
        eliminate the false detection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. With this in
        mind, we took the following steps to ensure the quality of
        SNPs detected in our data. First, to avoid the inclusion of
        sequences from additional closely related paralogous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>,
        we used a BLAST hit cutoff of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX>, so that only reads at
        least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX> similar to the query sequence were selected.
        Furthermore, reads that potentially affected amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>
        sequence were used for a BLAST search against the mouse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genome</ENAMEX> and removed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">B6/D2</ENAMEX> alignment if the best
        BLAST hit was on a sequence scaffold located in another
        part of the genome. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, to avoid the inclusion of
        changes due to poor-quality sequence, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phred</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>] scores of
        individual B6 reads were checked at changed nucleotide
        positions and poor-quality changes (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Phred score ‚â§ 10</ENAMEX>)
        eliminated. This step was not done with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">D2</ENAMEX> sequences
        because individual sequence traces and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phred</ENAMEX> scores were
        not available from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celera</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, by in-house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sequencing</ENAMEX> of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> gene coding variations found in the 
        in silico alignments of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from B6</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">D2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A/J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">129X1/SvJ</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">129S1/SvImJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, we
        verified that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> had not mislabeled the strain from
        which sequence reads were derived and showed that no mix-up
        or cross-contamination of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> had occurred. Even after
        the above steps were taken, there were still instances
        where some reads had one sequence and other reads had a
        slightly different sequence for the same strain. In-house
        sequencing of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">B6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">D2 DNA</ENAMEX> for a subset of interstrain
        frame shifts (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of the total) showed that all the
        apparent differences were false. In-house sequencing for a
        subset of intrastrain single <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>-pair substitutions (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX>
        of the total) was also carried out. This analysis showed
        that when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different intrastrain sequences (for example,
        in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the D2</TIMEX> strain) were detected, the correct sequence was
        always identical to the other strain (for example, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B6</TIMEX>), so
        that no interstrain variant appeared at that position. On
        the basis of this in-house sequence analysis we chose to
        operationally classify all frameshifts as false and
        interstrain substitutions present in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>, or fewer than
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>, of the reads for one strain as false.
        The number of nonsynonymous changes was totaled from all
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> within the chronic alcohol withdrawal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX> on
        proximal chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and mid-chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> for which
        allelic sequences were aligned, together covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> cM and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">12 Mb</ENAMEX> of the mouse genome and representing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210,019</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bp</ENAMEX> of
        coding region. In total, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> surveyed from
        the chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> showed nonsynonymous
        changes in their coding regions between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B6 and D2</TIMEX> animals
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). A search of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>'s SNP database found
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the nonsynonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">B6/D2 sequence</ENAMEX>
        changes which we identified by multiple alignment of BLAST
        hits. Of the nonsynonymous changes that we identified by
        multiple alignment of BLAST hits and verified by in-house
        sequencing, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than half</NUMEX> are listed in the SNP
        database.
        On chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">121</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> were compared, eight
        amino-acid changes were identified in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>).
        Of these, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are known genes and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> are based only on
        computational predictions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> known
        genes for which allelic variation was identified within its
        coding region sequence was 
        Slc5a7 . This encodes a high-affinity
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">choline</ENAMEX> transporter expressed in the brain and spinal cord
        and may be considered a plausible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> gene for
        underlying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> (see Discussion).
        On chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>, when looking only at changes that have
        multiple read coverage or were verified by in-house
        sequencing, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> amino-acid changes were detected within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>
        genes (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> additional changes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other
        genes within the chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> were also identified,
        but these were all of limited reliability in that only a
        single sequence read was available for either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B6</TIMEX> or D2
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allele</ENAMEX>. Of the 
        in silico predicted changes based on
        single-read coverage that were sequenced in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>,
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> were proven false. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> showing
        allelic differences with multiple read coverage span a
        range of functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> and include a zinc
        metalloprotease, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">60S ribosomal protein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hyaluronic acid</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">binding protein</ENAMEX> (gene 
        Habp4 ), developmental related
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (gene 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ptch</ENAMEX> ), transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">system kinase</ENAMEX> and
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> for which no functional assignments have yet
        been made. As discussed below, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> for which
        allelic variations were detected, 
        Srd5a1, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nrif-2</ENAMEX> , and 
        Hsd17b3 are thought to be
        particularly promising biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to underlie
        the chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Discussion
        While other studies have <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mined EST</TIMEX> databases to detect
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>], the work presented here is the first
        demonstration of the use of strain-specific genome sequence
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">databases</ENAMEX> to discover gene-coding variants for murine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX>.
        Whereas previous studies have focused on detection of SNPs
        in expressed sequence tags (ESTs) that map to locations
        throughout the genome for use as genetic markers, the
        present work searched strain-specific genomic sequence
        databases for coding-region SNPs underlying disease-related
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX>. In this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> application of the strategy, we
        surveyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX> QTL-localized genes covering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 7</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cM</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mb</ENAMEX> of the mouse genome and identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>
        that had altered coding regions between the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">B6</NUMEX> and D2
        progenitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> of the allelically variant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> - 
        Slc5a7 , detected within the proximal
        chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> QTL interval - is a promising biological
        candidate gene. 
        Slc5a7 encodes a high-affinity
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">choline</ENAMEX> transporter expressed in cholinergic neurons in the
        brain and spinal cord. Prolonged ethanol exposure decreases
        high-affinity choline uptake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat cerebral</ENAMEX> cortex [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>],
        and acute ethanol exposure decreases choline transport in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">erythrocytes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. There was a single amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid</ENAMEX> change of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arginine</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">B6</NUMEX>) to histidine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">D2</NUMEX>) at position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>, which is
        located in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> cytoplasmic loop of the transporter,
        with the arginine also being conserved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> and human.
        However, while synteny data between human and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> suggest
        that the gene is within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX>, data from Celera
        apparently places it on another chromosome. Therefore the
        question of whether 
        Slc5a7 remains a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for
        the proximal <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> must await resolution of this issue.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> for which allelic variations were detected -
        
        Srd5a1, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nrif-2</ENAMEX> and 
        Hsd17b3 - appear to be particularly
        promising biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to underlie the chromosome
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13 QTL</TIMEX>. The most compelling of these is 
        Srd5a1 , which encodes a steroid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5Œ±-reductase 1</ENAMEX> and is expressed in brain and is
        consequently termed a neurosteroid. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5Œ±</NUMEX>-reduced metabolites
        of the neurosteroids are thought to be involved in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">myelination</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>], and one of the key features of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> is the loss of cerebral white matter [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Steroid 5Œ±-</ENAMEX>reductase is also required for the reduction of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5Œ±</NUMEX>-dihydroprogesterone, which is further
        metabolized to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3Œ±,5Œ±</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">progesterone</ENAMEX> (allopregnanolone), which
        has neuroactivity at GABA 
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>]. Some symptoms of
        ethanol withdrawal appear to be produced through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neuroadaptive</ENAMEX> changes in GABA-mediated neurotransmission [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>]. It is known that many neuroactive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> have
        anticonvulsant activity [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>], and during ethanol
        withdrawal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B6</TIMEX> and D2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> have differential sensitivity
        to the anticonvulsant effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">allopregnanolone</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. We
        identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> changes within this gene
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the B6 and D2</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX>, one of which occurs at
        position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> with arginine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">B6</NUMEX>) being replaced by cysteine
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">D2</NUMEX>). Unlike arginine, cysteine can participate in
        disulfide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> formation and thus has the potential to
        produce a marked difference in the functional activity of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">5Œ±-reductase 1</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B6</TIMEX> compared to D2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
        Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> gene is 
        Nrif-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kr√</ENAMEX>ºppel-type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zinc</ENAMEX> finger
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> thought to function as a transcriptional repressor
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the identified amino-acid changes replaces
        the arginine at position <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">593</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the D2</TIMEX> strain with a
        glutamine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> in B6 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, and this occurs within a
        known binding site for the intracellular domain of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">neurotrophin</ENAMEX> receptor P75NTR [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>]. The 
        Nrif-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> gene is expressed in brain and
        several other tissues, but expression is highest in testis.
        Interestingly, the chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> is sex-limited and
        affects severity of physical dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> only in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>]. In males <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the D2</TIMEX> allele was associated with
        more severe withdrawal responses than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">B6</NUMEX> allele,
        whereas the opposite direction of effect was found in
        female <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>. Because the behavioral trait is sex-limited,
        this suggests that the actions of the underlying gene are
        sex-limited. Such a phenotype might be expected if the
        causal variant gene was expressed and/or active in gonadal
        tissue, as is the case with 
        Nrif-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> .
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A third</NUMEX> altered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> gene within the chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> is 
        Hsd17b3 . This gene encodes a
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17Œ≤</NUMEX>-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase expressed primarily in
        testis but also in several other tissues, including brain [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>]. 
        Hsd17b3 catalyzes the interconversion
        of androstenedione and testosterone, favoring the reduction
        reaction [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>]. Ethanol exposure has been shown to inhibit
        the reduction of androstenedione to testosterone in rat
        Leydig cells 
        in vitro [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>]. The amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> change
        within this gene replaces a cysteine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">B6</NUMEX>) at residue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX>
        with an arginine (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">D2</NUMEX>).
        While these data are consistent with the variant genes
        identified on chromosomes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and/or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> being the gene that
        underlies the respective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX>, it is also possible that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">polymorphisms</ENAMEX> identified in these genes are merely linked
        to the polymorphisms that actually underlie these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX>.
        Although 
        Slc5a7, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nrif-2</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Srd5a1</TIMEX> , and 
        Hsd17b3 are promising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to
        underlie these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX>, a significant number of altered
        genes were also identified that cannot formally be ruled
        out at this time, either in place of, or in addition to,
        these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. Additional fine mapping of these QTLs is
        needed to eliminate as many false candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> as
        possible from these QTL intervals. In addition, definitive
        confirmation that 
        Slc5a7, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nrif-2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Srd5a1</ENAMEX> and 
        Hsd17b3 (or other promising candidate
        genes if they arise) are involved in predisposition to
        physical dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> will probably require
        verification using transgenics (for example, allele
        substitution or bacterial artificial chromosome
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transgenics</ENAMEX>).
        Another feature of the approach described here is that
        it not only rapidly identifies gene variants within QTL
        intervals but, because it will find many genes that are
        unchanged between strains, can also quickly eliminate large
        numbers of gene-coding regions as possible candidates
        underlying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX>. Finally, it should be pointed out that
        even when a synonymous sequence difference is found between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">QTL strains</ENAMEX>, it can still be used as a new, easily scored
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marker</ENAMEX> to further narrow the QTL interval using
        fine-mapping resources such as interval-specific congenic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">recombinant mice</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>]. In this regard we identified many
        such synonymous changes between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B6 and D2</TIMEX> that fall within
        the proximal chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> or mid-chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX>, and
        therefore can serve as new informative markers for fine
        mapping of these QTLs.
        The approach described here has considerable general
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applicability</ENAMEX>. Many other murine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX>, encompassing a wide
        range of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> phenotypes of interest, have been
        identified using mapping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> derived from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> strains for which whole-genome draft
        sequences are now available, and therefore lend themselves
        to this 
        in silico approach. When we carried
        out a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">PubMed</ENAMEX> literature database search, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">276</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX>,
        corresponding to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX> different phenotypes, were identified
        that utilized <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> strains (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>).
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> intervals that were used in the present study were
        rather large, and many other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">QTLs</ENAMEX> that use strains amenable
        to an 
        in silico approach are considerably
        smaller.
        While the present study focused on QTL gene-coding
        region comparisons because of their potential functional
        importance [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>], it should be pointed out that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>-regulatory regions, which are also of considerable
        functional importance and have been shown to underlie some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34, 35</TIMEX>], can be studied in the same way. For
        example, the approach described here can be combined with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> from high-density <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> microarray studies of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the B6</TIMEX> and
        D2 strains (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.M.S.</ENAMEX>, unpublished work). In such a scenario,
        interstrain comparison of the expression levels of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> would be carried out, the genes that are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentially</ENAMEX> expressed between strains identified, and
        their chromosome location determined from the genome
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">databases</ENAMEX>. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">differentially</ENAMEX> expressed genes that map to
        a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> region would be selected and the upstream regulatory
        regions aligned 
        in silico to search for sequence
        differences that affect predicted transcriptional binding
        sites. Such binding-site differences, when present, would
        be promising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to underlie the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> in which the
        gene resides. Although less is known about sequences
        affecting gene regulation than about those affecting
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein sequence</ENAMEX>, there has been considerable progress in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> in our understanding of the sequences
        involved in controlling gene regulation [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36, 37</TIMEX>].
        It is also possible that sequence changes in the
        noncoding regions of mRNAs can have functional effects. For
        example, sequence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' untranslated region (UTR) can
        affect mRNA translation, and sequence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTR</ENAMEX> can
        affect mRNA stability. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">UTR</ENAMEX> region can also contain
        enhancer elements that affect gene regulation and
        expression. Whereas less is known about the functional
        relevance of sequence changes in noncoding parts of mRNAs
        than those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>-coding region, they can
        nevertheless be functionally important and, as such, could
        be included in surveys using the 
        in silico approach described
        here.
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>'s SNP database has the ability to quickly
        identify interstrain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> in QTL <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, the information
        available from the SNP database is not as complete as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> generated by our 
        in silico approach. Specifically,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> uses a different strategy for assigning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNPs</ENAMEX> in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse genome</ENAMEX> and the SNP database makes very conservative
        SNP predictions; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than half</NUMEX> of the SNPs we identified 
        in silico and verified by in-house
        sequencing are in the SNP database. The SNP database also
        misclassifies some SNPs as missense mutations when the SNPs
        are actually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.M.S.</ENAMEX>, unpublished
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>). And finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera SNP</ENAMEX> database does not
        indicate which regions of a gene's coding sequence are
        covered by reads in each strain, and therefore does not
        distinguish between completely sequenced regions in which
        no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">variants</ENAMEX> have been detected and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> where no
        variants are found because sequence coverage for one of the
        strains is absent. Such a limitation provides an incomplete
        picture of the interstrain variants that exist in a given
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX>, which in turn could result in passing over the
        critical SNP underlying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX>.
        Although the strategy presented here provides a
        significant new tool in going from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> to gene, a number of
        challenges still remain on the way to realizing this goal.
        For example, functional confirmation that an interstrain
        gene alteration underlies a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX>, while feasible, is not
        trivial. As more QTL-localized genes are identified that
        have potentially important sequence changes, as described
        here for example, it becomes more difficult to test them
        all functionally. A related ongoing development that should
        help this situation by reducing the number of potential
        candidate genes that remain within the QTL interval is
        reduction of the interval by fine mapping using specialized
        congenic <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> or recombinant progeny testing [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33, 38</TIMEX>].
        A number of interval-specific congenic strains have
        recently been developed for a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX> and, although
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">straightforward</ENAMEX>, fine mapping is still a large-scale
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX> because of the need to generate and test large
        numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> to identify and behaviorally assess
        informative recombinants, and because of the need for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markers</ENAMEX> to detect such recombination events.
        While such challenges remain, the new genomics tools and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> that are now available or are becoming available
        are clearly providing a major impetus to this field. The
        power of high-density microarray studies to identify
        QTL-related genes and pathways, draft genomic sequences for
        the primary mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> used for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> analysis, and
        evolving bioinformatics tools and databases are all making
        major impacts on this field, with more improvements to be
        expected. For example, after this work was completed, we
        used the 
        in silico approach on a QTL
        identified using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">B6</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A/J</ENAMEX> strains and found that coverage
        was considerably higher than reported in this study. We
        found that in an analysis of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 30</NUMEX> QTL genes the 
        in silico coverage for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">B6</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A/J</ENAMEX> was
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98% and 91%</NUMEX>, respectively, with a total coverage for both
        of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.M.S.</ENAMEX>, unpublished data). Finally, the anticipated
        completion of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">B6</NUMEX> genome sequence and deeper sequence
        coverage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the D2</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A/J</ENAMEX> genomes, in particular, if
        carried out would remove the last remaining obstacles to
        virtually complete 
        in silico discovery of gene variants
        for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTLs</ENAMEX> identified using these
        strains.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Identification of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">QTL</ENAMEX> regions
          A list of known genes within the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOD</ENAMEX> confidence
          interval for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> was found using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX> vs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGD</ENAMEX>
          human/mouse homology maps at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>]. This list was
          screened for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> genes on the basis of gene
          expression within the brain and functional relevance to
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> phenotype. GenBank accession numbers for the
          complete coding region sequence of each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> gene
          were found on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LocusLink</ENAMEX>. Coding region sequences were
          retrieved from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> and used as the query for BLAST
          searches.
          A more complete list of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and gene predictions
          within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> was found on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Celera Discovery System</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>]. The genetic marker with the highest LOD score for a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QTL</ENAMEX> was localized on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>'s physical map and a list of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and predicted genes within an interval on either
          side of this marker was generated and screened for
          candidate genes. Coding region sequences of the selected
          genes were retrieved either from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Celera</ENAMEX> or NCBI and used
          as the query for BLAST searches.
        
        
          BLAST searches
          A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MegaBLAST</ENAMEX> search of the mmtrace database on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX> [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX>] was used to retrieve B6 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX> from the public
          database. Low complexity was filtered, percent identity
          was set to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX>, and the number of alignments to return
          was set to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>. Results were saved as a text file. A
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLASTN</ENAMEX> search of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Mouse Fragments</ENAMEX> (masked)
          database on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>] was used to search for D2
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX>. The e-value was set to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>, and the number of
          hits to return was set to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>. The complete entries view
          of the results was exported to a file which was given a
          .txt extension.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAVA</ENAMEX> scripts to process BLAST results
          A script, named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouse Gene Selection NCBI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGS_NCBI</ENAMEX>),
          was written in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAVA</ENAMEX> and used to parse BLAST results from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX>. This script filters the BLAST results and only
          selects hits which have percent identity greater than or
          equal to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX> and e-value, which is a measure of the
          statistical significance of BLAST hits, less than or
          equal to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.0001</NUMEX>. The e-value is the number of hits with
          the same degree of similarity one would expect to find by
          chance if there were no true matches in the database.
          Another script, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouse Gene Selection Celera</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGS_Celera</ENAMEX>),
          was written in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAVA</ENAMEX> and used to parse BLAST results from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celera</ENAMEX>. This script filters the BLAST results and only
          selects hits with strain name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DBA/2J</ENAMEX>, e-value less than
          or equal to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.0001 and percent</NUMEX> identity greater than or
          equal to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98%</NUMEX>. After filtering the BLAST results, the
          script saves each alignment as an individual text file.
          When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hit aligns with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> region of the
          query sequence, the entire hit is discarded if any of the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alignments</ENAMEX> does not meet the above criteria. As both
          scripts are written in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAVA</ENAMEX>, they can be run on Unix,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX> or PC <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platforms</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Alignment of filtered BLAST results
          Filtered BLAST results were aligned using
          AutoAssembler <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX>. For each gene, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> alignment file was
          made of the filtered B6 BLAST results and a separate
          alignment file was made of the filtered D2 BLAST results.
          The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">B6</NUMEX> alignment file was then compared to the D2
          alignment file to identify sequence changes. When
          sequence variations were found within a strain they were
          regarded as true only if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> the reads for a
          strain contained the change. This criterion was checked
          for validity by in-house sequencing.
        
        
          In-house sequencing
          In-house sequencing was used to test 
          in silico sequence predictions and
          also occasionally to fill in gaps that remained in
          certain genes. C57BL<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/6J</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DBA/2J</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> were obtained
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Laboratory</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> were euthanized and
          the brains dissected. Whole-brain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was isolated using
          an RNeasy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxi Kit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>). cDNA was synthesized by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUPERSCRIPT First Strand Synthesis System</ENAMEX>
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invitrogen</ENAMEX>). C57BL<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/6J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DBA/2J</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A/J</ENAMEX>,
          129X1<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/SvJ</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">129S1/SvImJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">genomic DNAs</ENAMEX> were obtained
          from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackson Laboratory</ENAMEX>. Primer3 software [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>] was
          used to design primers to amplify either cDNA or genomic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. Template <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was amplified by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> in the Perkin
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elmer GeneAmp PCR</ENAMEX> system <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9700</TIMEX>. A typical reaction cycle
          was denaturation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94¬∞C</TIMEX> followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> cycles
          of denaturation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> s at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94¬∞C</TIMEX>, annealing for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min 15</TIMEX>
          s at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54¬∞C</TIMEX>, and extension for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 min 15</TIMEX> s at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">72¬∞C</NUMEX> with a
          final extension step at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72¬∞C</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Products</ENAMEX> were
          run on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.7%</NUMEX> agarose gel, stained with ethidium bromide,
          and purified using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QIAquick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gel Extraction kits</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were reamplified when necessary.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products were sequenced using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABI</ENAMEX> Big Dye
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terminator</ENAMEX> v.<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> chemistry and cycle sequencing and
          sequence traces read on an ABI PRISM <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3100</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Analyzer</ENAMEX>.
          When in-house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sequencing</ENAMEX> was done to fill gaps from the 
          in silico alignment, a minimum of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> forward read and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reverse read was run for each
          sample of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products. When-in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> sequencing was done
          to verify nonsynonymous changes found in the 
          in silico alignment, a minimum of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> forward reads and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reverse reads was run for each
          sample of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> products. Sequencing data for each strain
          were analyzed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Consed</ENAMEX> software <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>].
          Sequencing was repeated for regions of poor quality (that
          is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phred</ENAMEX> score <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">< 40</NUMEX>). High-quality sequence was
          exported and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B6</ENAMEX> sequence was compared to D2 sequence
          using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AutoAssembler</ENAMEX> to identify changes between the two
          strains.
        
      
    
  
