
  
    
      
        Background
        The rapid rate of sequence acquisition has
        revolutionized molecular biology. The sequencing of entire
        genomes, in addition to new computer-based search tools has
        allowed us to identify and analyze large sets of data very
        rapidly. The acceleration of data acquisition, in fields
        such as whole-genome sequence determination and genome-wide
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gene</ENAMEX>-expression profiling, has opened the door for the
        study of model <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> of importance to the
        study of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and disease <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> by allowing for the
        analysis of the entirety of genetic information in a given
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>. The recent completion of the sequencing of the 
        Anopheles gambiae genome provides us
        with the entire genetic makeup of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX>.
        Furthermore, the completion of the sequencing of both the 
        Drosophila melanogaster [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] and 
        Anopheles gambiae [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] genomes
        provides the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> opportunity for genome-wide comparisons
        from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> metazoans from the same order (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diptera</ENAMEX>). This
        presents new opportunities to detect synteny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and
        facilitates the comparison of splicing patterns and
        orthologous sequences between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>.
        The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel gene identified was cloned from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> . The 
        Shaker gene was isolated by
        positional cloning of a gene for which a mutation causes a
        leg-shaking phenotype in anesthetized flies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 4</NUMEX> ] . This
        gene encodes a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) subunit
        which assembles as a tetramer. This gene provided a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">molecular</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> by which other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> could be
        isolated by hybridization, and later, by computer-based
        homology search. This led to the cloning of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +channel subunits and the discovery of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel
        types [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX> ] . Subsequent to the cloning of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> from the 
        Shab , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> and 
        Shal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> (later renamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv2</ENAMEX>,
        Kv3, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv4</ENAMEX>, respectively, for clarity [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] ) were
        identified in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX>. These sequences are shown
        in the alignment in Figure 2aand a tree is shown in Figure
        3a. Later, other types of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel subunits were
        identified by hybridization, with the conserved pore region
        generally used as a probe, or by positional cloning using
        neurological mutants in 
        Drosophila melanogaster and other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>. Among these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel types</ENAMEX> were KQT channels,
        calcium-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, inward rectifier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-pore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . The
        sequencing of the 
        Drosophila genome provided evidence
        that the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> fly
        have been identified, since certain domains within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, particularly the pore region, are readily
        identifiable by homology.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> possess the same conserved pore
        domain sequence as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kv</ENAMEX> and KQT channels. Among the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-transmembrane channels, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> additional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The Eag gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> consists of 
        eag , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">erg</ENAMEX> ( 
        seizure ) and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elk</ENAMEX> ; one of each is present in the 
        Drosophila genome [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] . The other
        6TM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. These genes
        encode Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> of large conductance,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">intermediate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">conductance</ENAMEX> and small conductance: these are
        thought to be mediated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slo</ENAMEX>, slack and SK channels,
        respectively. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channels are shown in Figure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2b</TIMEX>.
        Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inward rectifier K</ENAMEX> +channels exists as well. Although these
        channels lack a voltage-sensor domain they play an
        important role in controlling resting potential and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +homeostasis. Between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> transmembrane domains these
        channels possess a pore sequence homologous to the pore
        domain found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kv</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eag</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel types</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> Kir
        genes have been reported in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of these
        genes, 
        Irk2 and 
        Irk3 , are quite similar at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54%</NUMEX> amino
        acid sequence identity while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">roughly 27%</NUMEX>
        identical to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other two</NUMEX>. Finally, although they will not
        be investigated in this study, a group of
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-transmembrane, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-pore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channels exists. These
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tandem</ENAMEX>-pore <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> may be involved in a wide range of
        physiologic processes but are generally thought to mediate
        leak conductances which influence resting membrane
        potential. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> mentioned here
        contribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel conductance in excitable and/or
        non-excitable cells. In the nervous systems of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX> and
        other metazoans <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channels are known to play an important
        role in perception, learning and locomotion. This paper
        will investigate the genes encoding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        distantly related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diptera</ENAMEX> now that their entire genomes
        have been made public.
      
      
        Results
        
          Neutral evolutionary distance values
          In addition to amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid</ENAMEX> identity we looked at
          neutral evolutionary distance (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NED</ENAMEX>) values. Values for f2
          (the percentage of identical codons for conserved
          twofold-redundant amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cys, Asp, Glu, Phe</ENAMEX>, His,
          Lys, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asn, Gln</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyr</ENAMEX>) between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> aligned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> are
          calculated by looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">codons</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> position in
          positions at which amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> with twofold degeneracy
          occur. These values may be more useful for evaluating
          divergence dates than amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid</ENAMEX> sequence identity
          because they are silent and mutation occurs in a
          clocklike fashion, rather than in the bursts that are
          thought to accompany rapid environmental changes. The f2
          values for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kv1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kv2 and Kv4</TIMEX> orthologs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> fly
          and mosquito were as follows: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.69</NUMEX> for 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv1</ENAMEX> vs 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.73</NUMEX> for 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv2</ENAMEX> vs 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv2</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.69</NUMEX> for 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv4</ENAMEX> vs 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv4</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">f2</NUMEX> values for 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> vs 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel genes
          were calculated, as shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.1</ENAMEX> vs 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.2</ENAMEX> gave a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">f2</TIMEX> value of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.74</NUMEX>. 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.1</ENAMEX> vs 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.3</ENAMEX> gave an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">f2</TIMEX> value of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.75</NUMEX>, whereas 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> . Kv3<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> vs 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.3</ENAMEX> gave a value of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.69</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">f2</NUMEX> value of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.3</ENAMEX> vs 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.2</ENAMEX> gave a value of
          only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.52</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">f2</NUMEX> value for the two 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> genes in 
          Drosophila , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.2</ENAMEX>, was
          0.60.
        
      
      
        Discussion
        
        Anopheles gambiae is the most
        important vector of 
        Plasmodium <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">falciparum malaria</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>, where <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 90%</NUMEX> of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>-specific
        mortality occurs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDT</ENAMEX> has been used extensively to control
        this mosquito. Because the target of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDT</ENAMEX> and pyrethroid
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">insecticides</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">voltage-gated Na</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> ] , and
        considering that the anti-malarial quinine blocks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, insights into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ion channels</ENAMEX> in the genomes of
        this mosquito and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX> may be useful for
        investigating how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDT</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> may be used with
        greatest efficacy and safety. Using the conserved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +-channel pore as a probe, I screened the entire 
        A. gambiae genome for the presence of
        voltage-gated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, Ca <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>+-activated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inward rectifier K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, as all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> possess
        a homologous pore domain. I have identified eight
        voltage-gated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eag</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, three
        Slo-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> inward rectifier channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> using
        this search. A greater number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> within a given
        family in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> compared to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> can be a result of gene
        expansion in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> or, alternatively, gene
        loss in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> . I considered the
        likelihood of either possibility for these cases, based on
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that were constructed using <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>-joining,
        parsimony, and maximum-likelihood algorithms.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channels are dispersed throughout the genomes of both
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> and 
        Anopheles , although multiple members
        of a given <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are most often clustered. Comparing the
        gross homology of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, both the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> and 
        Drosophila have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major metacentric
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autosomes</ENAMEX> and an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> chromosome (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">chromosomal arms</ENAMEX> in
        total). Of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> focused on here, only 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaker</ENAMEX> is located on the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> in
        both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, namely the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> chromosome; however, the
        locations of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> and 
        Drosophila are consistent with
        previously reported regions of major interarm homology
        between these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>). This was true for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shab</ENAMEX> ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3L</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag 2L</ENAMEX>), 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2L</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag 3R</ENAMEX>), 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shal</ENAMEX> ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3L</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag 2L</ENAMEX>), 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCNQ</ENAMEX> ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2R</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag 2L</ENAMEX>) and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slowpoke</ENAMEX> ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3R</ENAMEX>, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag 2R</ENAMEX>), as well as for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Slack ,</ENAMEX> 
        eag , 
        erg , 
        elk , and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> inward rectifier
        genes, as shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. The translocations between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">autosomes</ENAMEX> and chromosome <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>, observed for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eag</ENAMEX> and 
        Hyperkinetic , are notable: these
        examples raise questions about dosage compensation which
        will need to be addressed in future studies.
        There is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78-98%</NUMEX> amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid</ENAMEX> sequence identity between the
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-transmembrane <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene products</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> and their orthologs in 
        Anopheles , a value significantly
        greater than what other studies have calculated (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62%</NUMEX>
        identity and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX> in separate studies [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 17</NUMEX> ] ) as a mean
        value for sequence identity between orthologs in these two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>. Amino-acid sequence identity of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78-98%</NUMEX> is an
        impressive figure, given that these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> are
        thought to have diverged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">250 million years ago</TIMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
        Although this value may be slightly higher than the true
        value, as uncertainties resulting from splicing boundaries
        led us to disregard the more variable amino-and
        carboxy-terminal extreme ends, the sequence identities for
        the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles K</ENAMEX> +-channel orthologs over
        the core regions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel sequences are well above
        the mean values calculated by the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for
        orthologs between these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. It suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +-channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> are subject to a stricter selection
        pressure than other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>. This is
        consistent with the observation that transporters and
        channels are among the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> with highest sequence
        similarity between 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] .
        Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> voltage-gated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel types <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv1-4</ENAMEX>, the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaker</ENAMEX> , or Kv1 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> gene is, from
        a genomic perspective, arguably the most complex. 
        Shaker from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> is a gene with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 11</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exons</ENAMEX> and spanning <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 16 kb</NUMEX>. Exons are short in the 
        Anopheles ortholog of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaker</ENAMEX> as well, as it was not
        possible to find an exon encoding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 75</NUMEX> amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX>
        in this gene. The presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> pore region in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anopheles Shaker</ENAMEX> suggests that
        sequence diversity can be generated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">an integral part of</ENAMEX>
        the internal segments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>, rather than what has
        been reported for 
        Drosophila <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shaker</ENAMEX> - splicing at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' ends [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 19</NUMEX> ] . Alternative splicing at the pore
        region occurs in another arthropod, the lobster 
        Panulirus interruptus . Functional
        channels translated from genes with either of the two
        splice variants were expressed and exhibited different
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrophysiological</ENAMEX> and pharmacological properties [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> ]
        . It is tempting to assume that the two transcripts with
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> variable pore-regions in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> would encode channels with
        different properties as well, although this would be
        premature until it is shown that both exons are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcribed</ENAMEX>. An exon encoding the region containing the
        pore exists in 
        Drosophila , yet no transcripts could
        be found containing this putative exon [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] .
        In the coding region, the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shal</ENAMEX> and 
        Shab <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> and 
        Drosophila are made up of longer
        exons than the 
        Shaker gene. The lack of more than
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> splice variant at central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shal</ENAMEX> protein
        suggests that splicing may be confined to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>'
        regions of this gene. Although evidence of microsynteny was
        found for the region surrounding 
        Shal , flanking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> of the other
        channels did not provide evidence of microsynteny between 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> and 
        Drosophila at these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>.
        The identification of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> Kv3 ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> ) family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> (but only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> ) is intriguing. In
        mammals, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> activates at potentials
        considerably more positive than observed in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel types</ENAMEX>; these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> have the ability to produce
        currents that can specifically enable fast repolarization
        of action potentials without compromising spike initiation
        or height [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> ] . Also, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> are localized at
        specialized regions in mammalian brain associated with
        higher-order cognitive functions, such as the thalamus and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cortex</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> ] . Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kv3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> sequence
        identities are lower between 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> and mammals than are other
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel types</ENAMEX>.
        The identification of multiple Kv3 channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>, but
        only single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Kv1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kv2 and Kv4</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diptera</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> ) raises questions about
        the evolutionary history of Kv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. In some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> with very primitive nervous systems, such as 
        Polyorchis penicillatus (jellyfish,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phylum Cnidaria</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaker</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Kv1</NUMEX>)-family genes exist [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>
        ] ; moreover, in the electric fish 
        Apteronotus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Kv1</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shaker</ENAMEX>) family
        is the most diverse, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX> ] . One
        can predict from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> similarity that Kv3.1
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.2</ENAMEX> from 
        Anopheles diverged recently. The
        previously published 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88%</NUMEX>
        identical to the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.1</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX>,
        but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 70%</NUMEX> identical to the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> predicted Kv3<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> gene
        product. Regarding the relationships between 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.1</ENAMEX> and the two 
        Anopheles genes 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ag Kv3.1</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ag Kv3.2</ENAMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> has already
        stated that the ancestral sequence at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">node</ENAMEX> representing
        the divergence of these two 
        Anopheles <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> is the true ortholog
        of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.1</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gi 158460</ENAMEX>). Given the
        awkwardness of comparing an extant gene (for example 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.1</ENAMEX>) to its ancestral ortholog,
        it may suit the genomics and/or evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to
        devise new terminology for such cases. In relation to the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.1</ENAMEX>, the terms 'novolog'
        (corresponding to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ag Kv3.1</ENAMEX> or 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ag Kv3.2</ENAMEX>) and 'archaelog'
        (corresponding to the ancestral gene represented by the
        node from which the two 
        Anopheles <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes diverged</ENAMEX>) might be
        useful; these terms, as presented here, would apply to
        cases in which contemporaneous orthologs do not exist
        between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>, as opposed to the general phenomena
        of duplication and divergence.
        In the light of the high amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid</ENAMEX> identity, roughly
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87%</NUMEX>, the low f2 value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.51</NUMEX> for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.3</ENAMEX> and its ortholog in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> (as opposed to an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">f2</TIMEX> value
        of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.69</NUMEX> for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv1</ENAMEX> vs 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv1</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.73</NUMEX> for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv2</ENAMEX> vs 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv2</ENAMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0.70</NUMEX> for 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv4</ENAMEX> vs 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv4</ENAMEX>) suggests these two
        genes diverged longer ago than would be predicted by the
        amino-acid identity alone, and that selective pressure has
        prevented the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sequences from diverging; homoplasy may
        explain their high amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid</ENAMEX> identity and low
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-position (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">f2</NUMEX>) identity. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">f2</NUMEX> value comparing Kv3.1
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">vs Kv3.3</ENAMEX> from the mosquito is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.75</NUMEX>, higher than expected,
        considering that amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid</ENAMEX> identity between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64%</NUMEX>)
        is significantly lower than that observed between 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv3.3</ENAMEX> and its 
        Drosophila ortholog.
        It is likely that different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>+ channel subunits within
        the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would provide the potential to generate
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tetramer</ENAMEX> combinations. This would allow
        greater variation and specificity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Kv3</NUMEX> channels, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +channel subunits within a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> can readily form
        functional heteromultimeric channels [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] . The number of
        XXR repeats of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">voltage-sensor</ENAMEX> (where <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> is a hydrophobic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> represents arginine within the
        voltage-sensor) in non-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">vertebrate</NUMEX> Kv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> is of
        interest. The presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> such repeats in invertebrate
        Kv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> in vertebrate Kv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> may help
        explain the difference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">voltage-</ENAMEX>dependence observed
        between the mammalian and fly Kv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, as even single
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">amino-acid mutations</ENAMEX> in this domain can affect
        voltage-dependence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +channels considerably [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX> ] . The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">greater PAM</ENAMEX> distance between 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> and mammalian <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Kv3</NUMEX> channels
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAM</ENAMEX> distance <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>) compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kv1</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kv2</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Kv4</NUMEX> (for which
        the intra-family PAM distances between 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> and mammalian channel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> range from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25-40</NUMEX>) shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kv3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> have
        undergone more extensive adaptation than other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. It can be inferred that the greater complexity of
        the vertebrate brain made necessary a rapidly deactivating,
        high-threshold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel type which has not evolved in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protostomes</ENAMEX>; indeed, given the biophysical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">properties</ENAMEX> of
        Kv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> in mammals, the amino<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">-acid replacements</ENAMEX> that
        have occurred in mammalian Kv3 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> seem to have
        provided exactly this.
        Like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Kv3</TIMEX> ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KQT</ENAMEX> (KCNQ) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel
        genes are more abundant in 
        Anopheles than in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> . Sequence analysis
        suggests these channels evolved before other classical
        voltage-gated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv1-K4</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>-joining
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3a</NUMEX>) and maximum-likelihood <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> we constructed, in
        combination with the fact that mammalian <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">KCNQ1</ENAMEX> and 
        Anopheles KCNQ2 gene products share a
        striking <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75%</NUMEX> identity (despite the divergence of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">protostomes</ENAMEX> and deuterostomes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to 700 million</NUMEX> years
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>), suggest that gene loss in 
        Drosophila , specifically loss of an
        ancestral 
        KCNQ2 (mammalian 
        KCNQ1 ), is the cause of this
        difference, rather than gene expansion in 
        Anopheles , which may be the case for
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Kv3 and Irk3</TIMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3b</NUMEX>) gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Alternatively,
        lateral transfer of 
        KCNQ1 from mammals to 
        Anopheles must be considered, given
        the intimate relationship of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>. Although the
        genome size of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> is twice the size of the 
        Drosophila genome, the numbers of
        genes in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> are nearly equivalent [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX> ] ,
        suggesting that gene duplication depends on the advantage
        of additional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, rather than a
        general consequence of possessing a larger genome. Unlike
        other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel types, for which amino and carboxyl
        termini are highly variable, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KQT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel sequences</ENAMEX> are even
        more highly conserved in some regions of the cytoplasmic
        carboxy-terminal region than in the conserved pore region.
        The presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> potential splice variants within the
        carboxy-terminal tail raises questions about the role of
        this domain in channel function. Although the physiologic
        significance of this region is not yet known, evidence
        suggests it may be involved in calmodulin binding [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX> ] .
        For this region one homologous gene product can be found in
        
        Drosophila , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KCNQ</ENAMEX>, which raises
        questions about whether products of this gene mediate the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M-current</ENAMEX>, as has been postulated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">KCNQ2 and KCNQ3</TIMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mammals</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX> ] .
        The greater number of inward rectifier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel genes
        in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> compared to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> is striking, given that
        these organisms belong to the same order. Our analysis,
        based on maximum-likelihood and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>-joining
        algorithms, suggests that gene duplication in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> is the most likely
        explanation for the greater number of 
        Irk3 genes in mosquito. This also
        appears to be the case for 
        Irk2.1 and 
        Irk2<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> ; however, from the tree
        (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3b</NUMEX>) it appears that the divergence of 
        Irk2<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX> from 
        Irk2.1 and 
        Irk2.2 in the mosquito occurred
        earlier than the divergence of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Irk2</ENAMEX> and the two 
        Anopheles genes 
        Irk2.1 and 
        Irk2<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> , suggesting that gene loss in
        
        Drosophila may have occurred. The
        same <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> topology was supported by both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>-joining
        and maximum-likelihood <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, though lack of a clear
        ortholog from a more distant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> (for example, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deuterostome</ENAMEX>) makes this type of assessment, regarding gene
        history, more difficult. Future studies may help explain
        why the mosquito has twice as many of the inward rectifier
        genes as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> fly. Gene expansion in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> has been observed for genes
        involved in hematophagy and insecticide resistance; it is
        unclear to what extent these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> factors are involved here,
        although ion channels are clearly targets of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insecticides</ENAMEX>.
        The overall compositions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> and 
        Drosophila are strikingly similar in
        some respects, such as conservation of sequence and
        intron-exon boundaries of orthologs, and strikingly
        different in others, such as the number of 
        Irk homologs and lack of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microsynteny</ENAMEX>. The genome projects of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX>, such as
        
        Manduca sexta and 
        Bombyx mori , will help paint a
        broader picture of the composition of ion-channel genes
        within the genomes of these related <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusions
        Within the 
        Anopheles genome there are orthologs
        for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> major voltage-dependent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel gene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in 
        Drosophila : <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kv1</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kv2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Kv3 and Kv4</TIMEX> ( 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Shaker ,</ENAMEX> 
        Shab , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> and 
        Shal , respectively). In addition we
        have identified genes that encode the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shaker β</ENAMEX>-subunit, two
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KQT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>, as well as three
        Slo-family genes, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eag</ENAMEX>-family genes, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> inward
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rectifier K</ENAMEX> +-channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. In 
        Anopheles , the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is more diverse than in 
        Drosophila : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> from this
        family are located next to one another along chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3R</NUMEX>,
        in contrast to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> Kv3-family genes in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drosophila</ENAMEX>. The greater number of
        genes for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel types, inward rectifier, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KQT</ENAMEX>,
        and Kv3 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>), in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> is intriguing, given that
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> have roughly the same number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>: both
        gene expansion in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> and gene loss in 
        Drosophila , in separate cases, may
        account for these differences. The high level of amino-acid
        sequence identity, as well as the conservation of
        intron-exon boundaries, in combination with the chromosomal
        proximity of these genes in 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anopheles</ENAMEX> and 
        understanding of the molecular diversity and evolutionary
        history of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in the order <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diptera</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        I used BLAST [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> ] and PSI-BLAST at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCBI</ENAMEX> website to
        find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-channel homologs using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaker K</ENAMEX> +-channel pore
        sequence as a query initially and then other, longer, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
        +-channel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-specific query sequences for verification.
        The predicted splice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> were compared with results of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TBLASTN</ENAMEX> to help confirm intron-exon boundaries.
        Increases in nucleotide position number from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> putative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exon</ENAMEX> to the next were used to deduce the size of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">introns</ENAMEX>.
        This study utilized the Ensembl 
        Anopheles gambiae server [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX> ] to
        search for homologs of various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> +-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel types</ENAMEX> and to
        identify and visualize their respective chromosomal
        locations. The DARWIN server [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> ] was used to calculate
        the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">f2</NUMEX> values for the sequences, as well as a phylogenetic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> for the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX> sequences, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAM</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distances</ENAMEX> and ancestral sequences. Figures were visualized
        and optimized using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adobe Photoshop</ENAMEX>.
        Sequences were aligned using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ClustalX</ENAMEX> version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.81</NUMEX>.
        Phylogenetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> were generated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ClustalX</ENAMEX> (for
        neighbor joining) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHYLIP</ENAMEX> (for neighbor joining,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parsimony</ENAMEX> and maximum likelihood using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protdist, Protpars</ENAMEX>,
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ProML</ENAMEX>, respectively). The resulting <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> were then
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visualized</ENAMEX> and evaluated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treeview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bootstrap</ENAMEX> values
        were calculated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ClustalX</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PHYLIP</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
