
  
    
      
        Rationale
        The volume and diversity of expressed sequence tag (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> in the public databases makes them an important
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX> for gene identification, genome annotation and
        comparative genomics. The value of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> data is enhanced
        when the sequences are clustered (on the basis of sequence
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overlap</ENAMEX>) to reduce redundancy. In some cases these sequence
        clusters can be used to generate a consensus sequence that
        represents a virtual transcript. Examples of electronic
        transcript data resources include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UniGene</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">TIGR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
        Indices [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2, 3</ENAMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DoTS</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STACK</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. Each of these
        resources differs in the methods used to reduce the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redundancy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> sequence data and in how the data are
        represented. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UniGene</ENAMEX> uses pairwise sequence
        comparisons to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">partition EST</TIMEX> and other transcript
        sequences from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> into gene-orientated clusters with
        no consensus sequence. The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> (TIGR <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indices</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DoTS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STACK</ENAMEX>) cluster sequences from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESTs</ENAMEX> and
        known transcripts and then assemble the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of each
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cluster</ENAMEX> to produce a consensus representation of the
        transcripts. The algorithms and/or parameters used to guide
        the clustering and assembly process for the virtual
        transcript resources are similar, but not identical. These
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> also differ with respect to the number of species
        for which <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> assemblies are available. For example, the
        STACK database includes only human sequence data, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS</ENAMEX> has
        both human and mouse assemblies, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">TIGR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Indices</ENAMEX>
        maintains separate electronic transcript databases for over
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. In contrast to computational approaches to
        transcript analysis and representation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mammalian Gene</ENAMEX>
        Collection (MGC) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>] and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">RIKEN Mouse</ENAMEX> Encyclopedia
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>] are systematically generating full-length
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cDNA</ENAMEX> clones with the aim of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> full-length
        clone reagent and sequence for every human (MGC) and mouse
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIKEN</ENAMEX>) gene.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse Genome Informatics</ENAMEX> (MGI) database [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]
        provides integrated access to genetic, genomic and
        biological data for the laboratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>. The MGI database
        represents an integrated platform to which several related
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> contribute, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse Genome Database</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGD</ENAMEX>) [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>], the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Expression Database</ENAMEX> (GXD) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>], the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouse Genome Sequence</ENAMEX> (MGS) project [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>], the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse Tumor</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biology</ENAMEX> (MTB) database [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>], and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Ontology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GO</ENAMEX>)
        project [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> provides access to gene annotation and
        nomenclature, mapping, nucleotide and protein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sequences</ENAMEX>,
        mammalian gene homology, gene expression, phenotypes,
        allelic variants and mutants and strain data. The
        information in the MGI database is updated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> by
        professional scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> who extract relevant data
        from the scientific literature and other sources. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> staff
        curate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between genes and nucleotide and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein sequences</ENAMEX> in collaboration with other database
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWISS-PROT</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>], <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RIKEN</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>], and the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 16</TIMEX>]. Genes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> are given unique, permanent accession
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ids</ENAMEX> to facilitate stable cross-references with other
        databases even when such information as gene name,
        functional annotation, and so on changes over time [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>].
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1shows</ENAMEX> a summary of some of the MGI database
        content.
        The utility of both experimentally and computationally
        derived transcript resources are greatly enhanced when the
        transcripts are associated with well curated biological
        knowledge about the genes with which the transcripts are
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>]. However, manual curation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">computationally</ENAMEX> derived transcript data is not feasible
        because the underlying data for these resources are
        constantly changing. Therefore, we have developed a
        semi-automated curation process to create and update
        associations between constantly changing electronic
        transcript databases and the genes represented in the MGI
        database. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associations</ENAMEX> are based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequence
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accession identifiers</ENAMEX> shared between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and
        transcript clusters/assemblies. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>
        between the genes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> and the electronic transcripts
        could also be made on the basis of sequence similarity, the
        use of shared accession ids is faster and avoids
        inconsistencies in sequence-to-gene <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> that arise
        from highly similar sequence among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of multigene
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Transitive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and
        assembled transcripts
        To establish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genomic Research</ENAMEX> (TIGR) mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> index
        tentative consensus sequence (TCs) or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS</ENAMEX> mouse transcript
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assemblies</ENAMEX> (DTs), we used GenBank sequence accession
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">identifiers</ENAMEX> (GB) that are associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in the MGI
        database and are also component sequences of transcript
        assemblies as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>. All gene-to-transcript associations
        are represented as a set of graphs (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Nodes of the
        graph are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">interrelated MGI genes</ENAMEX> and
        transcript assemblies, and each edge is a group of GenBank
        sequence accession identifiers that are shared by the
        related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> gene and the transcript <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX>.
        We first generated a set of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequence accession
        identifiers that have trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> (that is they
        have been manually curated) with mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> represented in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> markers and
        GenBank sequences, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRK_Sequence.</ENAMEX>rpt, is available from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTP</ENAMEX> site [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. We removed sequences associated
        with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> gene object in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> (for example, large
        cloned inserts containing multiple genes) to avoid
        confounding multiple genes to sequence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>. After
        this filtering step, the relationships of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGI genes</ENAMEX> to
        GenBank sequences were maintained in a dictionary data
        structure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-GB</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> accession numbers as keys and
        GenBank accession identifiers as values.
        A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> dictionary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB-MGI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB</ENAMEX> as keys and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> as
        values), was generated by reversing the keys and values of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-GB</ENAMEX>. A report with all DT identifiers and their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">constituent GenBank</ENAMEX> sequences accession identifiers,
        musDoTS<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">_rel5_accessionsPerAssembly</TIMEX>.dat.gz file (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Release</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 August 2002</TIMEX>), was downloaded from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBIL</ENAMEX>'s website [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>].
        A report containing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR Mouse Gene Index TC</ENAMEX> identifiers
        and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequence identifiers was
        generated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR Mouse Gene Index Release 9.0</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1, 2002</TIMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Geo Pertea</ENAMEX>, personal communication). This report
        was used to create <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dictionaries, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC-GB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> as keys and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB</ENAMEX> as values) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB-TC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB</ENAMEX> as keys and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> as values) to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">map TCs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequence accession ids. There were many
        more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequences (mostly ESTs) in the TIGR <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouse Gene</ENAMEX>
        Index than in the MGI database because the TIGR <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouse Gene</ENAMEX>
        Index was built on all available GenBank sequences, and MGI
        curated only a subset of them (mostly mRNA and RefSeq
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX>). Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequence accession identifiers
        that appear in the MGI database were retained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC-GB</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB-TC</ENAMEX> because those sequences will bridge the transitive
        associations between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX>. Sequences
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> were removed.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the dictionaries described above, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-GB</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB-TC</ENAMEX>, were used to link MGI <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> on the basis of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared GenBank</ENAMEX> sequences. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-TC</ENAMEX>-via<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-GB</ENAMEX> (MGI
        as keys and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> as values), was used to maintain the
        gene-to-transcript <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and their supporting
        GenBank sequences. For each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> accession identifier in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-GB</ENAMEX>, the related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> identifier in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB-TC</ENAMEX> was retrieved
        and added as a value to the MGI accession identifier key,
        keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> accession identifiers as a line of
        evidence in support of the link. When <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> GenBank
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX> supports the same MGI-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> link, all were
        attached to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX>. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2ashows</NUMEX> examples of links
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> with the supporting GenBank
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX>. Of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> genetic markers with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequences,
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71.3%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,772</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,144</NUMEX>) of were linked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> in this analysis. The majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> markers with no
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequence, which is
        either <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">singleton mRNA</ENAMEX>/<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> sequence with no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> accession
        number assigned or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sequence excluded from building TIGR
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouse Gene</ENAMEX> Index. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2summarizes</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> markers and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR Mouse Gene Index TCs</ENAMEX>.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other dictionaries, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC-GB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GB-MGI</ENAMEX>, were used to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">link TCs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in the same way. A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dictionary</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX>-MGI-via<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-GB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> as keys and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> as values), was used to
        maintain links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and the supporting
        GenBank sequences. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2bshows</NUMEX> examples of links from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> to MGI genes with the supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequences.
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19.8%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,942</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105,520</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> (excluding singletons)
        were linked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGI genes</ENAMEX>.
        The same approaches were also used to associate MGI
        genetic markers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS DTs</ENAMEX>. A report with all DT
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">identifiers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequence
        accession identifiers was downloaded from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBIL</ENAMEX>'s website
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Release 5.0</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 August</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">musDoTS</ENAMEX>_<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-7-02_containedIds</ENAMEX>.dat.gz file can be downloaded
        from this site [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>]. The report lists both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS</ENAMEX> assemblies
        (excluding singletons) and singletons. We included only
        assemblies in our analysis. Statistics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> markers and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>. The analysis
        linked <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83.5%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,340</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,144</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> markers with
        sequence information to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20.1%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,799</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">128,341</NUMEX>) of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX>. It is not surprising that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 20%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> or TCs
        can be associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> because the majority of
        the assemblies are composed solely of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> sequences and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">curation</ENAMEX> processes focus primarily on collecting and
        curating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> with genomic and mRNA sequence data.
        There are a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26,440</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> (including singletons) with
        mRNA sequences and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,908</NUMEX> of them have MGI <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>.
        The remaining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,532</NUMEX> DTs with mRNA sequences might represent
        alternative transcripts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGI genes</ENAMEX>, known genes not yet
        represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX>, or novel genes. We will evaluate the
        component sequences of these DTs and incorporate them into
        MGI database over time through manual curation.
      
      
        and transcript assemblies
        
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>-to-many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between genes and
          transcripts are related to transcript diversity
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">TIGR Mouse</ENAMEX> Gene Index and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS</ENAMEX> databases are
          transcript orientated. That is, the sequence clustering
          and assembly process seeks to generate distinct
          assemblies for every form of transcript. The MGI database
          is gene-centric and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> transcripts from the same
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">locus</ENAMEX> to a single gene object in the database. Therefore,
          in many cases, there are <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple TCs</ENAMEX>/DTs associated with
          a single gene in the MGI database. The average numbers of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs/TCs per MGI</ENAMEX> gene among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many associations
          were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.29 and 2.24</NUMEX>, respectively.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Multiple TCs</ENAMEX>/DTs associated with a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> gene
          often represent alternatively spliced transcripts. For
          example, 
          Ncam1 (neural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> adhesion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">molecule 1</ENAMEX>) in the MGI database (MGI:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">97281</ENAMEX>) was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">TC549908, TC582634, TC582635,</ENAMEX>
          TC640342, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TC640343</TIMEX>) and with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.487850</NUMEX>,
          DT<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.87072470</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.87072472</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.97397085</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.97411237</NUMEX>). 
          Ncam1 is known to exist in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
          prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> isoforms encoded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX>
          different transcripts generated from alternative splicing
          [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least eight</NUMEX> distinct mRNAs have been identified
          by a variety of analyses, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> potential transcripts
          have been proposed [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>]. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many associations
          caused by alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">splicing</ENAMEX> (and/or alternative
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poly</ENAMEX>(A) addition sites, see below) were confirmed by
          mapping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> or DTs to the mouse genome assembly using
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSC</ENAMEX>) genome browser [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>]. Figure 3ashows how these
          virtual transcripts align to the 
          Ncam1 gene on mouse chromosome
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Multiple TCs</ENAMEX> or DTs could also represent products of
          transcription from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternative promoters</ENAMEX> and/or
          polyadenylation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> of a single gene. For example, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dtna</ENAMEX> (dystrobrevin alpha) in the
          MGI database (MGI:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">106039</ENAMEX>) was associated with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> TCs
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">TC546133, TC569762, TC577975, TC590157, TC633947</ENAMEX>) and
          with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.50316348</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.60101497</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.87050693</NUMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.91340878 and DT.91393353</NUMEX>). The 
          Dtna gene has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> that
          are active in tissue-specific manner [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>]. Figure
          3bclearly shows multiple transcripts from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX>
          of 
          Dtna <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> on mouse chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>.
          Experimental results suggested that 
          Ncam1 contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poly</ENAMEX>(A) addition site and produces transcripts with
          different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3</TIMEX>' untranslated regions [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>]. Figure
          3ademonstrates that multiple virtual transcripts with
          different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3</TIMEX>' ends align the 
          Ncam1 gene on mouse chromosome
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>.
          Another explanation for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many MGI gene to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs/TCs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> is multiple site-specific
          recombination or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA rearrangement</ENAMEX> that occurs normally
          in certain cell types. For example, the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Igh</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-VS107</ENAMEX> (immunoglobulin heavy
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chain</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S107</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>)) locus in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> (MGI: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">96490</ENAMEX>) was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TC632874</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TC632875</TIMEX>, TC632877
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TC643641</ENAMEX>) and with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.94166135</NUMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.94209475 and DT.94398318</NUMEX>). All above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs/DTs</ENAMEX> and
          sequences associated with 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Igh</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-VS107</ENAMEX> were mapped to the same
          locus on chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSC</ENAMEX> genome browser
          (data not shown). The sequence differences of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Igh</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-VS107</ENAMEX> transcripts are readily
          explained by normal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA rearrangements</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>)<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recombination</ENAMEX>) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>]. Another example is that 
          H2-Eb1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">histocompatibility 2</ENAMEX>, class
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> E beta) in the MGI database (MGI:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">95901</ENAMEX>) was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TC575977</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TC608775</TIMEX>, TC638140
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TC640785</ENAMEX>) and with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.493389</NUMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.55100612</NUMEX>). The 
          H2-Eb1 gene contains a
          recombination hotspot, which has a predominant role in
          generating different recombinants through meiotic
          crossing-over within the I region of the mouse major
          histocompatibility <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (MHC) [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>]. All above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs/DTs</ENAMEX>
          except <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TC575977</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.55100612</NUMEX> were mapped to annotated 
          H2-Eb1 gene on chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> using
          the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCSC</ENAMEX> genome browser (data not shown). TC575977 and
          DT<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.55100612</NUMEX> were associated to 
          H2<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-Eb1</TIMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequence
          AK012147, which was mapped to chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Further
          analysis indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AK012147</ENAMEX> was incorrectly
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with 
          H2<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-Eb1</TIMEX>. 
          Non-biological explanations may also explain some of
          the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> among genes and transcripts
          in our analysis. For example, low-quality sequence data
          or problematic sequences that are not filtered out before
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clustering</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> can cause errors in the sequence
          assemblies. Another possible explanation is that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nucleotide</ENAMEX> and protein <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sequences</ENAMEX> are occasionally
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with the wrong gene in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX>. This will always
          be a challenge to the database <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> when both
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">completeness</ENAMEX> (including as much data as possible in the
          database) and accuracy (associating every sequence to the
          right gene) are goals. Fortunately, non-biological
          reasons for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between transcripts
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> only account for a small percentage of the
          whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dataset</ENAMEX> based on our experience of ongoing internal
          quality control and manual check of portions of the data
          in this analysis.
        
        
          The many-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between genes and
          transcripts are evidence for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-clustering or gene
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redundancy</ENAMEX> in MGI
          In the analysis reported here, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.8%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,302</NUMEX> out of
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,144</NUMEX>) of MGI genes with sequence information were
          involved in many-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> transcript
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.4%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,621</NUMEX> out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,144</NUMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">many-to-one</TIMEX>
          gene to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> transcript <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>. The average numbers
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGI genes</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT/TC</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.16 and 2.23</NUMEX>, respectively.
          First, some of the many-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> are due to
          sequence clusters that contain mistakenly grouped similar
          sequences from closely related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (paralogs). For
          example, sequences from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
          defensin-related cryptdin gene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were clustered into
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TC6H932</NUMEX>) and to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94272645</NUMEX>). These
          genes share similar structure and sequence. Their mRNAs
          are distinguished by a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">45-nucleotide</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>' untranslated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX> (UTS) encoded completely by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> exon [
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>]. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, genes adjacent to each other in the same
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">chromosomal</ENAMEX> location were occasionally clustered together
          and assembled into one sequence because their transcripts
          overlap each other. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' end of 
          Stk11 (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">serine</ENAMEX>/threonine kinase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>;
          MGI:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1341870</ENAMEX>) is in very close proximity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3</ENAMEX>' end of
          a functionally unrelated gene dos (downstream of 
          Stk11 ; MGI: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1354170</ENAMEX>) and it seems
          that overlapping transcripts of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> are
          produced [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>]. Both 
          Stk11 and 
          Dos were linked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> DT
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.493186</NUMEX>) because sequences associated with both genes
          were clustered and assembled together. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, there are
          rare cases of polycistronic transcripts in mammalian
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genomes</ENAMEX>. For example, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snrpn</ENAMEX> (small nuclear
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ribonucleoprotein N; MGI</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">98347</ENAMEX>) and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snurf</ENAMEX> ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SNRPN</ENAMEX> upstream reading frame; MGI:
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1891236</NUMEX>) are expressed as bicistronic 
          Snurf-Snrpn transcript [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>] and
          both of them were associated with one single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TC619385</NUMEX>) and one single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.535946</NUMEX>) in our analysis.
          Finally, many-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> can be caused by
          uncorrected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene redundancy</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gene represented by
          multiple entries) in the MGI database. The majority of
          the redundant records are the result of genes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> that
          are represented solely by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> sequences. As these
          redundancies are identified in MGI they are
          corrected.
        
        
          Many-to-many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between genes and
          transcripts could be the result of any combination of
          many-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and one</NUMEX>-to-many associations
          In the analysis reported here, we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">531</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MGI-DT</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">454</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-TC</ENAMEX> many-to-many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>. There were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.1%</NUMEX>
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,202</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,144</NUMEX>) of MGI genes with sequence
          information and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,355</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> involved in many-to-many MGI
          gene to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> transcript <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.6%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,044</NUMEX> out
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29,144</NUMEX>) of MGI genes with sequence information and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,127</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> in many-to-many MGI gene to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> transcript
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>. The average numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGI genes</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT/TC</ENAMEX>
          were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.26 and 2.30</NUMEX>, respectively, and the average numbers
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs/TCs per MGI</ENAMEX> gene were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.55 and 2.48</NUMEX>, respectively.
          The majority of the many-to-many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> had only
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGI genes</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs/TCs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with the largest
          number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGI genes</ENAMEX> in MGI-DT <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paired-Ig</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> ( 
          Pira1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Pira2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Pira3</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Pira4</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Pira5</TIMEX>,
          Pira7, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Pira10</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Pira11</TIMEX> ) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.87053023</NUMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94272531</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA blot</ENAMEX> analysis indicated the presence
          of multiple paired-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ig</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> A genes in the
          genome, and cDNA sequencing analysis suggested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.7%</NUMEX>
          frequency of overall nucleotide variations [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>]. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> with the largest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGI genes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-TC</ENAMEX>
          associations included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> eosinophil-associated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ribonuclease</ENAMEX> ( 
          Ear1, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ear2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ear3</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ear8</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ear9</ENAMEX> and 
          Ear10 ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> guanylyltransferase
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5</ENAMEX>'-phosphatase ( 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rngtt</ENAMEX> ) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">TC561767,</ENAMEX>
          TC569331, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">TC557280 and TC557281</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse Ear</ENAMEX> family
          has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> functional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pseudogenes</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>]. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> within this family share a
          common genomic structure that is conserved with primate
          Ear genes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse Ear</ENAMEX> gene family forms <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> unique
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clades</ENAMEX> ( 
          Ear1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2/3/8/9/10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> form
          subfamily A). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of each clade share a high
          degree of sequence identity. Transcripts from 
          Ear1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2/3/8/9/10</NUMEX> were over-clustered
          into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TC561767</NUMEX>). TC569331 was associated with 
          Ear2 because of shared <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> sequence
          AA510162 and associated with 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rngtt</ENAMEX> because of shared GenBank
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">sequence AK002922.</ENAMEX> Sequence analysis indicated that
          AA510162 encodes 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rngtt</ENAMEX> instead of 
          Ear2 . Further analysis suggested
          that a typographical error in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>]
          caused the reported <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX> sequence associated with 
          Ear2 to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AA510162</TIMEX> instead of
          AA510161. This many-to-many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> can be resolved
          into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one many</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> to
          TC561767) caused by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-clustering and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX>-to-many
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> gene 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rngtt</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX>) caused by
          transcript diversity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with the largest number
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> in MGI-DT <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> and three
          immunoglobin heavy-chain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> ( 
          Igh-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Igh-VJ558</ENAMEX> and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Igh-V</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> with the largest
          number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-TC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> immunoglobin heavy-chain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> ( 
          Igh-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Igh-VJ558</ENAMEX> and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Igh-1</ENAMEX> ). The complexity of the
          many-to-many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> demonstrates the challenges of
          creating links between genes and electronic transcripts
          and highlights the caveats that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> of these resources
          must keep in mind.
        
      
      
        Comparison of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR Mouse Gene Index</ENAMEX>
        
          For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-DT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-TC associations</ENAMEX>,
          the number of shared sequences between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> pairs
          linked to the same MGI gene varies
          Our analysis reported <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,996</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MGI-DT</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13,451</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-TC</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,126</NUMEX> MGI genes had
          both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>. Among these, all
          except <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> had one or more GenBank
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sequences</ENAMEX> in common (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 4for</ENAMEX> details). There are
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,305</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MGI genes</ENAMEX>, whose associated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> pairs had
          exactly the same component sequences. The assemblies that
          were identical in the number of component sequences were
          generally small clusters. Of the assemblies associated
          with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,305</NUMEX> MGI genes described above, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">496</NUMEX> had only
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component sequences</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">635</NUMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three to five</NUMEX> component
          sequences, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> component sequences, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>
          had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than ten</NUMEX> but less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> component sequences.
          Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> pairs associated with the same MGI genes
          have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more sequences in common. The number of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> sequences between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> varies widely, ranging
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,000</NUMEX>. The maximum number of shared
          GenBank sequences is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,157 between DT.9133761</NUMEX> and
          TC615398 both associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> gene 
          Svs2 (seminal vesicle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>,
          secretion <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>; MGI: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1858275</ENAMEX>). These pairs generally have
          very different numbers of component sequences, ranging
          from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than a few thousand sequences</NUMEX>. TCs
          generally have larger numbers of sequences per cluster
          than do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX>. The maximum number of component sequences
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,592</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">DT.537719</NUMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9,193</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">TC619155</NUMEX>)
          respectively.
        
        
          For the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many MGI-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-TC associations</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TIGR Mouse Gene Index</ENAMEX> did not consistently
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cluster the GenBank</ENAMEX> sequences
          There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,522</NUMEX> MGI genes associated with multiple
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,975</NUMEX> MGI genes with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple TCs</ENAMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,475</NUMEX> MGI
          genes had both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">DT one</NUMEX>-to-many
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX>. We considered all TCs or DTs associated
          with the same MGI <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> as different forms of transcripts
          and grouped them together. We compared the identity and
          grouping of the component sequences between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> group
          and its corresponding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. We included only the
          sequences curated in the MGI database in the comparison
          because they are mostly high-quality mRNA sequences and
          should be reliably clustered. There were only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">245</NUMEX> pairs
          of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> associated with the same set
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequences, which were also
          clustered in the same way. The remaining pairs differ
          either in their set of associated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GenBank</ENAMEX> sequences or in
          the way of sequence clustering.
          The differences between the two electronic transcript
          databases are likely to be due to the different criteria
          used by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> for clustering and assembly of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>
          and mRNA sequences. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possibility is different degrees
          of trimming poor-quality sequences from the ends of ESTs
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.J.S.</ENAMEX>, personal communication). Less trimming in DoTS
          build might result in more assemblies than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR TCs</ENAMEX>. In
          testing, fewer larger assemblies were generated when
          trimming was not limited. Limited trimming was chosen in
          attempt to preserve better representation of
          differentially processed transcripts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS</ENAMEX> build. The
          comparison of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> databases using curated data from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> as a reference provides some measures to evaluate and
          improve computational methods.
        
      
      
        Utility of the analysis
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of MGI genes with electronic transcript
        assemblies supplies biological context to the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">computationally</ENAMEX> assembled transcripts and allows
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to access these data from biological as well as
        sequence perspectives. The curation process described here
        permits us to rapidly build high-confidence associations
        between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and electronic transcript sequences. The
        results reveal the complications that can arise from the
        clustering process as well as errors in the MGI database.
        The assessment of the results will provide measures to
        evaluate and improve <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the EST</TIMEX>-assembly protocols and to
        check the quality of gene representation in the MGI
        database.
      
      
        Access to the links between the MGI database and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBIL</ENAMEX> electronic transcript databases
        Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs/DTs</ENAMEX> that are
        supported by non-conflicting evidence (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>) are accessible from the web
        browsers for these resources. The links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> are available from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> gene detail pages.
        The links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCs</ENAMEX> to MGI genes are available from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TC</ENAMEX> report page and through another TIGR database resource,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESOURCERER</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>]. The links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> to MGI genes are
        available from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allgenes</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DT</ENAMEX> report page [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> can
        query for related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DTs</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> gene accession identifiers or
        symbols. The data files for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-DT/TC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> are
        available from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTP</ENAMEX> site [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>]. These data will
        be updated after each build of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouse Gene</ENAMEX> Index and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBIL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS</ENAMEX> database or after every major change in MGI
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">databases</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Additional data files
        The original datasets from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR</ENAMEX>(from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">TIGR Mouse Gene</ENAMEX>
        Index <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Release 9.0</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2002</TIMEX>)), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DoTS</ENAMEX>(from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DoTS</ENAMEX> mouse
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assembly Release 5.0</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 August 2002</TIMEX>)) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX>(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 October</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>) are available as additional data files. Links from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOTS</ENAMEX> ( <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many, many-to-oneand
        many-to-many) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIGR</ENAMEX> ( <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many,
        many-to-oneand many-to-many) electronic transcript
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associations</ENAMEX> from the analysis done on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 October 2002</TIMEX> are
        also available as additional data files. The most recent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> files for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI-DT/TC associations</ENAMEX> can be obtained from
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTP</ENAMEX> site [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>].
        Additional data file 1
        The original datasets from TIGR
        The original dataset from TIGR
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file 2
        The original dataset from DoTs
        The original dataset from DoTs
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file 3
        The original dataset from MGI
        The original dataset from MGI
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file 4
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to the DOTS - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to the DOTs - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file 5
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to the DOTS - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to the DOTS - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file 6
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to the DOTS - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to the DOTS - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file 7
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to the DOTS - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many</NUMEX>-to-many
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to the DOTS - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many</NUMEX>-to-many
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file 8
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to TIGR - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to TIGR - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file 9
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to TIGR - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to TIGR - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-many
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to TIGR - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to TIGR - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
        Click here for additional data file
        Additional data file <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to TIGR - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many</NUMEX>-to-many
        Links from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGI</ENAMEX> to TIGR - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many</NUMEX>-to-many
        Click here for additional data file
      
    
  
