
  
    
      
        Introduction
        Cystic fibrosis (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX>) is a generalized exocrine disease
        resulting from the defective regulation of epithelial
        chloride ion transport within various organ systems, most
        importantly the lungs [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2 3 4</NUMEX> ] . This dysfunction can
        arise from a variety of mutations within the cystic
        chromosome <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>, which encodes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">transmembrane</ENAMEX> pump
        responsible for regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transepithelial ion</ENAMEX> levels [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 2</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ] . This defect is associated with an increased viscosity
        of the airway surface fluid, and according to some studies,
        an altered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> concentration [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] . These and other
        pleiotropic effects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> gene abnormality increase the
        susceptibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to bronchopulmonary bacterial
        infection by opportunistic pathogens.
        
        Pseudomonas aeruginosa is the most
        common pathogen recovered from the lungs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> ] . This predisposition to 
        P. aeruginosa infection has been
        attributed to several factors. For example, an increase in
        asialo-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> 
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> glycoproteins on the apical surface of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> airway epithelial cells provides greater opportunity for
        adhesion by the type <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> pili of 
        P. aeruginosa [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 7 8</NUMEX> ] .
        Furthermore, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> extracellular domain of wild type
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFTR</ENAMEX> has been found to act as a 
        P. aeruginosa -specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>,
        which is involved in the clearance of 
        P. aeruginosa from the airways via
        epithelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> desquamation [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9 10 11</ENAMEX> ] , a process
        greatly impaired in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> lung. Other conditions that abet
        colonization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> lung include impairment of the
        "mucociliary escalator" and macrophage-mediated
        phagocytosis by the viscous airway secretions. If elevated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">salt</ENAMEX> concentrations exist within these secretions [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] ,
        they would inhibit Î± and Î²-defensins, endogenous
        antibacterial peptides produced by neutrophils and airway
        epithelia, respectively [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3 12 13 14 15</NUMEX> ] . This last
        point is still under review as recent evidence suggests
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> airway surface fluid may be isotonic not hypertonic
        [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> ] .
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> 
        Burkholderia cepacia has become the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> leading cause of death in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with chronic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">granulomatous disease</ENAMEX> (CGD). The phagocytes of such
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are deficient in their capacity to kill organisms
        by oxidative means because of a defective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NADPH</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oxidase</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 18</NUMEX> ] . 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> also poses a threat to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX>, either cocolonizing those already
        infected with 
        P. aeruginosa or as the sole
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">infecting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2 18</ENAMEX> ] . Although rates of colonization
        can vary widely (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 5 and 70%</NUMEX>), 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> is isolated from sputum in
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 10%-20%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 3</NUMEX> ] . 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> , a very diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>,
        has been divided into several "classes" of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, i.e.,
        genomovars, collectively referred to as the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genomovar III</ENAMEX> is
        the most common 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> genomovar isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, accounting for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 80%</NUMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> isolates in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genomovars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V</ENAMEX> have also been recovered from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> ] . Of critical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> are 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> 's transmissibility from
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> to another and its propensity to give rise to
        the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>, which results in
        a rapid decline in pulmonary function [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2 18</ENAMEX> ] . The
        ability of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> as well as 
        P. aeruginosa to cause chronic
        bronchopulmonary infections in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> is exacerbated
        by their intrinsic or acquired resistance to many
        conventional antibiotics. Peptide antibiotics, including
        protegrins, are currently under consideration as novel
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for treating pulmonary infections in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.
        Antimicrobial peptides are synthesized either
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonribosomally</ENAMEX> or ribosomally [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> ] . Protegrin-1 (PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>),
        a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> kDa cationic octadecapeptide (RGGRLCYCRRRFCVCVGR-amide)
        was originally isolated from porcine leukocytes [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> ] and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">falls</ENAMEX> into the latter category. We selected it for this
        study because it is rapidly bactericidal, functions well at
        elevated physiological <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt concentrations</ENAMEX> such as those
        that may occur in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> lung, and has a broad spectrum of
        activity [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 22 23</NUMEX> ] . PG-1's antiparallel Î²-hairpin
        structure and antimicrobial activity in physiological and
        elevated salt concentrations are maintained by its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
        intramolecular cystine disulfide bonds [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21 24 25 26 27 28</NUMEX>
        ] . The antimicrobial spectrum of PG-1 includes 
        Chlamydia trachomatis , 
        Candida albicans , 
        Escherichia <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coli</ENAMEX> , 
        Fusobacterium nucleatum, Haemophilus
        ducreyi , 
        Listeria monocytogenes , 
        Neisseria gonorrhoeae , 
        Porphyromonas gingivalis , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Prevotella intermedia ,</ENAMEX> 
        P. aeruginosa , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Staphylococcus aureus</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 22 25 29</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 31 32</NUMEX> ] .
        This study tested the hypothesis that the relative
        sensitivity or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> of 
        P. aeruginosa and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia strains to PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> correlates
        to the extent of peptide binding. A previously described
        two-stage radial diffusion technique designed for peptide
        antibiotics was used to determine susceptibility. Binding
        of protegrins to intact 
        P. aeruginosa and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia cells and to purified
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lipopolysaccharide</ENAMEX> (LPS) and lipid A prepared from these
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">organisms</ENAMEX> was measured by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different techniques.
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bacterial strains</ENAMEX> and growth media
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> sets of genetically related 
          P. aeruginosa strains were studied.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Strain 144M</ENAMEX>, a serum-sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mucoid</ENAMEX> isolate from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, contains short <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>-side chain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, while its
          serum-resistant derivative, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">144M</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SR</ENAMEX>), which is also
          mucoid, has long <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>-side chain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX> ] . Strain FRD-1
          is a mucoid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> isolate [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FRD-2</ENAMEX> is its
          spontaneous nonmucoid derivative [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX> ] . 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. aeruginosa ATCC strains 10145</ENAMEX>
          and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9027</TIMEX> are nonmucoid strains with long <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>-side chain
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPSs</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N L Schiller</ENAMEX>, unpublished results]. We also studied
          
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia ATCC</ENAMEX> strains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25416</NUMEX> and
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25609</NUMEX>, as well as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> clinical strains isolated from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, kindly provided by
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David P Speert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">British Columbia</ENAMEX>. These
          strains included: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C4813</ENAMEX>, genomovar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIa</ENAMEX>, 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> epidemic strain marker
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCESM</ENAMEX>) positive, cable pilin subunit gene A (cable A)
          negative; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C4878</TIMEX>, genomovar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCESM</ENAMEX> positive, cable A
          negative; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C6159</ENAMEX>, genomovar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IIIb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCESM</ENAMEX> and cable A
          negative. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BCESM</ENAMEX> and cable A are putative transmissibility
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">markers</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> ] . Log-phase cultures were grown at 37Â°C
          with shaking in trypticase soy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">broth</ENAMEX> (TSB)
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becton-Dickinson Microbiology, Cockeysville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Protegrin
          PG-1 was prepared as previously described [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> ] and
          was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 96.5%</NUMEX> pure. PG-1 was dissolved in and
          diluted with filter-sterilized acidified <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.01%</NUMEX>
          acetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>) supplemented with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.1%</NUMEX> human serum albumin
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>). The albumin in the PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> vehicle
          helped reduce nonspecific adsorption of protegrins when
          the stock solutions were serially diluted [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22 37</NUMEX> ] .
          These PG-1 stock solutions were filter-sterilized prior
          to storage at either <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-20Â°C</ENAMEX> for short term (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><3</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>)
          or -80Â°C for long-term storage.
        
        
          Radial diffusion assay
          The two-stage radial diffusion assay protocol as
          described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steinberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX> ] was altered by
          supplementing the underlay agar with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaCl</ENAMEX> to
          ascertain PG-1's ability to kill 
          P. aeruginosa and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia at an elevated salt
          concentration. These assays were interpreted as described
          below. The sample <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> Î¼l of PG-1 (various
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concentrations</ENAMEX>) or its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. We analyzed the radial
          diffusion assay results in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. In one, we
          calculated the lethal concentration (C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> ) as described by Hultmark 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al</ENAMEX> . [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39 40</NUMEX> ] from wells
          surrounded by net clear zones of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> mm. In the
          other, we defined the minimal active concentration (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAC</ENAMEX>)
          as the lowest concentration of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> that produced a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">measurable</ENAMEX>, totally clear, inhibition <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> around the
          well.
        
        
          Whole cell binding assay
          Binding of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to intact cells was measured with a
          monoradioiodinated variant of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. This protegrin
          variant differed from PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Phe7</NUMEX> replaced
          Tyr7 in the protegrin domain, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-terminal
          glycine-rich hexapeptide extension (GGGYGG) with a single
          tyrosine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> was present. In this report the modified
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX> and its monoiodinated variant will be called
          "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GGPG</ENAMEX>" and "I-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGPG</ENAMEX>", respectively. The full sequence of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGPG</ENAMEX> is GGGYGGRGGRLCFCRRRFCVCVGR-CONH 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . In preliminary experiments, we
          determined that PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGPG</ENAMEX>, and I-GGPG exhibited
          virtually identical antimicrobial potency and kinetics
          (data not shown).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGPG</ENAMEX> was iodinated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaI</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Na 125I</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>) by the iodobead method [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41 42</NUMEX> ] .
          Unincorporated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaI</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Na 125I</ENAMEX> was removed by solid phase
          extraction on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sep-Pak C-18 Plus Cartridge</ENAMEX>. I-GGPG was
          purified from uniodinated and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">di-iodinated GGPG</ENAMEX> by
          reverse phase-HPLC (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vydac, Hesperia</ENAMEX>, CA). Binding assays
          were done with stationary phase 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. aeruginosa 9027</ENAMEX> or 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25416</NUMEX>, both typically at
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2.5 Ã— 10 7CFU/ml.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> were incubated with
          125I-GGPG at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0Â°</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60 min</TIMEX> at pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM
          Tris-acetate buffer containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaCl</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSB</ENAMEX>, and
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>. Samples were layered over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.3</NUMEX> ml of a cushion
          composed of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> parts of dibutyl phthalate and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> parts of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">di</ENAMEX>-isodecyl phthalate (density 
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.01</NUMEX>) and centrifuged at
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 14,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g . After removing the supernatant
          and phthalate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>, the base of the tube was severed with
          a razor blade and the stub, which contained the pellet,
          was recovered for radioactivity counting.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">A</ENAMEX> extraction and analysis
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bacterial LPS</ENAMEX> was isolated according to the protocol
          of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darveau</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hancock</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX> ] with some modifications, as
          described below. Strains were grown overnight in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSB</ENAMEX>,
          collected via centrifugation (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">0Â°C</NUMEX>), and suspended
          in a pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX> buffer (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5.0 g</NUMEX> of wet weight bacteria<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/30</NUMEX> ml of
          buffer) that contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM Tris-hydrochloride, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mM
          MgCl 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 , 100 Î¼g/</ENAMEX>ml <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">DNase I, and 25</ENAMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RNase I.</ENAMEX> The slurry was passed twice through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
          Press set at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lbs</ENAMEX>/in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNase</ENAMEX> were again
          added, and the mixture was incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>.
          Then, to each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> ml of suspension, the following were
          added: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.0</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> tetrasodium <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> mM Tris
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buffer</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> ml of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris</ENAMEX> buffer, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>
          ml of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris</ENAMEX> buffer. The preparation was mixed and
          centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20Â°C</NUMEX> to remove the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptidoglycan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protease</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P5147</ENAMEX>) at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">200 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> was
          added to the supernatant and incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">37Â°C overnight</TIMEX>
          with agitation. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.375</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M MgCl</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> was added and the
          suspension was cooled to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0Â°C</TIMEX> before centrifugation at
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">0Â°C</TIMEX>. The resulting
          pellet was resuspended in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M</ENAMEX> tetrasodium EDTA
          in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris</ENAMEX> buffer and sonicated. This solution was
          incubated at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, and cooled to room
          temperature before protease (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">25 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) was added and
          incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. After re-precipitation the
          following day with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, the pellet was resuspended in
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris</ENAMEX> buffer and centrifuged at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20Â°C</NUMEX> in the
          presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> mM MgCl 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> . The final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> extract was
          suspended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> ml dH 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> and dialyzed overnight against dH 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> to remove any residual <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> prior to being lyophilized. Contamination of the LPS
          samples by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> represented <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">no more than 3.6% Â± 0.21%</NUMEX>,
          as estimated by measuring the dry weight and protein
          concentration with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bio-Rad Protein Assay Kit</ENAMEX>. Nucleic
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> contamination was considered to be minimal due to
          the repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNase</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">RNase</ENAMEX> treatments. LPS preparations
          were diluted using the PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> vehicle prior to assaying
          with PG-1.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipid A</ENAMEX> was extracted from isolated LPS preparations
          via acid <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hydrolysis</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44 45</NUMEX> ] . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isolated LPS</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25-30</NUMEX> mg)
          was suspended in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ml of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX> acetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid solution</ENAMEX> and
          heated in a water bath to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100Â°C</TIMEX> under refluxing
          conditions for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 hours</TIMEX>. Once the lipid A was hydrolyzed,
          it precipitated out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> and was extracted with
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> sequential <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ml aliquots of chloroform. Lipid A
          extracts were collected and washed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ml
          aliquots of dH 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> before being lyophilized. Lipid A
          was dissolved in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO), which
          was diluted to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.5%</NUMEX> with the PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> before
          application in the radial diffusion assay.
          In order to measure the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A to
          bind PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, we modified the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> radial diffusion
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assay</ENAMEX> so that we could ascertain the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lipid A</ENAMEX> (in ng), that reduced the antimicrobial activity
          of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ng of PG-1 by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> (called the effective
          concentration <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ). Briefly, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼l</NUMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml
          PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> solution and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.5 Î¼l</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or lipid A (at various
          concentrations based on their dry weight) were combined,
          and added to the radial diffusion <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>. After a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3-hour</TIMEX>
          incubation, a nutrient rich overlay gel was poured and
          the plates were incubated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following day</TIMEX>,
          zone diameters (including the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX>) were measured in mm.
          Since the height (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>) of the underlay gel was always <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.2</NUMEX>
          mm, the zone diameters were converted to volumes cleared
          of viable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> with the formula for the volume of a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cylinder</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V=Ï</ENAMEX>€ r <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2h</TIMEX>. Since the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> mm diameter sample well
          was devoid of both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> and peptide, its volume (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.5</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼l</ENAMEX>) was subtracted from the gross clear zone volume (Ï€ r
          2h) to derive the net volume rendered free of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>.
          As will be shown below, this net volume was a linear
          function of the amount of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> placed in the well, for
          amounts of protegrin between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0-50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ well.
        
        
          Surface plasmon resonance
          Binding of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or lipid A to PG-1 was assessed with a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biacore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2000</ENAMEX> system (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BiaCore AB</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Piscataway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>); a very
          similar approach was used to study LPS binding by peptide
          domains of horseshoe crab factor C [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX> ] . This
          innovative technology uses surface plasmon resonance to
          study biomolecular interactions in real time. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
          the binding takes place on a small chip coated with a
          thin layer of metal. It is monitored by monochromatic,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">p</ENAMEX>-polarized light whose electric vector component is
          parallel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> of incidence. Under these
          conditions, the intensity of the reflected light is
          markedly reduced at a specific incident angle, producing
          a sharp "shadow". This phenomenon is called "surface
          plasmon resonance" (SPR) and the incident light angle at
          which the shadow is observed is the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> angle".
          Detection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> angle depends on changes in the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">refractive</ENAMEX> index (RI) of the medium on the nonilluminated
          side of the chip. Since this RI depends on the mass
          concentration of macromolecules at this surface,
          monitoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> angle provides a real-time measure of
          changes in the surface concentration. The SPR spectrum is
          a plot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> angle against time, and displays the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interaction</ENAMEX>'s progress at the sensor surface. The SPR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> is expressed in resonance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU</ENAMEX>), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU</ENAMEX>
          is equivalent to a change in surface protein
          concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/mm <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2or</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml in
          the bulk <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> concentration.
          In our study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A samples from 
          P. aeruginosa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9027</TIMEX> and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25416</NUMEX> were immobilized
          on a hydrophobic HPA sensor chip (BR-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000-30</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biacore AB</ENAMEX>)
          that was found, in our preliminary experiments, to
          provide an optimal matrix for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> The
          surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPA</ENAMEX> sensor chips is composed of long-chain
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alkanethiol</ENAMEX> molecules that form a flat, quasi-crystalline
          hydrophobic layer that facilitates hydrophobic adsorption
          of liposomes or micelles on a user-defined polar lipid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monolayer</ENAMEX>. The chip was precleaned and conditioned by
          washing twice with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 mM n-octyl</NUMEX> glucoside (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical Co.</ENAMEX>). To immobilize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 Î¼l</NUMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 mg/ml</ENAMEX>
          LPS preparation was dispersed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NaCl</ENAMEX> containing
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 mM HEPES</TIMEX> buffer (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>), and passed across the chip's
          surface for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, at flow rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2 Î¼l/min. Lipid</ENAMEX> A was
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissolved</ENAMEX> and immobilized similarly, except that its
          concentration was reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml. Residual unbound
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A were washed away with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M HCl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NaOH</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml) was used to detect nonspecific
          binding on the surfaces coated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or lipid A. PG-1
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> was measured by observing the change in the SPR
          angle of the sample bound to the chip as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 Î¼l</NUMEX> of PG-1
          (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼M</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼M</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6 Î¼M, 3 Î¼M, 2 Î¼M</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼M</NUMEX>) flowed over
          the sample for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 min</TIMEX> at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼l/min. These PG-1
          solutions were also prepared in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NaCl</ENAMEX> containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM HEPES</ENAMEX> buffer (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>). Each binding study was done in
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triplicate</ENAMEX> and the chip was regenerated between trials by
          washing it with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M HCl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">M NaOH</ENAMEX>.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Activity of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> on P. aeruginosaand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX>
          cepaciastrains
          The C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAC</ENAMEX> for PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> on 
          P. aeruginosa and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> were determined in
          two-stage radial diffusion assays (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). The mean C 
          L of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> 
          P. aeruginosa strains was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.30</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>, and the mean C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia strains was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.02</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml,</ENAMEX>
          a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16.7</NUMEX>-fold difference. The mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MACs</ENAMEX> for 
          P. aeruginosa and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.17 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.40</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>, respectively. The C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAC</ENAMEX> values for 
          P. aeruginosa and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> differed significantly (
          
          P exact = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.004</NUMEX>) when the data were
          analyzed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mann-Whitney</ENAMEX> test.
          We also compared <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sets of genetically related 
          P. aeruginosa <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX>:
          144M<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">/144M</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SR</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FRD-1/FRD-2</ENAMEX>. Whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> of strain
          144M has a very short <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side chain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> from
          strain 144M(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SR</ENAMEX>) has a very long <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side chain</ENAMEX>.
          However, despite these differences both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> had
          comparable C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAC</ENAMEX> values. Similarly,
          comparison of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alginate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRD-1</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FRD-2</ENAMEX>, its
          spontaneous nonmucoid derivative, revealed that both
          strains had very similar C 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAC</ENAMEX> values.
        
        
          Intact/whole cell binding
          Incubation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125I</NUMEX>-GGPG with intact 
          P. aeruginosa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9027</TIMEX> (PG-1 sensitive)
          and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> 25416 (PG-1 resistant)
          cells demonstrated a marked difference in protegrin
          binding between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> strains (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). When the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> were exposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12.5</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g 125I-GGPG /ml,</ENAMEX>
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> sixfold more protegrin molecules bound to 
          P. aeruginosa than to 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> , and at an 125I-GGPG
          concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> times as many protegrin
          molecules bound to 
          P. aeruginosa . Another factor also
          merits mention in this regard. By light microscopy, the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia cells appeared larger
          than the 
          P. aeruginosa cells. By electron
          microscopy, we found that the mean cross sectional
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diameters</ENAMEX> and lengths of 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25416</NUMEX> cells were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.755</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Î¼m Ã— 2.55 Î¼m</ENAMEX>. The corresponding values for 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P. aeruginosa 9027</ENAMEX> cells were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.615</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Î¼m Ã— 2.35 Î¼m</ENAMEX>. Assuming a cylindrical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> for both,
          we calculated that the surface area of the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia cells (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.00 Î¼m 2</NUMEX>) was
          <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 33%</NUMEX> larger on average than that of 
          P. aeruginosa (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.54 Î¼m 2</NUMEX>).
        
        
          Binding of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A
          To compare binding of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A from 
          P. aeruginosa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9027</TIMEX> and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25416</NUMEX>, we devised a
          simple bioassay based on the radial diffusion assay. As
          shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, for protegrin amounts between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0 and 50</NUMEX>
          ng, the volume of underlay gel that was rendered
          completely free of viable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> was linearly related
          to the amount of peptide introduced into the well. By
          mixing a constant amount of protegrin (within this linear
          range) with graded amounts of purified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A,
          we could readily determine how much of these ligands were
          needed to reduce the activity of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> ng of PG-1 by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>
          (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> values). The results of our assays
          with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A purified from the strains we used in
          the above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125I</NUMEX>-GGPG binding studies are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3A.
          The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> values for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> isolated from 
          P. aeruginosa and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> differed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.6</NUMEX>-fold
          (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> ng versus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">460</NUMEX> ng) while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> values for lipid A isolated from
          the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains differed</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 16.7</NUMEX>-fold (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ng</ENAMEX> versus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> ng).
          To ascertain if these findings were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>, we
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prepared LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A from another pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> ( 
          P. aeruginosa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FRD-2</ENAMEX> and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C4813</TIMEX>) and repeated the
          studies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> values for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A
          obtained from 
          P. aeruginosa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FRD-2</ENAMEX> were each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ng</ENAMEX>. The values for 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A were
          estimated as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">approximately 2050</TIMEX> ng for both (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3B), a
          difference of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17.1</NUMEX>-fold when compared to 
          P. aeruginosa <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FRD-2 LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX>
        
        
          Surface plasmon resonance studies
          We also used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SPR</ENAMEX> spectroscopy to compare the binding
          of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A purified from 
          P. aeruginosa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9027</TIMEX> and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25416</NUMEX>. Injection of LPS
          or lipid A from both <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">strains</ENAMEX> was stopped when the
          increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU</ENAMEX> of both reached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>. Loosely bound
          molecules were washed away by increasing the flow rate to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 Î¼l/min</ENAMEX>, followed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one-minute</TIMEX> short pulse
          injections of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NaOH</ENAMEX>. Injections of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mg</ENAMEX>/ml BSA
          prepared in the eluent buffer were passed across the LPS
          or lipid A coated surfaces for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> period and
          showed an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU</ENAMEX>, whereas the same
          amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> passed across the uncoated, n-octyl
          glucoside washed surface showed an increase of roughly
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU</ENAMEX>. This demonstrated that the surface of the chip
          was fully covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> Since similar
          amounts of these ligands had bound to the chip, the
          response unit differences seen at concentrations between
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 and 20</NUMEX> Î¼M indicate that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately twice as much</NUMEX>
          PG-1 bound 
          P. aeruginosa lipid A as bound
          lipid A from the 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> strain (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). Binding
          differences were less marked when we studied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> from
          these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). Although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to one third</NUMEX> more
          <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">protegrin</ENAMEX> molecules bound to 
          P. aeruginosa LPS than to 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia LPS at</ENAMEX> protegrin
          concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-6 Î¼M</ENAMEX>, these differences disappeared
          when we tested higher PG-1 concentrations. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> Î¼M PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> from 
          P. aeruginosa and 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> bound PG-1 equally (â‰ˆ
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> response <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>). Equal binding was also seen at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> Î¼M
          PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (â‰ˆ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> response <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        In this study we compared the sensitivity of 
        P. aeruginosa and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia strains to protegrin PG-1
        with the ability of the intact <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> and key components
        of their outer membranes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A) to bind this
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peptide</ENAMEX>. The indices of susceptibility (C 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAC</ENAMEX> values) obtained from our
        radial diffusion assays established that 
        P. aeruginosa was considerably more
        sensitive to PG-1 than 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia .</ENAMEX> We also found that at
        any given peptide concentration, many fewer protegrin
        molecules bound to intact 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> and its lipid A than to
        the corresponding 
        P. aeruginosa preparations. In model
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>, the ability of protegrins to permeabilize
        membranes shows pronounced "concentration-gating", an
        indication that it is influenced by the density of bound
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">protegrin</ENAMEX> molecules per unit area of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">membrane</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX> ] . As
        prior quantitative studies of peptide binding are few in
        number, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> may be surprised to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
        1shows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">protegrin</ENAMEX> molecules are bound to an
        average bacterial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>, even at concentrations around the
        minimal active concentration. To acquire an equivalent
        density of surface-bound PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> molecules, 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia needed exposure to much
        higher concentrations of PG-1 than 
        P. aeruginosa . Thus, it is a
        reasonable inference that the relative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> to PG-1 is a consequence
        of the smaller number of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">protegrin</ENAMEX> molecules bound per unit
        area of bacterial surface.
        Earlier studies have shown that certain structural
        differences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS of Gram</ENAMEX>-negative <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> correlate
        with their susceptibility or resistance to antimicrobial
        (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">lipo</NUMEX>)peptides [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 23 48 49 50 51</NUMEX> ] . Particular attention
        has been given to alterations of the outer membrane that
        could modify binding to the cell surface. For example,
        sensitivity to the antibacterial lipopeptide polymyxin B is
        affected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">PmrA-PmrB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">regulon</ENAMEX>, which mediates
        substitution of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-aminoarabinose on the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4Â´ phosphate</NUMEX> of
        lipid A [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">52 53</NUMEX> ] . By reducing the negative charge of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lipid A</ENAMEX>, this modification decreases its electrostatic
        interaction with cationic peptides. Resistance to polymyxin
        B is also imparted by the absence or masking of critical
        binding sites required for polycation-mediated
        permeabilization of the outer membrane [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX> ] . Thus,
        attachment of polymyxin B to 
        Yersinia enterocolitica is reduced by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">steric</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hindrance</ENAMEX> generated by the size and/or branched
        shape of the outer core region of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LPS macromolecule</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> ] . Additionally, resistance to cationic peptides can be
        due to cytoplasmic clearance of the antimicrobial peptide
        by an efflux pump; e.g., 
        Yersinia resistance to polymyxin B
        caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RosA/RosB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">efflux</ENAMEX> pump/potassium antiporter [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> ] and 
        Neisseria gonorrhoeae resistance to
        protegrin PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> via an energy-dependent efflux system termed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mtr</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">57</TIMEX> ] .
        Given the notorious resistance of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> to conventional
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antibiotics</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] , its relative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> to PG-1 was not
        unexpected. What bacterial properties influenced
        sensitivity to protegrins? Certainly, the striking
        correlation with the extent of protegrin binding must be
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these. Our studies with genetically related 
        P. aeruginosa strains did not
        implicate the length of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antigen</ENAMEX> side chain as a key
        factor. Furthermore, genetically related 
        P. aeruginosa strains that differed
        in alginate production were equally sensitive to PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Both
        results were somewhat surprising, since long <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>-side chain
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alginate</ENAMEX> molecules should both bind PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Perhaps
        limited alginate production under our experimental
        conditions explains its failure to influence susceptibility
        to PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Additional studies focusing on the influence of
        alginate on PG-1 activity in a biofilm <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> are in
        progress.
        Why did fewer protegrin molecules bind to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> cepacia than to 
        P. aeruginosa ? Our radial
        diffusion/binding and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> studies strongly implicated lipid
        A as a prime suspect in the case. The acyl <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> of lipid
        A form an integral part of the outer membrane bilayer, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electrostatic</ENAMEX> or hydrophobic binding of protegrin to lipid
        A could easily disturb the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and acyl-chain
        packing of the outer membrane, both vital in maintaining
        its integrity and barrier function. Accepting a direct
        proportionality between measured plasmon resonance (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU</ENAMEX>) and
        the extent of peptide bound to the sensor surface, the
        responses shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4indicate that at saturation (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Î¼M</ENAMEX>), lipid A from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> bound almost exactly
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">one-half</ENAMEX> as many protegrin molecules as lipid A from 
        P. aeruginosa . How might this be
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rationalized</ENAMEX>?
        Lipid A typically contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">phosphate groups</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on
        each glucosamine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX>. In the lipid A of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> , one of these phosphates
        is modified by a phosphodiester-linked
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4-amino-4-</ENAMEX>deoxyarabinose <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">residue</ENAMEX> [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58 59</NUMEX> ] . It is
        noteworthy that a previous study reported that the
        phosphate content of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia LPS</ENAMEX> was only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of
        that of 
        P. aeruginosa [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX> ] . If most of the
        
        P. aeruginosa lipid A phosphates are
        unmodified, and if these phosphates are principal protegrin
        binding sites, then one would expect exactly the results
        shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. This is also consistent with the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestion</ENAMEX>, made in a recent report showing that cystic
        fibrosis isolates of 
        P. aeruginosa had lipid A isoforms
        derivatized with aminoarabinose (or palmitate), that these
        structural modifications could enhance resistance to
        cationic antimicrobial peptides [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX> ] . Although the acyl
        chains of lipid A might also provide alternative binding
        sites for protegrin, the orientation of lipid A on the HPA
        sensor chip ("<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>-side down") probably removes them from
        consideration, at least under our study conditions.
        The core and outer polysaccharide regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> should
        provide additional binding sites, including the carboxylate
        moieties of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KDO</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KO</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-glycero-D-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">talo</NUMEX>-oct-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-ulopyranosylonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> [ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX> ] . This
        could explain why 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia LPS</ENAMEX> binds about as much
        PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> as 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. aeruginosa LPS (Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) especially
        at peptide concentrations of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-20 Î¼M</NUMEX>, which allow binding
        to lower affinity sites. This interpretation helps explain
        why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3suggests that 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia LPS</ENAMEX> binds protegrin less
        effectively than the corresponding 
        P. aeruginosa preparation, while the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> results in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. 5show that 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> and 
        P. aeruginosa LPS bound equivalent
        amounts of PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> at high (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-20 Î¼M</NUMEX>) protegrin
        concentrations. To resolve these seemingly discrepant
        results, it is important to recall that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> assays, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sensor</ENAMEX> chips were constantly bathed with a fixed protegrin
        concentration ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1-20 Î¼M</NUMEX> and that in radial
        diffusion assays, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> received a fixed initial amount
        of protegrin (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 ng</NUMEX>). In the latter assays, the peptide was
        dispersed in a total volume of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼l</NUMEX>, making its maximal
        initial concentration <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 2.3Î¼M</NUMEX> - well below the
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-20 Î</TIMEX>¼M concentrations needed to saturate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>. Moreover,
        in addition to binding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lipid A</ENAMEX> molecules we
        added to the well, some of the initially added protegrin
        could diffuse radially into the underlay gel. Both initial
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">binding</ENAMEX> and radial diffusion will decrease the
        concentration of free (i.e., unbound) protegrin that
        remains in the well, and further skew its binding towards
        higher affinity binding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> on lipid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX>
        Although our data clearly establish the presence of a
        reduced number of binding sites for protegrin in lipid A
        from 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> , as compared to lipid A
        from 
        P. aeruginosa , they do not identify
        the cause of this phenomenon. These alterations could
        result from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-aminoarabinose substitutions on the lipid A,
        from other changes that reduce the number of ion-binding
        sites, or from changes that affect hydrophobic interactions
        or membrane insertion. Additional studies that characterize
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia LPS</ENAMEX> and lipid A can help
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pinpoint</ENAMEX> the exact structural differences that relate to
        the relative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia to protegrins</ENAMEX> and to
        endogenous antimicrobial peptides of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Conclusion
        Our studies demonstrate a correlation between protegrin
        sensitivity/resistance and protegrin binding in 
        P. aeruginosa and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia</ENAMEX> , and support a hypothesis
        that the relative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. cepacia to protegrin</ENAMEX> is due
        principally to a reduced number of protegrin binding sites
        on the lipid A moiety of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LPS</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> = bovine serum albumin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CF</ENAMEX> = cystic fibrosis; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFTR</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L</ENAMEX> = lethal concentration; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX> =
        dimethyl sulfoxide; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EC</ENAMEX> 
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> = effective concentration <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX> =
        ethylenediamine <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tetraacetic acid</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGPG</ENAMEX> = modified PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> with
        a glycine-rich hexapeptide extension (GGGYGG) containing a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hydroxyethylpiperazine</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>-ethanesulfonic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HPLC</ENAMEX> =
        monoiodinated variant of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGPG; LPS</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lipopolysaccharide</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAC</ENAMEX> = minimal active concentration; PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">protegrin</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RU</ENAMEX>
        = resonance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX> = sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dodecyl sulfate</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPR</ENAMEX> =
        surface plasmon resonance; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSB</ENAMEX> = trypticase soy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">broth</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
