
  
    
      
        Introduction
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> of inhaled particulate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and
        cigarette smoking with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pulmonary disease</ENAMEX>, such as chronic
        obstructive <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pulmonary disease</ENAMEX>, is well documented [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX> ] ,
        but the specific early responses of lung epithelial cells
        to toxic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> in particulates - that predispose the
        cells to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> - have not been elucidated. Cigarette
        smoke has also been considered a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the
        pathogenesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">asthma</ENAMEX> and as a trigger for acute symptoms
        [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . Exposure to cigarette smoke activates an
        inflammatory cascade in the airway epithelium resulting in
        the production of a number of potent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cytokines</ENAMEX> and
        chemokines, with accompanying damage to the lung
        epithelium, increased permeability, and recruitment of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">macrophages</ENAMEX> and neutrophils to the airway [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX> ] . Even
        brief exposure to cigarette smoke has been shown to
        increase expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-8</ENAMEX> in primary cultures of human
        bronchial epithelial cells (HBEs) in the presence of dust
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mite allergen</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . Increased release of the chemokine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-8</ENAMEX> has also been shown for cultured HBEs exposed to
        cigarette smoke extract (CSE) [ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 6</NUMEX> ] and diesel exhaust
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">particles</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] . However, the precise molecular events
        that bring about these intracellular changes and acute
        inflammation in lung epithelial cells are not well
        understood.
        Upregulation of cytokine gene expression in epithelial
        cells has been linked to activation of specific signaling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX>. Involvement of the mitogen-activated protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX> (MAPK) pathway, extracellular signal-regulated
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein kinase</ENAMEX> (ERK)-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p44/p42</ENAMEX>), in cytokine regulation
        has been demonstrated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBEs</ENAMEX> exposed to diesel exhaust
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">particles</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX> ] but not to cigarette smoke. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB is a
        ubiquitous transcription factor involved in regulating
        inflammatory responses, and its targets include several of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> encoding cytokines and chemokines. The activation
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB by oxidative <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX>, inflammatory cytokines such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX> and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF-Î±</ENAMEX> has been studied in depth [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX> ] , but
        much less is known about the effects of cigarette smoke on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB activation.
        The purpose of this study was to gain insight into the
        mechanism of inflammation induced by cigarette smoke,
        specifically the acute response to smoke. The human
        alveolar epithelial cell line <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> and normal human
        bronchial epithelial cells (NHBEs) were exposed to the
        particulate fraction of cigarette smoke (cigarette smoke
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condensate; CSC</ENAMEX>) and examined for the production of
        proinflammatory cytokines and activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎºB.</ENAMEX>
        The results demonstrate that the acute phase response of
        pulmonary epithelial cells to cigarette smoke involves
        activation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB
      
      
        Materials and methods
        
          Reagents
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1640</TIMEX>, penicillin, streptomycin, fungizone, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trypsin/EDTA</ENAMEX> were obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cellgro</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herndon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Fetal bovine serum was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> Biochemicals
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). The culture medium (BEGM), growth
          factors, trypsin, trypsin neutralizing solution, and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>' balanced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt solution</ENAMEX> for growing and treating
          primary human epithelial cells were purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clonetics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> was purchased from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murty Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and was
          prepared using a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phipps-Bird</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-channel smoking machine
          designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX> testing. The particulate matter from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> standard cigarettes (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1R3F</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was collected on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> glass fibre
          filters and the amount obtained determined by weight
          increase of the filter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> was prepared by dissolving
          the collected smoke particulates in dimethyl sulfoxide
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>) to yield <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a 4%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solution</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">w/v</ENAMEX>). The average yield of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">26.1 mg</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/</ENAMEX>cigarette. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> was diluted into DMSO
          and aliquots were kept at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-80Â°C</TIMEX>. Oligonucleotide primers
          for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> were synthesized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operon Technologies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alameda</ENAMEX>,
          CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Taq polymerase, deoxynucleotide triphosphates
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taq</ENAMEX> buffer were from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promega</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          Anti-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p44/p42</ENAMEX>) polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>,
          anti-phosphorylated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> polyclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX>, and
          horseradish peroxidase (HRP)-conjugated goat anti-rabbit
          IgG were purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Biolabs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Anti-phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IÎºB-Î± polyclonal antibody</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎ</ENAMEX>ºB
          monoclonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> and chemiluminescent detection
          reagents were from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cell Signaling Technology</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
        
        
          Cell culture
          The human alveolar epithelial cell line A549 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATCC</ENAMEX>,
          Rockville, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> fetal
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bovine serum, 100 U/ml penicillin, 100 U/ml streptomycin,</ENAMEX>
          and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml amphotericin-B in an atmosphere of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon dioxide</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> air at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX>. Primary cultures of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clonetics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) were obtained at
          <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> passage and cultured according to the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s instructions using the media and growth
          factors supplied with the cells. The cells were seeded
          into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-well culture plates at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 5cells</NUMEX> per well and
          used between passages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and seven</NUMEX>.
        
        
          Exposure of epithelial cells to cigarette smoke
          condensate
          Cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">A549 cells</ENAMEX> or NHBEs were grown to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50-75%</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confluence</ENAMEX>, then incubated with serum-deficient media for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> before exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>. Treatment with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>, at a
          final concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.4 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>, was
          carried out in modified <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium (MEM) containing
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earle</ENAMEX>'s salts at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min to 5 hours</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>
          cells were treated with the same concentration of DMSO
          without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> dose-response experiments, cells
          were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">37Â°C</NUMEX> with concentrations of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.004 to 20 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>. Cell
          viability after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> treatment was determined using the
          trypan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">blue dye</ENAMEX> exclusion test and was compared to
          viability of untreated control cells.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> assay
          The induction of apoptosis was determined by means of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nick</ENAMEX> end labeling) assay using a kit supplied by Promega
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Cultures of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">A549 cells</ENAMEX> or NHBEs were
          grown on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-well slides and treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> as described
          above, fixed with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 min</TIMEX> at room
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">temperature</ENAMEX>, then examined by fluorescent microscopy.
          Nuclei were counterstained by the addition of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4</ENAMEX>'<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">,6-diamidino-2-phenylindole</NUMEX> dihydrochloride (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAPI</ENAMEX>;
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molecular Probes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>, OR, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) to the mounting
          medium. The percentage of apoptotic cells was determined
          by counting green fluorescent nuclei relative to the
          total number of DAPI-positive nuclei.
        
        
          Reverse-transcriptase PCR
          A549 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> or NHBEs were grown to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 75%</NUMEX>
          confluence in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-well plates, treated with various
          concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.5%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMSO</ENAMEX>, and total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> was
          isolated using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNeasy</ENAMEX> method (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qiagen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valencia</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g</ENAMEX>) was converted to cDNA in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 Î</NUMEX>¼l reaction
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">containing 1 U</ENAMEX> of avian <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">myeloblastosis</ENAMEX> virus reverse
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transcriptase</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Biolabs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dNTP</ENAMEX>'s, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml random hexamer primers in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1Ã—</NUMEX>
          reverse transcriptase buffer at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42Â°C</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 min</TIMEX>; the
          reaction was terminated by heating to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">90Â°C</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> min.
          The resulting cDNA was used as template for PCR
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">amplification</ENAMEX> using the primer pairs (Operon
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technologies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alameda</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) listed in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>. As a
          loading control parallel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX> reactions were carried out
          using a primer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> for human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GAPDH</ENAMEX> (see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). PCR
          bromide-stained bands were digitally photographed using a
          ChemImager <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4400</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpha Inotech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Leandro</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scanned</ENAMEX> using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AphaEase</ENAMEX> version <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.5</NUMEX> densitometry
          program. The experimental values were normalized to the
          corresponding GAPDH value and expressed as relative
          intensity.
        
        
          Western blotting and immunocytochemistry
          A549 <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX> or NHBEs were treated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> as described
          above and whole-cell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein extracts</ENAMEX> were prepared by
          scraping cells into lysis buffer containing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> mM
          Tris-HCl (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDTA</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">orthovanadate</ENAMEX>,
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> mM sodium <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluoride</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1 Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX> each of leupeptin and
          pepstatin, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Î¼M PMSF</ENAMEX>. Cell lysis was achieved by
          sonicating the suspension on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three 10-second</TIMEX>
          bursts at a power setting of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 mW</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonic Dismembrator</ENAMEX>,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisher Scientific Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Lysates were
          clarified by centrifugation at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          g for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4Â°C</TIMEX> and the protein
          concentration of the whole-cell extracts was determined
          by the bicinchoninic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein assay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX> Biochemical
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>). Aliquots of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼g</NUMEX> of protein
          were separated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SDS</ENAMEX>-PAGE and electroblotted to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nitrocellulose</ENAMEX>. The filters were blocked with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nonfat</ENAMEX>
          dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> mM <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tris-HCl</ENAMEX> (pH <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> sodium
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chloride</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2%</NUMEX> Tween-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> (TBST) then incubated with
          primary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1:1000 dilution</ENAMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX> at room
          temperature. After washing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tris</ENAMEX>-buffered saline with
          tween <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> (TBST), blots were incubated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> at
          room temperature with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HRP-conjugated secondary antibody</ENAMEX>,
          washed again and detected by chemiluminescence. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein bands</ENAMEX> were quantified by densitometry as
          described above. For immunocytochemistry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> grown on
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-well chamber slides were exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> at a
          concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.4 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">min. Cells</ENAMEX> were fixed
          with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4%</NUMEX> paraformaldehyde, blocked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX>, immunostained
          using anti-phosphorylated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>, and visualized using
          HRP-conjugated secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> and bisbenzamidine
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">substrate</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Transfection with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB-luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constructs</ENAMEX> and assay for gene expression
          A549 cells were grown to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50-80%</NUMEX> confluence on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-well
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plates</ENAMEX> and transfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> pathway profiling
          system vector, pNFÎºB-TA-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luc</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, CA,
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), using lipofectamine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco/BRL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>)
          and used according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s recommendations.
          Cells were transfected using lipofectamine from Bibco/BRL
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). The plasmid, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">pVAX-LacZ</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alto</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was used as transfection control.
          <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>/lipofectamine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> were allowed to form for
          <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX> at room temperature in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> (without antibiotics)
          containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼g</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmid, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ng of pVAX-LacZ
          for monitoring transfection efficiency, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼g</NUMEX> of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lipofectamine</ENAMEX>. Cells were transfected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> h. Prior to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> challenge, the transfected cells were preincubated
          for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> in minimal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earle</ENAMEX>'s salts
          to remove serum factors. Assays were done in triplicate
          and consisted of untreated controls, treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ng/ml TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± and treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.4 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>. After
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">treatments</ENAMEX>, the cells were lysed by addition of cell
          lysis buffer as supplied in the luciferase assay kit from
          Clontech, scraped from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> and centrifuged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min</ENAMEX> at
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">g. Aliquots</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼l</NUMEX> of each lysate
          were transferred to flat-bottomed, white microtiter
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chantilly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and read on a Dynex
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLX</ENAMEX> plate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> in flash mode. The transfection
          efficiency was normalized by determining Î²-galactosidase
          activity in the lysates from the cotransfected pLacZ
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plasmid</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Analysis</ENAMEX>
          All values are expressed as mean Â± standard error of
          the mean (SEM). Comparisons of experimental values for
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>-treated cells to untreated controls were done by
          analysis of variance (ANOVA). Probability values of <
          <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.05</NUMEX> were considered significant.
        
      
      
        Results
        
          Effects of cigarette smoke condensate on cell
          viability and apoptosis
          To determine the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> on cell viability,
          A549 cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> were exposed to increasing
          concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> min then examined using the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">trypan</ENAMEX> blue dye-exclusion test (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1A). Maximum
          toxicity for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A549</TIMEX> at the highest concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>) was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15%</NUMEX>. At lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> concentrations (<<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.1</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>), survival was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">greater than 90%</NUMEX> for both A549 cells
          and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX>. Induction of apoptosis by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> was determined
          in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> by using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> assay and
          confirmed by DNA fragmentation analysis (data not shown).
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> showed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> apoptosis at moderate doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>;
          A549 <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> showed less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> apoptosis (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 1B).
          However, with increasing concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>, NHBEs
          showed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as high as 20%</NUMEX> apoptosis, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells
          remained unchanged.
        
        
          Changes in expression of specific cytokines and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemokines</ENAMEX> after exposure to cigarette smoke
          condensate
          To characterize the response of epithelial cells to
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> we determined the changes in message levels for a
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of cytokines, chemokines and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>-adhesion
          molecules. Total <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">RNA</ENAMEX> isolated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> following
          exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> was subjected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RT-PCR</ENAMEX>, and the results
          are shown in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX> was induced to a level <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9.5</NUMEX>
          times that of untreated controls, while the expression of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM-CSF</ENAMEX> was increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.7</NUMEX>-fold and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>-fold,
          respectively. Expression of the adhesion molecule ICAM-1
          was found to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 1.6</NUMEX> times the level of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-6</ENAMEX> and the chemokine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RANTES</ENAMEX> were elevated
          slightly (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). This pattern of enhancement of
          proinflammatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> expression implies that specific
          effector compounds are present in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>.
        
        
          Involvement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> pathway in response to
          cigarette smoke condensate
          To examine if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>-upregulation of cytokine production
          involves activation of MAPKs we examined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>-treated
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> for specific phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3Ashows
          the results of a western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blot</ENAMEX> of whole-cell extracts from
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> exposed to increasing concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> and
          probed for phosphorylated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>, the activated form of
          ERK1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>. Band densities on the film were measured and the
          protein loading variations were adjusted by normalizing
          to the levels of non-phosphorylated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>. The level of
          ERK1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX> phosphorylation increased rapidly with increasing
          exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>, to a maximum of nearly twice the
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. To confirm the results of immunoblot detection
          of phosphorylated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> were exposed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX> Î<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">¼g/ml</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 min</TIMEX>, then fixed and stained for phosphorylated
          ERK1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>. Exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> caused a marked increase in
          nuclear staining of cells with phosphorylated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibodies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fig 3B</ENAMEX>). This nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">localization</ENAMEX> and
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphorylated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ERK1/2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">staining</ENAMEX> was largely blocked by
          pretreating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MEK</ENAMEX> inhibitor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PD98059</TIMEX>. The
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>-induced increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX> expression was also reduced
          by treatment of the cells with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">PD98059</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB
          inhibitor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDTC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 3C). These results suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activates</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> in these cells within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX> min.
        
        
          Cigarette smoke condensate treatment induces rapid
          activation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB pathway
          To determine whether upregulation of cytokine
          production by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> involved activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB, we
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">examined CSC</ENAMEX>-treated epithelial cells for phosphorylation
          of the inhibitor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎºB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎºB</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> were treated with
          increasing concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> and whole-cell extracts
          were immunoblotted for phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎºB.</ENAMEX> Activation of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB involves the increased phosphorylation and
          proteolytic degradation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎºB.</ENAMEX> Treatment of cells with
          increasing concentrations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> resulted in an initial
          rise in phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎ</ENAMEX>ºB levels followed by a decrease
          (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4A). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Protein bands</ENAMEX> were quantitated by densitometry
          on the film and the phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎ</ENAMEX>ºB densities were
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">normalized</ENAMEX> to the levels of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎºB.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>
          also showed an increase in nuclear staining of
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phosphorylated IÎ</ENAMEX>ºB as detected by immunocytochemical
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">staining</ENAMEX> using an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> to phosphorylated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎºB</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>.
          4B).
        
        
          Effect of cigarette smoke condensate on
          transcriptional activation of luciferase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
          construct
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> appears to activate NFÎºB, which should result in
          transcriptional activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB-inducible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>.
          Therefore, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A549</NUMEX> cells were transfected with a luciferase
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmid containing a promoter sequence that
          <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bound NFÎºB</ENAMEX> and luciferase activity was measured after
          challenge with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>. Treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.4 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
          min resulted in significant enhancement of luciferase
          reporter expression compared to control (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4C),
          indicating activation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎºB.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± used as a positive
          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> also activated luciferase gene expression with
          the same plasmid system. Exposure of cells transfected
          with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmid to increasing doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>
          showed NFÎºB expression peaking at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> concentration
          <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4 Î¼g/</ENAMEX>ml (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. 4D).
        
      
      
        Discussion
        The complex changes in lung function, morphology, and
        gene expression caused by compounds in cigarette smoke
        involve a combination of direct and indirect effects on
        cells, but principally center around an increase in airway
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inflammation</ENAMEX> as a result of cigarette smoking. The results
        of our studies demonstrate that the mechanism underlying
        these acute inflammatory events involves activation of
        specific signaling pathways such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the important observations of this study is the
        effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX>. Even at a concentration of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.4</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Î¼g/ml</ENAMEX>, which does not induce significant changes in the
        viability of these cells, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> induced increases in
        expression of several cytokines at the mRNA level. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">IL-1Î²,</ENAMEX>
        which was significantly upregulated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>
        exposure, has been shown to be important for activation of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX> ] and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ICAM-1</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX> ] . This is also consistent with
        the report that epithelial cells regulate inflammatory
        events by secreting cytokines and chemokines such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IL-8</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM-CSF</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î±, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sICAM-1</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX> ] . These paracrine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">effectors</ENAMEX> can then produce further primary local
        inflammation or amplify the effects of previously activated
        macrophages, eosinophils, mast cells, or lymphocytes. A
        notable finding from our study is that exposure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> elicits the synthesis and release of a pattern of
        mediators similar to that seen in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">A549</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX> in response to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>. These results imply that neoplastic cells and normal
        cells respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> in a similar manner.
        Cigarette smoke has been shown by others to induce a
        synthesis of glutathione and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gamma-glutamylcysteine</ENAMEX> that
        was associated with transcription factor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-1 or an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-like response element [ <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX> ] . Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPKs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB
        have been implicated in the upregulation of proinflammatory
        cytokines, the role of these pathways in normal human
        pulmonary epithelial cells in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> has not been
        investigated. The results of our study implicate the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX>
        (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">p42/44</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> pathway as a key element in this inflammatory
        response, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> that has not heretofore been
        reported in normal human pulmonary epithelial cells. A
        significant finding of this study is that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAPKs</ENAMEX> such as
        ERK1<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p44/p42</ENAMEX>) are consistently activated in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX>.
        However, upon exposure to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>, the magnitude of
        phosphorylation increases. The finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL-1Î²</ENAMEX>
        expression and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> activation are concomitantly increased
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> exposure and inhibited by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">PD98059</TIMEX> is consistent with
        the report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPKs</ENAMEX> activate expression of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IL-1Î² genes</ENAMEX> [
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> ] . Although the control of cytok-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> confluence on
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-well plates and transfected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> pathway
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profiling</ENAMEX> system vector, pNFÎºB-TA-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luc</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>,
        CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>), using lipofectamine (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibco/BRL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and used according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s
        recommendations. Cells were transfected using lipofectamine
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bibco/BRL</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX>). The plasmid, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">pVAX-LacZ</ENAMEX>,
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clontech</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, CA, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) was used as transfection
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>/lipofectamine <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexes</ENAMEX> were allowed to form for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">min</ENAMEX> at room temperature in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPMI</ENAMEX> (without antibiotics)
        containing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1 Î¼g</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> plasmid, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ng of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">pVAX-LacZ</ENAMEX> for
        monitoring transfection efficiency, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 Î¼g</NUMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lipofectamine</ENAMEX>. Cells were transfected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> h. Prior to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> challenge, the transfected cells were preincubated for
        <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 hours</TIMEX> in minimal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s medium with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earle</ENAMEX>'s salts to
        remove serum factors. Assays were done in triplicate and
        consisted of untreated controls, treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ng</ENAMEX>/ml
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNF</ENAMEX>-Î± and treatment with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.4 Î</NUMEX>¼g/ml <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX>. After treatments,
        the cells were lysed by addition of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> lysis buffer as
        supplied in the luciferase assay kit from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clontech</ENAMEX>, scraped
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wells</ENAMEX> and centrifuged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">min</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12,000</NUMEX> Ã— 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">g. Aliquots</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20 Î¼l</NUMEX> of each lysate
        were transferred to flat-bottomed, white microtiter plates
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynex</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chantilly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>) and read on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynex MLX</ENAMEX> plate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> in flash mode. The transfection efficiency was
        normalized by determining Î²-galactosidase activity in the
        lysates from the cotransfected pLacZ plasmid.
      
      
        Conclusion
        In essence, these results demonstrate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBEs</ENAMEX> respond
        to moderate doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> by activating both the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ERK1/2</NUMEX> and
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB pathways, and by upregulating the expression of
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> encoding proinflammatory molecules.
      
      
        Abbreviations
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSA</ENAMEX> = Bovine serum albumin; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSC</ENAMEX> = cigarette smoke
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condensate; ERK</ENAMEX> = extracellular signal-regulated kinase;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBE</ENAMEX> = human bronchial epithelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interleukin</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IÎºB</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhibitor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎºB; MAPK</ENAMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">mitogen</NUMEX>-activated protein
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kinase</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MEK-1</ENAMEX> = <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAPK</ENAMEX> kinase; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFÎ</ENAMEX>ºB = nuclear factor-kappa B;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NHBE</ENAMEX> = normal human bronchial epithelial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> =
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phosphate</ENAMEX>-buffered saline; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDTC</ENAMEX> = pyrrolidine
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dithiocarbamate; RT-PCR</ENAMEX> = reverse transcriptase-polymerase
        chain reaction; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sICAM</ENAMEX> = soluble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">intercellular</ENAMEX> adhesion
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">molecule; TNF</ENAMEX> = tumour necrosis factor; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TUNEL</ENAMEX> =
        labeling
      
    
  
