
   
   
      
         
            

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

             

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 2</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taste Makers":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Fill in
the blank: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy Shutt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of marketing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>, told a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, "By sheer bulk, the _______________ are driving
cultural tastes now. They're amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>."
            

             

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday/Friday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 1</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monstrous Evil":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Despite the incitement
of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation Rescue</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Terry</ENAMEX> to fight "this monstrous evil,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> continues to do something. What?
            

            "Crush the small,
independent, mom-and-pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> pornographers with lower prices, endless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unlimited</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">browsing</ENAMEX>, and exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coffees</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            "Put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terry's</ENAMEX> memoirs in
the humor section."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Marx</ENAMEX>
            

            "Heavily promote the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">collected Edmund Wilson-Paula Barbieri</ENAMEX> letters."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Wolitzer</ENAMEX>
            

            "Continue to give a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20-percent</NUMEX> discount on hardback books to unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "Hold nude poetry readings
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Germaine Greer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Friedan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Baird</ENAMEX> (the abortion-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>,
not the famed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">puppeteer</ENAMEX>--who, by the way, has currently found work moving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette Funicello</ENAMEX>'s mouth)."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amaros</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>
continues to provide money to fund <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 st</NUMEX> -trimester abortions for women
accidentally impregnated while waiting in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> long line to pay for their
books."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sell Martha Stewart</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do-It-Yourself Guide to Festive Abortions at Home</ENAMEX> , along with its
companion video."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Franklin</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>
continues to permit browsing, instead of forcing its tightwad,
cappuccino-swilling, pick-up-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX> to BUY the books they have pawed
through."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M.G.</ENAMEX> Lord
            

            "Sell unauthorized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Resident Evil 2 'Walk-Throughs</ENAMEX>.' "-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Franzen</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up:
            

            Your
blazing hostility toward the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> is delightful. I've felt your pain ever
since our locally owned and operated notions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> fell to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolworth</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juggernaut</ENAMEX>. (We called them "notions." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> used an uglier word.) And
your anti-coffee sentiment does you credit. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> were a
serious literary bookstore, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> could get himself a drink. Maybe over near
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Self-Help</ENAMEX> section. Which is where I'll be if you need me.

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monstrous Evil" Literal Answer:</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX> fulminated against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX>'s selling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> art books containing photographs of nude
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Radiant Identities by Jock Sturges and The Age of</ENAMEX>
Innocence by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hamilton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> take credit for getting
pornography indictments against the bookseller in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>. Since
then, sales of both books have increased. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sturges</ENAMEX> book is sold out at most
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan Barnes & Nobles</ENAMEX>; some copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX> are still
available.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
