
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gamble</ENAMEX>

            Ever since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> ran
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> have puzzled over his penchant for self-destruction.
Yes, he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comeback Kid</ENAMEX>, but only because he keeps getting himself into
trouble from which he must come back. When things are going well, he finds a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to mess them up. You know the old joke: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s approval ratings are so
high he's going to start dating again."

            One
reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can make these recoveries is that he has no monopoly on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-destruction</ENAMEX>. When he's down, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> are up--and pretty soon,
they're the ones who feel ready to "start dating again." Now that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is in the deepest trouble of his presidency, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
think they're on top of the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> has spurned
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entreaties</ENAMEX> to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a plea bargain short of impeachment. On
with the hearings, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>.

            The smartest course for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would
be to bend over backward to show mercy, restraint, and fairness to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would be impressed by their nonpartisanship, grateful to be
spared further lurid disclosures, and increasingly open to voting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> in
future elections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would remain a cripple for the rest of his
presidency.

            Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
forging ahead with impeachment. The charitable explanation is that they're
thinking short-term, hoping to energize their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> and win extra congressional
seats in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> elections. The less charitable explanation is that
they're just as hot to nail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as he was to nail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. In the
long term, this pursuit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will backfire for several reasons.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
investigation is out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammo</ENAMEX>. On that subject, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> took his best punch in the report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has absorbed
the worst information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior, yet he's still standing. It's
hard to see what further information about the affair would bring him down.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The public's anger
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> can't last. It is already dissipating with the passage of time
and the venting of outrage by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> on
television, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in everyday conversation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> will always be
somewhat angry at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But like heat, anger inevitably diffuses and loses
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Anger at sexual
disclosures is growing. Post-video polls showing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> point surge
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s job approval rating are a signal that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> increasingly resent
the pursuit of sexual details about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair. Even people
who deplore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior are getting sick of seeing it rehashed on
television.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Anger at the
impeachment process will grow. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> may not care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but they
care even less for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who set aside the public's business in order to
focus on themselves. Now that the public has heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s information and has
vented its disgust, the congressional impeachment inquiry is being reduced to
an inside game. The more it consumes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' attention and the nastier it
gets, the angrier the public will become. And the party most likely to be
blamed is the one that controls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">talker</ENAMEX>. He has yet to lose a talking match with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. From a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">standpoint</ENAMEX>, the beauty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> investigation is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
finally been forced to shut up, since nobody wanted to hear anything from him
but apologies. But now that he has apologized and taken a beating, he is
gradually recovering the right to open his mouth again. The effect of his
videotaped testimony on public opinion shows what he can do. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
drag out the impeachment process and summon him for a verbal spanking before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, they might well be in for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ollie North</ENAMEX> (for a reminder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">North</ENAMEX>'s
stellar performance before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, click here).

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> base
will awaken. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> strategy for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> has been to let
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> sleep through the election, allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> base to
turn out and unseat vulnerable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officeholders</ENAMEX>. So far, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
scandal has smothered issues, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, that might have drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to
the polls. But if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> push the impeachment inquiry to the point of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antagonizing</ENAMEX> and mobilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s low-turnout strategy
will be ruined.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will be
investigated. He already faces a court fight over whether he has unlawfully
leaked grand jury information to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. Now that the background material he
sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has been released, the press has become interested in whether
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> doctored her tapes and whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
improperly detained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> or misrepresented their treatment of her in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 16</TIMEX> sting. The wise course for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> might be to accept a plea
bargain under which neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s will be further
investigated with regard to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> will turn
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s debauchery and deceit have
consumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' attention. To the extent the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have held their
fire, they have left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> alone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> to absorb the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s scrutiny,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mockery</ENAMEX>, and incredulity. By charging into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
offering the press an alternative political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>. This is particularly unwise
because after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of raking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are inclined to
demonstrate their "balance" by going after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>)
Should further revelations warrant impeachment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may have lost the
necessary credibility. Polls show most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't willing to impeach
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair, but they do think he's been exposed as a liar
and cover-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has yet to deliver his report on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX>,
Filegate, and other nonsexual scandals, which no doubt will accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of
lying and covering up those matters as well. That report could deliver a
knockout blow to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> won't be able to impeach him if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> has squandered its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> by overplaying an arguably
lesser scandal that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think boils down to lying about sex.

            Every
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walk into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> and rack up big winnings. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> stay in business because few of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have the prudence to walk
out while they're ahead. Instead, they keep playing until they've lost
everything. It's human nature. That's how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> squandered his
presidency. And that's how his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> will save him.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Unjust War</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
moral theory, point by point, as expressed in his testimony. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 21, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            Video <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Game</ENAMEX>: Was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
decision to air the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tapes a gross miscalculation? (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
