
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basic Instincts</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>'s tabs are filled
with news of an elemental nature, examining the desires of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marry</ENAMEX>, divorce, procreate, and swoop, godlike, into the lives of others,
changing them forever.

            The
recent big life events are the marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brolin</ENAMEX>
and the impending divorce of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demi Moore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX>. Because of their
deadlines, the supermarket tabs were unable to reveal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> if they managed
to breach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streisand</ENAMEX>'s perimeter of security. But the rest of the gossip media
did their best to glean details of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding</TIMEX> when they weren't being driven
mad by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streisand</ENAMEX> loudspeakers blaring music from the same heavy metal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>,
White <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zombie</ENAMEX>, once used by the military to drive former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panamanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel Noriega</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily</ENAMEX>
News .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streisand</ENAMEX>--a well-known, um,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perfectionist</ENAMEX>--almost delayed the much-rescheduled wedding because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caterer</ENAMEX>
delivered <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Pellegrino</ENAMEX> water instead of the requested <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Perrier</ENAMEX>. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brolin</ENAMEX>, pitchman for AAMCO
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Transmissions</ENAMEX>, has been badgering the reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> to go to the altar. For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three decades</TIMEX>, ever since the collapse of her marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elliott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> says, the idea of remarriage has given her cold feet.
But before this condition caused her to resemble one of those ancient, frozen
corpses that occasionally turns up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brolin</ENAMEX> melted her. He was so
overcome during the ceremony, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> , that he blubbered;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streisand</ENAMEX> remained dry-eyed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> did not report if this had
anything to do with the terms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s prenuptial agreement.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX> back
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, when they got married, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> was a mere TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demi Moore</ENAMEX>
was just one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hollywood Brat Pack</ENAMEX>, and neither was
thinking about a prenuptial, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . That's why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> is
salivating over the prospect of just how these now-full-fledged movie stars
will divide their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 million</NUMEX> fortune, which consists of everything from real
estate to an interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> to a doll collection
that numbers in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> supermarket tabs agree the reason for
the split was the basic one: the wandering eye. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> both place the bulk of the blame on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>. "I can't go on with
this charade," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> sobbed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in vintage tabloid-speak, according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> links <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> with everyone from his young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armageddon</ENAMEX> co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX> to a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> Tropic swimsuit
models. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, who once played a liposuctioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hester Prynne</ENAMEX>, is not
portrayed only as the wronged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> brings up her
"flirtations" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> and yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affleck</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>
hired a private eye to detail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>' activities, which included, it says, both
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriends</ENAMEX> and a penchant for hanging out at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip clubs</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> agreed to split after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> première, but then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moore</ENAMEX>
found out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> had "installed a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> in a love <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX>." So she made
a secret plan to announce the end of the marriage before the première. During a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s Day brunch at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramada Inn</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Farmington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M.</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had
gone to be with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> with the news, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> alleges. After the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> had a shouting match, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>
stormed out and installed himself in the Best Western motel across the
street.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , in a
contrarian mood, blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>. It reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>' latest philandering was
retaliation for her "dates" with, who else?, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>. In the tabloid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world DiCaprio</ENAMEX> is becoming the equivalent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Norse god Loki</ENAMEX>, a handsome,
mischievous shape-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shifter</ENAMEX> who leaves chaos in his wake.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore-Willis</ENAMEX> split is not the only uncoupling of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX>
supermarket tabs report the end of the marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitney Houston</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Brown</ENAMEX>, a decision the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> says was cemented by his latest
arrest, this time for allegedly having touched a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> against her will. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> says the usually forgiving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> is unmoved by his plight, but
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX> say she is concerned that sexy
videotapes they made to spice up their marriage may end up spicing up the
Internet. And aging bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Busey</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>, is getting divorced from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tiani</ENAMEX>, his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two years</TIMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . Although she
saw him through sinus <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overdose</ENAMEX>, she tells "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>" his
abusive behavior landed her in rehab. "Being Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Busey</ENAMEX> is hell," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> says she told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> also reports that the
other Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Busey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, is shrugging off his latest troubles.
"Unless he's laying bleeding in the street [a sometime occurrence with him], I
don't allow myself to get too involved," she's quoted as saying.

            Despite the frequency with which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> love dies,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">celebrities</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> are obsessed with having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, although in some cases
it's unclear whether the process or the outcome is the chief motivation.
Lustful newlyweds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Examiner</ENAMEX>
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Bronstein</ENAMEX> continue to go at it. "We just have sex
constantly," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> quotes her as saying. But it's all for a
higher purpose: "That old biological clock is really racing away," she
says.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reproduction</ENAMEX> is also the reason newly coupled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX>
can't keep their hands off each other, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . The star
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> allegedly confided to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>: "Every time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX> and I sleep
together I hope I'll conceive. I'm totally serious. I want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX>." But,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , other desires may be at work here. The
publication reports that after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> snuggled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, rock concert, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX> desperately--but unsuccessfully--canvassed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> for a condom. For the record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aniston's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> says the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are
"not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>."

            
And recent <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Hunt</ENAMEX> is
determined to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> with or without her fiance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Azaria</ENAMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . "I'm going all-out to get pregnant," the
publication reports her confiding to a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX>," although it doesn't explain what
she plans to do if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azaria</ENAMEX> refuses to cooperate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azaria</ENAMEX>'s reluctance to marry
stems from the fact that her earnings dwarf his--she is making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.25 million</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> to star in the sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad About You</ENAMEX> . Perhaps, once he gets back
from his honeymoon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brolin</ENAMEX> could do a little counseling.

            Not all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> are having such a hard time being fruitful. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> has
a photo display of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Randall</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>; their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-month-old</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>; and their newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> picture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX> is flat on his back,
with the infant next to him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">toddler</ENAMEX> on his chest. Unfortunately, it
looks as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is performing CPR on her aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX> tells the
Enquirer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson</ENAMEX>, is named after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Jefferson</ENAMEX> but does not say if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall</ENAMEX> actually attended any
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s performances.

            Finally, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s tabs seem to give an implicit warning
that too close contact with a celebrity can have unintended consequences for
the not famous. Take the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Sawyer</ENAMEX> and the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she began
tutoring in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX> became a sort of
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, whose own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were recovering drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> with
no steady employment. The newswoman helped arrange a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and
psychiatric care for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. She gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> clothes and gifts and took
her to her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">estate</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> pony rides, according to the
Star . "How was I supposed to compete with that?" it quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> as
asking. Then, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was in the hospital giving
birth to her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to ask if groceries
could be delivered. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , however, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> were at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> then
called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York's Administration</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Services</ENAMEX> to report the
situation. Thinking they were about the find themselves part of a PrimeTime
Live <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">exposé</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> swooped in and placed
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in foster care. In a statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sawyer</ENAMEX> said she "played no
role in this decision."

            The soon to be ex-husband of
a makeup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX> also says he couldn't compete with the trips
and gifts the generous talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> lavished on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . "Any time I tried to talk to her, she would cut me short and say
she was being elevated to a higher level," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says. Although he tries
to imply a romance between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> doesn't believe
him. They report the makeup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> took another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion-dollar</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>-hosted cruise.

            And according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , being famous is better than being young. At least, that is the
lesson <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Brooks</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, says she learned when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Hershey</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>, set her sights on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>' fiance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Lowe</ENAMEX>, also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> working on a film and, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>, "[s]wept into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> with her big-time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> ways, saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>--and decided 'that's for me!'
It didn't matter that she was old enough to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> is barely acquainted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX>,
who moved out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> she shared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowe</ENAMEX>, says of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX>, "I just
wish she'd go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and pick on somebody her own age!"

         
      
   
