
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Specter Wins the Slate Hackathlon</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have voted, the
ballots have been counted, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> have crowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Specter</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of the first

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackathlon</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 1,400</NUMEX> votes were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
events. Here's the final breakdown, by percentages:

             

            We contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX> to
offer our congratulations and ask how he feels about winning the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackathlon</ENAMEX>. "I'm far too overwhelmed with emotion to rely on mere words," he
e-mailed back. "Also, I can't really write anything anymore unless you give me
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> and a cheat sheet."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX> has a reputation for
being a sore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> that he bolstered during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackathlon</ENAMEX>. Although he led
the contest from the beginning, he obviously took no joy in his success.
Instead, he repeatedly accused his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hack protégé</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Gladwell</ENAMEX>, of cheating
by writing parody, which was prohibited under the rules, and filled the
Hackathlon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX>'s e-mail box with his whining.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX>
will return <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX> to defend his title against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX>.

             


            Who's the fairest hack in
all of journalism? With your help, we hope to settle that question with the
first 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackathlon</ENAMEX>.

            We've invited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite hacks</ENAMEX> to compete in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weekly</TIMEX> journalistic events designed to
showcase journalistic glibness, intellectual sleight of hand, greed under
pressure, and a total disregard for what the rest of the world thinks.
Actually, our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contestants</ENAMEX> have already demonstrated their disdain for what
others might think by accepting the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hackathlon</ENAMEX> challenge.

            Our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hackathletes</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Gladwell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanna Rosin</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Specter</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Wheatcroft</ENAMEX> , author of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Randlords</ENAMEX> and a contributor to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> too numerous to
mention. (For more on the hack ethic, click to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladwell</ENAMEX>'s exegesis.)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> events are:
an op-ed in the style of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> words or thereabouts);
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the Town</ENAMEX>" piece (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> words or thereabouts); the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> words of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> profile; and a breaking news story
(<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX> words or thereabouts).

            The subject of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hackwork</ENAMEX> will remain a mystery to all until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> of the competition,
when 
                  Slate
                will e-mail the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackathletes</ENAMEX> the assignment and a
cheat sheet of facts, figures, and quotes from which they can crib. The cheat
sheet will be posted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' inspection. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hackathletes</ENAMEX> may not make up
quotations (sorry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>). They may take no <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than two hours</TIMEX> to complete the
assignment. They may, if they so desire, do additional research. But they
shouldn't. As a great hack once said, the essence of hackery is "adjusting a
minimum of information to produce the maximum journalistic effect." (The only
editing 
                  Slate
                has done to the pieces is a quick spell check.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of the Hackathlon
will be determined by an online vote of 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX>
may vote once in each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> events. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hackathlete</ENAMEX> who polls the
greatest total will be declared the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> and will return <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to face
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX>.

            To vote you must be a
registered 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>. If you've never registered, we suggest
you do so now by clicking here. But you can always register later.

            Hackathletes, to your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX>!

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

             

         
      
   
