
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pickup Artists</ENAMEX>

            Sometimes
when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> first meet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> speaks words so true, so stirring,
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is helpless to resist. See if you can identify the world-class
smooth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> who spoke these opening lines:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) "I could
get lost in those blue eyes."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "You've
got eyes like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>'--they're so big." [If this fails, follow with:]
"Your eyes haunt me."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) "You're
really beautiful, you know that? ... Call me, it'll be fun."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) "You're as pretty as my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>."

            Sure, you
were tempted to guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> for all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, but the answers are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX> the tabs explore the sexual gambits of famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Chief among them is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> breaks news
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> with an account by a flight attendant on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> campaign
plane of an alleged sexual assault by him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was called Longhorn
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had to settle for this name; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Long Dong Silver</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monkey Business</ENAMEX> were already taken) and is described by the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lust-crazed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> has
figured prominently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> universe in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enquirer</ENAMEX> quotes an "insider" as saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> had his own
'Mile-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Club</ENAMEX>' up in the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> last week
ran pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> with, and with his hand on the leg of,
flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Schiff</ENAMEX>, who later went on to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receptionist</ENAMEX>.

            But it is
the account of flight attendant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cristy Zercher</ENAMEX> that fleshes out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
seduction style. His opening comment to her was Answer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, above. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zercher</ENAMEX>
claims that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late one night</TIMEX>, while almost everyone was sleeping--including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, who was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about six feet</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zercher</ENAMEX>'s jump seat--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> came over to
talk. He laid his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zercher</ENAMEX>'s shoulder, asked her to talk about herself
and, for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 minutes</TIMEX>, on and off, rubbed the side of her left breast. "I
thought, 'Is he really doing what I think he's doing?' " she recalls. While
feeling her breast, he also wanted to feel her pain. When she mentioned she was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorced</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> began asking repeatedly of the marriage, "Was the sex at
least good?"

            
On another occasion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zercher</ENAMEX> says, she pushed
open an unlocked lavatory door to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> standing there, unzipped. She
says he said to her, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, why don't you come in and shut the door?" Then
there was the time he saw the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX> reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>'
interview in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zercher</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> kept asking them what the
best part was. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiff</ENAMEX> finally said that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX>' comment that he was
good at giving oral sex. "That's pretty accurate," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zercher</ENAMEX> recalls him saying.
"It's one of my favorite things."

            He also
told them that one thing he was afraid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> uncovering was a story
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a couple</NUMEX> who were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of his. They were getting divorced because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> found the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> cheating on her with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">barnyard animals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zercher</ENAMEX> recalls
her reaction: "My God, can you imagine if he becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> that we were
sitting here talking about farm <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>--and he's the one that brought it
up."

            Finally, there's the orange incident. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> got a fruit
basket that contained an orange that was, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zercher</ENAMEX>'s words, "shrivelled and
deformed--it looked like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s sexual organ." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> brought it to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">galley</ENAMEX> to show the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. He said: "I'm going to keep this. This is
so great because I haven't been getting any of this lately." He carried it
around and flashed it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zercher</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two weeks</TIMEX>, until someone finally
had to take the deformed orange away from the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the free
world.

            This isn't the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zercher</ENAMEX>'s name has surfaced. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> story she says
that after being contacted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>, who wanted to know
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> events on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, she relayed news of the phone call to Debra
Schiff, who, in turn, relayed it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zercher</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> called her and urged her to say "all positive things" about her
experiences. It's become a pattern in reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sexual advances that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in question confirm the advance but often say it wasn't
unwelcome. Sure enough, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zercher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zercher</ENAMEX>, who is now an executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, told her several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> groped her and grabbed her breasts. But instead of
finding his behavior "humiliating," as she now tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> was the
case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> says she laughed it off.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiff</ENAMEX> has
also appeared recently in the tabs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> has an account from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s former chief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">steward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McGrath</ENAMEX>--who has testified
before the grand jury investigating the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> scandal--about the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schiff</ENAMEX> locked him in the pantry off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> and
reportedly said, "We don't want to be disturbed for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>." He said he
heard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schiff</ENAMEX> go into the study, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> later,
she let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrath</ENAMEX> out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schiff</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> the story was "absolutely not
true." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrath</ENAMEX> also solves the mystery of the account of the stained Kleenex
reportedly found by another steward, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bayani Nelvis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrath</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelvis</ENAMEX> told
him he saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> emerge from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s study looking "shaky"
and "in shock" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1995</TIMEX>. Like some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who reportedly emerge
from the study, her hair was mussed and her clothes askew. After she left,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelvis</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGrath</ENAMEX>, he went into the study, where he found towels smeared with
lipstick on the floor.

            
In the world of the tabloids, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
exploits are just an appetizer for someone whose sex life they really care
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiCaprio</ENAMEX>, who has obviously chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a role
model and who, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 23</NUMEX>, has a good chance of surpassing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
accomplishments. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , after he sorrowfully bid adieu
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> to his latest love, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alanis Morissette</ENAMEX>, he began chatting
up a blonde waiting to get on the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. He has been on a "date-a-day
spree" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> has
gone out with a string of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> and actresses, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire</ENAMEX>
Danes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliette Lewis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Moss</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> says he is no snob and that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX> doesn't have to be famous to merit his advances. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX>'s motto is, 'So
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, so little time.' " In this, too, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> is like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's story on the depositions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX> who acted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguards</ENAMEX> says of his liaisons, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ome</ENAMEX> [were]
on-going affairs, others just stands of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX>. The women
named included <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> of major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, beauty
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">queens</ENAMEX>, barflies, and even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> probably never anticipated their contribution to priapism but,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> is also an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of airborne sex. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , he hired a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>. He "served her champagne with
fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">strawberries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>, and they made love while looking at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> does not mention if any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX> were involved.

            And both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have found themselves in a
few cock-ups over their sexual escapades. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports
that while in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> ran into model <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Campbell</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> swam
naked at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> became outraged when she found out
DiCaprio was simultaneously dating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an 18-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> model. Later, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> were seen together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, although the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> who says the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are just
"good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>."

            There is
yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> love triangle, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> was smitten with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
Berkley, but in a strange Cyrano-like move, he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> conduct a phone
romance for him. During one phone call, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> picked up the
receiver and became furious. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> to meet him
in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX> were staying. A
brawl ensued, although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> emerged from the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> only after the
fight, to smoke a cigarette. As for the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eye</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> is now sporting, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> was accidentally hit by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s room door
at another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>.

            
All these high jinks have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
worried that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> could end up with the same medical condition for which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is receiving treatment. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has secretly
begun therapy for sexual addiction in a bid to save his presidency," the
publication reports.) According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> is still only a
sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX> in training. To avoid this fate, a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX>" warns, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> "needs to
settle down and find out what real love is all about."

            No one is worrying about the
fate of talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> labels his lines as
"dumb and dumber" in an account of how he tried to pick up a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
lovely" with an offer to fly her to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and give her tickets to his show.
"I burst out laughing--he just looked so desperate," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> says. Springer
does have one thing in common with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: He likes to use <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> to
approach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>,
would spot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> while he was speaking. According to one
trooper, he would then say: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in the red dress, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in the green
dress ... would you go get me her name and phone number? She has that
come-hither look." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springer</ENAMEX>'s approach is similar, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. "He
peeks at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> before the show to pick out pretty girls, then sends crew
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to get their phone numbers," says an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>.

            Perhaps no one's opening
line is lamer than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX>'s. "You're as pretty as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>" was his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pathetic</ENAMEX>, yet successful, approach with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzen Johnson</ENAMEX>, the former flight
attendant with whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> taped him having sex. (Perhaps the lesson
here is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> with sex problems should take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX>.) But now the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports there's hope for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who stray in even the most public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. After being wooed back for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and talk show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hostess Kathie Lee</ENAMEX> has told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, she forgives him. "At first I thought I'd
die. But now I've come to love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> more than ever," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX> told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> . "And I know our love will last
forever!"

         
      
   
