
   
   
      
         
            This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time It's for Real</ENAMEX>

            Every time something really
bad happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> seem to lose their innocence all over again. So too are
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>, ever hopeful about the promise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> love, constantly made
cynical by its failure. But who wouldn't be moved by the stirring vows famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> incessantly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>? Take this account in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wedding of Frasier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsey Grammer</ENAMEX>--his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. "Wildman Kelsey
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammer</ENAMEX> made a touching vow of eternal love to his [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pinup</ENAMEX>] bride
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camille Donatacci</ENAMEX> at a tender wedding filled with romance and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX>--that cost
a whopping <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450,000</NUMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Talk-show</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> beautiful weddings to infomercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwick</ENAMEX>--one in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> bed, while awaiting heart surgery, and one
post-angioplasty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> ,
so sure is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> that he has found "the love of his life" with his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
that he ignored the advice of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and his financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> to get a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prenuptial</ENAMEX> agreement. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> takes us inside former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girl Rue McLanahan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fairytale Wedding</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Hubby #6</NUMEX>." She says, "We both feel
that we've met the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soulmates</ENAMEX> that we've been searching for." Then there was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny Rogers</ENAMEX>' moving promise to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifth bride</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>'s
reported to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> : "I'm going to make this work no matter what!"
Of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>' waltzing with his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>-years-younger new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> told the
publication, "It looked like a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father-Daughter Day Dance</ENAMEX> at a high school." And
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Jaclyn Smith</ENAMEX> shed tears of joy at her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> wedding,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , promising all her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>, "This one is
forever."

            Though the tabs are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> for love, occasionally even they
find a wedding not touching but tawdry. That is how the marriage between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soon-Yi Previn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mia Farrow</ENAMEX>, was
portrayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> calls the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding</TIMEX>, which makes him Farrow's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son-in-law</ENAMEX>, a "wonderful thing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrow</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Herman</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child psychiatrist</ENAMEX>, is quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> as denouncing it: "rude,
nasty and most of all, it's a reflection of his own narcissism."

            Sometimes,
the tabs report, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding day</TIMEX> leads right to the divorce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s payday.
According to an account in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Lawrence</ENAMEX>'s
marriage to a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> cheerleader "began to deteriorate soon
after her fairy-tale wedding." For his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stacie</ENAMEX>, it ended when he beat her
up following a concert--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> charged him with battery. It legally
began to unravel when he had her served with divorce papers while she was
returning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CAT</ENAMEX> scan to assess her injuries. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Givens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX>'s ex, her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding day</TIMEX> actually was the only day of her
marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Svetozar Marinkovic</ENAMEX>, according to last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . At a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> after the ceremony she reportedly announced,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Svetozar</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of my dreams and I plan to spend the rest of my life with
him." Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Givens</ENAMEX> did not pass away during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>, her prediction was not
to be. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> says that in her divorce papers, she revealed the
couple separated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> they married.

            
This unwritten rule also emerges from the tabs:
The more elaborate the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">wedding</TIMEX>, the greater the trouble ahead. Take the saga of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geena Davis</ENAMEX> and her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renny Harlin</ENAMEX>. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their wedding</TIMEX> was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> extravaganza. As a wedding
present, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> had the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renny</ENAMEX>" and a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cupid</ENAMEX> tattooed on her leg.
However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reveals there's only a patch of very white
skin where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cupid</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Renny</ENAMEX>" used to be. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renny</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s biggest playboy while he was married to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geena</ENAMEX>." That assessment was borne out when, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reveals, it turns
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany Bowne</ENAMEX>, returned to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> not for some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R&R</ENAMEX> but to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. This only proves
another unwritten rule: Never, ever hire a personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiffany</ENAMEX>.

            Kelsey
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammer</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> are still together after their lavish wedding (the pastry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chef</ENAMEX> was flown in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> ), but all the tabloids
have taken to chronicling their bumpy road to bliss. While exchanging vows,
Grammer was so overcome that he burst into tears. "Excuse me, I'm so happy!" he
said, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . However, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
alleges, he was calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, asking, "What have I done?" after both he and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> took turns storming out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bel</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Hotel</ENAMEX>. They made
up in time to leave for their <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> honeymoon, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> says. But
there was another jolt, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , when he opened her wedding
gift to him: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stairmaster</ENAMEX>. "You're fat and I hate fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>," she told him.
Recently, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammer</ENAMEX> has been lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frasier</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> to give his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> a part on the show because she's so bored while he's
at work. Let's hope she doesn't decide to get a tattoo.

            Then there are the marriages that are giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whiplash</ENAMEX>--most prominently those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie Rowe</ENAMEX>, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dermatologist</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receptionist</ENAMEX>; and talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee Gifford</ENAMEX> and
her sportscaster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> made news with
the revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Marie Presley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, confided to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, that she had found evidence during her
marriage--which was never consummated, according to the story--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> was
sexually interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Stanley</ENAMEX>, went public
because of a recent report in the tabloids that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presley</ENAMEX> have
traveled the world together--with her young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by another marriage--even
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowe</ENAMEX> is pregnant with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowe</ENAMEX> said to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, "I told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> that I would share him
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Marie</ENAMEX>." She'll have to if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> is accurate when it reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> has talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowe</ENAMEX> serving as a surrogate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> for a child
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">artificially</ENAMEX> conceived between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presley</ENAMEX>. "He's convinced they could
create the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> .

            On the
Gifford front, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , in what it calls "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Tender Love Story</ENAMEX>," has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX> advising "skirtchasing" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> to reconcile with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>.
The counseling sessions gave her new hope that "she can reignite the flames of
passion with her own hubby." But according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , which helped
douse the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX> marriage when it videotaped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sportscaster</ENAMEX>'s tryst with an
unnaturally well-endowed former flight attendant, the flame is out. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX>
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Divorce Frank</ENAMEX>!" predicted a recent cover. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , meanwhile, is
hedging its bets. It reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX> is planning to get
breast implants "to save her self-esteem--and maybe her marriage." But the
publication also says that she is recording a blues album, all the better to
"[rub] her martyrdom in the face of her errant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>."

            
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> marriages could be called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ponce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">de León</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>. Take the wedding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Quinn</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">82</TIMEX>, to his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Benvin</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> told the
Star that after the ceremony, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quinn</ENAMEX> launched into his Zorba the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>
dance. "You could see him growing younger before your very eyes." When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
Shatner, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX>, married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nerine Kidd</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>, he told a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> : "She is my fountain of youth. ... Her love energizes me." It's
fortunate she is not his sole source of energy--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports she had
canceled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their wedding</TIMEX> plans <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times previously. But having to constantly
administer youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">serum</ENAMEX> can send a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> fleeing into the arms of someone who
actually is young. Take the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Steiger</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX>. He discovered that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>, was discussing more than drywall with their married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> was photographed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> seems
to have a sort of social consciousness about not letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> suffer the
delusion that they are happily married.

            Then again, the tabloids
have to give credit when love proves the cynics wrong. That's what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> had to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo Derek</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director husband</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>. When they married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said it
wouldn't last. But they showed what true love is when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo</ENAMEX> took over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s
medical care and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven weeks</TIMEX> forced him to drink <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gallons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to flush
out stubborn <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney stones</ENAMEX>. Concludes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> : "She's more than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">perfect 10</ENAMEX>!"

         
      
   
