
   
   
      
         
            This Is (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Not Quite) Your Life</ENAMEX>

            "Why would he do something
like that?" asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ware</ENAMEX>--the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ware</ENAMEX>, whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
was shot while riding on the handlebars of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sibling</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX> civil-rights strife of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>. A federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, also named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ware</ENAMEX>,
had to give up a promotion to the appellate bench <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>, when it turned
out that the dramatic story he'd been telling for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> about his martyred
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> actually happened to someone else. Why on earth would he tell such an
obvious whopper?

            You may
be thinking that asking why public figures lie is like asking why fish swim.
But this is not conventional résumé padding. Nor is it a standard
cover-your-ass prevarication (we are not involved in: the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pigs</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">invasion/</ENAMEX>bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>/trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>). Nor is it the
foolish bravado of a philandering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> ("put a tail on me ... you'll be
very bored."). Or the of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Robb</ENAMEX> (my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> "is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> I've loved,
slept with, or had coital relations with") or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>
is "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> I never slept with").

            No, we're talking about the "self-defining" kind of lie, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX> himself described it: the biographical embellishment for public
consumption. This kind of lie is remarkably common, even though it is also
often remarkably easy to expose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph McCarthy</ENAMEX>, for example, fabricated
an entire heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> history for himself as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tail Gunner Joe</ENAMEX>." But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> lied without compunction about nearly everything. The more interesting
cases are those involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who generally tell the truth.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ware</ENAMEX>'s
explanation is that he was confused. His actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, he says, was shot
around the same time as the bicycle incident. His "feeling of loss" and
possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kinship</ENAMEX> to the murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> led him to merge the two happenings in
his mind, he says. Doesn't seem likely. More plausible is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX> was
entrapped by his own rhetorical success. He'd been enthralling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> with
this tale for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. You tell a good story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> loves it. Word of your
marvelously moving speech gets around. You are invited to give more speeches.
How could you explain the sudden disappearance of your signature anecdote? "I
decided it wasn't so self-defining after all"?

            
Many a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> has been enticed into
self-enrichment by an appreciative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, or the anticipation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. In his
standard stump speech of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> presidential campaign, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Biden</ENAMEX> started
off by quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Labor Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Kinnock</ENAMEX> on the hard life of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uneducated</ENAMEX>, coal-digging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">forebears</ENAMEX>. Pretty soon, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinnock</ENAMEX> had dropped
out of the speech and it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX> himself whose ancestors "worked in the coal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mines</ENAMEX> ... and would come up after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hours</TIMEX> and play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX> grew up in a white-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandfather</ENAMEX> was a state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, and the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX> on record as having worked
near a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> was a mining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
galvanized the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> convention with his moving account of holding
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> while she died of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>--an experience that, he
said, caused him to "pour my heart and soul into the cause of protecting our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from the dangers of smoking." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> continued to seek the support
of the tobacco industry. "Throughout most of my life, I raised tobacco," he
told an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> bid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
nomination <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s death. "I've hoed it. I've chopped it
... put it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> and sold it."

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX> reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, the published memoirs of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> are
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of self-aggrandizing fictions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> is constantly the lone honest tribune
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> full of unattractive fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandees</ENAMEX> making
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">improbable</ENAMEX> and unflattering remarks.

            Over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> has got a lot of mileage out of remembering the blood of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX> that smeared his shirt when he cradled the dying leader
in his arms. Testimony from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> was
initially reluctant to go to the balcony where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> was shot, though he might
later have been close enough to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King's body</ENAMEX> to acquire some stains from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> on the floor.

            
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' discovered memories are less
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">melodramatic</ENAMEX>. At the recent campaign-finance hearings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Torricelli</ENAMEX>
waxed eloquent about his memories of the "first hearing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> I ever
witnessed"--the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1951 Kefauver</ENAMEX> hearings on organized crime, which he recalled as
a festival of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> prejudice. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torricelli</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days old</TIMEX> when
those hearings ended.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who never did get his draft story straight, said in a radio address
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that a wave of black church burnings brought back "vivid and painful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">memories</ENAMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> being burned in my own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>."
When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> pointed out there were no black church burnings in the
state then or perhaps ever, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> said he meant "black
community <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>" (though there is no record of that either). But, wherever
the fires were, she insisted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s recollections were "very vivid and
painful."

            No doubt. As the literature on lying often observes, those
who become skilled in the art of deception can easily fool themselves. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> regaled world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> with his story of having witnessed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberation</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, he probably saw the event as vividly
as he had once seen the film about it that he helped to make. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
was a special case. He made himself up as he went along, borrowing bits and
pieces from this movie or that. ("I paid for that microphone" probably came
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer Tracy</ENAMEX> political comedy; his faith in an invulnerable "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars</ENAMEX>"
nuclear shield perhaps came from the "inertia projector" portrayed in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>
movie in which he starred.) While some of his political lies were far from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harmless</ENAMEX>, most of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">autobiographical</ENAMEX> lies were relatively small stuff: "I
never wore makeup in films" (check the films); "I believe in tithing to
charity" (check the tax records); I got my nickname <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> because ... (choose
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> versions).

            Like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> like to pilfer their glory from the field of
battle. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dornan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, who went down in grudging defeat last
fall, described his military career thusly in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">House</ENAMEX> speech: "I went into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and volunteered for whatever dangerous assignment there was." In
fact, he avoided action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> by going to drama <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and his subsequent
military career was mostly spent directing and performing in armed-forces
theatrical productions (though he did crash <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> while
in pilot training).

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX>
described himself in résumés and a published autobiography as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
assigned to combat duty during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX>. In fact--with the help of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s connections--he was conveniently detached from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> headed for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battlefield</ENAMEX> and spent his tour doing administrative tasks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Cooley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>,
lost his seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> after falsely claiming a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX> combat tour--as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Forces</ENAMEX>, no less.

            Curiously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>,
that archetype of political deceit, provides no ready example of résumé
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rewriting</ENAMEX>--unless you want to count "I am not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX>." By contrast, pious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> once described himself as a "nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX>." He later
acknowledged that "nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>" was a more just description of his
academic qualifications. A modest fabrication, but not bad for a president
whose subsequent campaign slogan was "I'll never lie to you."

            Why do they do it? The
easiest answer is that, by and large, or at least for long periods of time,
public figures get away with it. And even when they are discovered, the public
is often forgiving (or at least forgetting). One theory has it that public
figures see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> as a distant, easily manipulated mass to which they
can lie with impunity. But maybe that's not the whole story. Perhaps we, the
public, don't mind being lied to if the lies evoke a vision not only of better
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> of uncompromising principle, noble deeds, and generous
spirit--but of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> that responds to such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
