
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of the Show Tune</ENAMEX>

            In the run-up to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broadway</ENAMEX> hit The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Rogers Follies</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cy Coleman</ENAMEX> took to doing
the big song--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never Met a Man I Didn't Like"</ENAMEX>--at benefit performances all over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>. Just before opening <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, he sang it at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ear</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Throat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX>. "You should have seen him," said his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lyricist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolph Green</ENAMEX>. "There
wasn't a dry eye, ear, and throat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>."

            But where
else would you hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">song?</ENAMEX> "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years ago</TIMEX>, we used to have records of our stuff
on the radio before the show opened," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cy sighs</ENAMEX>. Not anymore. When did you last
hear a show tune on the air? I don't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Cole</ENAMEX> doing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX>,
but new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> numbers--from, say, Big or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Victor/Victoria</ENAMEX> . The
last <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> song to make the charts was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Gaynor</ENAMEX>'s disco version of "I
Am What I Am" from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Cage Aux Folles</ENAMEX> , and she had to change a few of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Herman</ENAMEX>'s notes to pull that off. Before rock, the theater song sat at the
apex of popular music; the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">songwriters</ENAMEX> were show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, and the
pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tin Pan Alleymen</ENAMEX>--longed to cross the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving Berlin</ENAMEX>
did, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gershwin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jule Styne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Loesser</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Haley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">painted Broadway</ENAMEX> into a corner it never quite got out of: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Musicals</ENAMEX> stood aloof
from rock and became, by definition, staid, conservative,
middle-aged--something your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> go see on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their wedding anniversary</TIMEX>. Never
mind that on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>, long before "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rock Around the Clock</ENAMEX>," the score
to As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls Go</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">old-timers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Sunny Side of the Street</ENAMEX>")
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McHugh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Time on My Hands"</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adamson</ENAMEX> included a number called "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>!
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>!" with the tempo marking "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groovy</ENAMEX>."

            Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX> figures he can bridge that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year</TIMEX> gulf.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> , launched at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention</ENAMEX> and including a guest
appearance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie Wonder</ENAMEX> on its <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act II</ENAMEX> opener, is supposed to be a cast
album you can play on pop radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>. As every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reader
knows, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer- and Tony-</ENAMEX>winning "rock opera" version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Boh√®me</ENAMEX> , with a dramatis personae of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>-positive performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>,
transsexuals, and drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Village</ENAMEX>, whose cachet was greatly
enhanced by the death on the eve of opening of its young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer/lyricist</ENAMEX>/librettist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Larson</ENAMEX>. The show makes an interesting
contrast with that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puccini</ENAMEX> retread, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Saigon</ENAMEX> . The latter, a
British musical, relocates <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Madame Butterfly</ENAMEX> to the most controversial
conflict of our time, paints its story on a big, sweeping canvas and has gone
on to play around the world; the other brings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Boh√</ENAMEX>®me <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich Village</ENAMEX>, and thus further reinforces the parochialism of the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical</ENAMEX>, as it shrivels away to its core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. I would doubt its potential
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> or overseas. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> won its awards not just for its
subject but also for its score. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Sondheim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Larson</ENAMEX>
had managed to do what so many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> had tried and failed for years
to do: He'd used the language of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> to propel a theater piece. He'd fused
contemporary pop and drama. Rock 'n' roles.

            
Just for the record, there's a bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puccini</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> . At the end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger the songwriter</ENAMEX> finally finishes his song for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mimi</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Eyes</ENAMEX>"[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO AUDIO CLIP</ENAMEX>]--and in it, we also hear a brief snatch
of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Musetta's Waltz</ENAMEX>." As it's played on an electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guitar</ENAMEX>, though, it's
reminiscent less of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boh√</ENAMEX>®me than of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Don't You Know?</ENAMEX>," a pop adaptation
of the waltz that was a hit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Della Reese</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO AUDIO CLIP</ENAMEX>]and
which contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">laziest</ENAMEX> filler couplets in lyric-writing history:

            
               I have
fallen in love with youFor the rest of my whole life through ...

            As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">waltz</ENAMEX> echoes alarmingly through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> 's finale, you're reminded of a
basic fact: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX> is music. If a tune's muscular enough, you can do it as an
operatic waltz, a big pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ballad</ENAMEX>, an electric guitar solo. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>, like swing or
disco or bluegrass, is a style and, in the theater, its usefulness depends on
the story you're trying to tell.

            Musicals can't be on the so-called cutting edge, because
they take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> to get up on stage: By the time your grunge musical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opens</ENAMEX>, grunge will be out and splurge will be in. That's the problem with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> : Only on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> could it be mistaken for state-of-the-art rock.
The big driving numbers, like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What You Own</ENAMEX>," [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO AUDIO</ENAMEX>] come out sounding
like, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blue √ñyster Cult</ENAMEX>, full of the same charmingly overheated
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">metaphors:</ENAMEX>

            
               You're
living in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">AmericaAt the end of the millenniumYou</TIMEX>'re living in AmericaLeave your
conscience at the tone ...
            

            The
ballads, on the other hand, are overwrought and declarative. The best, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seasons</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX>," [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO AUDIO CLIP</ENAMEX>] affects the same ensemble solidarity as "What I
Did for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love" in A Chorus Line</ENAMEX> . [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO AUDIO CLIP</ENAMEX>]Both can find no
better use for the pop ballad than as group therapy--one for those suffering
the vicissitudes of life as a chorus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gypsy</ENAMEX>, the other for those "living in the
shadow of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>." But the spare, slightly awkward chanted admonition--"measure
in love"--is still a world away from the best pop lyric-writing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Jay</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lerner</ENAMEX> used to bemoan the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX> never went into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theater</ENAMEX>. But, since the advent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LP</ENAMEX> and the gatefold sleeve with the
printed lyrics and the college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that study rock songs for their elusive
allusiveness, pop texts have been freed from the first requirement of a
Broadway lyric: that it be made up of words you can catch when you're sitting
in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and they're flying through the air at you. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX> once took me
through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his songs, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hearts and Bones</ENAMEX>," which begins, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-half</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">wandering Jews</ENAMEX> ..."[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO AUDIO CLIP</ENAMEX>]

            
He explained to me that it was "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and
one-half" because the song was about him, and he's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, and his then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Fisher</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Fisher</ENAMEX>, who's also <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, and Debbie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX>, who's not; hence, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and a half</NUMEX>. So far, we'd spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 minutes</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decoding</ENAMEX> just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> words, but I felt on top of them and was ready to move on.
Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> said:

            
               "But
it's also a reference to the flower.""<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pardon?</ENAMEX>""There's a flower called
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wandering Jew</ENAMEX>.""There's a flower<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>""Yes.""Ah."
            

            And I
realized that, had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lerner</ENAMEX>'s advice and started writing musicals,
we'd have had to get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 in the morning</TIMEX> to read up on the
textual footnotes.

            In that sense, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geffen</ENAMEX>'s marketing efforts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larson</ENAMEX>
is straightforwardly <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> I finale, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Vie Boh√®me</ENAMEX> ," [LINK
TO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDIO CLIP</ENAMEX>] is a rock gloss on the hoariest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical comedy staples</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bravura</ENAMEX> laundry list. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Porter</ENAMEX>:

            
               You're a
rose!You're <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inferno's Dante</ENAMEX>!You're the noseOn the great Durante!
            

            Next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX>'s marriage of
the erudite and the everyday, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larson</ENAMEX>'s catalog seems somewhat
single-minded:

            
               To
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SontagTo SondheimTo</ENAMEX> anything taboo ...
            

            The
Sondheim reference is apposite. Songs like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tango: Maureen"[LINK TO AUDIO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLIP</ENAMEX>]--glib, brittle dialogue at odds with the exotic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tango rhythms</ENAMEX>--are a
reminder of such early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sondheim</ENAMEX> works as "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX>." [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LINK TO AUDIO CLIP</ENAMEX>] In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sondheim</ENAMEX> used the click-buzz of the telephone as a leitmotif for urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurosis</ENAMEX>; in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larson</ENAMEX> tries to pull something similar with his "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice Mail</ENAMEX>"
numbers, a series of a-cappella answering-machine messages.

            
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> good songs in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> .
They're called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red-Nosed Reindeer</ENAMEX>," and
they're briefly quoted in a yuletide scene. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larson</ENAMEX>'s own title for that
number--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christmas Bells"</ENAMEX>--reveals his greatest weakness. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> the
Red-Nosed Reindeer" is a title; so's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Saw Mommy Kissing Santa Claus</ENAMEX>." But
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christmas Bells</ENAMEX>" isn't; neither is "You'll See" or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Out Tonight</ENAMEX>" or "We're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Okay</ENAMEX>," all titles of songs in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> . "Without You" is a good title
but it's already been used in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Fair Lady</ENAMEX> and as a hit for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nilsson</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariah Carey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Gershwin</ENAMEX> used to say:

            
               A title
Is vitalOnce you've itProve it.
            

            A good title usually
indicates a good song idea, a good central lyric thrust, something to resolve.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop</ENAMEX> and theater have drifted apart, it seems that the rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> pays more
heed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gershwin</ENAMEX>'s advice than the musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. "Wake <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me Up Before You Go-Go</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Michael</ENAMEX>) or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Get Outta My Dreams, Get Into My Car"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Ocean</ENAMEX>) are
better titles and stronger images than you get in most show tunes. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX>,
there are few strong song ideas, few resolved lyric thrusts. That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason
why it's deficient as drama, but also why it will be hard to play on pop radio.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX> is likely to be disappointed: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> continues the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">musical</ENAMEX>'s long fade-out to a twilight limbo, caught somewhere between
not-quite-serious music and no-longer-popular pop music.

         
      
   
