
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star on the Starr Report</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> hit a macabre
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trifecta</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> with extensive reports on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of their major stories: the
murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX>, the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, and the dead duck
presidency of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">killed JonBenet</ENAMEX>, the 6-year-old beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>, has been an obsession of the tabs
since her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> found her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">mansion</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1996</TIMEX>. The coverage of the investigation has been like the
course of a long, fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>, with many remissions and recurrences. But this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, at least, the tabs indicate the end may be near. Each of the three
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weeklies</ENAMEX> touts different "bombshell" allegations that tie the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to
her death.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ramsey</ENAMEX>, wasn't as surprised
by the discovery of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> as you might suspect, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> , citing grand jury testimony by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramseys</ENAMEX>' former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend Fleet White</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> looked in the basement
for the supposedly kidnapped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> but, unable to locate a light switch, he
couldn't see anything in one of the pitch-dark, windowless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. Later, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enquirer</ENAMEX> says he testified, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey</ENAMEX> started screaming at the entrance to
that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> before he flicked on the switch, leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> to believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey</ENAMEX>
already knew his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> also says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey</ENAMEX> tried to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> that an intruder had entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> by
lifting a grate outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX>. But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports,
analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arachnologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Opell</ENAMEX> of a spider web covering the grate
indicates it had been undisturbed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a month</TIMEX> prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s
death. Oh, what a tangled web we weave.

            A pair of beaver skin boots
could implicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX>, declares the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . Referring
to "top-secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> files," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> says that a strand of animal fur
was found on the duct tape used to cover the murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s mouth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX>
suspect it will match the boots <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX> was wearing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of the murder.
Also, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> after the murder, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bookkeeper</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX> hardware store
notified police that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> had called wanting copies of receipts for
purchases charged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy Ramsey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> believe the duct tape was bought at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, but the receipt listed only prices, not specific items. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> that they had put their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to bed after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
dinner and never seen her alive again. But an autopsy revealed that at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX> had a snack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pineapple</ENAMEX>--fingerprints on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> bowl indicate she
and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> ate together--and that she died around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>
later.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> touts an "exclusive" from a "tipster" who claims that in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX> was discovered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ramsey</ENAMEX> gave away a box--supposedly of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s personal items--so they wouldn't "get ruined during the investigation."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> claims that the box actually contains the sheets and several
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuffed animals</ENAMEX> that were on her bed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of her murder, as well as the
nightgown she was wearing. An informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> the
allegations are "totally misinformed" and "completely inaccurate."

            
On the anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death, the tabs
exhume their theories about the nefarious reasons her life was cut short. The
Star floats what could be called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Boleyn</ENAMEX> theory--that is, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> murdered. Their evidence doesn't quite rise to the
level where it could be characterized as preposterous. Here it goes: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drunken</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> died, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Paul</ENAMEX>, had more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, although he earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $30,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. This indicates to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> that he was an informer for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intelligence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Tomlinson, an ex-employee of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MI6</ENAMEX> who was jailed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for trying to sell
his memoirs, asserts that only the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> would pay a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX> that well.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> intelligence would never pay him that amount of money," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomlinson</ENAMEX>.
Aside from the issue of pay scales on either side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX>, even if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
was an informer, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> doesn't grapple with why MI6 would want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
dead. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boleyn</ENAMEX>, she may have been an incompliant consort, but by then she
was a former <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            Into the
breach steps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , whose theory is that the car accident was the
result of a kidnapping gone wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intelligence didn't want to kill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodi Al Fayed</ENAMEX>, it simply wanted to scare them apart
because, asserts <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yaqub Zaki</ENAMEX>, "the idea of the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prince William</ENAMEX>, having a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> stepfather was intolerable. And the
idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">half-brother</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> with brown skin was unthinkable."

            If there was a murder plot, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> may have
unwittingly ended up pointing the finger at a really big <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
issue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> reports that shortly before she died, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana "</ENAMEX>told pals
she was planning to remarry the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX>!" Now, if this were true, there is
certainly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who would want to make sure such an event never came to
pass. Or to put it another way, does anyone really know where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death?

            The tabs
are filled with royal news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. Most disturbing is a report in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> might be suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> says royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> are worried about an apparent decline in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' short-term memory and say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> has turned to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> for
help. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helping Charles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> deal with their grief over their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s death is
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nanny</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiggy Legge-Bourke</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> "despised" her for calling the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> "my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>" (according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ), a royal insider says, "If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>'s looking down from heaven, I'm sure she's forgiven her." And love has found
an ex-member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. According the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Enquirer Sarah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> over heels" over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> Count <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaddo della Gherardesca</ENAMEX>. As
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> says, nobody would begrudge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fergie</ENAMEX> a little happiness, but
how much more euphonious it would be if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiggy Legge-Bourke</ENAMEX> had coupled with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaddo della Gherardesca</ENAMEX>. Finally an item in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> wins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When Hell Freezes Over"</ENAMEX> award. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barbara</ENAMEX>, has set her sights on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace Kelly</ENAMEX>'s widower, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainier</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monaco</ENAMEX>. Reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> : "Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX> say it's only a matter of time
before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>'s mourning is over and she flies off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monaco</ENAMEX> and a new life
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainier</ENAMEX>."

            Stuck in his old life is our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX>, and the
tabs take notably different approaches to his predicament. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enquirer</ENAMEX> delivered when it said it found out the "shocking truth behind
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zippergate</ENAMEX> scandal." And what is this new, depraved revelation?

            He fell in love with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>--and even told her he wanted to be with her when he left
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he passion and pain of the affair that shook the world has been
exposed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>' own words. ... A stunning picture of a love-starved
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> driven beyond reason by a passionate young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>. ... He assured her,
"I never really knew what love could be until you came along."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> is probably the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> in the world to go with this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Mercer</ENAMEX> hypothesis. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mercer</ENAMEX> was the lifelong love of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>,
and the revelation of their affair nearly ended his marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>. It's
probably safe to say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s real feelings for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> actually go in
another direction; see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Boleyn</ENAMEX> theory, above.)

            Romantics
will warm to further <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> disclosures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">l</ENAMEX>]onely
and starved for affection. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>] made him feel good about himself." He
told her, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, that his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was now
nothing more than a political alliance that would end when his term did. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> further charmed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> by fantasizing out loud how wonderful it would
be if he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>." Oh, to get an invitation to that bris! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
also at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point planned a tryst on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> finally
chickened out, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. This was before a vacation on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX> became a synonym for the first circle of hell.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> offers a preview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report on the great love affair, which will enumerate romps "in the
Presidential limo, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LINCOLN BEDROOM</ENAMEX>!" The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> says the report will include information on how "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> used a
cigar in a sexually uninhibited manner" and how "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used one of the ties
given to him by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> in sexy games during their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> trysts." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> also leaves the strong impression the report is being written
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Krantz</ENAMEX>, with dialogue such as:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>: You are the kinkiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I've ever been with.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>: 
               [laughs] .

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report will
disclose that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has particular ideas about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Second Coming</TIMEX> when it
depicts a sexual encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> church services. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> also has a thinly sourced account of
how, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "fondled and made crude remarks to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> at a posh
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, area country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>" after a round of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>. Reading the story
you first think, "This didn't happen; he couldn't be that stupid." Then you
think, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well ...</ENAMEX>"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , as usual,
is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's</ENAMEX> corner, complete with transcripts of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> family's heartfelt
conversations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> would make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tammy Wynette</ENAMEX> proud as she says: "I've
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forgiven Bill</ENAMEX>. ... I won't let that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> wreck my marriage or rob my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
of the place he's earned in my heart, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s heart or in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
history." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> also has some moving words for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>" ran
through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton AutoParser</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> said to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darling</ENAMEX>, whatever I've done, I have never stopped loving you for one
single moment." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AutoParser</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> really means, "It was legally
accurate to say that in my encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Lewinsky</ENAMEX> there was no
controlling genital authority." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> also told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>: "The hurt
in your eyes is torture to me. If you forgive me, I'll never look at anyone
else again." According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AutoParser</ENAMEX>, this means, "I will never again look
at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> named Anyone Else."

         
      
   
