
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morbid Fascination</ENAMEX>

            In the world of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tabloids</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all last days</TIMEX> are either tragic or brave--or preferably both. Take
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the long deathwatches now preoccupying the tabs. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bed-ridden Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brave Last Days</ENAMEX>," reads the headline of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> story that begins, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frail</ENAMEX>
and feeble <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> spends his tragic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX> mostly flat on his back."
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's cover read "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hope</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tragic Last Days</ENAMEX>"
and inside told of his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brave Last Goodbye</ENAMEX>."

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> demonstrates a frequent tabloid dilemma. While death is inevitable, it
is not predictable. A few tough old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> stubbornly refuse to make each
day their last. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> announced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Hepburn</ENAMEX>
was unlikely to make it through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> (but she's still around). And in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> had to resurrect the aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
Hope's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amazing Comeback</ENAMEX>," it announced. "He's turning back the clock at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brave Last Days</ENAMEX> have now stretched to a year. More in annoyance than
in sorrow, it seems, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> are
predicting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> won't preside over his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82</NUMEX> nd
birthday <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 12</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> is conceding he might make it, but insists
that this will be "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brave Sinatra's Last Birthday</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> are modern versions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Art of Dying</ENAMEX>
manuals of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Middle Ages</TIMEX>, which instructed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on how to die properly. In
the medieval world, death was not something to be feared or hidden but rather,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> event, a crucial stage of life that needed to be anticipated and
mastered. When death arrives at a celebrity bedside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the tabs defy modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">squeamishness</ENAMEX> and take you there to chronicle--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>--the end. A good
death, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> concluded, was had by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Stewart</ENAMEX>. Though the star
had become a recluse, refusing to see his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> following the death of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX>, he did keep up a telephone relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> .
In a series of interviews about his impending death he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
that he would miss his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, but added, "It's time they started living
their own lives and not have to worry about this old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
detailed his last meals (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter</ENAMEX> and jelly for lunch and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX> game hen
and carrots for dinner) and the final treatments for a blood clot in his right
leg. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amazingly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> talked to the publication <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only four hours</TIMEX> before he
died, saying, "This isn't a sad day--it's for the best."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchum</ENAMEX>'s death wasn't as uplifting as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart's</ENAMEX>, but the tabloids gave him
credit for departing honestly. Despite lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and emphysema--and the fact
that he used an oxygen tank to breathe--on his last night <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchum</ENAMEX> got out of
bed for a cigarette, reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , and one of his last meals was a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-martini lunch. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchum</ENAMEX> also took the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's calls
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. In an interview, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> did an organ<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by-</NUMEX>organ
assessment of the dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. After asking about his lungs and his liver, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> inquired if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchum</ENAMEX> had any other health problems. "Yeah, I've
got terminal dandruff on my eyebrows," he replied. He also told them, "I've led
a very full life, a good life, and I don't want to ruin it by prolonging it any
further. I'm ready to meet my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>."

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> as in foxholes, there are no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">atheists</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> have specific plans for the next life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>'s
last words, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , were, "I'm going to be with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria</ENAMEX> now."
According to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> hopes to reassemble a heavenly
version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rat Pack</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>
says he has spoken with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Davis Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lawford</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean Martin</ENAMEX>
recently. He is also sweating his final judgment. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Peter</ENAMEX>'s going to have to
do a double-take when I get there, but I'm hoping to squeak by," he reportedly
said. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Hepburn</ENAMEX> just wants to be reunited with her great love,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer Tracy</ENAMEX>, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> in its greatly exaggerated report of
her supposedly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">final days</TIMEX>. She sleeps in his nightshirt, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hepburn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , and sits around reliving old memories and "murmuring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Spencah</ENAMEX>.' " Country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Cash</ENAMEX>, who the tabloids say is unlikely to
recover from a deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, said, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , "I always expected my good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX> would be
waiting for me in heaven. Now it looks like I'll get there first to greet
him."

            The
tabloids abhor sudden departures, especially unnatural ones, which almost by
definition are bad deaths. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> is the ultimate example of this. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Denver</ENAMEX> died piloting his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
both saw things the same way. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Depressed & Boozing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He Gambled</ENAMEX> With His
Life," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's headline. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Denver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death-Wish Tragedy</ENAMEX>,"
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> pulled off a good death after all, according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> cover line: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Denver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heroic Last Seconds</ENAMEX>." Inside we
learn, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hero John Denver Steered Crippled Plane Away From Crowded Streets</ENAMEX>."
Just to reassure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that he died well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX> quotes him as
having said in an interview, "I want to be lucky and die doing what I love
most--flying."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> also like to cover how still-healthy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> might make it to their deathbeds. Dramatic weight gains, in
particular, are seen as a come-hither gesture to the grim reaper. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> recently described <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Farley</ENAMEX>, who they say weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">375</NUMEX>
pounds, as "a heart attack waiting to happen," and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Marlon Brando</ENAMEX> as
"a walking time bomb." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyne Daley</ENAMEX> has packed on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> pounds, says the
Star , and a "a source" worries that "her heart may give out from
carrying so much weight."

            Then there
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> who appear to have a power over death. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evidence</ENAMEX> is mounting that country music brings <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of
comas!" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> tells how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeAnn Rimes</ENAMEX> sang her hit "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blue</ENAMEX>" to a comatose
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-year-old</TIMEX>, who then opened her eyes for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since a car accident.
Recordings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan White</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> have had similar effects on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other
comatose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>-accident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> .

            
For the tabloids, no celebrity death is ever
final. Breaking a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year</TIMEX> silence about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Wood</ENAMEX>'s mysterious drowning
death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Walken</ENAMEX> says that nothing unusual took place the night
she disappeared off her docked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonrevelation</ENAMEX> gives the publication a chance to rehash other accounts that
claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walken</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wagner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>) got in a fight over her,
following which she stomped off in anger, never again to be seen alive. And
then there is the unsolved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> murder case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heroes</ENAMEX>
star <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Crane</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> doesn't explain that one either, but it does
report on a séance conducted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crane</ENAMEX>'s spirit to rest.
Anniversaries can also prompt a reassessment of a demise. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">20 th the Star</ENAMEX> concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">King "Could Have Been</ENAMEX>
Saved."

            There is one mysterious
death that has been haunting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 24 years</TIMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> does solve. It turns out that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>, the talking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, died of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug overdose</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitter</ENAMEX> mistakenly thought Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> was having a seizure
and gave him a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tranquilizer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> died within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. Though the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> doesn't say so, it was surely an end that was both tragic and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brave</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
