
   
   
      
         
            Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>

            The headline in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reads, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone Cellulite Shocker</ENAMEX>." The photo--an enlarged
patch of thigh--is highlighted with a circle and an arrow, a graphic like one
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> might use to indicate the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> where a
massacre took place. Together, headline and image signal that the tabloids
finally have returned to form.

            Yes, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> hagiography continues. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> did a story on "The
Real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Di</ENAMEX>," with such unlikely revelations as the alleged fact that she
did her own ironing and joined the help in washing dishes. The article also
stated, "In an age when so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> put on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> image in public and hide
an ugly, private side, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was just who she was, wherever she went." Of
course, a chance to look at that ugly, private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> is the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> pick
up the tabs in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. So it was comforting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to be told by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie Griffith</ENAMEX>'s bee-stung lips "appear to be the result
of collagen overload," and by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaquille O'Neal</ENAMEX> supposedly
just had breast-reduction surgery.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> and the National

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> proffered written manifestoes denying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> such as
theirs were responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death, or even for harassing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> in
general. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , which is staking out the strategically
questionable territory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> with taste, explains that many
celebrities "ask us to interview them and take their pictures." However, other
celebrities "are furious because they can't stop us from telling the truth,
even with their powerful publicity machines." The statement ends on a
constitutional note: "You live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. You have a right to buy The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ."

            But for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> seemed to lose its way. There was a strange, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>-thin
issue, full of stories such as one about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> who was fired for trying to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perform CPR</ENAMEX> on a dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby chimp</ENAMEX>; and another about a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>, lost for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22 years</TIMEX>,
that was found embedded in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX>. And then there was this shocking headline
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">JonBenet Top Cop: Mom and Dad Are Innocent</ENAMEX>." Could it be that,
after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a year</TIMEX> of relentless accusations against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy Ramsey</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> was having second thoughts? No, as it turned out. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> alleged that the retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> brought in to work on the case was
not admired by the other cops. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the story was back on track with
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mommy and Daddy to Be Arrested by Christmas--Cops Convinced</ENAMEX>."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Viewers</ENAMEX>
are tired of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fran Drescher</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reveals pluckily <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.
Their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of the sitcom The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nanny</ENAMEX> and one of the
tabs' noisier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>--has "turned off too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, especially with her
complaints about the tough lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-rich celebs</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX>
predicts her show will be canceled. On the other hand, do we detect a defensive
note in a story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merle Haggard</ENAMEX>, which finds it necessary to explain
why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> had chosen this moment to portray <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haggard</ENAMEX> as a
bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haggard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty</ENAMEX>, is speaking out, the article
explains, because "his famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is working on a biographical feature film
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty</ENAMEX> says will be an outrageous whitewash of the truth."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> has maintained a more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pugilistic</ENAMEX> pose since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death. It, too, has attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> who
attacked it: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clueless</ENAMEX>--sorry, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clooney</ENAMEX>--used to beg us to run stories on
him ... when he was a struggling nobody appearing in such schlocky movies as
Return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Killer Tomatoes</ENAMEX>! " The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> rewards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> who
understand its rules. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX> even signed up for an endorsement:
"Like all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, I love the art of communication and I fully support the
freedom of the press," he says. "I love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> ." The caption on a photo of
a pregnant and smiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Locklear</ENAMEX> reads, "She's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> who really
knows how to act like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> as she happily smiles for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hint,</ENAMEX>
hint.

            The
Star also has taken to congratulating itself for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it gets to
speak willingly. On a recent cover, the logo "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look Who's Talking to</ENAMEX>
Star " appeared over stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariah Carey</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchess of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>. And what talk! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariah Carey</ENAMEX> tells all about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camp Mariah</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> for
inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Of her life she says, "It's all about my career--and those
great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>." Fergie, meanwhile, both mourns her late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> and
touts her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weight Watchers</ENAMEX> holiday diet. "For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in my life, I've
found a way of eating that works."

            Offering no self-justification is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> --which
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> helped arrange the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-afternoon stand that's turned into a
cottage industry: the one between surgically enhanced former flight attendant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzen Johnson</ENAMEX> and football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX>, perhaps now better known
as the cheating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX>. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> mourning
period, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> went supernatural with this exclusive: "<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess</ENAMEX>
smiles down from Heaven on her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave Boys</ENAMEX>." But it returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>,
interviewing an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> who had treated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX>. The shrink's
diagnosis: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fayed</ENAMEX> suffered from something called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Borderline Personality</ENAMEX>
Disorder. "When I first heard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX> was dating my former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>, I wanted to
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">phone Kensington Palace</ENAMEX> and scream: 'Run, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>, run.' "

            In the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death, it appeared that even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> was
trying to find the pretty side of things. Take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this October</TIMEX> story on the
volatile marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX>. "Let's Start
Over!" read the headline on an account of how the "battling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovebirds</ENAMEX>" were
"vowing to put passion and togetherness back in their marriage." The logical
outcome, said the story, was "an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX>." But all that togetherness
was apparently a mistake, judging from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> headline, "JFK
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr</ENAMEX>: I married the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> has him telling a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>,
"Some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> I wake up shuddering and bathed in sweat."

            
The differences among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> publications
are probably best illustrated by their varying explanations for the mysterious
cast that recently appeared on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">George</ENAMEX> slammed down his hand during an argument with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> and broke a bone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's version is that he injured his hand
while kayaking. Leave it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> to conclude, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">JFK Jr, Slashed</ENAMEX>!
Emergency surgery after wild brawl with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn</ENAMEX>--say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> have
cover stories about plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Hoefflin</ENAMEX> (the man
who takes credit for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>'s nose) and whether he exposed and
discussed the genitals of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity patients</ENAMEX> while they were under
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anesthesia</ENAMEX>. It's a natural story for the tabloids, but it caught them all with
their pants down when it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appeared in a long, entertaining piece in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
