
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rap Victoriana</ENAMEX>

            What hip-hop and parlor
music have in common.

            
               By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Steyn</ENAMEX>
            

            ( <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1242</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 1</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 8</TIMEX> )

             

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just over a century ago</TIMEX>,
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX>, a cocky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> hung a shingle outside his
door:

            Begin block quote here

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHARLES K. HARRIS</ENAMEX>

            BANJOIST AND
SONGWRITER

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">SONGS WRITTEN TO ORDER</ENAMEX>

            End block quote here

            And
with those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> stigmatic words, the music business was born. There'd been
music before, but, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that impresses. His
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> effort was the prototype pop hit "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After The Ball</ENAMEX>," which, 104 years
later, you can still hear every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> in the current <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
revival of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show Boat</ENAMEX> . Back then, it began earning him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> per week
almost immediately, and went on to sell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5 million</NUMEX> copies of sheet music. This
was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1892</TIMEX>, remember, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX> bucks was still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX> bucks, and you didn't
have to split it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, coke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>, and any traumatized
ex-catamite whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has a smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            We've come a long way since then: ragtime and radio,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hillbilly</ENAMEX> and race records, big bands and showtoons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">45s</ENAMEX> and triple concept
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">albums</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> and CDs and horror-core. ...

            You're
not hep to horror-core? Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronin Ro</ENAMEX>, whose book, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gangsta</ENAMEX> , comes out
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>, explain: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horror</ENAMEX>-core," he writes, "was to hip-hop what death metal
is to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brahms</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>." To be honest, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ro</ENAMEX> is indulging in a little
rhetorical exaggeration here: I suspect horror-core is a lot closer to hip-hop
than death metal is to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brahms</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>. Come to think of it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brahms</ENAMEX> isn't
that close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>. But pop music has always had a hazy grasp of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX> said on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bing Crosby Christmas Show</ENAMEX>" when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> asked him if he liked any of the older songs: "Oh, sure, I love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nilsson</ENAMEX>."

            But even rappers are getting into the nostalgia act these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. They're on the new <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">West Side Story</ENAMEX> recording where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-Pepa</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Def Jef</ENAMEX> and others do "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krupke</ENAMEX>," and, between choruses, add their
own machine-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun interpolations</ENAMEX>, beginning with:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLOCK QUOTE, SINGLE SPACE</ENAMEX>
THE ITALICIZED LINES THAT FOLLOW

            
               Music by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX>!
Lyrics by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sondheim</ENAMEX>!
            

            
               I'm talkin' 'bout West
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Side Story</ENAMEX>, it's before my time!
            

            
               ...
            

            
               So don't criticize the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that I party
            

            
               This ain't <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, we
learned it the hard way!
            

            NOTE: WE'RE SENDING YOU
THE CD <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OF THIS...WE SHOULD PUT IN AN AUDIO LINK HERE</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">END BLOCK QUOTE</ENAMEX> HERE

            It's a cute joke, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cockiness</ENAMEX> and special pleading remind us how things have changed: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Sharks</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX>' cool was parodic and laughable; in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX> version, these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> are cool for real. Their braggadocio is a cliché--even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where,
according to record-industry statistics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Day</ENAMEX> reissues outsell all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> rap. You remember the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weber</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fields</ENAMEX> joke?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLOCK QUOTE, SINGLE SPACE</ENAMEX>
THE LINES THAT FOLLOW

            
               "Who was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> I
saw you with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>?"
            

            
               "That was no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, that
was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>."
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">END BLOCK QUOTE</ENAMEX> HERE

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Eye</ENAMEX> updated it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> gangsta rappers:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLOCK QUOTE, SINGLE SPACE</ENAMEX>
THE LINES THAT FOLLOW

            
               "Who was that ho I saw
you with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>?"
            

            
               "That was no ho, that
was my bitch."
            

            END
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLOCK QUOTE</ENAMEX> HERE

            Which reworking of the protean vaudeville gag prompts a
thought: Maybe, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>'s rise and fall, rap is the final ebbing of
commercial pop, back to its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1890s</NUMEX> origins. Even as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bennett</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Political Congress</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> renew their assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
that profit from gangsta rap and claim that it marks a shameful new low in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> pop culture, and even as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> assert (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck D</ENAMEX> does) that
it's a counter-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> for the disenfranchised, gangsta rap is merely the wheel
coming full circle--back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Harris</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After The Ball</ENAMEX>." If the defense
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1990s</ENAMEX> rap is documentary--"the authentic sound of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>"--well,
so were those verse-and-chorus ballads of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>. These were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> songs
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, cautionary tales of the vicissitudes of urban life:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX>," "She is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More</NUMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pitied Than Censured</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX>' hits
were (as TV movies say) "based on a true story"--like his grisly ballad of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orphan girl</ENAMEX> asking the telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> to be put through to her dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>,
"Hello, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>, Give <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me Heaven</ENAMEX>." My personal favorite is a pop hit of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX> by
the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gussie Lord Davis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an overnight</TIMEX> train full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>
irritated by a sobbing infant and demanding to know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is. As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> explains, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mahogany</ENAMEX> casket "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Baggage</ENAMEX>
Coach Ahead."

            If you think that sounds a
little lurid, that's the whole point: These were ripe metropolitan melodramas
served up for the genteel piano <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parlors</ENAMEX> of the suburbs. Same with rap: For all
it's hailed as the voice of the urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of its sales are to
suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, for whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Enemy</ENAMEX>'s "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Joke" or Niggaz Wit</ENAMEX>'
Attitude's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fuck tha Police</ENAMEX>" offer the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">delicious</ENAMEX>, voyeuristic frisson of
life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Compton</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Bronx</ENAMEX> without actually having to live there.

            For
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">songwriters</ENAMEX> after "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After The Ball</ENAMEX>," for everyone from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving Berlin</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carole King</ENAMEX>, lyric-writing was an exercise in compression. Rap returns us to
the same sprawling prolixity as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1890s</ENAMEX> ballads--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-verse story songs,
whether they're lilting waltzes or numbingly hard-core, are rarely
distinguished as music . Almost all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blockbusters</ENAMEX> have
the simplest of tonal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>. Similarly, rap is the logical consequence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> promotion of street cred over music: the reduction of the tune to
a banal pneumatic backing track, the debasement of lyric-writing to a formless
laundry list of half-baked hoodlum exhibitionism. 1990s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsta</ENAMEX> rap is
rhythmically simple and harmonically negligible, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1890s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ballads</ENAMEX> are melodically
simple and harmonically negligible, but the effect is the same: Even as the
subject matter in each case proclaims its modernity (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">railroads</ENAMEX> and telephone on
the one hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and crack on the other), in both cases, the music underneath
belies it.

            There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major difference, of course. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles K. Harris</ENAMEX>
just opened the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, found a suitable story and wrote it up. Gangsta
rappers have eliminated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">middleman</ENAMEX>: They are the stories in the
papers. Half of 'em wind up getting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">shot</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ol' Dirty Bastard</ENAMEX> (liver blown away),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tupac Shakur</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groin</ENAMEX> blown away), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Weaver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strictly 4 My N.I.G.G</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.Z."</ENAMEX> (everything blown away) The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> take
pre-emptive action: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slick Rick</ENAMEX> recorded his last album while serving time for
attempted murder; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snoop Doggy Dogg</ENAMEX> was acquitted on technical grounds. "Out
here, it's not just about making the records," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapper</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronin Ro</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gangsta</ENAMEX> . "It's about staying alive after they're released." Rappers,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ro</ENAMEX>, "battle over who drinks more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">40s</ENAMEX>, kills more niggaz, jacks more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>,
slaps more hos," and all for the amusement of those white 'burb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the
reverse baseball caps.

            Pop music is mostly
minstrelsy: Following "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After The Ball</ENAMEX>," while black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ragtime composers</ENAMEX> starved,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">white Tin Pan Alley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> stuck "rag" in the titles of their novelty songs and
sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>. Today, we can see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>'s ever more bleached
complexion as a shorthand for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop</ENAMEX>'s history: He's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> to
become his own white cover version--to start out as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Richard</ENAMEX> and
transmogrify into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX>. But gangsta rap is something else: You'll hear
nothing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.C. Handy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellington</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie Wonder</ENAMEX> in rap; it's a negation of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of black music. Instead, in its principles, in its forms, in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunism</ENAMEX>, in its willingness to pass off individual pain as mass
entertainment, it returns us to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1890s</TIMEX>, to the whitest popular music we've
known in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Gangsta rap is the whitest black music there is. At
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX>: reverse minstrelsy.

             

         
      
   
