
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theme Party</ENAMEX>

            For most
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>, it's been a routine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> sneer that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have no sense
of irony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s poll numbers may finally be proving the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brits</ENAMEX> right. Dole
has run the most ironic, postmodern presidential campaign ever seen--starting
with his campaign theme song, the only conceivable purpose of which is to serve
as an ironic negation of everything campaign themes are meant to do. "" is a
takeoff on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> hit "I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Soul Man</ENAMEX>," and its most immediate quality is
that it's so un-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. It's a parodic campaign song: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> obviously has never
heard of it, any more than he's heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tupac Shakur</ENAMEX> or those other gangsta
rappers his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> periodically call on him to denounce. Then again,
considering that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98 percent</NUMEX> of all pop songs are gender-neutral (though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> toyed with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Can't Get a Man With a Gun"</ENAMEX>), the number seems to have
been especially picked for the blithe insouciance it shows toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
campaign's "gender gap." What do they do for a second <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chorus</ENAMEX>? "I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chick</ENAMEX>"? More ironic is that the song is an exquisite musicalization of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s most frequently cited defect: his campaign's lack of any central
theme. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole Man</ENAMEX>" isn't about anything at all. You can't blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> for having
trouble staying "on message" when the only message of his song is that you
should stand around twitching:

            
               I'm a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole Man</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Na</ENAMEX>-na-na-na, na-na.I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole Man</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Na</ENAMEX>-na, na-na .(Repeat until
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fade</ENAMEX>)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam &</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> sang the song back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> gave the campaign permission to
use it. I forget how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> voted on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> revisions to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 17</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Code, but it clearly never registered with him that, in pop songs, copyright
belongs to the copyright <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX>--in this case the recording <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>--not to the
recording <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the song's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> objected to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole Man</ENAMEX>," the
recording <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> backed him up, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s permission proved to be irrelevant.
So much for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s line that though he may not have a lot of fancy words, he's
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> and knows how things work.

            Compare all that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'92</TIMEX>, who went on the stump
to a that suited him perfectly. Yes, that's a cruel thing to say about anybody,
but the point is that it was a plausible soundtrack to his campaign:

            
               Don't
stopThinking about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>,Don't stopIt'll soon be here.
            

            This
quatrain distills brilliantly both the vapidity and ruthless single-mindedness
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. We can't say we weren't warned.

            For a campaign song that's pithy you have to go back to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1931</TIMEX> and the satirical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">musical Of Thee I Sing</ENAMEX> , in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John P.</ENAMEX>
Wintergreen campaigns for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> with a powerful slogan ("A Vote for
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wintergreen Is a Vote for Wintergreen</ENAMEX>") and a (by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gershwins</ENAMEX>) of just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
lines:

            

               Wintergreen for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>!Wintergreen for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>!He's the man the people
choose,Loves the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.
            

            
Unfortunately, the strategy wasn't so successful the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time around. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let 'Em Eat Cake</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John P. Wintergreen</ENAMEX> runs for
re-election and is defeated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John P. Tweedledee</ENAMEX>, with his :
            

            
               He's the man the
country seeks!Loves the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>!
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Gershwin</ENAMEX> was much better at spoof campaign songs than
the real thing. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>, he reworked "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It Ain't Necessarily So" for Adlai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevenson</ENAMEX> (and included the first sung reference to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-</ENAMEX>presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L'il Nixon</ENAMEX> was small, but oh, my/His office expenses were high") as
well as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Is Sweeping the Country</ENAMEX>" (also from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Of Thee I Sing</ENAMEX> ):

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai</ENAMEX>'s
sweeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>!He will be the next prez,We'll be leaningOn words with
meaning,For he means every word he says.
            

            It's funny
how hard it is to find anything to sing about. Most presidential elections in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>'s history have had specially commissioned themes: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teddy, Come</ENAMEX>
Back," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>--That's All," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Back Again</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>." But it wouldn't have made any difference if they'd been "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>'s the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Back Again</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>--That's All," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>,
Come Back."

            
As if to concede the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John P. Wintergreen</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P. Tweedledee</ENAMEX> interchangeability, most campaigns eventually settled for an
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">INSERT NAME OF CANDIDATE HERE</ENAMEX>" approach, shoehorning their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> into the
handiest existing song. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Cahn</ENAMEX> if he'd been pressed into
service. "Funny you should mention that," he said, "but I got a call from some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> who are backing a fellow called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>. So I wrote 'My Kind
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis Is</ENAMEX>).' "

            "A bit tricky to rhyme,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Dukakis</ENAMEX> is'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            "Sure,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy</ENAMEX>, "but there's always a way around. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> asked me if he could
use ',' I realized his name didn't fit any part of the tune. Where can you put
it?

            
               "Just
what makes the little old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ant</ENAMEX> Think he'll move a rubber-<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree plant</ENAMEX>?Ev'ryone
knows an antCan't Move a rubber-<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree plant</ENAMEX>,But he's got high hopes.
            

            "So, instead of that, I
spelled it out:

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K-E</ENAMEX>-double
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N-E-D-YJack</ENAMEX>'s the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ev</ENAMEX>'ryone wants to back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JackJack</ENAMEX> is
on the right track,And he's got high hopes."
            

            When I subsequently encountered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>, it seemed highly
unlikely that he could be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cahn's</ENAMEX> (or many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>') kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>--and, of
course, he wasn't particularly. Cahn was simply plying his trade. "I'm a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">songwriter</ENAMEX> and I play straight down the middle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> asked me to do a lyric
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiro Agnew</ENAMEX>, so I did." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amazingly</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who wrote "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Call Me</ENAMEX>
Irresponsible" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All the Way</ENAMEX>" insisted that the song he wrote to mark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meese</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> was one of his best lyrics ever.

            Perhaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrises</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Rollinses</ENAMEX> will find it easier to pick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who already
have the names of popular songs. Watching the shamelessly bogus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>! ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> "walking across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>," accompanied by
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in immaculately pressed plaid shirts they'd clearly changed
into in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, you began to wonder if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> himself wasn't just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Schmoe</ENAMEX> who'd changed his name just so he
could use "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ragtime Band</ENAMEX>" as his theme song.

            Should all else fail, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> can always resort to the theme from , which, on the basis of no
scientific evidence, is credited with mystical powers to transform any flagging
campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> has been using it in his post-"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dole Man</ENAMEX>" phase. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>,
facing similar difficulties, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> switched from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Copland</ENAMEX>'s "Fanfare
for the Common <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man</ENAMEX>" (too high-toned) to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gonna Fly Now</ENAMEX>," the theme from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> as the plucky little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX>). As we all know, he swept to a
fantastic victory that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
