
   
   
      
         
            Just Say No

            Every meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> impeachment inquiry ends with the same
bizarre ritual. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> go to the nearest microphone, call the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>'s conduct of the inquiry unfair, and accuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of
partisan warfare. Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> step before the same microphone, deny
that the inquiry is partisan, and insist that everyone is getting along. "No,
we're not," say the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. "Yes, we are," snap the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            It's not
hard to figure out who's going to win this fight. Politics, like litigation and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sports</ENAMEX>, is stacked in favor of the defense. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, it's far easier to
disrupt an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> yard drive than it is to sustain it. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good tackle
ruins a brilliant sequence of passes. In a criminal trial, one slick
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-examination of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> can plant enough doubt to hang the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>.
And in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, every eruption of "partisanship" or "unfairness," whether real
or manufactured, bleeds away the institutional credibility necessary to impeach
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who dominate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> don't like to
view politics this way. Cursed with a combination of irrational idealism and
irrational narcissism, they insist on interpreting public opinion and behavior
in ideological terms. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
Standard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> argued that the politics of the
impeachment inquiry "reminds me of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> on this date
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> announced the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With America</ENAMEX>, and the consensus in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> was ... <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> [had] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">overreached</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> were
mistaken then and are mistaken now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> suggested. "The underlying tide, I
think, is anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>."

            Of course,
hardly anyone who voted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> knew what was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With America</ENAMEX>. The
contract was designed not to win the election but to spin it, by inflating an
essentially negative referendum on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his health care reform plan into
an affirmative referendum on the conservative agenda. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> wasn't
endorsing conservatism when it threw out the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, any more than
it was endorsing liberalism when it turned against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s proposals for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> reform in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX>. It was just saying no.

            
In recent polls, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have essentially
said no to the question "Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior be tolerated?" But once
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> released his oversexed report and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> began parlaying it into impeachment proceedings, the question
changed to "Should he be impeached<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> said no--not because they
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">love Clinton</ENAMEX> or his agenda, but because they don't trust the impeachment
process any more than they trust national health insurance. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are deliberately and successfully exacerbating that mistrust.

            Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> understand this strategic disadvantage but mistakenly think that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> is the problem. They propose that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s high profile "bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>."
But no matter who becomes the "bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will attack him, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>, always hungry for conflict, will flock to the fight. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
console themselves by noting that some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will vote for a formal
impeachment inquiry. They're missing the point: The longer the inquiry drags
on, the more it will invite resentment, acrimony, and backlash. Conversely,
some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> worry that by accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> of bias, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> are making a nonimpeachment deal more difficult. But who says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
really wants a deal? From a purely political standpoint, now that he's
confident he won't be convicted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, his best move might be to let
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> antagonize more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> by marching all the way to an
impeachment vote.

            Recognizing the futility of arguing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, has begun to yield to their
demands. He agreed to send a bipartisan staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> to inspect documents
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> withheld from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> (which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> suspect may include exculpatory
evidence), ordered a hearing to address the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' query on what
constitutes an impeachable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>, and endorsed the idea of giving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> subpoena power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> "would like to make process, procedure
... the issue," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> observed. "We are doing our level best to be credible. If
we aren't credible, what we do amounts to nothing."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>'s
accommodations are noble but futile. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> can always find further
"unfairness" and "partisanship" to complain about. No sooner had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> announced
his concessions than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> amended their objections: The hearing on
impeachable offenses should have been at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> level, they argued, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> to examine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s records should include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> members
themselves, not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. "These are concessions, no question," admitted Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX> "But it's still not bipartisanship."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will be satisfied only if the
inquiry is transformed so thoroughly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> no longer stands to gain from
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> would like to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s encouragement of the
alleged quid pro quo in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> supposedly secured help in her
job search in exchange for submitting a false affidavit denying her affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. They'd like to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s taping of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as well as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s use of those tapes to launch his investigation. A federal grand jury
recently questioned conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Mellon Scaife</ENAMEX> in connection with
alleged witness tampering by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s Whitewater
investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> won't shut up about partisanship unless <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
agree to include those matters in the inquiry. And at that point, from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> standpoint, the inquiry isn't worth it.

            So how do
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> break through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' defense and carry the ball into
the end zone? The cynical answer is: They don't. They punt or fumble, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> carry the ball the other way. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> counteroffensive
has already begun. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> are on the campaign trail, accusing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> of substituting partisan impeachment proceedings for legislation to
address the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s ills. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> is conferring with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal activists</ENAMEX> about a nationwide ad campaign to bolster <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">denounce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> for bogging down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in "scandal, cynicism, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partisanship</ENAMEX>." Eventually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will overreach again, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>,
ever wary, will turn against them. It's not about ideology. It's about
cautiousness.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Games</ENAMEX>"
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gamble</ENAMEX>:
Why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by destroying themselves. (posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 25, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Unjust War</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
moral theory, point by point, as expressed in his testimony. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 21, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
