
   
   
      
         
            Where Have You Gone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Hammerstein</ENAMEX>?

            The subtitle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>'s new book tells you the whole story-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enchanted Evenings</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Musical From Show Boat to Sondheim</ENAMEX> . For some of us, that's not
progress. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX>, what was once the mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> popular
culture, an ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> river that seemed set to jes' keep rollin' along forever,
has shriveled away to one toxic little stream on a dry, barren mud flat. You
can measure the difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show Boat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sondheim</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a thousand</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> is as good a way
as any. Defending the cause of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebonics</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Emmons</ENAMEX> of Los Angeles
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City College</ENAMEX> asserts, among other fancies, that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black English</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spirituals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Dat Ole Man River,' 'Ah Got Shoes'</ENAMEX>)."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ol' Man</ENAMEX>
River" is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> spiritual. It's a show tune cooked up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX> by a couple
of middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">honkies</ENAMEX> who needed something for a spot in the first act. Yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Hammerstein</ENAMEX>'s lyric is full of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">dat" and "dese"</ENAMEX> (obviously, he was
self-taught at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebonics</ENAMEX>), but funnily enough, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Robeson</ENAMEX> sang the song in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> production of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show Boat</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>, the biggest problem he had
was wrapping his beautiful, impeccable vowels around the soi-disant
dialect lyric. Ever since, most black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> have preferred to sing
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Ol' Man River</ENAMEX>." If I were a sweating stevedore on the levee out by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City College</ENAMEX>, it would be sorely tempting to mock the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ol</ENAMEX>' man
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmons</ENAMEX>,Dat ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmons</ENAMEX>,He mus' know sumpin'He don' check nothin'.

            But, in a way, he has a point, albeit not the one he thinks
he's making: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>'s is an unobtrusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>, an artless art. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ol</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man</ENAMEX>
River" was the song in which he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> found his lyrical voice, compressing the
suffering, resignation, and anger of an entire race into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> taut lines and
doing it so naturally that it's no wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> assume the song's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spiritual</ENAMEX>. If it's any consolation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>'s very last lyric,
"Edelweiss" from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sound of Music</ENAMEX> , is invariably assumed to be a real
Austrian folk song--indeed, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> went further,
playing it at a state banquet for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, under the impression
that it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s national anthem. The great strength of these songs,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the reasons they seep into our collective consciousness, is that they
barely seem written at all.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of music at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puget Sound</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Music</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tacoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>, is determined to change all that. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enchanted Evenings</ENAMEX> is
less concerned with enchantment than with the painstaking artistic judgments
that lead to it. So here he is getting stuck in to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show Boat :</ENAMEX>

            In the
thrice-repeated opening phrase of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where's the Mate for Me?</ENAMEX>" the first shown in
Example 2.5a ("Who cares if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> goes up stream" and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> statements of "I
drift along with my fancy"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">) Kern</ENAMEX> ingeniously varies the harmony of the final
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">melodic</ENAMEX> note D (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Example 2.5b</ENAMEX> and c). Its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appearance on the words
"upstream" (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> measure) is paradoxically the lowest note of the
phrase--after all, the point is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ravenal</ENAMEX> does not care whether he is going
upstream or downstream. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kern</ENAMEX> harmonizes the tonic or central key, D, with
a conventional tonic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-major triad. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> measure of the next statement
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Example 2.5b</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kern</ENAMEX> sets the word "fancy" with a fancy (and deceptive)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> to a minor triad on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> degree of the scale. On the final
statement of this phrase (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Example 2.5c</ENAMEX>), <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ravenal</ENAMEX> hears
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnolia</ENAMEX>'s piano theme and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kern</ENAMEX> displays his fanciest chord, again on the word
"fancy."

            
Ah, they don't write 'em like that anymore.
There's only one problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>'s approach: That's not how it happened. In
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99 percent</NUMEX> of his songs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome Kern</ENAMEX>'s music was written before the words, and
he was notorious for declining to accommodate his lyricists--no extra notes so
that an ingenious word might be made to fit, and certainly no concessions to
literal meaning in his melody or harmony. He didn't "set" the word "fancy" at
all, and that fanciest chord was there long before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX> fixed the words
to those notes. It's possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>, coming upon "the lowest note of
the phrase," thought, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, I'll write 'upstream' there. How's that for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">paradox?</ENAMEX>" but I doubt it: That's not the way the ear hears music, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX> was too sensitive a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lyricist</ENAMEX> to be so numbingly literal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>
Kretzmer, one of the lyricists of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Mis√©rables</ENAMEX> , put it to me this way:
"It's a question of finding what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Mercer</ENAMEX> called the sound of the
music. You're trying to capture something as elusive as a sound, which suggests
a word, from which eventually a complete lyric emerges."

            Still, you can't blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>
for trying. He's coming at it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conservatory</ENAMEX> end of things and, if
you're used to opera, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> of words and music in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> song must take
your breath away. Operas have plots and lyrics. But the words have no
relationship to the music. Or, to put it the other way round, the music takes
no account of the words.

            
"
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La donna √</ENAMEX>® mobile. " The worst <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tin Pan Alley</ENAMEX> hack wouldn't give
so much weight to the definite article because he'd know it was the most
insignificant word in the line. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verdi</ENAMEX>? He couldn't give a hoot. Insofar as
he gives the lyrics a thought, it's only to say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stand</ENAMEX> well back, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. I'm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flyin</ENAMEX>'!"

            Good musicals are both specific and universal. But they're
specific because the words fit the shape of the tune, not because the tune is a
translation of the words--the method <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX> appears to favor. Here he is
banging on with his upstream/downstream, high note/low note approach again:

            [I]n
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're the Top</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX> does not capitalize on the text's potential for
realism. Although the "I" always appears in the bottom throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most of the</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">song</ENAMEX>, the "you" blithely moves back and forth from top to bottom. The upward
leaping orchestral figure anticipates the word, "top," but the sung line does
not, and at the punchline, "But if <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby</ENAMEX> I'm the bottom, / You're the top," both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> ("I'm" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're"</ENAMEX>) share a melodic line at the top of their
respective ranges.

            Phew! That entire paragraph deserves a rousing chorus of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're the Pits</ENAMEX>!" With his fixation on tops and bottoms, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>'s beginning to
sound like the gay personal ads in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX>. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kern</ENAMEX> with
his top paradoxically on his bottom, poor old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX> gets no credit for having
his bottom paradoxically on his top. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>'s so busy following the vocal score
that he's not hearing the song. For nonmusicologists, that "upward leaping
orchestral figure" he mentions is the bit that goes:

            
[Plink-plink!] You're the top!

            
[<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plink-plinketty-plink-plink</ENAMEX>!] You're the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Coliseum</ENAMEX> ...

            Not only
is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You're the Top</ENAMEX>" one of the few songs where the little orchestral fill-ins
are an intrinsic part of the song but, more than that, the fill-ins actually
are the song: The sung bits "paradoxically" are the fill-ins--little
conversational lyric phrases that fall in the gaps between the
plinketty-plinks. If you know that, good for you; if you don't, it doesn't
matter. But how could you sit down and analyze the thing and fail to notice it?
As to the bottoms winding up on top, as a self-contained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lyricist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX> knew enough to let a good strong lyric-thrust set itself. How could
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX> be so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>-headed as to think that "But if <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby</ENAMEX> I'm the bottom,/ You're
the top" could possibly be improved by putting "I'm" and "bottom" on low notes?
It's the (relative) musical monotony of the phrase that makes it so insistent,
so driving, and such a brilliantly effective cap to the song. It's the punch
line; it's the exclamation point. How sad that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>, for all his technical
ability, can't hear that.

            So maybe we're better off with ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmons</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misattributing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>'s work to dirt-poor <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pickers</ENAMEX> and lonely
goatherds than with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>'s misguided praise. In great popular art, after all,
you notice the art, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>. Which brings us to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>'s final chapter:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Sondheim</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ol' Man River</ENAMEX>" is a powerful, memorable lyric is
that there's no rhyme until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>
rhymes when the song requires it--a lesson his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pupil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sondheim</ENAMEX>, has forgotten.
In Into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> (as in the beanstalk) tells her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to sell the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> because:

            We've no time to sit and
dither

            While her
withers wither with her.

            We're back
to the pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX> era: you're distanced from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> because all you
can hear is the voice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sondheim</ENAMEX> has given us plotless musicals
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Company</ENAMEX> ) and characterless musicals ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Overtures</ENAMEX> ) and
pointillist musicals ( <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park</ENAMEX> With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> ) and musicals that
go backward ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Merrily We Roll Along</ENAMEX> ), but for all the supposed range and
depth and variety, what you mainly notice about these musicals is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sondheim</ENAMEX>.
It's the triumph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> over the art: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who knows more than anyone
else about musicals except how to write one where you don't notice how much he
knows; the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> who repays <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Block</ENAMEX>'s analytical approach if only because
that seems his natural home. I think of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Thing Going</ENAMEX>," his wonderfully
brooding ballad from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrily</ENAMEX> , with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> title resolution:

            "We had a good thing going
...

            Going ...

            Gone."

            And, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sondheim</ENAMEX>, it
is gone.

         
      
   
