
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cohen</ENAMEX>

             

            
               I give the answer; you
give the question and identify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I think it's obvious that I
haven't looked for a way out here; what I've looked for is a way
forward."
            

             

            by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to
e-mail your answer (NewsQuiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>).

            
               Responses
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 2</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taste Makers":</ENAMEX>
            

            
               Fill in
the blank:
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffy Shutt</ENAMEX>, president
of marketing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>, told a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, "By
sheer bulk, the _______________ are driving cultural tastes now. They're
amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>."
            

            "Special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Kelly</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Milner</ENAMEX> had a similar
answer)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEETLE GIRLS</ENAMEX>. And, as a
side note, I'm taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy Shutt</ENAMEX> as my new porn name."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sherman</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Producers</ENAMEX> I've slept with
who then go right to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain alcohol</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Franzen</ENAMEX>
            

            "McCaugheys? (Actually, is
it the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl audience</ENAMEX>? Just a hunch.)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Wolitzer</ENAMEX> (similarly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> )

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX> banking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conspirators</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zionist Operated Government</ENAMEX> soon to be brought low by my
military-grade anthrax; soon that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX> of seething <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pervs</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> of sin
called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, will see its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> rivers run with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and ...
what? Oh, sorry, wrong Web page."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rakoff</ENAMEX>
            

            " 'The pendulous testicles
of aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Berle</ENAMEX> ...' Although the real answer may be: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) financially independent lipstick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX>; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>)
roving bands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX>--I refuse to give a legitmate response to any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">'fill</ENAMEX>-in-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blanks</ENAMEX>' that involve any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Buffy Shutt</ENAMEX>.'
"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Amoros</ENAMEX>
            

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Lippert</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Right Wing Conspiracy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nut Moms</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            "Olestra-shunning fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teen-agers of America</ENAMEX>. (Think about it: If you can't read, what else are you
going to do but eat?)"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Franklin</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Doughty</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who have had sex
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and been bought off with a job."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Stewart</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s
Wrap-Up:
            

            Your contempt for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
taste is as bracing as a splash of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Spice</ENAMEX>, now with real buttery flavor.
Thank heaven for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Sherman</ENAMEX> (same initials as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy Shutt</ENAMEX>: suspicious?), who
clearly knows--as did several of you--that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> taste is in the hands of
teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. This accounts for the popularity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> ; and that new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV Mutual Fund</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the adorable
drawings of ponies on the prospectus.

            That's
why, as a campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, I advise my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to be sexually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unthreatening</ENAMEX>, have very little body hair, and possess voices that can
effortlessly lift an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inoffensive</ENAMEX> pop tune well into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soprano</ENAMEX> register. Which
perhaps explains the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX> (if you accept a bald
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> as a substitute for a bare chest).

            
               "Taste <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Makers</ENAMEX>"
True<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-Life Hollywood Answer:</ENAMEX>
            

            "young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>"

            Buffy
Shutt was offering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> consensus that teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are becoming the
dominant force influencing the success of movies. Unlike teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, who go
to a movie once with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> often see the same film many times,
and frequently attend in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disclaimer</ENAMEX>: All submissions will become the property of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> and
will be published at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's discretion. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> may publish your
name on its site in connection with your submission.
            

         
      
   
