
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Worst Songwriter of All Time</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> wrote one of the most recognizable, most parodied, and (for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">non-Streisand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>) most irritating lyrics of all time:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">PeoplePeople</ENAMEX> who need
peopleAre the luckiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world.

            I don't
know whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who needed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and, if he did, whether he
considered himself lucky for so doing. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other week</TIMEX> he went out to the
driveway of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and shot himself. He was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>. When the elderly
kill themselves, we gloss over that fact: It isn't really a tragedy, not like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen-ager</ENAMEX>'s suicide, or a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s. But, for the record, aside from
self-destructing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Cobain</ENAMEX>, I can't think of another hit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">songwriter</ENAMEX> who's taken his life. I only had a very slight acquaintance with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>, but it seems a sad end for someone who wrote more determinedly happy
songs than anyone in history.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of pop music, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Merrill</ENAMEX> pretty much has a
hammerlock on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of the 1950s</TIMEX>. Even then, he wasn't exactly a
household name--and, if you beg to differ, chances are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household</ENAMEX>'s mixing
him up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Merrill</ENAMEX>, the great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX> baritone who appeared
around the same time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>) chose the diminutive deliberately to avoid
confusion with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>), though it's hard to see why anyone would think
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who makes his living singing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verdi</ENAMEX> would go home at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
and write "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">If I Knew You Were Comin', I'd've Baked a Cake</ENAMEX>." That was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> hit. He'd been head <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> and dialogue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
Pictures, but when he tried to break into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tin Pan Alley</ENAMEX>, they kept telling him
his stuff was too complex. He took their advice to heart--and how:

            If I knew you were comin',
I'd've baked a cakeBaked a cakeBaked a cakeIf I knew you were comin', I'd've
baked a cakeHowdja do?<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Howdja</ENAMEX> do?<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Howdja</ENAMEX> do?

            Not
exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenz Hart</ENAMEX>. But it sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> followed it with an
even bigger song, "(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How Much Is) That Doggie in the Window?</ENAMEX>" a hit for Patti
Page--or, to give her her formal title, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Singing Rage</ENAMEX> Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patti Page</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Posterity</ENAMEX> hasn't been that kind to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patti</ENAMEX> and her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-legged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. "It would
be unfair to call this a nursery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rhyme</ENAMEX>; it was childish rather than childlike,"
writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Clarke</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rise and Fall of Popular Music</ENAMEX> . "Nobody
knows how many music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> stopped listening to the radio after hearing 'Doggie
In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Window</ENAMEX>' too many times." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>'s being a little harsh. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '50s</TIMEX>,
don't forget, were the heyday of the dog song, and rare was the pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> who
managed to avoid having one inflicted on him: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century later</TIMEX>, Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> will sock you on the jaw if you so much as mention "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama Will Bark</ENAMEX>,"
his canine love duet with the big-breasted faux-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dagmar</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Singing Dogs</ENAMEX>, who barked their way through "Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Susanna</ENAMEX>," are more relaxed
about it, but then, of course, they are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. By these standards,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>'s song was, as they say at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Kennel Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best in Show</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novelty</ENAMEX> songs, they used to call them. But, in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '50s</TIMEX>, novelties weren't so much a novelty as terrifyingly ubiquitous.
If you want the entire history of pop music on one single--the tug between its
highest aspirations and its basest instincts--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> wrapped it up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>: on
the B side, "I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fool to Want You</ENAMEX>," an almost painfully exposed ballad that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ranks as one of his greatest recordings; but, on the A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> ... yes,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama Will Bark</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Miller</ENAMEX>, top <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Records</ENAMEX>, insisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>
do it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> wound up leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, but he never forgave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>
later, they happened to be crossing a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> from opposite ends. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
extended his hand in friendship; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> snarled, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fuck you</ENAMEX>! Keep walking!"

            But so what? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> was a loser. The smart money was on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s new discovery, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>--nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, pleasant voice, no trouble. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> didn't want "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sparrow</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treetop</ENAMEX>," so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> gave it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell</ENAMEX>, along with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Truly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truly Fair</ENAMEX>,"
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Belle, Belle, My Liberty Belle</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Feet Up</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Him</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Po-Po</ENAMEX>)," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"She Wears</ENAMEX>
Red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Feathers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And a Hula-Hula Skirt</ENAMEX>)" and "There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Pawnshop on the Corner</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>"--the biggest hit ever written about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>.

            All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
songs were by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Merrill</ENAMEX>, all were arranged with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s unrelenting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jolliness</ENAMEX> (whooping <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> horns throughout), and all were smashes. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>
had a yen to write <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>-meets-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, it didn't show: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>-meets-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">girl-</ENAMEX>meets-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, sparrow-meets-treetop ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> songs are supposed to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Will Always Love You"</ENAMEX>--but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> was specific with a vengeance:
Even if you were minded to write a song about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gal</ENAMEX> who wears red feathers and
a huley-huley skirt and lives on jes' cokeynuts, why would you open with the
line "I work in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>"? It remains, incidentally, the biggest hit ever
written about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> who meets a hula-hula <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.

            He composed, in case you hadn't guessed, on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s toy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">xylophone</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1950 and 1955</TIMEX>, it also cranked out "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where Will the Baby</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dimple Be?</ENAMEX>" "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mambo Italiano</ENAMEX>," and my personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oooh</ENAMEX>, Bang, Jiggily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jang</ENAMEX>." Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> don't like these songs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary Clooney</ENAMEX>, revisiting
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mambo Italiano</ENAMEX>" for a recent autobiographical album, explains in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX>
notes how much she loathes all her early hits--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come On-a My House</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Armenian</ENAMEX>
novelty song), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who Don Mon Man</ENAMEX>" (calypso novelty song), "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Botch-a Me</ENAMEX>" (botched
novelty song). But you have to admire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>'s resourcefulness: Any old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opportunist</ENAMEX> can write a novelty <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> song (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"That's Amore</ENAMEX>") or a novelty
mambo song (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Papa Loves Mambo</ENAMEX>"), but to write a novelty song about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>
doing the mambo--that takes guts:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, Mambo!Mambo Italiano
...Go, go, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>!You mixed-up Siciliano

            The guy
who wrote that gets hammered from both ends. To those who love the great
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> standards, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who single-handedly produced the worst
songs of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> and so debauched the currency of mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tin Pan Alley</ENAMEX>
that it had no moral authority to resist rock 'n' roll. And, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-boom
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rockers</ENAMEX>, when all other musical, lyrical, and sociopolitical claims for the
rock 'n' roll revolution have collapsed, the memory of growing up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> songbook will always be justification enough.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX> moved on to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>.
Having been told he was too complex for pop music, he was now regarded as too
simple-minded to write show scores. But, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33 years</TIMEX> after he gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streisand</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>," she's still singing it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, over the instrumental
break, she's prone to toss in a homily about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">world</ENAMEX> peace and how, whether we're
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>; are young, old, black, white, gay,
straight, or transsexual, we're all still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. When
she first sang the song, in the musical biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fanny Brice</ENAMEX>, Funny
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girl</ENAMEX> , it was about precisely the opposite: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fanny</ENAMEX> was so obsessed with her
public identity that she'd neglected the personal; she could love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> but
not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brolin</ENAMEX> and the more assiduous tabloid reporters
know whether that's true of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra</ENAMEX> in private, but it's increasingly the case
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">professionally</ENAMEX>: She declaims her love songs as if addressing an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> rather than "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ostensibly Bob Merrill</ENAMEX>'s most
general lyric, it is, in fact, the most specific of all.

         
      
   
