
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Only Living Boy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>

            I wasn't
paying much attention to the in-house music on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX>--I think it was
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Drummer Boy</ENAMEX>" in the bookstore, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jingle Bell Rock</ENAMEX>" in the toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, or
maybe vice versa--but, entering the flower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, it hit me instantly:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernadette</ENAMEX>." From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Songs From the Capeman</ENAMEX> . The bit just
before he slows the whole thing down and goes:

            I am Sal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mineo</ENAMEX> and I need you so.

            It's a
gorgeous song. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>'s voice sounds as young as it did on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homeward Bound</ENAMEX>," and
the number brims with all the possibilities of teen romance in those hot '50s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summers</ENAMEX>. I've been singing it ever since I heard the demo tape, and I'm glad
that that florist liked it enough to play it.

            But I wonder how many others will get to hear it. The
Capeman , the story of an adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican killer</ENAMEX>, is having a hard
time taking off. The album is selling tepidly; the show's been picketed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>'-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and is under threat of more pickets by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Ricans</ENAMEX>
opposed to racial stereotyping; the opening's been postponed to the end of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>; and, depending on which rumor you believe, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s either so
complacent that he only bothers dropping by once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so dozy</TIMEX> that he
hasn't noticed he's been more or less replaced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Graduate</ENAMEX> )
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Saigon</ENAMEX> ) Hytner or, most recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolls ) Zaks</ENAMEX>.

            So far so
normal for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> show in previews. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Capeman</ENAMEX> isn't just
another dud musical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like Sideshow or The Scarlet Pimpernel</ENAMEX> . It
was supposed to be the show that would heal the great historic rift between pop
music and theater scores, the first show written specifically for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> by a
major rock songwriter and the one that would entice all the others in, ending
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great White Way</ENAMEX>'s dependence on its shrunken nontalent pool of insipid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sondheim</ENAMEX> clones.

            
"They say they want something new, but
they don't really," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX>. "They want something old." We're standing
a gazillion <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> above <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week or so</TIMEX> before it all began to go
wrong. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> wouldn't want to characterize the diminutive, balding rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> as
being (in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole Porter</ENAMEX>'s marvelous phrase) down in the depths on the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">90 th</NUMEX> floor, but a faint tinge of melancholy hangs in the air. "What
do you think?" he says. "Do you think they want something new?"

            "They"
are the elderly, lizardlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> who preside over what's left of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>--the nonshowy showmen, party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bookers</ENAMEX>, and theater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> into whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hands Simon</ENAMEX> has more or less delivered himself. He seems genuinely befuddled by
them. In the rock biz, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are old, too. But at least they
make an effort, sporting ponytails and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U2</TIMEX> tour jackets; they don't continually
give the impression that they wish there was a part for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Goulet</ENAMEX> in
whatever it is they are working on. Around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> the standard line is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>, with his reputation for "arrogance" and as a "control freak," has
disdained their expertise.

            
"In the beginning," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>, "they said to
me there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world who can do this, and here are
their names. And I believed it--what did I know? That's why we've been through
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Walcott</ENAMEX> and I didn't want an auteur <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. We had
taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to write it, so why would we want someone who says, 'I think this
part should go over here and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is really a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" His voice
trails away. "If that's arrogant ..."

            To prepare
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Capeman</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> put himself through a dispiriting crash course in
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> attractions. "I saw a couple of shows I liked, but most I
didn't. I really liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> ... I liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolls</ENAMEX> ... er
... I kinda liked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show Boat</ENAMEX> . But the rest of the stuff, I can't say I
found interesting." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> wouldn't want to exaggerate the points of contact but,
curiously, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Capeman</ENAMEX> is the first musical since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Show Boat</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</TIMEX> to use the word "niggers" in its opening number:

            Afraid to
leave the project, to cross into another

                      
neighborhood

            The blancos
and the nigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>, well, they'd kill you

                   
   if they could.

            They're not quite the first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> lyrics to be heard
on-stage. That distinction belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> "theater
piece," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> , which contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> quatrain by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>:

            Half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
stonedAnd the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> are waiting for the next electionHalf the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
drownedAnd the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> are swimming in the wrong direction.

            "He just
liked the lyrics," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>. "I said he could have them in return for
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">opening-night</TIMEX> tickets--which he never sent me." They were originally written
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zeffirelli</ENAMEX> film that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> were working on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny</ENAMEX> fancied
himself as pretty hip, but his young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborator</ENAMEX> wasn't impressed by the older
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s attempts at rock. "He played a melody, and it was an awkward moment. He
said: 'If we're going to collaborate, we have to be completely honest. So what
do you think?' I said: 'Well, that's not very good. That's not rock 'n' roll.'
He was taken aback." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> drew himself up and said huffily: "This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Bernstein</ENAMEX> music."

            If you're a bona fide rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, it's hard to take
seriously the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>'s nervous tiptoeing into the territory. "I never thought
Hair was really rock 'n' roll," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX>, "but now, supposedly"--he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grins</ENAMEX>--"it's a classic!" Hair , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godspell</ENAMEX> , the title song of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phantom</ENAMEX> , the current sensation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rent</ENAMEX> (the "rock opera" that so
distracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit</ENAMEX> nanny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX> from her household duties), all
are unconvincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hybrids</ENAMEX>--neither good rock nor good show tunes. The
conventional wisdom, argued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sondheim</ENAMEX> among others, is that rock is difficult
to use dramatically. "Well, I don't think it's difficult," retorts
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>. "But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were trying to write it weren't coming from rock 'n'
roll--they were doing an impression of rock 'n' roll. And, since
everyone knows what rock 'n' roll sounds like, it wasn't fooling very many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>."

            In
fairness, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> found it hard to attract genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX>. At the end of
his life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Jay Lerner</ENAMEX>, author of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Fair Lady</ENAMEX> , used to bemoan that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> had never written for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>. But rock lyricists
earn their reputations with the kind of elliptical poetic impenetrability that
looks great reprinted on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> gatefold LP sleeve. However, when you're
sitting in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chance to grab those words as they're flying
across the footlights at you. It's a surprise, then, to find that The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capeman</ENAMEX> 's lyrics are more direct, less allusive--that, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of
writing more and more about himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> has been able to write in the voice
of characters far less articulate. I don't know whether he's "arrogant" or a
"control freak" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> or the rehearsal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, but where it counts--in
the music and lyrics--you can hear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who is, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57</NUMEX>, still trying to
learn.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just under a decade ago</TIMEX>, I did a TV special
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> that was filmed partly at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brill Building</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> setting up a perfect shot for the interview, looking
down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>, the picture framed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cats marquee</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX>
Garden and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> nd Street billboard in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peeked</ENAMEX> through the camera and said: "That's just a generic shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>.
That's nothing to do with who I am." So everything was dismantled and the crew
set up at the opposite corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, away from the window. It was a
telling image: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> was literally turning his back on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>.

            Not anymore. Clearly, it's
still not an entirely comfortable fit. But, whatever happens to The
Capeman , I hope he won't give up on the theater. There's more musical
invention in a song like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trailways Bus</ENAMEX>" than in the entire score of the much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ballyhooed Ragtime</ENAMEX> . It's nothing to do with rock vs. showtunes, only
with the cruel truth that most contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> music isn't very good: not
popular music, not serious music, but existing in some grisly limbo in between.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broadway</ENAMEX> can't afford to kiss off a rare musical voice like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon's</ENAMEX>, no matter
how much glee it might afford the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schadenfreude</ENAMEX> set. Negotiating a
tricky midlife career change, caught between rock and a hard place, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX>
figures that sometimes, as with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graceland</ENAMEX> , the gamble pays off. "Every
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> decide they're bored and they want something fresh. So that's
a good time to have something fresh." He shrugs fatalistically. "The rest of
the time they say, nyyah, I don't get it."

         
      
   
