
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wandering Eyes, Drifting Chin</ENAMEX>

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and soul it has been
difficult for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tabloidland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, with a surfeit of romantic
calamities, plastic surgery disasters, and urological deaths and rebirths.

            A more
perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> (of the catastrophic type) than that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> producer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Evans</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX>, and onetime <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dynasty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Oxenberg</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>,
would be hard to achieve. It was summed up by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, who
observed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , "Who'd have guessed the marriage would go bad
faster than the leftover <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their wedding</TIMEX> reception?" While details
differ, all the tabs agree that courtship to annulment took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> less than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oxenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">princess</ENAMEX> (who knew there was such a thing?), believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>--who is recovering
from a stroke--when he promised to help her career. But she began to have
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thoughts during their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX> honeymoon, which she spent
weeping on the phone to her live-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, who was home watering their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> says the marriage effectively ended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> and
officially ended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> says the marriage, his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>, lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>. The romance began when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> told her he had a vision of an angel who
looked just like her during his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>-induced near-death experience. She
agreed to marry him out of sympathy, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, believing he
wouldn't live <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than six months</TIMEX>. He must have been disconcertingly robust on
their honeymoon, because during it she told him she was returning to her former
and possibly future fiance.

            According
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> , the marriage endured for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 whole days</TIMEX> before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxenberg</ENAMEX> returned home to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>. In its version, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxenberg</ENAMEX> had recently
been at a spiritual retreat in which she was told to help others. When she met
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and he told her about his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, she "thought this was a
sign"--a sign, apparently, to behave as if she had had a stroke. The
publication quotes her telling a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> told me he couldn't have sex
since his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>, I figured, what the hell--I'll marry him because I
desperately want to help him." Unfortunately for their marriage, she was too
effective a helper. As she napped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, he came in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , "stark naked--and it was obvious he was quite capable of
consummating the marriage." <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Oxenberg</ENAMEX> behaved as would any young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>: She
"jumped out of bed and said, 'I'm not you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> anymore. I'm leaving you and
never coming back.' " On the other hand, perhaps this is a custom of what must
be the ever-dwindling band of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> royals.

            
Also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, the tabs implicitly pose the
question: Can love flourish again once the restraining order has expired?
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Thomas</ENAMEX> recently
showed up hand in hand at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, having skipped a court
date for their divorce suit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne</ENAMEX> and her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard husband</ENAMEX> became
estranged on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, when in an excessive spirit of revelry he
threatened to drive his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> through their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> filed for
divorce and got a court order keeping him <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100 yards</NUMEX> from her. But now a friend
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> reveals <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> has stopped drinking, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> has supposedly
said, "I feel like I actually divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> and married a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>--because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> is a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." No word if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Ben</ENAMEX> has to abide by the prenuptial agreement
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Old Ben</ENAMEX>.

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halle Berry</ENAMEX>, who
had obtained a restraining order against her ex-husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Indians</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">outfielder David Justice</ENAMEX>, during their acrimonious divorce, was recently seen
dating him, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . Also in a forgiving mood is singer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitney Houston</ENAMEX>, who, report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , was seen in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> with her often-arrested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Brown</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only weeks</TIMEX> after the tabs
promised their marriage had come to an end.

            While the
Star is alleging that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> realizes his marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Demi Moore</ENAMEX>
is really over and that he is ready to fight for joint custody of their three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> believes reconciliation is in the air. According
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> is willing to consider giving it another try, but
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> she wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> to compile a list of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> he slept with during
their marriage, in order to have "an honest relationship." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>, probably
fearing that compiling such a list would cause crippling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s cramp, has
refused. And he would certainly be backed up on that decision by a couple
currently in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1600 Pennsylvania Ave.</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> does not speculate on the legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ramifications</ENAMEX>, but it does report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accuser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> has
completed her makeover with a nose job. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> has not yet unveiled her
newly diminished honker, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> offers a computer generated "preview"
that makes her look terrifyingly like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee Gifford</ENAMEX>.

            While it's
too early to tell if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> will join the legion of plastic surgery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, the
tabs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> report on attempts at surgical improvement gone awry. Pity poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melanie Griffith</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reported that the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> "desperately" needed a face lift. So, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reports, she underwent a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five hour</TIMEX> overhaul. Let's hope she's
taken the advice of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Banderas</ENAMEX>, as reported in the
Star , and laid off the lip collagen. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, he is
concerned that her lips--the upper one sometimes appears as if a hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> has
been inserted in it--are starting to look "unrealistically big."

            
Uncooperative implants are another celebrity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plague</ENAMEX>. After getting cheek and chin implants and facial liposuction, talk show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Jessy Raphael</ENAMEX> ended up with such a "lopsided smile," reports the
Star , that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> called in wondering if she'd had a stroke. The
publication also alleges that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Burnett</ENAMEX>'s wandering chin is the result of
an implant that won't stay put." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocker Stevie Nicks</ENAMEX> solved the wandering
implant problem by having her silicone breast implants removed and keeping them
in her freezer "to remind me of the agony," according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Turner</ENAMEX>'s breast implants "drifted
so far apart she lost her cleavage." She went back to her plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>, and
after he fixed them she admired his handiwork so much that a romance between
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> might have ensued, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>.

            A change
in ethnic identity is another danger of an overzealous scalpel. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's plastic surgery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome Craft</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, TV news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchorman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> had his face pulled a "bit tight,
giving his eyes a slightly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> look." Changing identities is the goal of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> . Though the publication
doesn't report any plastic surgery in her future, when her legal troubles are
over she wants to make a "fresh start" and plans to do so with a name change.
Her current favorite is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audrey Seville</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> doesn't report where
"Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>" ranks on the list.

            Perhaps if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had suffered the same terrible
fate as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley Moore</ENAMEX>, he would now be suffering less. According to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s estranged <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Rothschild</ENAMEX>, claims he
became impotent after they wed. "All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley</ENAMEX> ever wanted to do was go to bed
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> reports she said. "But when he became impotent, it
took his identity away." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> did what any loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> would do in those
circumstances: "I tried everything. I had my breasts enlarged. I had a nose
job. Nothing worked." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> is in dire shape after a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. It does not report whether he has sought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Oxenberg</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Hefner</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX>, allegedly
needs no nursing, just a little blue, diamond-shaped pill. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> "are worried that
he's popping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX> and eventually his heart is going to explode."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hefner</ENAMEX>, recently separated from his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX>, a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Playmate of the Year</ENAMEX>, has been seeing a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centerfold</ENAMEX>, among others.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX> is worried that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, who had a stroke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, will be "found
dead of a heart attack while in bed with one of those bimbos," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX>
claims. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hefner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> says his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> does not appear to be in any danger of
imminent demise, but if he does die the way his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> fears, "I'm sure that's
how he'd want to go."

         
      
   
