
   
   
      
         
            Executive Privileges

            Her lips as vivid as the
plumage of the vermilion flycatcher, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> returns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to the
covers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> . In a detailed
account of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> trysts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as a sort
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Salome</ENAMEX>, arousing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with her dance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> dress, only
to hand the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of Bill the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Baptist</ENAMEX>.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexual</ENAMEX> encounters (depending on your definition of the phrase) in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            
Apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with precise, if deranged, views on the
matter. How many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51-year-olds</TIMEX> could write philosophic treatises on getting to
first, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> base? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> allowed them to engage in kissing and "heavy petting" while they had
their clothes on. Once things got hot, however, "[h]e and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> would
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unclench</ENAMEX>--and she would perform a private strip show for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," making
sure "the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> refrained from touching each other." All right, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abelard</ENAMEX> and
Héloise it's not--with the staining of the dress it's probably closer to "Hints
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heloise</ENAMEX>." The damned spot occurred, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , during one of
these episodes, while the dress lay on the carpet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>"
explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "believes that if they weren't touching in any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undress</ENAMEX>, that it's not technically sexual relations." Let's see, making out
with someone, then ejaculating while she strips in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> does not
constitute sexual relations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, that's good, that's good.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> also reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> agent
and former top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes "</ENAMEX>walked in on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and his
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> while the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were enjoying an extended stay in the private study."
It does not report if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> subsequently began to hang "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do Not Disturb</ENAMEX>" signs
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> doorknobs.

            Ickes
makes a very different kind of appearance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> package. In it he is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra</ENAMEX>, cursed to have his prophecies
disbelieved: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When Ickes</ENAMEX> first tried to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> was spreading
stories that could be harmful to him, he refused to listen." In this version of
events, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> got sucked into an innocent "paternal" relationship (we're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entering Woody Allen</ENAMEX> territory here) with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he supposedly characterized
as "wide-eyed and young and I knew she got a thrill out of talking to me." What
he eventually came to realize, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> quotes him telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>,
is that "[t]he <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is dangerous. She hallucinates. She fantasizes. I don't
know if she even knows what the truth really is anymore."

            
On the other hand, according to another story
in the very same issue, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports what no one else has--that
she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> went all the way. In this version of events, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> believed
their dalliance was a true love affair. "I thought he turned to me because his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is so cold," another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> has her saying. But soon she realized she was
not to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallis Warfield Simpson</ENAMEX>. "I saw my dreams start to unravel
when he told me I should return the gifts," she is quoted as saying. Despite
feeling humiliated and enraged, she did it, because "I didn't want him to be
hurt. I loved him."

            Since
it's difficult to reconcile the portrait of the "virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychopath</ENAMEX> who had
created an entire fantasy world involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who now wanted
to destroy him," with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was pursued then "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coldly</ENAMEX> dumped" by him,
the only prudent conclusion to draw from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> is that we have
one wacky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> also calls in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of forensic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judianne Densen-Gerber</ENAMEX> to analyze the meaning of the dress.
"It's very, very bizarre. Why would she keep the dress? Why would she send it
to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>? The normal thing is if you stain something, you wash it off."
Densen-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerber</ENAMEX> is obviously a disciple of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One-Hour</TIMEX> Martinizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">psychiatry</ENAMEX>.

            Finally, this whole sordid
episode might open a new category of collectible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Fishler</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collectibles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>, tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> if the dress contains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">semen</ENAMEX> and it leads to impeachment proceedings, it could fetch <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX>. Semen,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">schemen</ENAMEX> is the reaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Briggs</ENAMEX>, who has already made
an offer (are formal bids being accepted?) of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> for the frock, no matter
what the result.

            And don't look to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> for more <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica madness</ENAMEX>. It is staying out of this whole tawdry
mess, preferring to examine more elevated topics such as the possibility that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX> believes the spirit of late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Kaufman</ENAMEX> has taken
over his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.

            More Flytrap
...

         
      
   
