
   
   
      
         
            Bowie Bonds

            I have seen the future of
rock 'n' roll and it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudential Insurance</ENAMEX>. In case you're one of those
old-fashioned rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> who doesn't read the financial press, let me explain:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several weeks</TIMEX> back, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55 million</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX> was put on the market and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudential</ENAMEX> snapped it up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>.

            You can
now buy bonds in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX>--if you can find them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody's</ENAMEX> gave
them their much-coveted triple-A rating, based on a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.9 percent</NUMEX> annual return
against the projected earnings of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Oddity</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Genie</ENAMEX>," and the rest of
the back catalog. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowie</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> to hold a bond offering, so you
can't buy bonds in, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary U.S.</ENAMEX> Bonds, though that may be because he's only
had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 15 years</TIMEX>.

            You'd think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Bowie</ENAMEX> Class A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Royalty-Backed Notes</ENAMEX>,
as they're officially known on Wall Street, would have caused a big splash in
an industry that prides itself on permanent novelty, but in all the hubbub over
his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> -birthday celebrations, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowie</ENAMEX> forgot to mention it. When the
story did emerge, the rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> was mostly silent or flummoxed. Rolling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> gave it a paragraph. Pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> know their idols are rich, and they
consider excess a respectable musical tradition. Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> begrudge him his llamas, or even the young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scandinavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> look-alike competition, who accompanies him on his
world travels.

            But bonds?
That's not megastar hedonism, just boring squaresville suit stuff. It was left
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowie</ENAMEX>'s business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> to argue that, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">au contraire</ENAMEX> , it was just
what you'd expect from the old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rebel Rebel</ENAMEX>. "The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> is the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> to do it is wonderful," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Zysblat</ENAMEX>, bullishly, "because he is
always on the cutting edge." So that's what a cutting-edge rock 'n' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roller</ENAMEX> is
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with a triple-A rating on Wall Street. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zysblat</ENAMEX>'s other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crosby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stills</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>--that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, not a brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>--are also
expected to go public.

            
Once upon a time, rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> weren't rated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moody's</ENAMEX>. They were moody. They self-destructed, they choked to death on
their own vomit, they hoped to die before they got old. But those who failed
(to die, that is) grew increasingly concerned about the fine print. In the
'80s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> was so anxious to sign <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> to a new album deal that
they offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX>. Chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX>, he said; what else have you got? They
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rummaged</ENAMEX> around for a bit, and then told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCartney</ENAMEX> they'd throw in the entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">song</ENAMEX> catalog of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Loesser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> of, among others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolls</ENAMEX>
noticed, both shows have had successful '90s revivals on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> and their
scores have been continuous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCartney</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, can you
name a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> album from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 15 years</TIMEX>? So who do you think came
out on top of that deal? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCartney</ENAMEX>'s no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX> in this area: Among the other nest
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> he owns are the score to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie</ENAMEX> and, believe it or not, "Happy
Birthday to You." The latter was written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1883</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mildred J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Smith Hill</ENAMEX> but, thanks to a legal judgment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, is
still in copyright. Every time it's sung in public--for example, whenever a TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">station</ENAMEX> uses that clip of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> serenading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCartney</ENAMEX> gets a check.

            McCartney, of course, is now
Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> to be knighted. Having spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> trying to
maintain their pose as countercultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>, the aristrockracy is
finally coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>. To his credit, though, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mick Jagger</ENAMEX> feels
the trend toward rock respectability is going too far. Recently, he dropped in
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshire</ENAMEX> and was shocked by his old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>'s condition: "I've never seen so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain</ENAMEX>," he complained,
wondering what happened to the glitterballs, strobe lights, amyl nitrate,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, and louche young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. "If I see another fucking piece of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">porcelain</ENAMEX> ..."

            Not so
long ago, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton</ENAMEX> was routinely reviled in the tabloids as a corpulent,
drug-addled old poof (as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> say). Now, having conquered the demons of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">booze</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, he's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> to be in danger of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OD</ENAMEX>'ing on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gentility</ENAMEX>. A beloved national treasure, second only to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen mother</ENAMEX>, he's
known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> of rock 'n' roll" and offers such
fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pop stars</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Bon Jovi</ENAMEX> his services as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior designer</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>,
he was invited to jive with her majesty to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rock Around the Clock</ENAMEX>," dancing
queen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>.

            Ah, yes: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rock Around the Clock</ENAMEX>." "It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-'50s</TIMEX> rock 'n'
roll," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Palmer</ENAMEX> once wrote, "that blew away, in one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mighty</ENAMEX>, concentrated blast, the accumulated racial and social proprieties of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>." Revolution is a crucial part of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>'s self-image. Like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>, after their own "mighty, concentrated blast" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>, rock
even has its own <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year Zero</ENAMEX>. Pick up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billboard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hot 100</ENAMEX>-chart reference
books--or almost any pop reference book--and they all start on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 1955</TIMEX>,
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX> of "the rock era," when "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rock Around the Clock</ENAMEX>" got to No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Never
mind that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> of the song was born in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell Parish</ENAMEX>, veteran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lyricist</ENAMEX> (though born in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>, just) of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleigh Ride</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stardust</ENAMEX>," once described
it to me as "a good, conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tin Pan Alley</ENAMEX> song"--there go the social
proprieties of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>.

            Some of those proprieties
have proved surprisingly resilient. And, since rock's into defining moments,
perhaps we can agree that, if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 1955</TIMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Year Zero</ENAMEX>, then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Bowie became the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man Who Sold Himself</ENAMEX>--for a rock 'n' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roller</ENAMEX>'s only inventory
is his image and his songs--is Year <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Zero-Zero-Zero-Zero-Zero-Zero</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55</NUMEX>
million day rock 'n' roll finally gave up on revolution. Maybe we should
treasure all those bullet-riddled gangsta rappers, the only pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> who don't
just talk the talk but walk the walk, even unto the grave. But how long can
they hold out? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASDAQ Shakur</ENAMEX> anyone?

         
      
   
