
   
   
      
         
            Marriage, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> disappears
from the tabloids <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> as they return to their classic themes: lousy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">marriages</ENAMEX>, loss, licentiousness, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> all agree the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-month</TIMEX> marriage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Hamilton</ENAMEX>--his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>--is over. There appear to
be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) his continuing affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzy Amis</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe , Hamilton</ENAMEX>'s realization--along with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billion people</ENAMEX> who watched the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>--that he's a "jerk." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> were an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> (they have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>) when they suddenly
married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. It's usually a bad sign when, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports,
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are more surprised by your wedding than by your separation. The
marriage permanently unraveled, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> moved
out of his marital home a day after he was spotted making out with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX> in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humvee</ENAMEX>. Ah, romance! Most shocking of all is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's assertion
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> did not sign a prenuptial agreement. According to the
Star , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> wants <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> earnings,
which could be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>.

            Enough money for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX> is also at stake in the
marital woes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Improvement</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Allen</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> the tabs were
reporting that if the sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> did not go into rehab, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>, was going to leave him. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> he is in rehab and, says the
Star , his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> wants out anyway. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s part, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , his stay at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Promises</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rehab center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malibu</ENAMEX> (where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slater</ENAMEX> is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>) has made him realize he wants out. If one of them gets
their wish it could make a big dent in what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> estimates is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110</NUMEX>
million fortune. The tabs leave the impression that the Promises counseling
sessions are patched directly into their newsrooms. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enquirer Allen</ENAMEX> said part of the reason he is having so many problems
right now is that he is unhappily married. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> says he's asked his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> not to come for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> family picnic. But he has had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visitor</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> : his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

            There are
mixed signals about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the marriage of newlyweds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Examiner</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Bronstein</ENAMEX>. According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , when they're together in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> home, they make love
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">incessantly</ENAMEX>. "From the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>, they've christened practically
every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>." Maybe a session in the broom <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> killed their passion because,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , "the honeymoon is over." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> wants her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to give up his job and work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, but he "hates the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
scene," reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>. He has also "fumed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, 'There's no way
I am going to give up my life and become a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> trophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.' " This
has left some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with no option but to start "taking bets on how long the
marriage lasts."

            
The deaths of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda McCartney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Wynette</ENAMEX>
were widely covered by the rest of the press, but one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>' special
missions is to give you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>' final words and farewells. The tabs were
certainly taken in by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>'s subterfuge about where his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> spent
her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last days</TIMEX>. To protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s privacy, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> told the press
she'd died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, when she actually died at a ranch the
family owns in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>. So it seems unlikely that, at the end of her life, she
said, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reports, "I want to smell the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>," or that an
"insider" saw her there.

            McCartney issued a statement
saying he held his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in her final <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> and told her they were riding
horses together on a fine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> "closed her eyes and gently slipped
away." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> preferred that her life end this way: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whispered to Paul</ENAMEX>, "I love you. I want you to be brave. We'll meet again to
continue our love affair."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> had its own
version of her parting words. " 'Give me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last kiss,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> weakly begged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul minutes</ENAMEX> before she closed her eyes for the last time. 'I won't leave you,'
he whispered. 'I'll always love you.' " The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , too, had her dying in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX>, although its own reporting turned up a neighbor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> who
said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was on its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> shortly before her death.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> also fell for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Barbara</ENAMEX> story, and it has the most florid
deathbed scene. " 'There is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on earth who can take your place,' sources
say a heartbroken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> sobbed to his dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> as he tenderly
clutched her hand. 'I will never marry again.' " It seems unlikely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> would
have wanted, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> have made, such a promise. (It is a vow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>
did make to his dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. Keeping it may have led to the situation with that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">woman Miss Hemmings</ENAMEX>.)

            Matrimony was also very much a part of the tabs' coverage
of the death of country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wynette</ENAMEX>. Although she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 55</NUMEX> when she died,
she managed to cram in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> marriages. Her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Euple Byrd</ENAMEX>, who,
reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , when she drove off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>,
shouted after her: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream on</ENAMEX>! Dream on!" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years later</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wynette</ENAMEX> was signing
autographs after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her concerts, there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX>, standing in line. She
turned his picture of her over and signed on the back, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream on</ENAMEX>! Dream on!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tammy</ENAMEX>."

            There
probably aren't many <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> marriages that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 20 years</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wynette's</ENAMEX> did. Her
last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Richey</ENAMEX>, was more than overcome by her death.
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> after she died, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> ran
up to the casket and tried to lift <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tammy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX> out of it, saying, 'Come on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">honey</ENAMEX>, I'm taking you home.' " During her funeral, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> says, "he
lunged from his front pew--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tearfully</ENAMEX> wrapped his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> around the
flower-strewn casket of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>." All this led a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to conclude, reports
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , "He won't be long behind his beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tammy</ENAMEX>."

            
On the sex front, nonpresidential illicit
encounters are all the tabs can muster <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> has an
interview with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 12</TIMEX> became the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of the most
reviled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kay LeTourneau</ENAMEX>. LeTourneau, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>, is back in
jail, pregnant a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>--their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is now a year
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old</ENAMEX>. LeTourneau was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in both <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grades, and he
describes their relationship thus: "When I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven</TIMEX>, she encouraged me
in my drawing. ... We were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. But my feelings toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> became more
romantic when I reached the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6 th</NUMEX> grade." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yessiree</ENAMEX>. It seems the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> could have taught <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bronstein</ENAMEX> a thing or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> describes
how they "made love in nearly every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of her home while her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
was away. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> we sometimes had sex outside on the deck--and even in a
swing hanging from a tree in her front yard."

            Just when
you start thinking private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> vouchers would curb such situations, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> throws you a curve. The tabloid interviews <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX>, who reveals that his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> seduced him when he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>. "Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston</ENAMEX> changed my life," he says. She introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX> not only to sex
but also to poetry. He says she gave him the confidence to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, and he
ended up helping to support her at the end of her life.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> covers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Michael</ENAMEX>'s arrest for exposing
himself in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Los Angeles' Will Rogers Memorial Park</ENAMEX> as if it's
writing a review. A "close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> says: "He's a performer
through and through. But he needs help." The arrest--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s subsequent
acknowledgment of his homosexuality--did give the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> the opportunity
to print pictures it had from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> cruising the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. And
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe and the Enquirer</ENAMEX> note <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>' most famous
quotation: "I never met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I didn't like." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">helpfully</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Goss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>'s current live-in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny Goss</ENAMEX>. The heartfelt but likely ineffective reaction from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goss Sr.</ENAMEX>, who
lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, was, "I've got to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenny</ENAMEX> and sort this out.
Kenny needs to come back home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>."

            Finally, the tabs deliver on
their implicit promise to reveal every stray fact about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>.
Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 23</NUMEX>, this means scouring a rather meager past. So we
learn from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> that as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> he took <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> Cecilia
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garcia</ENAMEX> out on a date. She recalls: "He looked in my eyes, put his arm around me
and kissed me on the lips. It was a dry, short peck and it felt weird." Perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> later had a helpful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>: According to the account in the
Star of more a recent former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, swimsuit model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kristen Zang</ENAMEX>,
"he's a terrific kisser on top of everything else." But what he's not, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> documents, is a terrific spaghetti <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eater</ENAMEX>. A series of photos shot
through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> window shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> slurping up his
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta</ENAMEX>. He obviously needs the carbohydrates. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX>
was romancing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Moss</ENAMEX>, but she dumped him when she learned he had
cheated on her with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX> has
turned his interest from model <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Campbell</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Paneka</ENAMEX>. It's
probably lucky that, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX> was rebuffed by
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby Spice</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma Bunton</ENAMEX> while he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. All this has led to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX> now
finding his life "a living hell," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> says. So he is taking the
next step every young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> must take. That is, talking about going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> to
work with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mother Teresa's Missionaries of Charity</ENAMEX>. Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nirmala</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> , "Of course we would welcome
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX>! The door is always open."

         
      
   
