
   
   
      
         
            Machiavellian

            We've become used to rock
stars leaving curiously apt or ironic song titles just before they die. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> expired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, his current single was "," which ended with those three
low notes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Way on DOOOWN</ENAMEX> ." "That's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>, 'Way on down.' And I guess
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> way or another he is," said a disc jockey on that sad day. "Well, at least
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 feet</NUMEX>."

            But, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> after the
death of 2Pac <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shakur</ENAMEX>, the ironies of his passing are looking not so much
accidental as suspiciously well orchestrated. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just a few days</TIMEX> after the murder
of their biggest-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row Records</ENAMEX> couriered his last video,
I <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ain't Mad At Cha</ENAMEX> , to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>, coyly suggesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> might like to
rush it into high rotation. Filmed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks earlier</TIMEX>, the video shows, by
amazing coincidence, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2Pac</TIMEX> dying in a drive<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by</NUMEX> shooting in a car not dissimilar
to that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suge Knight</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row</ENAMEX> gangsta impresario in whose passenger
seat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2Pac</TIMEX> met his fate.

            Since
then, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> have argued that, as with that other binarily monikered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wordsmith Mark Twain</ENAMEX>, rumors of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2Pac's</TIMEX> death have been greatly exaggerated. The
gangsta rapper, they claim, faked his own death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is still in the 'hood,
not the shroud. But, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> bemoan the way contemporary pop has
degenerated into sampling, remixes, and cover versions, so 2Pac's death seems
to be merely a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cunningly</ENAMEX> sampled remixed cover-version medley of previous
celebrity deaths. There's the question of physical evidence: No autopsy was
conducted, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> was cremated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>--so how do we know he's
really dead, eh? This is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Morrison</ENAMEX> strategy. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who saw
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> were Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morrison</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who signed the death
certificate, and, since both these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> died soon after, how can we ever
be sure? Then there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> approach. Just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCartney</ENAMEX> started
rumors of his death by appearing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey Road</ENAMEX> cover without shoes
and on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sergeant Pepper</ENAMEX> wearing an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">armband</ENAMEX> marked "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OPD</ENAMEX>" (alleged to mean
Officially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pronounced Dead</ENAMEX>), so did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2Pac</TIMEX>, on his new album, slyly adopt the
name "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Makaveli</ENAMEX>"--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Machiavelli</ENAMEX>, who, according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2Pac's</NUMEX> rapping confrere
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck D</ENAMEX>, faked his own death to fool his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>--and pose on the cover in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crucifixion</ENAMEX> pose, suggesting he intended a resurrection.

            There are several flaws with these theories. This may be
disheartening for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2Pac</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to contemplate, but, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> did return, it
wasn't for long. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck D</ENAMEX> seems to be the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machiavelli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> who has
heard anything about that wily courtier dodging death. Possibly, he's confusing
him with that other wily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">courtier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rasputin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> behind the czarist throne,
who was poisoned, drowned, etc., but managed to keep coming back. (See Boney
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>'s seminal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> disco hit, which runs, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ra-ra-rasputEEN</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>.") And while it's pleasant to think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2Pac</NUMEX> sitting around,
pondering whether to stay or depart this world--"To pack or not to pack, that
is the question"--the best evidence against the faked-death theory is the album
itself, credited to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Makaveli</ENAMEX> and cumbersomely entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Don</ENAMEX>
Killuminati/<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The 7 Day Theory</ENAMEX> . It indicates, frankly, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pac/Mak</ENAMEX> didn't
have that much imagination.

            The only
reference you'll find on the album to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mak</ENAMEX>'s previous identity is in the small
print on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX> notes: "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Exit--2Pac</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ENTER</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAKAVELI</ENAMEX>." But, alas, the first
stage of that maneuver is easier to accomplish than the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>. Pop stars
periodically reinvent themselves, but even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Nelson</ENAMEX>'s radical decision to
drop the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">y</ENAMEX>" and relaunch himself as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Nelson</ENAMEX>" was accompanied by a switch
to gloomier, more adult material by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Hardin</ENAMEX>. From "2Pac" to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Makaveli</ENAMEX>," on the other hand, is merely a matter of nomenclature ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mantovani</ENAMEX>"
would, at least, have been different.) From the opening track, it's clear the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> has nothing to say in his new identity beyond the same old clapped-out
self-justification. "" begins with a mock news bulletin announcing the name
change, and gloating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notorious B.I.G.</ENAMEX> and "several other
corny-sounding muthafuckerz" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> will want to assassinate
him.

            It's hard to figure out the East-West rap wars. In the
1950s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nat</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> declared playfully that "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cole</ENAMEX> Won't <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock 'n' Roll</ENAMEX>."
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> despised disco. But the rap wars are a civil war,
occurring within the genre. The only real precedent is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1940s</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX> of
the crooners; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> depicted his competition by parodying
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Always</ENAMEX>" as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Todd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Haymes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Como</ENAMEX>." These
mock-rivalries were contrived to attract publicity and promote sales--surely,
that's true of the rap wars, too. Why else would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suge</ENAMEX> and his record company
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mak the Knife</ENAMEX> to bore on ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nauseam</ENAMEX> throughout his album about all those
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">muthafuckerz</ENAMEX>? In what may be the ultimate postmodern
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">self-referential</ENAMEX> auto-commentary in contemporary popular culture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mak</ENAMEX> begins ""
with a radio phone-in in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> is discussing 2Pac's previous record,
on which the rapper taunted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notorious B.I.G</ENAMEX>--who he believed had a part in
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> shooting--with a reference to Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.I.G.</ENAMEX>: "I fucked your bitch, you
fat mutherfucka." If only all these rivalries could be resolved with the grace
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Harrison</ENAMEX>, who, after losing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patti Boyd</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Clapton</ENAMEX>, recorded a
version of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bye, Bye, Love</ENAMEX>," amending the line, "I hope she's happy, I sure am
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blue</ENAMEX>," to "I hope she's happy, ol' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clapper</ENAMEX>, too."

            But, with this album, musical comparisons are irrelevant.
The most melodically interesting track is the exhibitionist provocation of
""--a love letter to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>--and it soon dawns on you that that's only because
he's swiped the tune from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie Wonder</ENAMEX>'s "." Otherwise, most of the creative
energy seems to have gone not into the music, but into the dialogue and sound
effects that precede and increasingly disrupt the songs. Those who bemoan the
decline of radio drama should listen to all the screeching tires and gunfire,
and marvel. Those who hail 2Pac as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> should realize that, on this album,
the lyrics are the merest afterthought; by this stage, he was more gangsta than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rapper</ENAMEX>. The only interesting musical effect is the funereal bell tolling
throughout "."

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tolls</ENAMEX>, it tolls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tu</ENAMEX>. Yes, he's dead. And, if his death seems exquisitely
well timed, let's tactfully put that down to shrewd career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> on the
part of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suge and Death Row</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, I was driving around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>-TV film, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> went over a pothole and the radio
jumped from some tasteful doo-wop on WCBS-FM to a rap <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This</ENAMEX>," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> sadly, "is the perfect soundtrack for an age of instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gratification</ENAMEX>."
Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death Row</ENAMEX> is the first record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to understand, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> and home-entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> do, the need for built-in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obsolescence</ENAMEX>. Happy is the gangsta <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapper</ENAMEX> who lives to celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years</TIMEX> in
show business.

         
      
   
