
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exit Paula</ENAMEX>

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frame Game</ENAMEX>" is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">occasional Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> based on the premise that who wins in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is often determined by how the issue is framed. The author neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endorses</ENAMEX> nor condemns any of the views expressed, however laudatory or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">repellent</ENAMEX>.
            

            At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:15 p.m. ET</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Webber Wright</ENAMEX> was granting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
motion to dismiss the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> sexual harassment case. Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> waded into the media to frame the decision. In one scene,
replayed on television throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> what the ruling meant. "It means that
there never was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>. "I trust you'll put the
proper spin on that."

            Actually,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> didn't have to spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>'s remark or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> put out by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> gave them the spin prepackaged: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was
"vindicated," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most honest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> had lost the legal excuse for his vendetta against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The most breathtaking spin of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>--that "there never was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case"--was swallowed whole. The war of words between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> looked, as it so often does, like the ground war between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side advancing with remorseless efficiency, the other side
fleeing in disarray.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Merit</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> like to show off
their savvy by picking out the most obvious spin they've been fed and exposing
it as such. In this case, the buzzword put out by former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flacks</ENAMEX> was "vindication." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> were so
fixated on maintaining a skeptical distance from the V-word that they neglected
to screen out subtler phrases through which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s surrogates equated his
legal escape with moral exoneration. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> proclaimed, "This wipes away any question of guilt." Seizing on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s conclusion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' legal case was "without merit," the Clintonites
constantly repeated this phrase to imply that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> had dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' whole
story. By the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World News</ENAMEX> 
               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Tonight</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Jennings</ENAMEX> was
telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> that according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, "the charges against the president
had no merit."

            The advantage of the "no
merit" line over the "vindication" line was that it enabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> to maintain their delicate policy of defending him without having to
vouch explicitly--and perhaps falsely--for his innocence. "I've never believed
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'] story," proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandy Grunwald</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossfire</ENAMEX> . On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> offered a
magnificently hollow testimonial: "I believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s denial."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> disputed the "vindication" spin but failed to organize an effective
message of their own. The most promising line, auditioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossfire</ENAMEX> , was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged behavior, even if legal, was
offensive. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Whitehead</ENAMEX>, lacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s delicacy
in making the point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> had ruled that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' allegations were true,
they still didn't amount to a breach of law. Whitehead simply removed the
hypothetical. "She presumed, basically, what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> testified, did
happen," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehead</ENAMEX> declared on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry King Live</ENAMEX> . "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> says very
clearly that the attitude of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was boorish." At every opportunity,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehead</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graphically</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had fondled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' crotch,
exposed his genitals, and asked her for oral sex. News <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> responded to
these clumsy tactics by turning to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> and changing the subject.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Judging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. When a federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> acts against you, you can't just profess shock and outrage, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> did after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s decision. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> starts with a presumption of
fairness, and you have to tear that presumption down. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s
assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is a textbook example. There were obvious avenues for a
similar attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>: her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in law
school and her previous ruling--subsequently overturned--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> couldn't
be sued until he left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> failed to organize a
concerted attack on these points. In one breath, they doubted her integrity; in
the next, they affirmed it.

            The Jones
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX> also tried to take the focus off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> and put it back on what happened
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> in the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. If the case was bogus, asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, why did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX> offer <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> and an apology to
make it go away? Ordinarily, this is a good strategy. But in this case, the
story line of the hour--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> dismisses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case"--was too strong to evade.
On television, as in court, you need an alternative theory (e.g., that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fuhrman</ENAMEX> planted the evidence) to lend coherence and persuasiveness to the
various holes in the prosecution (e.g., that the gloves don't fit). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX> failed to put out an alternative story line explaining not just
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> had ruled incorrectly, but why .

            Consequently and disastrously, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s expressions
of shock played into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s spin: that the surprise in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s
decision lay in her defiance not of the facts of the case, but of the politics.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">surrogates</ENAMEX> advertised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX>, and numerous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>, highlighted that point. By saying
nothing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the Jones
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">camp</ENAMEX> allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> to define it as adversarial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s successful
petition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for a better grade became, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX>'s words, an
illustration of her "long, often unfriendly, history with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s most impressive feats was to sell the idea that throwing out the
case was courageous. Beginning with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> press
conference--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX> should be complimented on her courage to make the
right decision, notwithstanding all of the political atmosphere surrounding the
case"--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> incessantly lauded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>'s bravery. Network legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> followed suit, marveling at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright</ENAMEX>'s "guts" and
"gumption," even as their own instant polls showed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> favored the
ruling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s willingness to buy this line was a result, in part, of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s ongoing campaign to depict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as the victim of an inexorable
right-wing machine.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> vs. whom? 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may be the case's official title, but it isn't the matchup the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> wants. To begin with, it threatens to pit the world's most powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> against working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in general, a theme assiduously promoted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehead</ENAMEX>. And since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> is widely regarded as poor and stupid, the very idea
of a contest between them makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. For both of these reasons,
victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, regarded as such, would actually be a defeat for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
Hence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitehead</ENAMEX>'s argument, repeated in several venues, that the ruling would
discourage sexual harassment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> from coming forward. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> put it,
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Room</ENAMEX>" had "won a little victory <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> over this little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who is going to be denied justice."

            
Recognizing this trap, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> instructed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> not to gloat. Even his pit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bulls</ENAMEX> restrained themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> told reporters that the decision spoke for
itself, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> brushed aside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> as a pawn of larger, darker
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> had a worthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX> in mind. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crossfire co-host</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Press</ENAMEX> summed up their story line: "Big victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, big loss for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> fought off the linkage, telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that his criminal
investigation was "independent of the civil litigation." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp's
message was less nuanced and therefore more effective. On every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s expensive and fruitless
investigation and about his obligation to "put up or shut up," as Rather
expressed it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Franken</ENAMEX> declared that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> were
"joined at the hip."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> owed this portion of their victory in part
to shrewd preparation: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, they had argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was in "collusion"
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> foolishly cooperated by
grumbling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was "shadowing" them and hijacking their investigation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">surrogates</ENAMEX> also held the high ground in the context war.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> covered up an affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
arose in the context of the depositions both gave in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case. No matter
how carefully <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX> explained the distinction between the two
cases--and even the superior gravity of the criminal case over the civil
case--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> fell back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonite</ENAMEX> spin that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX> put it,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s probe "grew out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case" and had therefore lost its
viability.

            To this
end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> weren't content to pronounce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case dead. They
proposed to erase it from history, as though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depositions</ENAMEX> had never happened. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX>'s assertion that "there never was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case" echoed a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> refrain, first delivered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
Torricelli, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case--and hence the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
investigation--"no longer exists." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Press</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schneider</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> soon adopted the "no longer exists"
formulation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> opened its front page analysis by
saying, "it is now politically inconceivable that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will consider
impeachment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged lies and obstruction in a case that
no longer exists." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> camp's plea that cover-ups should be judged by
their significance at the time they were committed, not by their significance
today, was washed out in a tide of Orwellian revision.

            Not everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp wants Jones erased.
Carville, who has always been a step ahead of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in framing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fights (remember when he declared war on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>?), sees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' suit as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> that can be turned against its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. He wants her captured alive.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> is but one part of a larger mosaic," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carville</ENAMEX> charged on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
King <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Live</ENAMEX> , weaving together reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX>, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accusers</ENAMEX> had received right-wing money. "I don't want this to end
anything. I want this to go on. Because I want this to be the linchpin of an
investigation of who got paid, how much, by whom, and to say what." The
Orwellians, it turns out, were too modest.

         
      
   
