
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sourpuss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Illiquid Forbes</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN</ENAMEX>:

            I don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX> had the brains to even perceive
of teaching anyone a lesson.

            I still disagree with you about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>. Yes, of course,
there is the massive hypocrisy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> when they say in polls
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is scum: They love all the coverage, love the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Di</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal</ENAMEX>
Family hagiography, etc. And of course a large mass murder at a high school,
especially with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> and goth and geek overtones, resonates with the
public, and media, more than day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, but the coverage was
mind-numbing. It was telling to me that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> of airtime on the
funeral of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who was killed. That smacks of patronization to me.
And you have to admit that the coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX>'s death was over the top:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> milked it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> top-selling issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaacson</ENAMEX>'s personal remarks about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> were embarrassing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Brinkley</ENAMEX>
has ruined his career as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> by rushing to every TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> to talk
about his good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>. His case reminded me of when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Burdon</ENAMEX> suddenly
became <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimi Hendrix</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> after he <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.D.'d</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'70</NUMEX>.

            Well, we've both been admonished from the 
                  Slate
                chieftains for
straying from the news of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. My heart says: Fuck them, let's talk about
what we want. However, since they were kind enough to invite us to the table, I
do have a few things to say about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s "news." I know you're not as
fascinated by electoral politics as I am, dismissing it all in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>
sort of way, but I cannot for the life of me understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s
continuing love affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> is sleazy: Talk to any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> (which no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> pundit does) and you won't hear about
what a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX>" he is. Instead, they'll draw a picture of a sour,
press-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scumbag</ENAMEX> who's not very nice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and has shady business
dealings to boot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> forget he was part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keating</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Seib</ENAMEX> writes the same story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> that
we've seen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>: He's unpredictable, angers <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> with his campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> and tobacco stands (making him an honorary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> with that sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lunacy</ENAMEX>), but is fiercely pro-life. And of course his POW <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">résumé</ENAMEX>. I wish boomer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> would get over the guilt of not serving in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>: They were right. It
was a stupid war and not worth fighting and dying for. Get over not having that
"experience."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> , and other papers, reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>
isn't quite as "liquid" as everyone thought and is going to have to sell some
assets to compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. I wonder how his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> feels about his quixotic,
and ultimately selfish, presidential campaign? If I were one of his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, I'd be sort of pissed. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> has caught the presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aphrodisiac</ENAMEX>. Instead of dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, and getting a plum position in his
administration, or running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, where he'd stand a
better chance than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Whitman</ENAMEX>, he's enriching the television stations in
various states to get out his message. I like his message, but I read it every
day on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s editorial page.

            I'll get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX>'s redesign next time, which is handsome, but
I'll close with a tidbit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Swanson</ENAMEX>,
the under<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-30</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> who writes like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> has
added a new biweekly column called "Pucker Up," about anal sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX> writes
in his sniffy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> way: "Nobody ever said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> was all
about the high road" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> to the headline of the column "I Am <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Butt Girl</ENAMEX>,
Hear <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Ass Roar</ENAMEX>!" He then asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Forst</ENAMEX> if that isn't a bit too much.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, what prudes we have in the media! Anal sex in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> , or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPress</ENAMEX> , is the norm. I'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> won't raise an eyebrow.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RUSS</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
