
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Butter</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DES MOINES</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>--No sooner do I write a few nice words about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> than I run smack into him and his red-polo-shirted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Fair</ENAMEX>. This is the big event in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Des Moines</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, and all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have been dropping by to eat corn <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink ethanol</ENAMEX>, and hand out
tickets for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> straw poll. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>, when I happen upon him, is standing in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Agriculture Pavilion</ENAMEX> gaping at a life-sized interpretation of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX>
Supper--sculpted in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>.

            The work was created by an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> folk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Duffy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lyon</ENAMEX> who calls herself the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butter Cow Lady</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butter Cow Lady</ENAMEX> is
locally famous for the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> she crafts out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> for the
state fair. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown Swiss</ENAMEX>, stands in the refrigerated case
next to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> containing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. (She has also done a butter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>, a butter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> Clydesdale <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter bas</ENAMEX>-relief of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant Wood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Gothic</ENAMEX> .) The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Supper</ENAMEX> took
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX> and a ton of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> to make.

            If this piece turned up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX> labeled
as an "installation" and funded by an NEA grant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> would rise to
decry it on the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>. But because it's at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa State Fair</ENAMEX>, sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midland Dairy Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> come
instead to have their pictures taken with it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> was here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. He
was captured in a photograph beaming up at the butter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> with his arm
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> stares, slack-jawed, at the display case,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butter Cow Lady</ENAMEX> herself is inside of it, applying more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land O'Lakes</ENAMEX> to the
left shoulder of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apostle</ENAMEX> who might be <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judas</ENAMEX>. "What do you think?" I ask
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>!" he says. Long pause. "I'm not usually at a
loss for words."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> is the most gaffe-proof of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. I
can't think of anything he's ever said that has gotten him in trouble. This may
be part of his problem -- the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> seems to respond better to risk-taking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> than diligent, calculating types like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>. Even now, with
everyone declaring his candidacy toast, he's not about to speak his mind just
for the sake of it. I try to provoke him a bit more.

            "Sort of walks a fine line between religious and
sacrilegious, wouldn't you say?"

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>!" he starts again. "It's ... it's ... it's
enormously creative."

            Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> has not been reading his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">obituaries</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> told me he had come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> to do a story
about "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lamar's Last Ride</ENAMEX>," but that it wasn't going to work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> wouldn't go
quietly. Having downgraded his expectations, he now says that even a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
place finish in the straw poll will keep him in the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. Though
all but abandoned by the press, he seems determined to hang on. Walking around
the state fair, he hurls himself at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. Anyone who looks at him twice gets
invited to eat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBQ</ENAMEX> and hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Gayle</ENAMEX> perform at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s
tent at the straw poll. Encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> but only
vaguely are sometimes a bit awkward.

            "What's your name?" a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> sitting on a bench asks
him.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>."

            "Are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>?"

            "I'm running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."

            "So you're not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> moves on. With his remaining resources, he's
running a new TV commercial that takes a witty shot at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>. It opens with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">livestock</ENAMEX> auction--only this one is an auction of the
presidency. Dudes puffing on big cigars signal higher and higher bids. Finally
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with a big cowboy hat takes the prize for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">30 million</NUMEX>. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> comes
on: "The presidency is too important to be bought or inherited," he says. "It
has to be earned."

            This is his new message: not choose me, but think
twice about choosing him. Back at the fair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> tells me that it would be a
big mistake to nominate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> without putting him through the hazing of a
hard-fought primary. "I propose a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">12th</ENAMEX> Commandment," he says, playing off
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">11th</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thou</ENAMEX> shalt not criticize a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. "Thou shalt have a
contest."

            The scene around <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s campaign couldn't
be any more different. When he arrives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianola</ENAMEX> a little before sunset, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well over a 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> and perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are already in
place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has a full-scale traveling campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX>
acting the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>. There's a sense of excitement when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> refer to them, emerge against a
Reaganesque backdrop, the porch of a picturesque <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX> belonging to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Lester</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Bushes</ENAMEX> are positioned in such a way that the fading light
infuses them with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">honeyed</ENAMEX> glow. Just behind them, a large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> flag
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undulates</ENAMEX> in the breeze. It's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McKinnon</ENAMEX>, weaves through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> with a handheld video camera, shooting
scenes he'll use in future commercials.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is in shirtsleeves despite the fact that it's
rather cool outside, suggesting that he too is keenly aware of his visuals. He
delivers an upbeat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy Noonan</ENAMEX>-esque speech on his already familiar theme of
"prosperity with a purpose." Though he's pretty smooth, a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bushisms</ENAMEX> creep
in. "I love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>," he says. "Feel fortunate to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>!"

            Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> shines is in less formal situations after
he's done with his speech--greeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-wishers</ENAMEX> and taking questions from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. He has a hearty, disarming manner, and expresses his enjoyment of
the moment with body language that is fluid and comfortable. Grenades don't
faze him a bit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Franken</ENAMEX>, here on assignment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>,
gives him a chance to lose his balance. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>, have you ever manufactured
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal meth</ENAMEX>?" he asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. "In a bathtub or anything?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, not thrown for a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, cracks up. "Are you looking for work?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says, "I'm looking for a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX>."

            The style of his responses is far superior to the
substance. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asks if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> regrets giving an interview to
Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> (in which he repeatedly used the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-</ENAMEX>word and mocked Karla
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fay Tucker</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was about to be executed).

            "It wasn't an interview," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> says.

            "What was it?" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> asks.

            "Somebody came in to get a flavor of the campaign. It
wasn't a sit down meeting."

            But before he can pursue this Clintonian distinction
any further, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Hughes</ENAMEX> steps in to rescue him.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX>," she says, "you need to get back to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>."

             

         
      
   
