
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lamest Company on the Planet</ENAMEX>
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s topic is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX>, which filed for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 11</ENAMEX> bankruptcy a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week ago</TIMEX>. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s question is: Won't someone just put this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> out of its
misery?

            Planet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, a trailblazer in the booming field of cheesy
celebrity-themed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> featuring mediocre <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, has been struggling for
almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> now. It has reported shrinking earnings, which eventually
turned into losses, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every quarter in the last two fiscal years</TIMEX>. If even a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> it owns around the world are making money, I'd be
shocked. And since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has been in default on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX> worth
of junk bonds. Trading in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock has been suspended, and the
announcement of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 11</ENAMEX> means that the stock is essentially worthless. (Thus
demonstrating the important lesson that buying a cheap stock because you're
sure it can't go any lower is a mistake.)

            It's hard to feel sorry for either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>,
since this was a train wreck you could have seen coming <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> away. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here for
an earlier piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX>.) But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s proposed restructuring
plan is nonetheless dismaying. It keeps current management in place and hands
over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the equity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to an investor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> comprising
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> for what is, relatively
speaking, a small investment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX>. Current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> will probably
walk away with nothing, current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX> will get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than 50 cents</NUMEX> on the
dollar (and that's if everything goes perfectly), while current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Earl</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Waleed Bin Talal</ENAMEX> will get most of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            Still, my dismay is contained by the fact that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of nothing is
nothing, and in the end it seems clear that that's all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX> is
worth. The striking thing about the restructuring plan is not that the equity
is being redistributed but that so much energy is being put into an enterprise
the upside of which seems so small. Why, after all, do we need a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>? There isn't a ravenous consumer demand that is going unmet. Themed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX> have a terrible track record. And the restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> is capital-intensive, high-risk, and low-reward.

            In that sense, the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX> won't just die testifies to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things: the continued strength of inertia in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business and the
continued distance between the interests of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. Despite all the talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schumpeterian</ENAMEX> gales of creative
destruction that are raging through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy (and they are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">raging</ENAMEX>), there are still plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that stay alive just because they
are alive. In an ideal economy, capital will migrate away from inefficient and
unproductive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and toward productive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.

            But even though in the long run that does happen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy (as
evidenced by the steady decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s stock price, for
instance), and even though it happens here much more than in any other
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s economy, the "long run" can be very long indeed. And sometimes the
mere fact that a company exists can be enough to trick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> into believing
that it should exist. In a perfect world, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX> would have
disappeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, at the point when it became clear that the novelty
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> had worn off and that all the future held was empty restaurants
and mounting losses.

            The other thing keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> afloat is that it's been run by people
who were taking home nice salaries and plenty of corporate perks even as they
were destroying shareholder value with each passing day. For <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, the best thing would have been the liquidation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which
would have let them take their money and put it into real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. But for
Planet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, liquidation would have meant an end to their jobs.
If you're being paid well to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>, it's a lot better to let the ship
slowly sink, even if scuttling it is what's best for everyone on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s hypercompetitive world, it's easy to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Grove</ENAMEX> is
right, and that only the paranoid survive. But when you look at how tenaciously
Planet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is clinging to life, it seems clear that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX> can
survive. Perhaps what only the paranoid do is thrive.

         
      
   
