
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intriguing Disenchantment</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            Yeah, right: a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet Underground</ENAMEX>, a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hendrix</ENAMEX>. And
occasionally, they'd kick back with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Babbitt</ENAMEX> or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ornette</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> stole all his ideas from.

            If history is written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>, is rock history written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>?
By wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> correcting popular slights, redeeming ignored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> gets his most contentious in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Velvet Underground chapter</ENAMEX>, when he
challenges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Fricke</ENAMEX>'s statement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvets</ENAMEX> were " 'exiled from
the mainstream' ... greeted with " 'almost total rejection.' " No, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvets</ENAMEX>' debut had an "instant impact," going on to peak at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 171</NUMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billboard</ENAMEX>'s album chart. He then spins this not especially supportive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">datum</ENAMEX> (think how many fewer records were released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>) by saying how it
should be compared not with the sales of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stones</ENAMEX> but
with those of minimalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Monte Young</ENAMEX>, whose influence, via violist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cale</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvets</ENAMEX> brought to rock 'n' roll. This has got to be some of the
most tortured logic I've ever seen. Why can't he just say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvets</ENAMEX> were a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>, hugely influential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult band</ENAMEX>? Maybe he didn't want to recycle the line
about how few bought their records but everyone who did formed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>.

            As I skim <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dustbin</ENAMEX> for fresh anecdotes (which we agree
may be the book's real pleasure), I realize how many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s vignettes seem
chosen with an eye to '90s academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX>--gender, thanatos, whiteness
studies. Not too shocking given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX> job, but sometimes these pieces of
"evidence" seem pretty chimerical, other times just hilarious.

            For instance, did you know ...

            

               That the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> singular revolution in rock sensibility was "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>," and
that this was achieved through "the intersection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>'s alienated look
and [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">impresario</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Epstein</ENAMEX>'s] longing gaze"--"a reverie of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lads</ENAMEX> in
leather"?

               That the original lyrics of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tutti Frutti</ENAMEX>" were not just off-color but full
of, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> puts it, "thinly veiled anal eroticism"? And that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Richard</ENAMEX>
didn't shop that song to labels because he wanted to be "a straight blues
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">singer</ENAMEX>" and " <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Tutti Frutti'</ENAMEX> was too queer"?

               That not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wynonie Harris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Jordan</ENAMEX> but also sax legend <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lester</ENAMEX>
Young got their starts with black minstrel shows?

               That the strict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grammarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX> made a point of introducing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fats</ENAMEX>
Domino cover in concerts as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Isn't That a Shame"</ENAMEX>? And that, because he
was so proud of his Ivy League education, he posed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>
for his first album cover?

               That when he was playing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Monte Young</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cale</ENAMEX> was given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX>, pot,
and opium to help him "sustain a note on his viola for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> at a stretch"?
Do you believe this?

            

            Such apocrypha is the envy of any popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, and it's definitely a
major selling point for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s book. It also serves to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> seem a lot
more with-it than he might otherwise. You're right that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> is a
personal project. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> says as much in the preface, beginning with his
magical discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> and going on to share his eventual
disenchantment with this "routinized package of theatrical gestures" in the
'80s. This puts him in an odd, if touching, state for a critical endeavor.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intrigued</ENAMEX> by [his] own disenchantment"--as elusive a mind-set as I've ever
heard--he decides to figure it all out, to clarify "the cultural essence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX> and roll." Others might have just got into gardening.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretenders</ENAMEX>. Are you sure you aren't thinking of, say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Precious</ENAMEX>"
(with its "fuck off" line) or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tattooed Love Boys</ENAMEX>" (with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hynde</ENAMEX>'s quip "I shot
my mouth off/And you showed me what that hole was for")? Both a bit edgier than
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brass in Pocket</ENAMEX>," no?

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
