
   
   
      
         
            The Conformists
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles biographer</ENAMEX>, I forget which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, once said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sgt. Pepper</ENAMEX>
"brought the world closer together than any event since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>." Whatever that means. Maybe "monoculture" is too strong a word
for this way of thinking, maybe not. But you've certainly hit on something by
focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s partiality to music that "brings us all together." He's an
e pluribus unum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Kelly</ENAMEX>, one of the interchangeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Clark</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bandstand</ENAMEX> , as saying: "The craziest part of it was that many of
us became these instant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>, yet none of us really had any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>."
There is an implicit criticism here of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>'s role in creating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">problematic</ENAMEX> (to put it mildly) celebrity culture.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> is not awfully concerned about authenticity. For him, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> is

            
               the product of the coldest sort of commercial calculation, true,
but also embodying a not ignoble vision, of an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> transformed, of Mind and
Body, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>, dancing the same dance, moving to the same beat, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, en masse, joined in their own brand of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionysian</ENAMEX> revelry, watered down
and trite, but genuinely uplifting all the same.
            

            But this is ignoble. This is where rock turns into the
feed-bag-for-morons, the opiate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>, that its harshest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have
always condemned. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> understand the political implications of
Dionysian revelry, it gets turned to rotten ends. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merengue</ENAMEX> is terrific music,
too, but when, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trujillo</ENAMEX> ordered that sound systems be set
up to play it all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican Republic</ENAMEX>, it wasn't to "uplift" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but
to render them passive.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> has its roots in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>; it is, at least in part, the musical
expression of outrage at the uniformity and boredom of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> suburbia. But
like so many protest movements, it partakes of the very vices it purports to
critique. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>--at least the canonical line of it that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> describes
here--has been a greater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for unthinking conformism than anything
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Levittown</ENAMEX> wrought.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> understand this. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> doesn't always. That's why he gets blindsided
by punk and disco. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sex Pistols</ENAMEX>, of course, are incomprehensible without a
glance at the two-track uniformity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-to-late 1970s</TIMEX> music: lugubrious,
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11-minute-long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">navel</ENAMEX>-gazing guitar dirges by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Browne</ENAMEX> on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand; ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jingles</ENAMEX> like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Undercover Angel" and "Heartbeat--It's a Love Beat</ENAMEX>"
on the other. Not that there weren't a few truly emetic songs that united the
vices of both: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Rafferty</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baker Street</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Egan</ENAMEX>'s (was that his
name?) "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magnet and Steel</ENAMEX>."

            But what is disco? Since I know little about it, and since you make big
claims for it, I would love to hear more. At the time, it seemed like a bid by
"out" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>--both urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and the last of urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working class whites</ENAMEX>--to
partake of the license and self-expression that rock had provided to privileged
classes. Since disco came precisely at a time when the privileged classes, in
their political incarnation, were busily pitting working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> through such innovations as forced busing, this seems like an odd
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX>, to say the least. Unless the white participation in--and enthusiasm
for--disco was a mirage. But it didn't seem like it at the time.

            Maybe you're right that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> is not listening to much modern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>. I don't
listen to much, either, and most of it's poppy stuff I hear on the drive to
work. I too, find a lot of what's come out of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1990s</NUMEX> derivative. Sheryl
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crow</ENAMEX>'s guitar licks seem so familiar that I have often suspected they're simply
mixed out of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stuck in the Middle With You</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smashmouth</ENAMEX> makes me certain that,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Morrison</ENAMEX> may be dead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Manzarek</ENAMEX> is not. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Radicals</ENAMEX> sound
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Rundgren</ENAMEX> has just emerged from the cryogenics <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> where he's lain
frozen since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. Beck, whom I find a consistent delight, seems to draw from
less mainstream stuff--a hybrid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> and that terrific high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duo Godley Creme</ENAMEX> (who had a pop incarnation as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">10cc</ENAMEX>).

            I'm sure these are fogeyish and undiscriminating sentiments. My point is
that any casual acquaintance is bound to lead to similar ones, because the
surface of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> is exciting only at rare and lucky moments.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
