
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed-Hendrix Syndrome</ENAMEX>, and Other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX> Maladies
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            You're right. Surely I'm in the advanced stages of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed-Hendrix Syndrome</ENAMEX>--if
I liked something, it must have been the most esoteric thing on the album.

            Your sharp demolition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Velvet Underground chapter</ENAMEX>--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man-oh-man</ENAMEX>, I would not like to be on the wrong end of your critical
contempt--convinces me that he suffers from a parallel syndrome. Call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Cale-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Jones</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Matlock Disorder</ENAMEX>. Except in the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>,
where he's a convinced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lennonolater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> seems compelled to place at center
stage the lesser-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. He grants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mick Jagger</ENAMEX> only a
marginal role in the early <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Stones</ENAMEX>. Same with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Rotten and the Sex Pistols</ENAMEX>.
(Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> seems to be leaning too heavily on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Savage</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sex Pistols</ENAMEX> book
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX>, another rock history overstuffed with intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genealogy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savage</ENAMEX> attributes such Svengalian omnipotence to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm McLaren</ENAMEX>,
and focuses so heavily on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaren</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> antecedents, from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">structuralism</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Situationist International</ENAMEX>, that you could easily forget
there was any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> there at all.)

            Trying to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Reed</ENAMEX> any meaningful role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvets</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> does,
is a little tortured. I'm grateful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> for sticking up for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nico</ENAMEX>, whom a
lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dismiss as a rock stunt, a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Gaedel</ENAMEX>-but-sexier of the
downtown art world. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All Tomorrow</TIMEX>'s Parties" haunts me as much as it did when I
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> heard it sometime during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, and "I'll Be Your
Mirror" has some claim to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great Rock Love Song</ENAMEX>. But if there's a lyrical
voice to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvets</ENAMEX> it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed's</ENAMEX>, particularly when he's in good humor:

            

               
                  Yes, there are problems in these times,
But--wooooo!--none of them are mine!
               

            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> is to be admired, too, for pointing out the role of "texture" in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvets</ENAMEX>' best music. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo Tucker</ENAMEX>'s drumming on "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>" is groundbreaking,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sterling Morrison</ENAMEX> on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heroin</ENAMEX>" ... well, what compares to them? But
it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s song, for goodness' sake--you could even call it his "anthem"--and
trying to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cale</ENAMEX> all the credit for such things is like claiming "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Day</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>" is a great piece of music by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Symphony Orchestra</ENAMEX>.

            One thing I wanted to raise with you before I sign off on this very pleasant
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>: What did you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s reggae <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, which seems to make
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> stand for all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Rock</ENAMEX>? In a book so preoccupied with
intellectual ancestries, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> music seems to have gotten short shrift. Not
just "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">La Bamba</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Santana</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feliz Navidad</ENAMEX>"--but also such
thoroughly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> songs as "P.S. I Love You" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Will You Still Love</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me Tomorrow?</ENAMEX>"

            I have another, more morals-focused question about his treatment of reggae.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Marley</ENAMEX>'s stance as "uplifting unruliness," and notes that
when <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Harder They Come</ENAMEX> set <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>'s record for box-office take, it
replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sound of Music</ENAMEX> , "a musical that perfectly symbolizes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">goody-goody</ENAMEX> moralism that, for better or worse, reggae, like rock and roll,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mocked</ENAMEX>, ridiculed, and beat into cultural retreat." Did it? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> seems to have
its own mile-wide streak of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goody-goody moralism</ENAMEX> (with some standouts like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janis Ian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Browne</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Hornsby</ENAMEX> who are nothing but). After all,
we live , as all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> realize, in an age of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goody-goody moralism</ENAMEX>. So
what is it in rock and roll that has allowed it to maintain its cultural
pre-eminence in such an age?

            Someone ought to know. After all,

            

               
                  If there's a rock 'n' roll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' Heaven,
You know they got a hell of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Faculty</ENAMEX>!
               

            

            Best,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
