
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online Buffet</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ</ENAMEX>,

            Apparently you are a morning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. I'm not--I have to stumble out of bed,
have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, sit around reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--or if it's my turn go into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to
get them <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, no home delivery up here. Hopefully something in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> will
stimulate a little adrenalin (not much luck <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>; last time I did one of
these things I had <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> to write about). Only then can I begin to face such
questions as ... What do I think of 
                  Slate
               ? Well, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, my
relationship to 
                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> too, has been much more like
my relationship to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> than to any print publication. I go there
occasionally, sample whatever looks interesting, often because somebody has
mentioned a piece to me ("you should try the ..."). It's like my relationship
to the rest of the Web, actually, casual and uncommitted, without intense
expectations about what ought to be there or any necessity, as with newspapers
and magazines I read regularly, to see what 
                  Slate
                has to say
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X. Plus</ENAMEX>, there's much too much stuff to do anything like read a whole
"issue." I didn't subscribe to it when you had to pay. I might now, just
because it's become more prominent in the public conversation, and if I did
have to pay I might pay closer attention to it in the interest of getting my
money's worth.

            But I'm not sure 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "professionalism" is an asset. What
most interests me about online journalism is it's so much looser and more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serendipitous</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, I'm intrigued by this e-mail dialogue form. It's
less like writing a piece than like participating in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> discussion, only
allowing me to do what I can't in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> discussion--express myself as well as
I can in writing. I like the idea of talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I don't usually get to
talk to, at least where they can talk back. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinsley</ENAMEX> himself, he is a
conventional "high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>," as I think of them; in my view it would be a
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> if all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> would
simply merge into one composite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> who would write once a week so I
could find out what the latest conventional wisdom is without having to spend
so much time at it.

            What I meant in saying that techno has cultural-political significance is
that it's the medium of a counterculture; techno <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> are looking for ecstasy
(I mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of mind, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>, though that too), for a kind of erotic
communalism that's basically missing from the larger culture right now ... but
where the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> counterculture was anti-technological (even though rock 'n' roll
was totally dependent on technology), this one resonates with the
techno-utopianism of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> (I'm not saying the techno <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> or overlaps with them, I really have no idea, just that there's
a common impulse there). And this is what makes pop music, or popular culture
of any kind, compelling: that it becomes the catalyst for a new oppositional
and/or competing sensibility--it holds out the possibility of seeing life and
art and the relation between them in some fresh way. Whereas rock 'n' roll in
its various forms just seems to be rehashing and cannibalizing the past.

         
      
   
