
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> Is the New Star Wars
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Polly</ENAMEX>,

            Like you, I began this assignment with a mixture of puzzlement and
skepticism. I was, for one thing, suspicious of the media hype--to which we are
now, of course, contributing--around these books, and I still dread the
eventual movies and the inevitable merchandising frenzy that will follow. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son</ENAMEX> has just graduated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tellytubbies</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>, and I fear the day
isn't far off when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky-Winky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laa-Laa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.W.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francine</ENAMEX> will have to
shove over on his shelves to make way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldus Dumbeldore, Hermione Granger</ENAMEX>,
and the other must-have action figures, not to mention the toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broomsticks</ENAMEX>,
wands, owls, and endless other wee wizard paraphernalia sure to flood the
market soon. And then there will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter Magic</ENAMEX> Happy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meals</ENAMEX>, the CD-ROMS, the cut-rate knock-offs, and the other excrescences of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kid</ENAMEX>-culture overkill. Look what they did to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> Winnie-the-Pooh!

            I also had to overcome some grownup resistance to the books themselves,
mostly owing to the atrophying of my capacity for the kind of
flashlight-under-the-covers, breathless absorption you evoke so nicely. That
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books restore this capacity with brilliant efficiency must be
part of the reason they appeal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. But, as you point out, they're hardly
unique in this. They're not better than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Phantom Tollbooth</ENAMEX> , or Ursula
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LeGuin</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earthsea Trilogy</ENAMEX>," or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.H. White</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Once and Future King</ENAMEX> .
Nor are they better (you asked for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX>) than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.L. Konigsberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mixed-up Files</ENAMEX> of Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basil E. Frankweiler</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Fitzhugh</ENAMEX>'s books
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harriet the Spy</ENAMEX> is best known, but the one I remember best is
Nobody<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'s Family Is Going To Change</ENAMEX> ). But that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> merits
mention in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> suggests that he's the real thing.

            I don't know why it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult readers</ENAMEX>--including myself, since my
reading life (which is to say, my life) is divided evenly between bedtime
stories for younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and serious adult fiction (plenty of dreck
there!)--eschew the pleasures these books afford, especially since we are
likely to have fond, intense memories of just those pleasures. We try to
recapture them with genre schlock, as though the dream world of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> were
a tacky theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>. And yet it's evident that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.K. Rowling</ENAMEX> is a formidably
talented--and, more important, a rigorously competent--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>, much better at
the rudiments of effective fiction writing than any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> novelists
under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>. She's meticulous in her plotting, economical in her descriptions, and
exact in her portraiture. There's no reason why solid storytelling, brisk
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prose</ENAMEX>, and vivid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> should appeal exclusively, or primarily, to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are less likely to submit to being bored, pandered
to, preached at, or intimidated.

            In each of these books--ingeniously structured around the cycle of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Hogwarts school year</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowling</ENAMEX> manages to impart new information about the
wizard world (and slyly fill you in in case you've missed the earlier
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">installments</ENAMEX>, something that will become increasingly important as the series
fills its projected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> volumes and sales figures mount into the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillions</NUMEX>),
to advance the long-term narrative conflict (about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s search for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origins</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Manichean</ENAMEX> struggle with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voldemort</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizard</ENAMEX> who's gone over to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dark Side</ENAMEX>), and to create and resolve enough satisfying short- and
middle-term conundrums to make the volume stand alone.

            She also understands the importance of evil, both metaphysical (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voldemort</ENAMEX>),
and human: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petunia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Dursley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muggle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> who raise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> in his orphanhood, along with their doted-on, sublimely piggish son
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dudley</ENAMEX>, are grotesques worthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roald Dahl</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Draco Malfoy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis</ENAMEX> at
Hogwarts, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Severus Snape</ENAMEX> (she's terrific with names), the diabolical potions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, are brilliant foils for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s flawed, instinctual goodness. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowling</ENAMEX> understands that goodness is not the same as innocence, a concept in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have no interest (knowing, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> refuse to, that they are
entirely without it). The threesome of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Weasely</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermione Granger</ENAMEX>
(who is likely to be everybody's favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>) are believably
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mischievous</ENAMEX>, competitive, vain, and, for all their intelligence, prone to
childish foolishness (e.g. the clever, studious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermione</ENAMEX>'s stubborn crush on
the egotistical charlatan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockhart</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Secrets</ENAMEX> ).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> craze, I think, is not unlike the Star Wars phenomenon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers ago</TIMEX>, which also took the world somewhat by surprise (although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars was more carefully calculated to appeal to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>,
whereas the adult appetite for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s escapades seems to have been anticipated
by nobody). Like the first Star Wars movie, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books have
an instantly classic, ineffably old-fashioned quality about them. They
ingeniously recombine elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale, religious allegory (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> as the
chosen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-remembered childhood reading, and pop culture (including,
fairly explicitly in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX>, the Star Wars cycle itself)
into something new, fresh, and irresistible. You feel, somehow, that they have
always been there, waiting for you to discover. You also feel, in spite of
being one of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several million</NUMEX> crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, that they were written for you alone,
a wizard stranded in an uncomprehending <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muggle</ENAMEX> world, waiting for someone to
recognize that what everyone else calls your abnormalities are really powers.
This, I think, is the deep appeal of these books (and of a number of the others
we've mentioned). They tap into a universal condition of childhood--the sense
of being misunderstood, different, special.

            But why these books, why now? It's probably a mistake to try to read to much
cultural significance into their extraordinary success--just as it would be in
the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midnight in the Garden of Good and Evil</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashes</ENAMEX> , or the other out-of-the-blue runaway bestsellers of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. But it must mean something, no? What do you think?

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>

             

         
      
   
