
   
   
      
         
            Questions and Answers
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and the rumors that he snorted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> when
he was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 20s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX> also spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few moments</TIMEX> discussing the political
strengths and weaknesses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> marriage and the political standing of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>; and the news, reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
leave his job as independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> agree that questions about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has ever tried cocaine
are relevant to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s presidential campaign and a legitimate part of
public discourse. They also agree that the imbroglio in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> now finds
himself will probably not severely damage the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> election effort. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gergen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the</ENAMEX>
Press ) believe that unless someone comes forward with a specific allegation
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> the issue will likely fade from public notice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) believes that the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> position--that he
has been drug-free since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>--is an eminently reasonable one, and other
pundits point out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> simply does not care a great deal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> whether, as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 20s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> dabbled in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>.

            Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> are highly critical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s handling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> issue.
They believe it raises serious questions about the character and credibility of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, and they accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> of giving a series of muddled
responses to questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. They attack him for sounding
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> evaded questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use and
draft-dodging in an eerily similar manner. And they argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, who has
refused to state flat-out if he has ever used illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, emerges from the
controversy looking like a waffler and, worst of all, a hypocrite of the first
order.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
Late <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edition</ENAMEX> ), and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> explain it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is running a campaign
based in large part on his personal biography. He has trumpeted his credentials
as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful husband</ENAMEX> and fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, volunteered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that he no
longer <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>, and attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> for being an immoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philanderer</ENAMEX> who has
tarnished the dignity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has promised that as president
he would uphold the dignity of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> wonder how he can talk
about some aspects of his personal life without discussing other, less pleasant
parts of his past. Also, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gergen</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> point out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> may have a
tough time squaring his own past <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use with his image as a law-and-order
tough who supports stiffer sentencing guidelines for convicted drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Duke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Week in Review</ENAMEX> ,
warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX> has been a "dead" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. And
indeed, other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> cocaine controversy, the opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> has little
to say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that is new: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) attacks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> for being a waffler on the abortion issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gigot</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> is
running a listless campaign and needs to start focusing on major issues of
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital Gang</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Black</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late</ENAMEX>
Edition ), speaking from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vacationing</ENAMEX>, marvel at how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has rebounded from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal of a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year earlier</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Tumulty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ) engage
in a heated debate about the merits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> and his lengthy investigation
into wrongdoing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hume</ENAMEX> says the independent counsel
almost brought down a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and has been, by most measurements, a
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tumulty</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> a failure.

            
               Infotainment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>-style: 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> routinely airs
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sensational</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-second</TIMEX> spots that titillate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> and try to convince them to
stay tuned for upcoming segments. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> advertise
an upcoming dialogue on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> cocaine controversy by playing the popular
'80s dance song "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Lines</ENAMEX>" and showing footage of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protester</ENAMEX> running across
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> carrying a sign that reads, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snort</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
