
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day Ganja Defeated Wiener Schnitzel</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            I want to close this quite enjoyable week with a plea for clemency. Let's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forgive Miller</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points.

            One is his valuation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>'s lesser-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Matlock</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cale</ENAMEX>, etc.). At this point, these come mostly as correctives to what's
been drummed into our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> by countless bios and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time-Life</ENAMEX> specials.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Flowers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dustbin</ENAMEX> is idiosyncratic enough that it's hard to imagine
someone taking it as a definitive text on rock history--believing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Reed</ENAMEX>
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX> puppet or that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Rotten</ENAMEX>'s rheumy dynamism was simply a
product of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Situationists</ENAMEX>. (And yes, the latter perspective does owe more
than a little to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savage</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dreaming</ENAMEX> . This must have been said
before, but if someone named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Savage</ENAMEX> wasn't born to write about the Sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pistols</ENAMEX>, I don't know who was.)

            I've also come to appreciate the subtlety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s critique a bit more
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few days</TIMEX>. While doing his best to expose the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> behind the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">curtain</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ertegun</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warhol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaren</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> rarely falls into the pat stance of
so many social-crit rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who, unable to trust their ears, rely upon
unspoken formulations like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial = Sucks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> all music accordingly.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> actually tries to address the nuances that make a music succeed or fail,
which is pretty uncommon in his milieu. He recognizes that even prefab,
target-marketed music can have life-changing effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            As far as the reggae <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, I'm not sure how much slack to cut him. Is the
inclusion of reggae a worthy redress of a common rock-historical oversight, or
is it a cursory attempt to include still another music that discerning
white college-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> tend to have in their record collections?

            I think you're right that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX>--as befits his mode of
intellectual genealogy--mostly to represent rock's effect on the world and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>-versa. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> even ends by imagining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SÃ</ENAMEX>£o
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulo</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capetown</ENAMEX>, as "rock and roll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in Third World disguise." But
that's pretty parlous ground to dash over in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> pages. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> obviously
enjoys the moment of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Harder They Come knocking The Sound of</ENAMEX>
Music out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX>'s No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> slot--implying it was a triumph of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">rock-'n'-</ENAMEX>roll attitude over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goody-goody moralism</ENAMEX>. Of course, it's also a
triumph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Cliff</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Andrews</ENAMEX>, ganja over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiener</ENAMEX> schnitzel,
and--isn't this a bit more important?--local art over cultural imperialism.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moralism</ENAMEX> is certainly alive in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> (mostly around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> like the
death penalty and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>), but it seems quite ably offset by crass irony, silly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">provocation</ENAMEX>, emotional <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">retardation</ENAMEX> of most pop culture. If we're going to
compare the moralism of this <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multimillion dollar</NUMEX> culture industry with that at<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
say, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar Night</ENAMEX>, I know which one I prefer.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>: What a time to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> hear "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Tomorrow</ENAMEX>'s
Parties"! Energy crisis. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>. Village <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>. I think I first heard
it during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term. Crack. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huey Lewis</ENAMEX>. How differently did
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>, you, and I hear it? Obviously, popular music needs some context
in which to be understood. But more and more of these disengaged <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of audio
expressionism are floating around us, daring us to make sense of them. To
listen intelligently, which I believe is still possible, you have to draw
parallels, be alert to links and exchanges, respond both musically and
socially. Which--to answer one of the first questions you asked me--is one
reason why it's hard to write well about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>.

            But maybe we're all being too sloppy with this term "rock." Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s
actually right to end his chronology at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, a year that most of my
favorite trends in this, er, "cultural form" began. Did all of the music,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">personalities</ENAMEX>, and ideas that first captivated me--the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sex Pistols</ENAMEX>, Grandmaster
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flash</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Enemy</ENAMEX>--do nothing but recycle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s paradigms? That would sure
make things easy for us content <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, but I don't think so. Still, maybe
all this newer music--born of new technologies, multiculti babble, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>/media
feedback loops--falls under some other rubric we have yet to define. The really
trenchant analyses often come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>. Maybe the etymological evolution
from "rock 'n' roll" to "rock" to whatever else we decide to call this intense,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">edgy</ENAMEX>, corrupt, joyful form of musical expression is long overdue.

            I'm accepting suggestions.

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
