
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anatolian Toll</ENAMEX>

Times lead with the political and public health aftershocks of the
earthquake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> carries the story as its top non-local
piece.

            Although the numbers are still rising, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> agree that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 10,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have died and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34,000</NUMEX> have been injured (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35,000</NUMEX>,
reflecting both its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later closing time</TIMEX> and the speed with which the numbers are
climbing). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story documents how shoddy building standards
exacerbated the effects of the earthquake. Rescuers sifting through the rubble
have found thinner-than-recommended steel rods and cement "filled with so much
sand that it crumbles in [the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>'] hands." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are vociferously blaming building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> for violating
safety standards. But the piece explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> has virtually no standards
to violate. Once construction begins on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, it is never subject to
state-mandated inspection.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story covers the public health angle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feverishly</ENAMEX> scrambling to bury its rotting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> before they spawn disease.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Muslim clerics</ENAMEX> have allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> customs to be disregarded for the sake of
speedy burials, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> ordered that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> be buried as soon as
they are found (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> will have to identify their dead through a
pre-internment photo). But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX> has announced that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> themselves are not a health hazard; open sewage and lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> are
far more dangerous. This caveat gets only a single sentence, and no further
explanation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s possibly misplaced priorities.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager continues the review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>'s strike on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sudan</ENAMEX> in retaliation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s story contends that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> bombed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Shifa</ENAMEX> pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s
warning that it hadn't yet confirmed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> was producing chemical
weapons ingredients. An "unnamed official" tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that the
administration has since backtracked on its initial assertions that a toxic
substance was manufactured at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and that its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX>. The
story admits that the bombing may have required a difficult judgment call,
asking, "Just how certain does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> need to be before it uses force
against a suspected terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> overseas?"

            The papers print virtually identical stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tenet</ENAMEX>'s revokation of the security clearance of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John M.</ENAMEX>
Deutch, for transferring classified material to an unsecure PC at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. All
papers note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> was fired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> after
allegedly transferring classified computer files to his own computer. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> implies that the revocation is a P.R. stunt, intended to convey the
government's tough line on security. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutch</ENAMEX> played along, swallowing his
medicine without protest and even issuing contrite remarks about the security
measures he should have taken.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> cover story tracks how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo Joe</ENAMEX>
financial chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, may have suckered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX> trading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park</ENAMEX> touted an obscure e-commerce stock as "the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priceline</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>." The stock
rose wildly until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. But when it began to drop, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> were
suddenly disconnected from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tokyo Joe</ENAMEX> site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> weakly blamed a failed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">server</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Park</ENAMEX> boasted that he had made a quarter of a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> off the stock's fall.

            An WP inside piece reports on the indictment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> smugglers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimps</ENAMEX> who brought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> girls--some as young as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years old</TIMEX>-- to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> as indentured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> and forced them to work as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> until
they repaid their debts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">smugglers</ENAMEX> had duped many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into
thinking they would be working as seamstresses or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masseuses</ENAMEX>. In a fit of
numerical detail, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calculates that a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> had to have
sex with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">428</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to pay off her <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> debt.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reveals that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>'s most ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX>
is leading a drive against Web sites that support a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> presidential
candidacy. He is doing so because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> has no plans to run and fears that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> will disappoint--and lose the support of--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>
can participate in [the wrestling event] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summerslam</ENAMEX>," said one defiant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">follower</ENAMEX>, "then I can put up a Web site."

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story profiles a particularly splenetic radio talk
show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. He trails <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX> in the ratings, but he heaps similar scorn
on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX>. "There is something deranged about you," he told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>.
"Either you don't read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> carefully enough or you're so prejudiced
and biased that you block out the truth," he railed at another. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> is
none other than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
