
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s victory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straw Poll</ENAMEX>.  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly 25,000</NUMEX> voting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowans</ENAMEX> descended on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> for a day of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>,
entertainment, and politics that, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , confirmed most
expectations about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , which
also fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, leads instead with a report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> slighted by HMOs
are having greater success bringing their grievances to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>. The WP
fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s announcement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> will demand that states intensify efforts to combat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water pollution</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> follow-up stories to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> community center
shooting. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sets the diversity of the medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that saved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kadish</ENAMEX> against the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>'s racism; a sidebar reports heated debate
over whether or not the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should confront <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> more
aggressively. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> took <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 percent</NUMEX> of the mock votes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa State University</ENAMEX>
basketball arena, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>
with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX>. Places <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> went respectively to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s less than overwhelming margin of victory in the mock election does not
reflect current opinion polls elsewhere: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> led a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> poll <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> outspent
everyone (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX>), hoping to emerge from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s sole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s solid finish
beat back fears that her candidacy might not survive a poorer showing. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> article mentions twice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> delivered a recycled speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, who dismissed the event as a "sham," will concentrate instead on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming weeks</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports in its
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Political Briefing"</ENAMEX> column.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> are beginning to have
greater success suing for medical malpractice. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 20 months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
have started to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> sue, but not for punitive damages--only for the
value of the denied benefits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX> have found ways to sidestep a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> law
that shields the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> from liability for their decisions. A recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bill granting protections to some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> awaits a presidential
veto. 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> will force <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to clean up
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> rivers, lakes, and bays currently too dirty to swim or fish in, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report.  State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> will determine the
level to which pollution must be reduced in a body of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and then assign
quotas to individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">polluters</ENAMEX>. The latter would then have to cut back
emissions or buy discharge rights from someone polluting below allowed
level.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> continues its detailed coverage of atrocities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> with
a report that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovars</ENAMEX> may be waging an organized ethnic cleansing
campaign.  Citing local and Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that patterns have
emerged in vandalism, threats made to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>, and execution-style killings.  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> are stepping up their
campaign to disarm and perhaps dismantle the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>. 

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the WP front obituaries of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lane Kirkland</ENAMEX>, former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>,  who died of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 77</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kirkland</ENAMEX>
expanded the labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">federation</ENAMEX>'s influence abroad (for example, by sending money
and equipment to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>), but is said to have neglected
domestic issues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> runs its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-related cover story of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lloyd</ENAMEX> explores political fallout in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> (and on the
presidential campaign trail) from botched Western policy initiatives undertaken
in post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Russia</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s top foreign-policy specialist faults the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton-Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> with clinging to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>' empty rhetoric.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> camp will propose that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> step away from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> internal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kaiser</ENAMEX> also plays the blame game in the WP : He asks if
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> jeopardized the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s relationship to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> run front-page accounts of grotesque
mistreatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> abroad.  The former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, reported
cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse are rising against a backdrop of record unemployment and
increasing divorce and remarriage rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Legislators</ENAMEX> may scale back laws that
give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> significant autonomy and power. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager peeks
inside <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orphanages</ENAMEX> for the mentally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX>--or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gulags</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>." The piece details the nightmarish conditions under which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in
these borderline <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> live.

            
               D'oh!:  If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> get their way, the grounds of the defunct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trojan</ENAMEX>
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rainier</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ore.</ENAMEX>, may become a new state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, according to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>
story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> is thought by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> to be the
inspiration for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer Simpson</ENAMEX>'s workplace  because of its proximity to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Groening</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>.  (The show denies a link.) Despite <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of acres</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">woods</ENAMEX> and rich wildlife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> wonder who would feel safe enough to camp
there.  Link or no link, maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> will find comfort in that the
Simpsons have lived near an unsafe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> for so long without any adverse
effects on their health.

         
      
   
