
   
   
      
         
            What the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Net Hath Wrought</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Joe</ENAMEX>,

            Well, I guess we probably will not ever agree. But I only need to use your
examples as proof that what the Internet has wrought in an unbelievably short
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> has been profound--the entire computer industry (as evidenced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dell</ENAMEX>'s success) has been turned on its ear, the retail industry is reeling (did
you see the many news stories <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstrom</ENAMEX>'s striking a deal with a
well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture firm</ENAMEX> to jumpstart its Web efforts?), and
traditional media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are in full-scale alert.

            Consider the daily impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, which has risen from obscurity to disdain
to prominence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only five years</TIMEX>. I think you don't even have to take a poll of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> to get them to agree that they think this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is an
important one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. Consider its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> as the best indicator--right now,
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> have painted a big red target on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and are taking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aim</ENAMEX> on multiple fronts.

            And why is this? Because, finally, after all those years of promises, the
interactive age is upon us. I used to joke that the idea of interactive
television has been around since I had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>, but that it never seemed
to work. Now, pretty much every major communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is formulating
plans to shove a fully loaded digital set-top box into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>
to move interactive services from the computer to the television--or any device
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, really. Did you hear about the Internet refrigerator that links
to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grocery sites</ENAMEX>? Of course, I am probably the only one who thinks this is a
good idea. It's clear to me that either via a plethora of wires or satellite or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wireless</ENAMEX> means, we are all going to be plugged in more than ever before in the
coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. I myself am a cell phone freak, who cannot imagine being without
my little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nokia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6160</TIMEX>. Relying on cell phones completely, I had even abandoned
land-line phones from the local telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> until I was recently forced
to link up again to get high-speed Internet access over telephones. I used to
be mocked for my cell addiction, but now I am regularly sought after for advice
on just which plan to get.

            But to a bigger point, we should all think about what this means to society
and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> on a more personal level. For this, I turn to an article in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> today about an outbreak of syphilis in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
being linked to one chat room on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. Apparently, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who have contracted
the disease have said they met those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> offline after meeting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cyberspace</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. To say nothing of the idea that the Internet is replacing the
bar as the best place to hook up, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> asked the more pertinent
question: "When does the right to online privacy yield to public health
issues?" The big problem is that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> knew their infected partners
only by their AOL screen names. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, which can identify these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>,
was not giving out the real names.

            I would be curious what you think of this and perhaps about the broader
issues of so much personal information sloshing around about Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">users</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> is really a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">marketer</ENAMEX>'s dream, giving them the ability to glean a lot
of highly specific information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their habits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
and more to come are focused solely on recording and interpreting user
patterns.

            It also cuts both ways. Several missives ago, you did hit on a good point
about the Internet's being important in giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> perfect knowledge
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> products and, most important, prices. This is another big idea to me and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that I have been waiting to happen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>. I was a retail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> before I started covering the Internet, and my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> major
conclusion from the job was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. Any new system that
allows a consumer to take back some of the power that is rightfully theirs to
begin with--it is their money, after all--is one I will back
immediately. I am particularly taken with the new sites called "demand-driven"
retail. In this system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ask for what they want and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> respond
rather than being told what they like and don't like. But is there some problem
with this? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>, for example, there eventually be a site dedicated solely to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Nocera</ENAMEX> and his needs? And, dare I ask, what would be on it?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Kara

         
      
   
