
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>, Sex, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnology</ENAMEX>
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are still milking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and the drug thing because they're filling
the vacuum that has arisen because you have to cover the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX>, but
he isn't saying anything substantive, let alone controversial. The reason
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> won't be honest about their marijuana use is simple: If they
admitted they had enjoyed pot and suffered no adverse effects, this would raise
uncomfortable questions about why they don't come out against laws that put
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in jail and confiscate their property for doing the same thing. And
they're just too cowardly to take on the drug-war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>. Even legalization
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> are for the most part scared to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use as a legitimate
pleasure or the right to alter your own consciousness as a civil liberty; they
just talk about "harm reduction." There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> opinions you can't voice in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> without being dismissed as a crackpot, if not worse: The '60s
experiments in consciousness expansion were basically a good thing; organized
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX> is oppressive; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> have a right to enjoy their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sexuality</ENAMEX>.

            And speaking of religion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> had a story on a
coalition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> of various religions who are suing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> to get
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to label genetically engineered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, on the grounds that food
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> may violate religious dietary laws. I'm on
their side on this one, as I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bioengineers</ENAMEX> are mad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> who
bio-arrogance, and I want to boycott their products, just as I don't want to
eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> with antibiotics or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> with growth <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>. Of course, this is just
what the industry is worried about, as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotechnology</ENAMEX>
Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> admitted in the article. They argue that since such a
boycott would be irrational and would ruin the industry, the information should
be withheld. Now, here's an issue for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of the free market. How can I
make a free choice of what to buy if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> won't tell me what I'm buying
(and I can't simply not buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>)? And don't I have the right to reject goods I
don't want for whatever reason I please, rather than have biotech companies
decide what's best for me? Where is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cato Institute</ENAMEX> on this one?

            I look forward to your take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> . I haven't seen the new
model--I would have to drive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX> to get it, and anyway, I think they
get issues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> late.

         
      
   
