
   
   
      
         
            Provoking the Hosts
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN</ENAMEX>:

            I'll be brief on this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, as I've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s appt. at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 a.m.</TIMEX>, but
I promise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more dispatches <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, you lucky old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.

            So, you're just assuming a recession is around the corner. So do I, but I've
been saying that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. In fact, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy was in the
turlet, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie Bunker</ENAMEX> would say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> never
would've made it through his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> (and I use her name as just a catchall
for all his scandals, which are too numerous to repeat) travails. The
public, which by and large cares more about its pocket than politics, would've
said send the skunk to the showers. And, as a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> would be the
front-runner in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> elections.

            Explain to me, re: your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> post <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, how techno is "interesting in
a larger political sense." I fell off the pop music <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '90s</TIMEX>; my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nephew</ENAMEX>, who's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>, knows all the new stuff, just like I did when I was his age.
I gave him a copy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pogues' Rum, Sodomy & the Lash</ENAMEX> when I was
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, as an artifact of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, and one of my top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that era</TIMEX>,
and he thanked me, but I bet he hasn't played it yet. Let's be provocative.
What do you think of 
                  Slate
               ? There have been rumors that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is going to close it down, just as their <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX> is crumbling. I
don't mean to be a drunk at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>'s cocktail party, but I have mixed
feelings. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX> is an incredibly overrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and really
belongs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , where his mediocre talents would fit
right in. But as a Web site, 
                  Slate
                has its moments,
even though on a crummy computer, like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my year-old</TIMEX> laptop (which means it's
already obsolete) it's very slow. The links are valuable, especially the
transcripts of TV shows; the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Diary</ENAMEX> can be interesting; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, who
writes like he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>, is fun to make fun of. But 
                  Slate
                is far
better than the amateurish <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , which I hear (doesn't everybody?) is
in trouble. 
                  Slate
                is professional, and is more like a print
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, obviously like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> . I was one of the few paid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> and would subscribe again, just for the services.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> just woke up, so I've got to run. I haven't shaved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>,
so now I have the growth that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> did by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> want me to
grow a beard; I tell them it's not possible, but I'll give it a try. More
later.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RUSS</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
