
   
   
      
         
            Getting the Lead Out

Times lead with, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> fronts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
government's moves to accelerate earthquake clean-up efforts and answer rising
criticism of its disjointed response to the disaster. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with
reports suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are doing a wildly uneven job of testing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> contamination.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> gives its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> coverage a human face, using extensive
interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of the dead to paint a macabre picture
of the quake's aftermath. It also reports that efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Izmit</ENAMEX>,
at the epicenter, to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s skating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX> as an overflow morgue turned
disastrous when the power went out. "As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> lay in their body
bags," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ice</ENAMEX> grew soft and watery, and a thick pungent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mist</ENAMEX> rose from it." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> focuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s sluggish
mobilization in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> following the quake. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> finally appeared in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, picking up garbage in an effort to stem the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suleyman Demirel</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> he understood their concerns over the low
profile the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> has taken thus far, but also cautioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> not to expect
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to "work miracles." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> of three
damaged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">provinces</ENAMEX> will be fired because they failed to put together efficient
rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> zeroes in on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulent Ecevit</ENAMEX>'s plan
to commandeer private hearses, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, and construction equipment for the
relief effort. And it cites <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who predict the death toll could
pass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> and a
special federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> say most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are failing to comply with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> law
requiring lead screening for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> show that child
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>--who often live in older <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> with peeling lead-based
paint or contaminated dust--are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as likely as other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to have
dangerous levels of lead in their blood. The worst offender? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
where not even <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were tested. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 900,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of 1</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5</TIMEX> carry enough lead to cause behavioral problems, learning disabilities, or
neurological damage.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>'s off-lead is a startling piece about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> cancer death
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Harding</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> at a government-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harding's</ENAMEX> remains, prepared as part of a lawsuit but never
published, indicated that even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after leaving his job his bones
showed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> levels up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">133</NUMEX> times higher than normal. Despite suffering
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stomach cancer</ENAMEX>, perforations in his lungs and fingernail-like growths on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX>, wrists, and shoulders, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harding</ENAMEX> was refused a disability pension; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> maintained that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harding</ENAMEX>'s health problems were the result
of smoking cigarettes and eating "country <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harding</ENAMEX> claimed that a thick
haze of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> dust at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, operated until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carbide</ENAMEX>, covered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' skin and even their teeth.

            The LAT fronts a detailed profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buford Furrow Jr.</ENAMEX>, the man
allegedly responsible for opening fire inside a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community center</ENAMEX> and
killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Filipino</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 10</TIMEX>. It describes him as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bumbling loner</ENAMEX> who was largely invisible to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> and was
consumed by periodic bouts of rage. The story says only in the white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supremacist</ENAMEX> movement was he able to find a measure of acceptance.

            The WP fronts a story about <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX>'s controversial support
for a proposed new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> known as the "techway" that would connect the suburbs
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Virginia</ENAMEX>. Residents along the corridor worry that the
highway would open up huge areas of land for new development. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barb Emmons</ENAMEX>, a
database <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of a local environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, tells the
Post that as soon as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> was backing the project,
"Our worst fears were realized." This controversy is in contrast, the paper
reports, to the situation on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>, where high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> have pushed for public transportation improvements
and measures to protect open space.

            At press time, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Bret</ENAMEX> had not moved near enough the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> coast to
merit any front-page coverage, but its alarming increase in speed suggests it
could grab big headlines by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports on Page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A2</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bret</ENAMEX>'s strength may well match that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurricane Andrew</ENAMEX>, which pummeled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX> with wind speeds as high as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">145 mph</NUMEX>, and predicts it will reach
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late Sunday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early Monday</TIMEX>.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Kermode</ENAMEX> is disdainful of a
new biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Bedell Smith</ENAMEX> that claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Di</ENAMEX>
suffered from "a borderline personality disorder." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kermode</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
employs a "laborious accumulation of detail" to back up her diagnosis that the
late princess "was unpredictable, egocentric, aggressive, insecure,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manipulative</ENAMEX>, paranoid, possessive, easily bored, uneducated and a habitual
liar." That's not all--she also "steamed open other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s letters."

         
      
   
