
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boomer Segregation</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Kara</ENAMEX>,

            Believe it or not, word of your splendid wedding had spread to the East
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast</ENAMEX> even before it took place. I heard about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Tetzeli</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s hot young technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, who is also (I believe)
a childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of yours. In that lovably sardonic way of his, he described
your impending nuptials as "the event of the season" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>. From
your sweet account, it sounds like he wasn't far off. I was deeply impressed,
by the way, with your ability to recall the details of the affair--the main
thing I remember about my wedding is what a blur it was. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> I
could barely recall who was there, much less what they said to me. Here's the
good news: That was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, and I'm still very happily married. I wish
you the same.

            It is, of course, ridiculous that there is political <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> to be made by
trying to prevent same-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> from adopting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. It makes sense only
in the context of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential politics--that is, such extreme
positions can rally the hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX> who vote in primaries, and thus help
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> gain the nomination, but will only be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> once the general
election rolls around.

            But the truth is, though I'm a white, middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hetero</ENAMEX>, I don't understand
the anti-gay forces any better than you do. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason is that I live in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northampton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, which has a very large lesbian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and where
tolerance is pretty much taken for granted. (Though not always: We had a
terrible murder here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, when a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> stabbed a 16-year-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> on a downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. It later turned out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> had been taunted
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> by the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> because he was gay.)

            But another reason, I think, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> in particular have tended
to segregate themselves along political lines as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and racial
lines. I've lived, for instance, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northampton</ENAMEX>. (I also lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, but that's
a whole other story.) Although I was considered something of a lefty in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>--and am now somewhat to the right of many of my liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northampton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>--I've always had more in common, politically and culturally, with my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> than not. There may well be large pockets of gay hatred in the land,
but it's not something I can gauge because I rarely see it in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life. So
my impulse is to think, as you do, that despite the murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepherd</ENAMEX>,
that gay-bashing is fading. (The entertainment culture also buttresses this
view.) But I also have to acknowledge that my isolation could be leading me
very astray. After all, I am also utterly baffled by the extent to which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> engenders so much rage in so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. But obviously he does.

            Anyway ... before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> is out, I hope to engage you on your area of
expertise: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, the Internet as a business and cultural phenomenon, IPO stock
madess, and so on. Just for fun, though, check out the story in the New York
Times sports section <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">River Little League</ENAMEX> team
winning its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> game in the Little League <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>. I realize this is a
real story for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River</ENAMEX> is in its circulation area, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is a powerhouse--but there was something awfully weird about the way
the story was written, as if it were a big league game with big league
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballplayers</ENAMEX>. ("[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaynor</ENAMEX> again baffled the opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> with a mix of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and raw power ...") Even the quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star pitcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaynor</ENAMEX> sounded
like something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Clemens</ENAMEX> might say. "I just wanted to throw strikes and
make them hit the ball," he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geez</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years old</TIMEX>.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.s.</ENAMEX> where are you going on your honeymoon?

         
      
   
