
   
   
      
         
            Will There Be Life After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>?
            

            If you blinked you missed it, but for a short while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> the
stock and bond markets dived after a rumor that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> was resigning
hit the Street. The story was quickly ... well, it wasn't exactly refuted,
since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> didn't say actually say "I'm not resigning," but it was
rejected as unlikely, and both markets rebounded nicely.

            Fleeting as it was, the momentary episode of selling panic was interesting
for a couple of reasons. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, the rumor had all the makings of a
story that was being floated by someone who had taken a large short position
(in other words, who was wagering that the market was going down) and was
trying to knock the market down after it opened strongly. There's something
weirdly old-fashioned about the idea that a big Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX> could say
"Pssst! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>, I hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>'s on his way out!" and send stocks tumbling. It
fits our ideas of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>, when the market was incredibly manipulable, or
even of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> more than it does the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX>.

            But the truth is that in the short run, markets can occasionally be pushed,
especially when so many decisions to buy or sell are keyed off what everyone
else in the market is doing. Chain reactions are not much harder to start (in
fact, given how quickly price moves get noticed, they may be easier) than they
were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years ago</TIMEX>.

            All that notwithstanding, the interesting thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>
resignation rumor was that it raised an obvious question: Would it really
matter? As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> just pointed out in " 
Ballot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> is apparently the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who doesn't think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> has done a terrific job as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. And most of us would be
happy to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> stay in office even after his current term expires in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">middle of next year</TIMEX>. But it's interesting to note that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple</TIMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> there have been more than a few voices--including those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Mankiw</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Barr</ENAMEX>--suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> has been more the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> of good economic fundamentals than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of them.

            That position may be a bit overstated, particularly since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> has
shown an unusual ability to let his thinking on inflation, productivity, and
the economy's possible growth rate evolve in response to changing data. But the
essential point, that the soundness of this economy does not depend on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s presence at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>, is right. That might not be the
case if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> were either an inflation dove like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greider</ENAMEX> or a perma-bear like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Grant</ENAMEX>. But whoever would succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>
would be nothing of the sort. He or she would be, in a word, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenspanian</ENAMEX>,
still concerned about the possibility of an overheating economy but also
convinced that important technological changes have allowed this economy to
grow faster than in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> without sparking inflation.

            If anything, in fact, the bond market should have rallied on news that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> might be stepping down, since he has long since stopped being
paranoid enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bondholders</ENAMEX>, who seem perpetually convinced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> is about to become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. There are certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> out there
who would be far more likely to raise interest rates aggressively at the first
hint of price pressures than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>.

            The momentary sell-off, though, was not driven by any rational consideration
of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s departure might mean. Instead, everyone assumes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s resignation will knock down the market, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s
resignation--or rumors of it--knocks down the market. But this is not the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 1998</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1997</TIMEX>. We don't need <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> to reassure us that
the world isn't going to fall apart anymore. When he leaves, the market will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hiccup</ENAMEX>. But it would be surprising if it did more than that.

         
      
   
