
   
   
      
         
            Take Those <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old Records Off the Shelf</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            Here we are, on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">22nd</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX>'s death, debating rock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'n</ENAMEX>' roll--or at least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Miller</ENAMEX>'s version of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> brings a deep
intellectual understanding of what certain major acts have contributed to rock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'n</ENAMEX>' roll but short-shrifts others. I admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s erudition, but I found his
book dull.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> first heard rock in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, won early renown as a rock
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> , and was rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. He tells the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock anecdotally</ENAMEX>--through
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">few dozen</NUMEX> isolated vignettes--and conventionally. Here's how it goes. Rhythm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'n</ENAMEX>' blues (the music of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>) and other manifestations of the black
"sound," like urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doo-wop</ENAMEX>, came to the attention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>--like the record
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mogul Ahmet Ertegun</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">songwriters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Leiber</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoller</ENAMEX> (who wrote "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hound Dog</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>") in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Freed</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>, who was totally immersed in black
music almost by accident. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Phillips</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>, said, "If I
could find a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> sound and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> feel, I could make
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion dollars</NUMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>'s training as an intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> is the source of most of the
strengths and weaknesses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dustbin</ENAMEX> . In a To the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finland Station</ENAMEX> sort of way, ideas have consequences, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> has an
intellectual genealogy for everything. Freed and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ertegun</ENAMEX> bring commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rapacity</ENAMEX> to rock. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Clark</ENAMEX> brings technical fixing, lip-synching, and the
dressing up of weak voices. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> globalize this music. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX> enter when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> turns the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> on to pot, and become central with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful</ENAMEX>
Dead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Velvet Underground</ENAMEX> (through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>) marries rock to a bleak,
minimalist urban counterculture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janis Joplin</ENAMEX> invents primal screaming and Jimi
Hendrix a kind of vatic solipsism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX> brings in kitsch and hype.
Finally, the Sex Pistols unite all the nihilism and flimflam that's been
accumulating like sediment in the rock industry and the rock mind-set, and an
era ends--roughly around the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> dies. All these "trends" strike me as
artificial and overdetermined.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the striking differences between this rock history and others is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> looks at rock as being over --since roughly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, we've had
nothing but reprises of old themes. Do you buy that? I distrust it. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>
says that the "most profound sentimental basis" of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> is nostalgia , I
hear not a critical insight but the moaning of one who's, like the rest of us,
getting old.

            And what about the general sweep of the narrative? I'm particularly
impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s discriminations from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '70s</TIMEX>,
when rock must have been freshest to him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Gaye</ENAMEX> is every bit the giant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paints</ENAMEX> him as, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Morrison</ENAMEX> every bit the pseud. (Some of the
freshest lines in the book come with his description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>'s film
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doors</ENAMEX> , which "offers an inadvertent parody, a portrait of an amateur
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oracle</ENAMEX>'s excruciatingly dull metamorphosis into a pitiful, drunken slob.")

            But I'm troubled by things that are missing:

            

               Where is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Cooke</ENAMEX>, who is a plausible bridge between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills Brothers</ENAMEX>'
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Found My Million Dollar Baby</ENAMEX> (In the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX>-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cent Store</ENAMEX>)" and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaye</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let's Get It On"</ENAMEX>?

               Where's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX>, which played such a role in turning a counterculture
into a culture?

               Where are the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beach Boys</ENAMEX>, whose dissolution, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Wilson</ENAMEX>'s,
shows that the drug-addled despair of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> ran as deep in glee-club <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> as it did in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Factory</ENAMEX>?

               Where is disco, surely as reliable an indicator of musical decadence as the
Sex Pistols?

               Where are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steely Dan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Zappa</ENAMEX>?

            

            And what do you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s take on race? Most accounts tend to view
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX> as either <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> column in the war on racism, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2</NUMEX>) another venue for
capitalist race theft. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> is subtler. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, he shows just how many
1950s rock hits had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> versions--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bad White One</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Boone</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ain't That</ENAMEX>
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shame"</ENAMEX>) that hits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Black One</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Domino's "Ain't</ENAMEX>
It a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shame"</ENAMEX>) that languishes in the middle of the charts. But he also shows
that borrowings worked both ways, and that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> were more daringly
receptive to certain rock innovations, if their delight in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Richard</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filthy</ENAMEX> lyrics is any indication.

            The musical descriptions in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>'s book strike me as flat and formulaic,
as in: "An up-tempo rocker built around a boogie riff and a dramatically
unconventional modulation between major and minor keys, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Hold Me Tight</ENAMEX>' was
written in one style alone--that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>." This is
equal parts music theory, pseudery, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teen Beat gush</ENAMEX>. But strip it
away and what are you left with? Business writing, a narrative of how
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Agent X</ENAMEX> reneged on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Performer Y</ENAMEX>'s contract and took her to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Label Z.</ENAMEX> So a closing
question for you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>: Why is it so hard to write well about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>?

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
