
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrifying Turkish Temblors</ENAMEX>

            The earthquake in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> takes center stage as the death toll
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skyrockets</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 2,100</NUMEX> dead, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 13,000</NUMEX> injured, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 10,000</NUMEX> missing. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
which reefered initial quake reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, goes with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-column
headline. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with the quake except <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , which off-leads
it. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s decision to prohibit over
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from giving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in order to preclude a theoretical risk that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">transfusions</ENAMEX> could spread <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">mad cow disease</ENAMEX>--a story fronted by no other paper.
The ban affects anybody who spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over six</NUMEX> cumulative <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isle of Man</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel</ENAMEX> Islands from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 1980, to Dec. 31, 1996</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Red Cross</ENAMEX> said the restriction
will decrease the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> supply by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.2 percent</NUMEX> per year.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45-second</TIMEX> temblor struck at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in the populous region
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surrounding Istanbul</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seismologists</ENAMEX> said it measured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.7</NUMEX> on the Richter
scale, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seismologists</ENAMEX> said it may have peaked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.8</NUMEX>. (This is a
bigger difference than it seems: The Richter scale is logarithmic, not linear,
so a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.8</NUMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 10</NUMEX> times as strong as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.7</NUMEX>. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> explains
this. To learn how the Richter scale works, click here; to
learn what damage will typically result from a given Richter reading, click
here.) Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that the quake may be downgraded to a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7.4</NUMEX>. There have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 250</NUMEX> aftershocks.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times notes that so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izmut</ENAMEX>--located <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">65 miles</NUMEX> east of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Istanbul</ENAMEX> and perched over the epicenter--that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> turned the local ice skating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX> into a backup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">morgue</ENAMEX>. Because it
took government rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine hours</TIMEX> to arrive there, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> at first
attempted to dig out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> with pickaxes and sledgehammers. (The LAT
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post appear to be the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Izmut</ENAMEX>, and it
shows.) Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> quake in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX> killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> calls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s temblor "one of the worst
earthquakes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>," but what does this mean? Do they mean in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> or
the world? Do they mean fatalities or the magnitude of the shockwaves?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front the announcement by former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> that he will head a center-left coalition
designed to win the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> parliamentary elections and put forth a
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatherland</ENAMEX>-All-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, was
created <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuri Luzhkov</ENAMEX>. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX>'s
support, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> now expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>--now
controlled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>--and the presidency--now controlled by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outgoing Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> chose new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>
as his preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatherland</ENAMEX>-All-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> presidential candidate
will be either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX>--whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> fired as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>--or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luzhkov</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> report that defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> have drafted a proposal outlining
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s nuclear weapons policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> would never be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to strike, and
it would retaliate only against a nuclear power that had used nuclear weapons
against it. The proposal also envisions a large nuclear command-and-control
system consisting of land-, sea-, and submarine-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, and it would
limit nuclear strike authority to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX>
speculated that the announcement of the proposal--which cannot become policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> against a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> strike and at reassuring the world of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s sense of
nuclear responsibility.

            The LAT fronts a story documenting unexpected spin-off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> research. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have long criticized the research as
disproportionate to actual suffering--when compared to more common diseases
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>, for instance--but the advances in virology,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">microbiology</ENAMEX>, and immunology brought about by the research have now led to
several non-AIDS-related <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--such as a new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> treatment
and a valuable treatment for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> B--have been effective against many
chronic viral <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, historically among the hardest to cure.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gives above-the-fold treatment to allegations by the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">counterintelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> that the espionage investigation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> is racist. It waits until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> paragraph to credit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , which broke this story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. For its part, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> does not even mention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s report on the
theft of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in international relief to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>.

            Correction: On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" stated that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> article
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>'s possible presidential bid did not mention the movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> . It did. TP regrets the error.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several months ago</TIMEX>, 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>
wrote about the 
extremes to which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> will go to give a story an economic
spin. In this spirit, the lead paragraph of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s earthquake
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> merits quoting in full: "A powerful <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45-second</TIMEX> earthquake cut a swath
through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">heartland</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, shutting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, wrecking major power lines and jolting national confidence just as
the economy showed signs of leaving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>'s recession behind."

         
      
   
