
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay Marriage Backlash</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Joe</ENAMEX>,

            So I got married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, to be exact, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half past 11</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o'clock</ENAMEX> on an impossibly sunny <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco Bay</ENAMEX> and
its spectacular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate Bridge</ENAMEX>. There was a touch of wind blowing off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, which was enough to keep my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> cool, but not enough to blow their
carefully coifed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX> into a mousse mess. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">amber</ENAMEX> light sparkled all along
the bay as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> lay like a crown jewel in the
distance.

            If I say so myself, it was a completely perfect wedding to go along with the
perfect weather. There were of course the superficial details of the
event--from the wildflower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch</ENAMEX> in front of which we took our vows to the tower
of festively decorated individual cupcakes that an ingenious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baker</ENAMEX> hand
fashioned into a unique kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wedding cake</ENAMEX> to the delightful surprise I got
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> each time I noticed the antique <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> around my finger that had
previously and always been bare. And there were the much more profound moments
that come from finally committing to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for the rest of your
life--looking into each other's eyes as you are promising to love and cherish
one another, the joy radiating from the sea of faces of loved ones who had
traveled from near and far to share in the event, the rush of happiness as
their glasses clinked in a unified toast to our shared lives that lay ahead
with so much possibility.

            Imagine my chagrin then, to read an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story that had popped up over the
same <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> that several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> had pledged to
oppose allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX> to adopt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, same-sex relationships
under the term "marriage," discussion of homosexuality in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and federal
laws to specifically protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> from discrimination, part of an
overall effort by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> anti-gay groups in this latest election cycle.

            Well, since I had just held <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these dreaded same-sex weddings (icky
term, don't you think?--I prefer my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride-bride</ENAMEX>" hitching
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phraseology</ENAMEX>), I guess they told me. Except, of course, I don't seem to be
paying an ounce of attention to the continuing and perplexingly tireless
efforts of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> they manage to strong-arm into
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intolerance</ENAMEX>. Apparently, a great gob of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had signed on, although
only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> (and, no, even though his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>, was widely rumored to be gay, I am not going to go there in
this obviously ironic twist of dysfunctional familial fate) had confirmed their
pledges.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> plus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xena Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>, and
current phenom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, did not sign, along with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and all around nice-seeming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>.

            So what am I to make of all this? The anti-gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> never seem to want to
give up on their battle to meddle in the private lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>,
while more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are learning more and more about the lives of gay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. The venues are many--from massive news coverage of
the coming out of a television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> (I loved the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yep</ENAMEX>, I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">title</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>--it was more like "Of course, she's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homo</ENAMEX>,"
since most of gay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> had gaydared Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Degeneres</ENAMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> she walked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">onscreen</ENAMEX>) to the tragedy of the brutal and senseless killing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepherd</ENAMEX>. Now, I am not a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--in fact, I am nearly
anti-political. Being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> all my life, I have naturally shunned any
side-taking. And covering the Internet as I do now, it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> for me, but
IPO.

            And yet, there I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, standing up in front of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> more <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night before</TIMEX> at a pre-wedding party we also
threw--doing something that is apparently at the heart of our current political
debate. Now, I know I live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> of sin <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to
some--but I did not get the feeling that I was some radical <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> that had
invaded the body politic. I simply felt like I was someone in love with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kindred soul</ENAMEX>, who wanted to be able to declare that in a way that had been
going on since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of time</TIMEX>.

            It's hard to imagine then that, given these complex times, with so many
important issues to deal with that are likely to challenge this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> going
forward, there seems to be such intense focus on this topic. I'd like to know
what you think about this, because I cannot for the life of me see why this
issue seems to inflame so many. Is it the religious thing? Is it the last gasp
of a former culture that wants to hold back the new one? Is it just a
smokescreen to inflame <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> rather than actually inform them? I only know the
words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> who came up to toast my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, who talked of love,
commitment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and the future, and not much of politics.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> she was marrying, but it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>," came the response. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> have been marrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">centuries</ENAMEX>."

            I could not have said it better myself. So I won't.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Kara

         
      
   
