
   
   
      
         
            Same As the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Rock</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            It's a strange rock history indeed whose pivotal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter concerns</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Bowie, but here you have it. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bowie</ENAMEX>'s failure to sell big in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Miller</ENAMEX> isolates what I suspect is the real tragedy in his own critical
life. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowie</ENAMEX>'s failure was, he writes, "an early indication that global youth
culture created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>, and ratified at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Monterey Pop Festival</ENAMEX>, was
already beginning to fall apart ..." What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> really seems to lament--more
than the hype, silliness, or commercialization of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>--is the death of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monoculture</ENAMEX>. Earlier in the book, he describes the global impact of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sgt.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX> --when you could hear it wafting out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafes</ENAMEX> "from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>"--with the wistfulness of an old
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> rhapsodizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> mass. Then again, who can blame him? Covering a
record that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times</ENAMEX> cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> called "a decisive moment
in the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> civilization," must have been a heady enterprise
indeed--especially if you bought the hype. Rock criticism must have seemed
fresher, more important, and probably easier then.

            Yes, new sounds can really ruin critical paradigms. Show me someone like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX> and I'll say, OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s right: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> is a "finished cultural
form--a more or less fixed repertoire of sounds and styles and patterns of
behavior." But show me someone like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wu-Tang Clan</ENAMEX>--whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> as "musically <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, gleefully obscene, and just plain silly" (as well
as "the triumph of the psychopathic adolescent")--and I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s simply
not listening. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Classifying Wu-Tang</ENAMEX>'s strange, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">chilly</TIMEX>, beats-and-glass
aesthetic--along with trance, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and trip-hop--as simply "new forms of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX>," requires either some impressive semantic gymnastics or deafness. I have
to mistrust someone who, while bemoaning the bland repetitiveness of current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX>, concedes that occasionally new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> do "catch [his] ear--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">En Vogue</ENAMEX>,
Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latifah</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardigans</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardigans</ENAMEX>?

            Still, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> have aligned to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> a nice context for his book
tour. We are, after all, in the age of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puffy Combs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Limp Bizkit</ENAMEX>, and that
life-affirming spectacle that was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Woodstock '99</NUMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flowers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port</ENAMEX>-a-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>?)
Given the last, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s snapshots of the riots that accompanied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moondog</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coronation Ball</ENAMEX>" and the early screenings of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Blackboard Jungle</ENAMEX> seem
judiciously chosen. I'm also glad a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> feels obliged to recognize the
real-life chaos and violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock unapolegetically</ENAMEX>, even a bit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">joyfully</ENAMEX>--closing with the image of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liverpool</ENAMEX>
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, disappointed that there wasn't a riot.

            What I like about the early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>'s
serendipitousness: the idea that jokes, studio tricks, and technical accidents
created a new pop form. That, and the way youthful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twitchiness</ENAMEX> and
uncertainty--from an uncomfortably pandering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Brown</ENAMEX> to an amateurish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankie Lymon</ENAMEX> to a jittery <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX>--formed a new musical vocabulary.
These kinds of unorthodox responses to rock's creation myth were fresh enough
to make me expect more from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> chapters than a gloss on punk as simply
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX>'s "quintessence" of "stunning ugliness." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s writing sure is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uneven</ENAMEX>, isn't it? When he's in teen-spirit mode, he'll lapse into
bodice-ripper-isms like "These records touched me in ways that I'd never been
touched before." And when he's trying some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greil Marcus-y</ENAMEX> fabulism, he'll
resort to a scene-setting device like "As the sun rose in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> ..." Hard to
believe the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> wrote those gorgeous meditations on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Gaye</ENAMEX> and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strawberry Fields</ENAMEX>."

            But I liked the sweep. I enjoyed the flashback, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Roeg</ENAMEX> approach
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> took to this overtold narrative, and actually, I bought a lot of his
seemingly perverse omissions, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX>. I certainly don't need to
hear this fetishized event described again, and I respect his choice of
Altamont as the more relevant chapter in rock's dark lineage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> that
bored me most were the retreads, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springsteen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, which basically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condensed Fred Goodman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mansion</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful Dead</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genesis</ENAMEX>, which seemed ancillary and, well, about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deadheads</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steely Dan</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Zappa</ENAMEX> strike me as tributaries pretty distant from the mainstream
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> was trying to trace, I think you're correctly suspicious of disco's
absence--and not just as a high-point of decadence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX> spends an entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX> lovingly detailing the design and production of the Fender electric
guitar, showing how the technology enabled an amateur musical expression that
would change mass culture. Disco prefigured the most cataclysmic reordering of
rock sound and attitude in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>: hip-hop, a form in which the technical
"gimmickry" that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> seems to both enjoy and distrust became central to
music-making. And that's leaving aside the race issues--until the next
letter.

            Yours truly,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Norris</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
