
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Net Access</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Kara</ENAMEX>,

            A new day, and I'm back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northampton</ENAMEX> after a quick trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. Between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> ride to and from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> out <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> might
be nice, but on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> it's hell--and the awful fluorescent lights in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Inc.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> is headquartered, I was a pretty
cranky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. My mood is much improved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, back in my lovely little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> overlooking this lovely little downtown, reading about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX>
victory <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>--rooting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> of all native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Englanders</ENAMEX>--perusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> before I saddle up for a day in
front of my computer. I check my e-mail, and there is your latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">missive</ENAMEX>--sent, it says, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 a.m.</TIMEX>! I'm happy to get it--though momentarily
worried that you're not getting enough sleep on what is supposed to be, after
all, a short vacation for you. In any case, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> I didn't think I could
muster another thought about the Internet if you put a gun to my head. But as I
say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I've got a whole new outlook.

            The distinction I was trying to make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was between the Internet as a
tool to make the world a better place (which I don't buy) and the Internet as a
powerful business tool (which I very much do buy). And so there is not that
much in your message that I disagree with, because you are focusing on the
business dynamics. Where we do differ, clearly, is our level of enthusiasm for
the coming of interactivity. You're right: I roll my eyes at the thought of an
"Internet refrigerator." I'm not all that sure I'd even want to have a Web site
dedicated to me and my needs--which are pretty mundane and pretty well
satisfied without such a site. For that matter, I'm not even much of a cell
phone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>--I've got a digital phone, but it only works <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the time,
and I don't bother to get anything else.

            (To answer another query of yours: On the privacy issue, I subscribe to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott McNealy</ENAMEX> position. When asked about this one time, he said something to
the effect of: "You've already lost your privacy. Get over it." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years ago</TIMEX>,
I wrote a book that was devoted, in part, to the rise of the credit card
industry. In doing that research, I became painfully aware of how much personal
information was already "sloshing around," as you put it. In other words, long
before the Internet, this battle had been lost. And in truth, I don't much care
what is discovered about my "habits" through my Web use.)

            I was particularly glad you brought up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, for the story in the
Times that caught my eye <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America Online Offers Free</ENAMEX>
Internet Use in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>." This is big, and potentially very dangerous for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>.
The reason it is the most successful Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is that it has a huge
revenue stream because it charges a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> subscription fee. There is no way
it wants give away free what it used to charge for, but it is being forced to
do so by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that is offering free Web access--and has taken away
a big chunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s market share in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. This, of course, is precisely
what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> did to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>--it gave away for free a product (the browser)
that produced most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>'s revenues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Andreessen</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wonderboy</ENAMEX> who now works at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, must be having nightmares!

            There it is again, though--the Net's ability to blindside an established
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, to squeeze away profits, and to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> a deal that seemingly
makes no economic sense but is great for them. The irony is that the
established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in this case is not some so-called bricks-and-mortar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX>, but a Net <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>! My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Serwer</ENAMEX> predicts that
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 to 24 months</TIMEX>, nobody will charge for Internet access. Where in
the world will that put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> then?

            I will say this for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>, who never figured out
what to do when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> took away their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>, those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> at AOL
are awfully resilient. They proved it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, when it was widely
believed that their service would be rendered irrelevant by the growth of the
Internet. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s performance during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> has been
little short of astounding. I have no doubt they will adapt to broadband, and
deflect the threat posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>. And they've done a great job keeping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> from eating their lunch, which is no easy task. But can they adapt to
the potential loss of most of their revenue stream? I dunno. Do you?

            I leave you with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other question, which I've been wondering about for
awhile. When I was covering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial, I got to see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> AOL
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> testify: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Colburn</ENAMEX>, who was on the stand twice, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
Case, who was deposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> when the trial was in recess. They were both
smart, clever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who could not be rattled, and easily deflected even the most
hostile questions from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colburn</ENAMEX> struck me as one mean
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOB</ENAMEX>.) But the trait they had most in common is that were both real wiseacres,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sarcastic</ENAMEX> and darkly funny. Is that kind of sarcasm part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> culture?
And if so, what does it say about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>?

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
