
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vast Wasteland of Politics</ENAMEX>
            

            On the market, well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> is blipping back and forth, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> is on a
downward trend, high-tech stocks are going down ... Not that I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>.
Just looking at the numbers.

            Not to get heavily into the (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill) Clinton</ENAMEX> thing, since I'm tired of it,
too, but whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> should be judged just an ordinary totalitarian federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> or the central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in a witch-hunt depends on whether you think
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair should ever have been dragged into the Whitewater
investigation in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place, which I obviously don't. A terrible sense of
public relations, I certainly agree with you there, but blaming the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
spin machine for that insanely prurient report is something of a stretch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
isn't really <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, though, except in the sense that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
talent as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> can't help but emphasize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s lack of same. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are
going to vote against him because of him, not because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Let's
see--right now I suppose I prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>, but that's probably because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX>
hasn't opened his mouth. Basically, he's of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX> ilk. I don't
see any particular reason to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, who is fundamentally conservative
economically and socially, as well as married to one of our great
anti-popular-culture pests. At least <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has smoked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>. No, I'll probably
vote for some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">third-party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> and hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will lose the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> so that whoever wins the presidency, nothing much will get done in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next four years</TIMEX>. From my point of view, so long as there is no functioning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> movement on the left, mainstream politics will continue to be a vast
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wasteland</ENAMEX> and my main criterion in voting will be how best to stave off the
ultra-right lunatics.

            By a functioning left I mean among other things a left with ideas, a left
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> can put forward an analysis of what's wrong with the
restructuring of the economy and the repressiveness of the culture, rather than
avoid looking at the quality of their own lives via sentimental moralizing
about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Strauss</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springsteen</ENAMEX> review actually refers to as the "poor
huddled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>." This is what's really wrong with the review--and ultimately
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springsteen</ENAMEX> himself. His wealth is beside the point; it's his moral
earnestness that grates. I confess I had skipped over that story, basically
because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Springsteen</ENAMEX> at this point is about as newsworthy in terms of
contemporary popular culture as, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verdi</ENAMEX>. I don't follow pop music much
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, but the genres that are most interesting to me in a larger cultural
and political sense are techno and hip-hop. And I can't say I find much
intelligent crit on either.

         
      
   
