
   
   
      
         
            Why Isn't There a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soccer Network</ENAMEX>?
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the more perplexing--actually, I'll say it's the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perplexing</ENAMEX>--facts about television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is that there is essentially nowhere,
other than pay-per-view, where you can watch international soccer such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FA Cups</ENAMEX>, let alone regular-season matches from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premier</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serie A.</ENAMEX>

            This depressing fact has already prompted a welcome cri de coeur from

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contributor Michael Hirschorn</ENAMEX> in the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s
Content , where he points out how odd it is that in the wasteland that is
the upper reaches of the cable box, there's no room for true international
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Beckham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ronaldo</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davor Suker</ENAMEX>. But the paradoxical
situation is that something that is incredibly valuable abroad--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>,
you might remember, was willing to shell out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> to acquire the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester United</ENAMEX> franchise--is thought to have little or no value in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. And while we might well ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>, "Wouldn't it make more sense
to show <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> great international matches a week instead of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SportsCenter</ENAMEX> reruns?," it costs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> nothing to run the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">SportsCenter</ENAMEX> reruns, while buying the rights to international
matches--which are, in any case, mostly controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>--wouldn't
necessarily come cheap.

            The key words here, though, are "thought to have little or no value."
Despite the ascendance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> moms into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political iconography,
despite the fact that a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> has now grown up playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, and
despite the success of successive <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>) here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> and
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the essential operating assumption of television programmers for all
the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>--broadcast and cable--is that no real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for
international soccer exists. But more and more, this seems to be a clear case
where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the reasons that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> has failed to materialize is because the
opportunity for it to materialize has never existed.

            It's not, after all, as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> had given international soccer the
old college try, found that it failed, and then abandoned its plans. On the
contrary, if you want to watch international soccer, you usually have to pay
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> for pay-per-view, which, no matter how much you love soccer, is a
lot of money. And even then the publicity for the games is essentially
nonexistent. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> played a match in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meadowlands</ENAMEX>, which is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX> away from where I live. I didn't hear
about it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the match was played.

            What's odd about this is that in certain respects soccer seems to be a
natural. Not to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football or baseball</ENAMEX>, but maybe to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ESPN2</TIMEX>. There are more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> descent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> than ever before, who you would think might be interested in watching
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ronaldo</ENAMEX> play for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inter Milan</ENAMEX>. More than that, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play the game,
which presumably must make them curious about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who play it better
than anyone else.

            And then there's this interesting fact, which was actually noted in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front-page</ENAMEX> article in the business section of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> :
The most popular video game made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Arts</ENAMEX>, the largest video-game
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> in the world, is <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FIFA '99</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> game featuring all the great
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. Is it really plausible that there's a huge market for an
international soccer video game, and no market at all for international soccer
on television? As it happens, I'm a devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">FIFA '99</ENAMEX>, and its sister
game, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup '98</ENAMEX>. And everyone I've met who plays these games cares about
international soccer and would be ecstatic were some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> to take a flyer
and show some of these games.

            In theory, if an opportunity to make money by showing international soccer
exists, someone would have already taken advantage of it. But it's almost
certainly true that none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in charge of programming grew up
playing or watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, which is why you always hear the same criticisms of
the game--too slow, too boring, not enough scoring. At the same time, the
continuing woes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>--have made it seem as if
there is no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for the game. But although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLS</ENAMEX> is much better
than it was, it's still vastly inferior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> game, so the popularity
of one is a poor measure of the potential popularity of the other.

            The point isn't that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> will ever become a huge cash cow for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
network. But it has all the makings of a perfect niche market. The problem is
that until someone gives that market a real chance to show itself, we can't
prove it exists. Until then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Arts</ENAMEX> will keep raking in the profits of
which some television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> might otherwise claim a nice share.

         
      
   
