
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> Should <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stick With What It Knows</ENAMEX>
            

            For a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> whose roots are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Labs</ENAMEX>, source of innumerable
technological breakthroughs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> is surprisingly unembarrassed about buying
technology that it can't, or doesn't want, to build itself. Since it was spun
off from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> has made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> acquisitions at a cost of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32 billion</NUMEX>, including a major deal it closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, when it agreed to acquire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excel Switching Corp.</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 billion</NUMEX>.

            While it's now well known that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least half</NUMEX> of all mergers fail--in the
sense that they destroy rather than create shareholder value--it's also become
well known that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are exceptionally good at integrating
acquisitions into their existing operations. Not coincidentally, perhaps, two
of the best are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, namely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent and Cisco</ENAMEX> (which, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> beware, I
own shares in). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco</ENAMEX>, in fact, closed a small deal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$143</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MaxComm Technologies</ENAMEX>, which specializes in high-speed Net
access. And before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> is out, expect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent and Cisco</ENAMEX> to announce more
deals. It's a kind of acquisition arms race.

            For the most part, the logic behind that race is compelling. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX>, with
its roots in more traditional telephone equipment, is trying to move strongly
into computer and data networks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco</ENAMEX>, for its part, wants to build on its
already commanding position in data networking, even as it shifts more and more
of its business to take advantage of the explosion in the Internet. And with
technology shifting and developing as rapidly as it is, it's difficult (let's
say impossible) for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to keep everything in-house. Instead, smaller
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> create and develop technology, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> step in, buy up
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with their pricey stock, and reap the benefits. Needless to
say, this strategy works only if you're good at bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> on board
without wrecking them or yourself. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent and Cisco</ENAMEX> are.

            The danger in all this, though, is overreaching, stretching a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> beyond
what it's really good at. Take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.7 billion</NUMEX> acquisition by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Network Services</ENAMEX>, a telecom consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that helps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> design, install, and maintain computer and data networks. The deal
was hailed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and the press as a powerful move by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> into
"services," offering the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will now be able to come to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> for one-stop shopping. Not only will we sell you the equipment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX>
can now promise, but we'll help you install it and keep it running. Hell, we'll
even tell you why you should buy it in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            That last point signals one of the obvious problems with the deal, which is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>'s business depends on the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> trust it to give them
the best advice possible. If, every time a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> asks an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> what
kind of system it should install, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> says, "Why, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX>, of
course," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> aren't going to be trusting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> much longer.

            But even aside from that, this was a dubious acquisition, because in essence
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.7 billion</NUMEX> to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> whose profit margins and earnings
growth are significantly lower than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent's</ENAMEX>. This may seem counterintuitive,
given that all you hear about lately is how important it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> is moving
into services--i.e., its e-business initiative--or that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> is
revitalizing itself as a services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. But the truth is that it's better to
make hardware or software than to be in services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consulting</ENAMEX> is a fine
business, on its own terms. But next to making switches or routers--let alone
Windows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">98</TIMEX>--it's mediocre at best.

            The reason is obvious: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> require <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and always will. When you're
making hardware or, even better, licensing software, all your costs are under
your control, and once the product is actually developed, your profit margins
are very high. And production lines can be automated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consulting</ENAMEX>, though, is by
definition a labor-intensive, time-intensive business. Profit margins are much
lower. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>'s net margins--profit divided by revenue--are <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 8 percent</NUMEX>,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco's</ENAMEX> are at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>. This is inherent in the nature of the
business--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> won't be able to change it.

            It's understandable, what with the new vogue for one-stop shopping, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> would want to offer services in addition to equipment. But in acquiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucent</ENAMEX> appears to be forgetting one of the most important lessons of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two decades</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> do best when they do only what they do best.

         
      
   
