
   
   
      
         
            Will There <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Be Trouble With Harry</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Polly</ENAMEX>,

            According to a clipping from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> passed along by our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted sorceress</ENAMEX> in her own right), there are now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> editions of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books designed especially for adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. The content is
the same, of course, but the grown-up version cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about two pounds</NUMEX> more than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' version, and, I presume, looks more sober and serious. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">thousand</ENAMEX> have been sold. I thought this was funny, but then again when I was
reading these books in public places in preparation for our chat I would make
sure to have a notebook and pencil and even my laptop handy, to make clear to
the utterly indifferent world that I was working , which probably made me
look even sillier.

            I take your point about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and preaching, though I think that they tend to
tolerate the moral if the story is good enough. But then again, they may learn
their morals in part from the stories they hear. I do suspect (you imply that
you do, too) that the boomer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who so gleefully force-feed their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
lesson-heavy, humorless, politically correct books seize upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> novels
because they're so blessedly free of didacticism. Of course, there are subtle
warnings against prejudice and snobbery (as embodied by the odious Malfoy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clan</ENAMEX>), and affirmations of the virtues of honesty and friendship. But there is
also ample recognition of the fact that it's sometimes necessary to break the
rules, talk back to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, or fling a fistful of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX> at someone who
pisses you off. This flexible, realistic moral sense coexists with reassurances
that the important moral categories are, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, stable. Good and evil
exist in this world, and their struggle for dominance is what makes it go
around.

            I agree that the books get better and better, and that as you proceed from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to the next the series acquires more richness and density of detail. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
the neatest tricks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowling</ENAMEX> pulls off is to make the narrative move backward and
foreward at the same time: Part of the drama of each installment involves
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s finding out something new about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' deaths, and about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world of Hogwarts</ENAMEX> in their time. (Hogwarts seems to be the center of the wizard
world. Not only is every wizard presumably a graduate--unless we learn about a
rival <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a later</TIMEX> volume--but a surprising number of the best pupils
seem to return as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.) And there is a lovely mirroring of past and
present--an almost typological reflection between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s
rivalry with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malfoy</ENAMEX> is foreshadowed by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s rivalry with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snape</ENAMEX>, who is
still around to torment the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of his tormentor. And the themes of loyalty,
friendship, and betrayal that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> uncovers in the story of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demise</ENAMEX> (a story about which we still have much to learn), cast their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> on
his friendships with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermione</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>. The petty tensions between them that
begin to unfold in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prisoner of Azkaban</ENAMEX> may be the harbinger of something
more catastrophic in future books.

            I wondered, as you did, about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Percy the Prefect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>'s older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, who
becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head Boy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Azkaban</ENAMEX> . In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Secrets</ENAMEX> he began
behaving oddly, and it seemed as though he might be harboring thoughts of the
Dark <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Side</ENAMEX>. And I think (I hope) he still may be headed there: the great,
corrupting sin in this moral universe seems to be ambition, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Percy</ENAMEX> clearly
possesses. But so might <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Voldemort</ENAMEX> (whose name is never uttered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizards</ENAMEX> with less temerity than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dumbledore</ENAMEX>) is, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darth Vader</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>, a classic rebel angel, undone by his lust for power. And he may
decide at some point that it's better to co-opt the blessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> than to
annihilate him. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dumbledore</ENAMEX>'s benevolent but strict theology, involving the
operations of free will in a supernaturally determined world, is classically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miltonian</ENAMEX>--an odd note of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestantism</ENAMEX> in this decidedly pagan cosmos.) It is
always the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> who turn evil in this kind of story. It seems to me that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s final confrontation with the dark <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> will have to involve his
overcoming the temptation to join them. There is an inkling of this possibility
early on, when the sorting hat, which places new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in their residential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houses</ENAMEX>, tries to entice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX> to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slytherin</ENAMEX>, where baddies like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snape</ENAMEX> and
Malfoy hang out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> is promised greatness if he chooses their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, but
he opts for goodness and joins <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gryffindor</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, instead.

            Still, I suspect he'll face this dilemma again before long. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>
is not only a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, and a favorite with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogwarts</ENAMEX> faculty
(Snape excepted); he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gifted athlete</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quidditch</ENAMEX> pitch (how to explain?
It's the wizard pastime, something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> games of lacrosse played
simultaneously on broomsticks, with magic balls), and a natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> among
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. His decency has for now held his pride in check, but this might
(should, I daresay) change. I don't think the series can continue to be as
interesting if the menaces he faces continue to be strictly external. The
deeper darkness is within. Before long <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s terror and revulsion at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voldemort</ENAMEX> and what he represents may be overcome by curiosity, and his
veneration of his martyred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> may be colored with doubt, even anger. The
fact that each book so far allows him a greater measure of fallibility--and
that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> seem to slip and slide in the twilight zone between benign
and malevolent wizardry--suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowling</ENAMEX> may be aware of these
possibilities. In any case, I trust her to keep us enchanted.

            And let's not forget that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> has, at the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> of
Azkaban , just turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. We have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> books to go, and the stirrings of
puberty can't be far off. What is wizard adolescence like? Adolescence of any
kind is risky territory for the "young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>" book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, perhaps especially
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the present time</TIMEX>. How will Rowlings handle the dark
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magic</ENAMEX> of sexuality? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogwarts</ENAMEX> is coed, after all, and there's also the proud
tradition of English boarding school buggery to consider. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Harry</ENAMEX> and
Hermione get it on? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermione</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>? Does a cracking voice mess
up your spells? Is there a potion to cure <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">acne</ENAMEX>? Do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizards</ENAMEX> ever date
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">muggles</ENAMEX>?

            Can you divine the future? I await the magic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX> bearing your answer to
these vital questions.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
