
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bret</ENAMEX>? Don't Fret

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with weaker-than-expected <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Bret</ENAMEX>, while
continuing to front updates on relief efforts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> earthquake
zone.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> along the southeastern coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> fled in advance
of the hurricane, which lost strength <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and made <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">landfall</ENAMEX> in a
sparsely populated area south of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> and north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownsville</ENAMEX>. Bret
spawned winds as high as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">140 mph</NUMEX> but was itself rather slow, heading north and
then northwest across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf of Mexico</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7 mph</NUMEX> before coming ashore <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 6</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX> local time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenedy County</ENAMEX>, population <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">420</NUMEX>.

            That lumbering pace, though, has raised new fears of flooding in southern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. Meteorologists are now predicting more than a foot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> in some
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>--plus a sea surge of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 15 feet</NUMEX> along the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> coast between Corpus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christi</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> border--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bret</ENAMEX> takes its time moving out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>
region. The papers offer detailed reporting on the sections of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bret</ENAMEX>'s
path. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> quotes a pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> interviewed while videotaping the
approaching storm on a rain-drenched <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> beach, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> notes that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenedy County</ENAMEX> and adjacent
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kleberg County</ENAMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> ... vastly outnumber the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>." But all the papers
fail to explain how a storm qualifies as a hurricane (once its top sustained
winds pass <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">74 mph</NUMEX>) as well as the quaint method by which tropical storms and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hurricanes</ENAMEX> are named (an alphabetical system that starts over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> with a
name beginning with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>" and is planned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in advance, so that we already
know that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such storm of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> region will be called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bertha</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hortense</ENAMEX>).

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> clean-up efforts turned to clearing debris and
stemming the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> as it became clear, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> after the quake,
that few if any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> remain to be discovered alive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">divers</ENAMEX> searching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea of Marmara</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since the
disaster, found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, apparently those of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> who lived in
houses facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also describes the growing profile of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> military in relief work, and says anger among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> at slow
government response to the quake is still quite strong. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>,
Cumhurriyet , published a front-page editorial calling for governmental
accountability that carried the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Complete Change of Mentality Is</ENAMEX>
Needed." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> devotes its front-page quake coverage to the story of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuksel Er</ENAMEX>, who was pulled from the wreckage of his apartment
building south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Istanbul</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> after spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">97 hours</TIMEX> trapped beneath
rubble.

            On the op-ed page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> calls on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> directly whether he has ever
used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>. "An honest declaration would serve him, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, well,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> writes. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is also clearly dismayed that the national press,
which failed to pursue with any energy what he considers credible charges that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> raped a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, has not let up on the question of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX>. "Whatever happened to 'scandal fatigue'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> wonders.
"It appears that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> have gained their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> wind."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> bounty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> who follow fleeing bail-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumpers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> are increasingly winding up
behind bars themselves. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 18 months</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> searching for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fugitives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baja</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> have been jailed. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> cops "often winked at"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bounty hunters</ENAMEX>' tactics in the past, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, but now consider those
efforts rogue police work and a serious violation of national law.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager suggests that a byproduct of aggressive policing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> has been a rise in the number of what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> calls "flawed arrests." City <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> tossed out arrests last year
at a rate more than twice as high as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>, with drug charges more
likely than any other kind to be dropped. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is also paying more to
settle lawsuits claiming false arrest--a median amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,500</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first four months of this year</TIMEX>, up from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> figure of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cover Story</ENAMEX>" gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Baker</ENAMEX>, a self-styled
"master <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX>" whose folksy radio shows, how-to books, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> specials
recommend dousing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> with mixtures that include chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, mouthwash,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX>. A former undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> who began writing a gardening column in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> is adored by older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>--and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, since
he ranks as one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most successful on-air fundraisers for public
television. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, call him a huckster whose advice
could be unhealthy for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> alike, and imply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> puts him on the
air primarily because he's so good at getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to pull out their
checkbooks along with their trowels.

         
      
   
