
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Tony</ENAMEX>,

            You raise a truly terrifying specter--romance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermie</ENAMEX> sitting in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">K-I-S-S-I-N-G</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eight-year-olds</TIMEX> around the world will turn queasy at the
thought. Of course, we did get the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glimmerings of it in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of</ENAMEX>
Secrets , when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermione</ENAMEX>--along with half the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogwarts</ENAMEX> and
everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>--go all dewy-eyed at the thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilderoy Lockhart</ENAMEX>, that
god-awful blowhard of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Against the Dark Arts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the
perfect profile. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowling</ENAMEX>, please! You're giving girlkind a bad name.) In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Azkaban</ENAMEX> , there are hints that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s sweet on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cho Chang</ENAMEX>,
who plays the same position he does on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ravenclaw's Quidditch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. She's a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> year, which makes her an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Then there's the littlest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weasley</ENAMEX>,
Ginny, who conceives a crush on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> early in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. It gets her into trouble
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book 2</ENAMEX>--evidently, wanting to make a good impression on your beloved is
another impulse that can inadvertently put you in the hands of darkness. Is
there more story to be milked there? Ginny, for example, could turn into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">knockout in Book 5</ENAMEX>, when she should be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 or so</TIMEX>, winning--too late--the
hitherto impermeable heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX>, then extracting just revenge by scorning
him utterly, sending him off on a quixotic love-quest just when he's most
needed to save the world. No? I doubt it, too, but it's a thought. I'm more
inclined to look for the sexpots of supernatural tradition: sirens, vampires,
various enchantresses, those green <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> with rotten or serpentine lower
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>--what are they called?--who show up in (for example) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleridge</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christobel</ENAMEX>." Can you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malfoy</ENAMEX> vying for the attentions
of a mermaid? Well, whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowling</ENAMEX> does with sexuality, you can be sure it'll
be funny.

            We know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizards</ENAMEX> date muggles, from time to time--I'm pretty sure some
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are products of mixed marriages. (Can't remember who, though.)
That's an interesting idea--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowling</ENAMEX> could bring in a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">muggle hero</ENAMEX>. It
needn't be a love interest; it could just be someone with whom frustrated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> lacking all magical talents can identify. Someone utterly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unmagical</ENAMEX> who
nevertheless enters the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">wizard world</ENAMEX> and makes a difference. I agree with you
that we all know ourselves to be misunderstood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magicians</ENAMEX> trapped in a horribly
mundane world. (This is particularly true in childhood, but I'm not over it
yet--are you?) Still, there's that nasty inner voice that revels in whispering
words of reason, and I, for one, believe it, too--it makes a plausible case
that you and I are ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> after all. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowling</ENAMEX> might do us a service
by writing a place for us. (Well, me, anyway. You're clearly a real
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magician</ENAMEX>.)

            I'll be astonished (though delighted) if any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> turn out to
be gay. Bet you a silver sickle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX> themes are treated with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sublimation</ENAMEX> and symbolism.

            As far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s being tempted by power, I see what you mean, but I don't
really think that's where the series is headed. We've seen it so often
before--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saruman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord of the Rings</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milton</ENAMEX>'s irritating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX>, even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Voldemort</ENAMEX> himself--and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> isn't the type. He's too ordinary. Sure, he loves
winning at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quidditch</ENAMEX>, but he's just not into power. Or fame, even,
really--remember how grossed out he gets (as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>) when Gilderoy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockhart</ENAMEX> gives him tips for grabbing the spotlight? I say his failings will be
less about power, more about love. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Sorcerer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> , he's tempted
by a mirror that shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>'s heart's desire. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazing</ENAMEX> in it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> sees
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX>: his dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and a whole array
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ancestors</ENAMEX>. He can hardly bring himself to turn away, and sneaks back for
another fix whenever he gets the chance. I think he's more likely to be caught
by that kind of temptation than by a hunger for power. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voldemort</ENAMEX> could pose as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guardian</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s heritage, as someone who loves him. But you could be
right about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s anger towards his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>--they did leave him dramatically
in the lurch, after all, despite saving his life. I'd sure be mad if I had to
go live with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>.

school. There are the ambitious <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slytherins</ENAMEX>, the brainy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ravenclaws</ENAMEX>, the "just
and loyal" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hufflepuffs</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gryffindor</ENAMEX>, "where
dwell the brave at heart." It's not immediately clear why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sorting Hat</ENAMEX> puts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> it chooses. For example, wouldn't you guess scholarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hermione</ENAMEX> would belong in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ravenclaw</ENAMEX>? And I'm still waiting to find out what's so
brave about poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neville Longbottom</ENAMEX>, who keeps losing his pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">toad</ENAMEX>, getting
scolded by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, and cowering in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX>. What's he doing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Griffindor</ENAMEX>? He does have a brave moment when he stands up to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>--he
thinks they're up to no good--but it's not quite enough. So far, we don't know
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ravenclaws</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hufflepuffs</ENAMEX>. I'd like to see a book in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowling</ENAMEX> calls
upon the strengths of each <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>--even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slytherin</ENAMEX>--to aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> in his epic
struggle.

            What would you like to see? Got any suggestions for the divine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enchantress</ENAMEX>?

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polly</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
