
   
   
      
         
            Pig Out

            The "voting" will continue until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">p.m.</TIMEX>, but the early results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> straw poll are already in. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> threw huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> pitched around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>. They competed on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, music, and celebrity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. Here are the rankings in order.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Overall
atmosphere : <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> dance--minus the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Famous BBQ</ENAMEX> sandwiches good though a bit salty. Best coleslaw.
               

               
                  Music : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX>, a sultry country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> and the grunge-country band The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nadas</ENAMEX> rocked
out.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrities</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Staubach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Elliott</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio Spurs</ENAMEX> and assorted other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jocks</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  Bonus : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. 
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Nighthorse Campbell</ENAMEX> crashes the chow line.

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Buchanan</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Overall
atmosphere : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oktoberfest</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> 1934.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBQ</ENAMEX> by far the best of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. Also <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">husk</ENAMEX>-roasted sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> dipped in
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  Entertainment : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heartbeats</ENAMEX>, a decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">R&B</ENAMEX> cover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in cowboy hats.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrities</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.
Just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> autographing anything presented to him.
               

               
                  Bonus : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>
arrive in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tractor-trailers</ENAMEX>, honking feroiciously.
               

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lamar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Overall
atmosphere : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Ol' Opry</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Pulled pork
on a roll is overcooked and a little dry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Baby</ENAMEX> back ribs are better.
               

               
                  Music : <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 Stars</ENAMEX>. Country
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">singer Crystal Gayle</ENAMEX> proves a major draw.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrities</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Majors</ENAMEX>, the football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  Bonus : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>
autographs pictures for awestruck teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
Hatch
            

            

               
                  Overall
tone : <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mormon</ENAMEX> school picnic.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Tasty fried
chicken in addition to ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBQ</ENAMEX> ribs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berry</ENAMEX> cobbler for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  Music : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legendary Vic Damone</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrities</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Utah</ENAMEX>
Jazz power forward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Malone</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Forbes</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Overall
tone : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richie Rich</ENAMEX>'s 12th
birthday.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. More pulled
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork sandwiches</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  Music : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debby Boone</ENAMEX>
singing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Light Up My Life</ENAMEX>."
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Celebrities : Zero.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armstrong Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Weyrich</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Barr</ENAMEX>. You call these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> ?
               

               
                  Bonus : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Moonwalk,
air slide, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX> on stilts, and face painting. Plus an air-conditioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tent</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>
Dole
            

            

               
                  Overall
tone : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take Our Daughters to Work Day</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. Better
than it looked sliced pork <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BBQ</ENAMEX>. Ketchuplike <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>. Root <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> floats.
               

               
                  Music : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. Prairie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cats</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX> swing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrities</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            
               
                  Bonus : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX>-T <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> painted Liddy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow</ENAMEX>.
               
            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Overall
tone : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fraternal Order of Elks</ENAMEX> picnic.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sliced pork BBQ</ENAMEX> with
too-sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato salad</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chocolate milk</ENAMEX> to drink--yuck.
               

               
                  Music : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. Truly awful
Andews-Sisters type imitators.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrities</ENAMEX> : Nope.
               

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Overall
tone : 
                     The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">700 Club</ENAMEX> .
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N/A.</ENAMEX> I couldn't look
at another pulled pork <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwich</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  Music : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> rock band 4 Him. "The Him is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> helpfully
explained.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celebrities</ENAMEX> : None
spotted.
               

            

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  Overall
tone : Tent revival meeting.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Food</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. Vanilla
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate syrup</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  Music : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. An
out-of-tune <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass band</ENAMEX>.
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Celebrities : Ambassador</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>.
               

            

         
      
   
