
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raspberry Tomatoes; Cleaning</ENAMEX> Up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN</ENAMEX>:

            I think you're on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>-'n'-buggy side as far as genetically altered
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> goes. I suspect this will be a huge political issue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a few years</TIMEX>,
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five to ten years from now</TIMEX>, after the boycotts and hoopla, we'll all be
eating very strange (as we currently perceive it) <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>. A tomato that's
one-fifth raspberry. Steak with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX> component, for that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> rush.
Whatever. I don't think there's any fighting it. It took me a while to get used
to waiting behind someone on line at the coffee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> near work who ordered a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hazelnut-strawberry latte</ENAMEX>, decaf, with skim <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> "coke" story will be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> for a few more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. As this
story has progressed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, in retrospect I think that instead of
talking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> about not using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>, thus passing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> test, he should've just kept to his original
strategy: "Fuck you. I ain't playing your game." It'll be interesting to see
what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is cooking up for the general election as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
goes: that is, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Orin</ENAMEX> wrote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s New York
Post that she puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s chances at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>. I think that's
conservative, if you can believe it. Granted, I live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, but my many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are all backing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. And that's why I repeat that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are just sick of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. Period. Yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s run a crummy campaign, but he's got a huge, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horny monkey</ENAMEX> on his
back.

            As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> , don't make the trek to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX>: The design
changes are minimal. Looks fine to me; just some tinkering with typefaces,
feature designs, and column headings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Musto</ENAMEX> now has a caricature of him
with his column. Big deal. As usual, the hype in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> was
misleading, with the absurd headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> Is Cleaning Up Its Act."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Forst</ENAMEX> was quoted as saying, "We felt we wanted to have a cleaner,
more unified, more modern look." The same mumbo-jumbo most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> say when
there's a design change.

            Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comics</ENAMEX> have been moved to the front of the paper, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Rall</ENAMEX>, both of whom are sydicated in numerous alternatives and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dailies</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Hentoff</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. I wonder if he's being
phased out? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> never takes my advice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MUGGER</ENAMEX>, but what they
need to do editorially to make it vital again is this: Bust the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, get rid
of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deadwood</ENAMEX> that's cramming its pages, reduce its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, find
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> who have distinct views, and give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Christgau</ENAMEX> a gold watch.
Perhaps you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loyalist</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> is far more dull than say,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , even though the politics are roughly the same.

            In sports news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Vescey</ENAMEX> had a good column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
begging all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to stay away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> games, etc. I agree. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> don't give a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shit</ENAMEX> who
wins or loses, and just cause huge traffic jams and inconveniences to real fans
with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brigades</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vescey</ENAMEX> makes an exception for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>:
"Whatever else one thinks of him, he has earned the right to wear a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX> cap.
He loves that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> ... As for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, wearing the ballcap of somebody
else's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in somebody else's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> could be the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Snoopy helmet</ENAMEX> in the tank."

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RUSS</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
