
   
   
      
         
            From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disco to Hip-Hop</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hmm ... Feedbag for Morons</ENAMEX>. Isn't that a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead Kennedys album</ENAMEX>? I don't know,
maybe the great, big, arena-rocking songs are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>-opiating tools of social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>, but I really can't believe that everything in the pop
marketplace is just numbly imbibed by a passive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. (Also, isn't pinning
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s celebrity culture on rock letting the tabloids, glossies, talk shows,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, etc., etc., off a bit easy? Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> was the first modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX>--riding the emergent nexus of TV, film, and records to a new level of
global acclaim--but I hardly blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Bandstand</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess Di</ENAMEX>.)

            As someone who routinely got his head pounded into school lockers by Led
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeppelin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, I'm pretty aware of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>'s role in fostering unthinking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conformism</ENAMEX>. Still, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s somewhat overheated "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dionysian</ENAMEX>" riff does
make an important point: that even a music with the crassest commercial aims
can have liberating, transformative effects in the world.

            At least on other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX>. Had you heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s anecdote about Dylan
mishearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> before? I really liked that one, where he thought the
line "I can't hide, I can't hide" was "I get high, I get high," and concluded
it was a "song about dope." Not exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Das Kapital</ENAMEX> , I realize, but the
tale is suggestive of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>'s power as charged, volatile, as they say, "open
text." If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s ears weren't caught up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>' sound first, he
never would have imbued the song with such possibilities--which I have to
believe were pretty subversive back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>.

            Whether or not rock still has such possibilities depends, I think, on your
definitions of "rock." One thing that makes a popular music rock , as a
verb, is its ability to take private but common feelings and put them into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> public language. This phenomenon gets more interesting as the culture
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">splinters</ENAMEX> and technology creates new languages--which is one of my main
problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s critique. As a critical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> must
know how subjective his rock narrative is (even the jump-cut structure suggests
it), yet he still seems to present pop music as the product of the same shared,
single history. I'd say that construct breaks down near the end of his
book.

            While I don't mean to make too great a claim for disco, I do think it
represents a moment in which cultural forces that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> doesn't account for
realigned in a way that changed "rock." The polarizing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disco Sucks</ENAMEX>" movement
revealed a mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> not just splintering, but clashing along certain
demographic lines. Meanwhile, the music's sound and technology was providing
the sonic space and public rituals for hip-hop--as electrifying a pop form as
I've ever heard. I'd say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NWA</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fuck Tha Police</ENAMEX>" was every bit the protest song
that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Times They Are A-Changing</ENAMEX>" was and way more fun. I'd also say
similar, if less broadly significant upheavals are happening in the worlds of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX>, techno, and other electronic music even now. Musics that emphasize
rhythm and texture over melody and lyrics aren't necessarily apolitical or
content-free, but they do tend to occur on narrower bandwidths.

            Some smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>--Cocteau I think--said that style is a way of saying
complicated things simply. No, I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smashmouth</ENAMEX> is saying anything too
complicated. But others well within pop's debased, commercialized, 50-year-old
landscape--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nas</ENAMEX>, say, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Pavement</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Radiohead</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.J. Harvey</ENAMEX>--often are.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nowadays</ENAMEX>, you just have to work a little harder to hear it.

            Which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>, by his own admission, stopped doing over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>. This
raises a question we've both evaded. Is this book really necessary? Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s
style or his point of view compelling enough to merit another go-round on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">rock</ENAMEX>-history tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>?

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>

            P.S. I don't think your sentiments are fogeyish or undiscriminating. I must,
however, give you kudos for being the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> I've ever seen limn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Godley Creme</ENAMEX> influence.

         
      
   
