
   
   
      
         
            There <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Goes Chicago's Last Hope</ENAMEX>

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sondheim</ENAMEX> might have said, when you're a bitch, you're a bitch all the way. The
great bitches of entertainment history understood this. They knew that
bitchiness must be both extreme and extremely meaningful, or it just comes off
as unpleasant. Nineteen-fifties noir diva <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Graham</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> with a
little-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> voice and bad-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> smarts, gave her quips an irresistible
countercultural edge. Trash-mouthed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> made everyone else look middlebrow
by comparison. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two decades</TIMEX> or so, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All My Children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucci</ENAMEX> has waged a scorched-earth campaign against small-town feminine niceness.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Hope</ENAMEX> had on their hands a bitch of
potentially equal greatness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Lahti</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Austin</ENAMEX>, and they never
let her achieve it. She never got to be more than wishy-washy, insecure, a good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who went wrong and apologized and would really be a lot nicer if she
just got laid. A bitch without the courage of her
convictions.

            If she was such a compromised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, why get upset about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lahti</ENAMEX>'s not being asked back for the coming
season? After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Hershey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Holly</ENAMEX>, hired more or less to
replace her, are powerful actresses. But you can't imagine either of them
inspiring the following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lahti</ENAMEX> did--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> of professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who used to
call each other up and rage at the crap <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Austin</ENAMEX> had to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>. To
them, this must seem like the final betrayal. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> was a brilliant,
sharp-tongued, and of course, being a bitch, somewhat manipulative heart
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surgeon</ENAMEX>, but instead of enjoying the occasional triumph over her supercilious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, she just had more bad stuff happen to her than maybe anyone else in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nighttime</ENAMEX> soap history. Really bad stuff: Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> died. She lost her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in a custody battle with an evil, power-mad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> (her own fault, of
course--she tried to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> what to say in court). She kidnapped the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, got arrested, was fired, and then, when rehired, was forced to endure the
humiliation of being the best heart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with the least seniority.
She put up with petty bad stuff too, like the constant carping of her male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> about her lack of a gentle touch, or the punishments doled out by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> for her--a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>--occasional forays into romance. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> went off for a little yoga-and-sex retreat with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>,
for instance, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> wandered off into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and nearly died
of hypothermia.

            If we're talking betrayal, the real
betrayal was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lahti</ENAMEX> didn't leave the series once the troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>
clone started to abandon its blue-scrub realism for the creepy random
fancifulness that passes for creative on television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. Here's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> with a rare knack for
emotional realism, the kind of intelligent, commanding presence that drains
reality from lesser co-stars. Cast her in a second-rate movie as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">steals Ted Danson</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Tyler Moore</ENAMEX>, and suddenly you're
thinking, without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistresses</ENAMEX>, who'd ever realize the falseness of a false
marriage? Cast her as a flaky ex-radical on the run from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in
Running on Empty , and she comes off as the ultimate cool
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>--competent under pressure, endlessly inventive, a fountain of love.
Maybe the reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> saddled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Austin</ENAMEX> with so much misery was that
she suffered more interestingly than anyone else on the show.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
Hope never managed to do anything more interesting with her
interestingness than cause her to aspire to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and become an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">astronaut</ENAMEX>, the ridiculous quest to which she devoted her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> on the
series. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Workaholic Austin</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">one-woman</ENAMEX> stress fiesta, a full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-hour</TIMEX>-a-day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> bumping her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> constantly against the glass
ceiling. She was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> ready to wreak some serious havoc. Let her loose and
she could have been, to say the least, memorable. Instead they tried to send
her into orbit. In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>, presumably, no one could hear her scream.

         
      
   
