
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura Suite</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
lead with the Dow's record close--a fraction of a point shy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,300</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the overturning of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition 5</ENAMEX>, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">legalized Indian</ENAMEX> reservation casinos in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>'s top non-local story is the resignation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notra Trulock</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whistleblower</ENAMEX> who insists that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
stole nuclear secrets from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> article underscores that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trulock</ENAMEX> resigned to protest the
curtailment of his role in the continuing nuclear espionage investigation. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trulock</ENAMEX> chose to provide secret testimony to a congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> that
investigated the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> spying allegations. He claimed that his investigation
was slowed by political interference. The resignation comes amid growing doubts
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> whether classified data leaked from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> and allegations that
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Trulock</ENAMEX> targeted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ethnicity</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision, declaring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> to
be in violation of a constitutional prohibition against gaming, threatens to
shut down the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.36 billion</NUMEX> gambling industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
USAT front-pagers note that the overturned proposition was passed after
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> campaign by interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. Pro-gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> spent
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of that total. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> casinos fearing encroachment on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>'
turf bankrolled an opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> vowed to find a
constitutional way to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>, which employ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX>, in
business.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">199</NUMEX>-point jump in the Dow Jones industrial average came amid
anticipation of a quarter-point raise in short-term interest rates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Board</ENAMEX> will announce its rate decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> explains that the market is
interpreting the anticipated rate hike as the last raise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and an
effective means of keeping inflation at bay without slowing economic growth.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> predicts that the market would deflate if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> hints it might
raise interest rates again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> to hue to its
"neutral bias" by indicating no predisposition toward a future rate
adjustments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> has risen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX> so far this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, outpacing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> gain.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> earthquake follow-ups make the front-page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ; the rest of papers carry the story inside. Relief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> complain
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is encouraging them to leave, even though a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-year-old</TIMEX> was rescued from the rubble <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> have been
uncovered in ruins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> after previous quakes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> are leaving the earthquake zone because of a lack of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX>, fear
of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, and doubts that the devastated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> will be rebuilt.

            Tests of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> missile-defense system were rigged, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater High Altitude Area Defense</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15.4-billion</NUMEX>
system designed to protect battlefield <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> by tracking and shooting down
hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. It is intended for deployment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>, most likely in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korean Peninsula</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> said favorable tests were "highly scripted" and
further review, simulating field conditions, is necessary.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts an article on the academic pork barrel. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Universities</ENAMEX>
once received <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> grants through scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> that rigorously
reviewed research proposals. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> short-circuit this process by
lobbying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for earmarked appropriations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> insert
deliberately obscure provisions into unrelated legislation to provide money for
favored educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Colleges</ENAMEX> in the home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of powerful
Appropriations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> benefit from a disproportionate share of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> cover story reports that a managed-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> is attempting
to cut emergency service costs by encouraging its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to call the health
plan before dialing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">911</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> condemn the attempt at "telephone triage."
They fear that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> will fail to send the closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance</ENAMEX> and deny care
to dire cases.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One week</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> published an inaccurate lead story, which left the
false impression that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in international aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> was stolen, the
Times editorializes on why foreign aid is an unpopular cause. The paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condemns Congress</ENAMEX>' myopic intent to cut foreign aid and argues that
international assistance is a good investment because it can bolster political
stability. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Thursday</TIMEX> the paper editorialized, "Outside help will soon dry
up unless corruption is brought under control." Now it opines, "Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
foreign aid money has been wasted in the past. But that is no reason to starve
the entire program."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> has gained another
distinction. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom suite</ENAMEX> has been named in his honor at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> brothel he
once frequented.

         
      
   
