
   
   
      
         
            Trying To Read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s Mixed Messages
            

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Greider</ENAMEX>'s long book on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secrets</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX> (a fascinating book but, in retrospect, a remarkably ill-considered
indictment of inflation-fighting), there's not much mention of the conversion
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> into a bully pulpit. But as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s quarter-point hike
in the discount rate--in addition to the expected quarter-point hike in the
federal funds rate--demonstrates, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> has, at some point in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years or so</TIMEX>, come to see inflation-fighting as not merely a matter of raising
or lowering rates. It's also a matter of sending the right messages to the bond
(and, to a lesser extent, the stock) markets.

            I've 
touched on this point once before, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> announced at its last
meeting that it was keeping interest rates steady but changing its bias. Where
once the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> kept its deliberations secret and acted as sphinxlike as possible
about its intentions, it now tries to indicate what it's concerned about and
the direction in which it's leaning. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sense, this has made the exercise
of trying to game the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> easier, since there's more material to go on. In
another sense, it's made everything trickier, since there are a host of signals
to interpret, and sometimes they're not in harmony.

            Today, for instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> didn't make what would have been the surprising
move, namely hiking interest rates by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> basis points instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> basis
point is equal to one-hundredth of a point.) Had it pushed through the larger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hike</ENAMEX>, the sell-off in the stock market would probably have been frightening, at
least at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. But the increase would certainly have slammed the brakes on an
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> that's still running very hot.

            You might assume that the quarter-point hike means the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> isn't that
worried about inflation, even though there are signs that continued strong
demand and tight labor markets are beginning to make themselves felt. But then
there's the discount-rate hike to consider. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time since the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring of 1995</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> has increased the discount rate (which is the
interest rate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> charges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> who want to borrow money from it). And
while the discount rate itself is not that important, which is to say that an
increase in it will have no material effect on the economy, the message the
increase sends is important, and that message is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> is more concerned
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about</NUMEX> inflation than the small hike in the federal funds rate would indicate. I
think.

            In addition to the rate increases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> also shifted its bias back toward
neutral, which suggests that the economy is still growing faster than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>
believed it would be. But the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> isn't biased toward further
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tightening</ENAMEX> suggests that the economy isn't necessarily growing faster than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> would like it to be.

            Got all that? Good, because I'm not sure that I do.

            In the long run, worrying about all this stuff probably doesn't matter very
much. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> and the bond market will determine how fast the economy goes by
determining interest rates, and the concrete impact of the federal funds rate
and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s printing or not-printing money will far outweigh any
psychological effect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s symbolic gestures. But it also seems true
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> has come to recognize the beneficial effect of using those
gestures to push interest rates in a certain direction without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s having
to take concrete action. It's as if he can speed things up or slow them down
without doing much of anything real.

            Of course, mixed messages are a persistent danger here, as evidenced by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s herky-jerky market, where bond prices rose sharply, while the Dow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meandered</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> actually went up. But the truth is that in the end the
market will do a good job of sorting through the messages and finding the ones
that matter. It's trying to interpret the messages on your own--like I just
tried to do--that's a recipe for utter confusion.

         
      
   
