
   
   
      
         
            Oldies but Goodies
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            Yes, I loved the anecdote about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>'s mishearing "I can't hide" as "I
get high." And you're right about how easy it is to get caught up in the sound
and supply your own meanings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> can be almost pure <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Keatsian</ENAMEX> negative
capability. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> I thought the big <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tears for Fears song</ENAMEX> was
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everybody Wants To Live Alone</ENAMEX>." And for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good two decades</TIMEX>--until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, in fact--I listened to one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Waits</ENAMEX> songs, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Wish</ENAMEX>
I Was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> (In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth Ward</ENAMEX>)," thinking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth Ward</ENAMEX> was a wing
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bellevue</ENAMEX> rather than a neighborhood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>. All this time I
knew what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth Ward</ENAMEX> was--and the song is about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>.
But my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will to Narrative</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nietzsche</ENAMEX> might have called it, was stronger than
my ear.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> such story, often told in the drug-dimmed dorm <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralf Hutter</ENAMEX> (of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kraftwerk</ENAMEX>) wrote "(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wir</ENAMEX> fahren, fahren, fahren
auf der) Autobahn" after mishearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beach Boys' "Fun, Fun, Fun</ENAMEX>" as "She'll
have fahren, fahren, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fahren</ENAMEX> till her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> takes her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-Bird</ENAMEX> away." I
have always assumed it to be totally apocryphal. On the other hand, it makes
perfect sense.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX> anecdote reminds me that the book is chock-a-block with excellent
tidbits--some familiar, most not--and it would be unfair to let <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> pass
without sharing a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX>:

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Perkins</ENAMEX> wrote "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blue Suede Shoes"</ENAMEX> never having seen the word "suede" in
print. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blue Swaed Shoes</ENAMEX>," he called it.)

               Listen to the mere stage names of the overproduced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Liverpudlian</ENAMEX> rock studs
who preceded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Steele</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty Wilde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Fury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rory</ENAMEX>
Storm.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Clark</ENAMEX> had no particular interest in the rock he was promoting, or in
music whatsoever. When, shortly before appearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward R. Murrow</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Person</ENAMEX> , he was told that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murrow</ENAMEX> would want to ask about a
record collection, he had to borrow one. He didn't have a record
collection.

            

            I'm still trying to figure out what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> means when he talks about rock as
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for nostalgia. I'm convinced that this is largely a personal project.
There's much in the elegiac tone of this book that reminds me of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larkin</ENAMEX>'s collection <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All What Jazz</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larkin</ENAMEX>, to whom "jazz" meant
everything you could hear in war-depleted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>--basically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kid Ory</ENAMEX> and Bix
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beiderbecke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver</ENAMEX>--was turned loose as contemporary jazz
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> a quarter-century later, having not
listened to any jazz in the interim. He heard a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mingus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coltrane</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monk</ENAMEX> and threw up his hands as if to say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What's this crap?</ENAMEX>"

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> can't write like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larkin</ENAMEX>, his nostalgia project is a more
responsible one. He gives us a history of the term "oldies but goodies," and
mentions "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Still of the Night</ENAMEX>," scarcely noticed when it came out in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, but by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> a staple of the oldies circuit. In my own life, I remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX>
Green as a serious but secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1970s</TIMEX>; if the air-time on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oldies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> is any indication of his ultimate stature, he's one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giants</ENAMEX>. Similarly, I remember that on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretenders</ENAMEX>' debut album, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Town</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stop Your Sobbing</ENAMEX>" got the most play--but only on alternative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stations</ENAMEX>. The album didn't have any "hits." Today, no matter what town you're
listening to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classic Rock</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in, it's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brass in Pocket"</ENAMEX>--maybe the
edgiest, least mainstream thing on the whole album--that gets all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airplay</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ahem</ENAMEX> ... after writing that sentence, I looked in a rock reference book and
found that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brass in Pocket" hit No. 14</ENAMEX> stateside. But I think I'll leave it,
as evidence that it's my memory that's failing. Perhaps rock history is
like retrospective politics. If you poll <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on how they voted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>
percent say they backed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the vote.
And if you ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what they were listening to in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-to-late '60s</TIMEX>,
they'll tell you, "Oh, you know ... a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet Underground</ENAMEX>, a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hendrix</ENAMEX>."

            But I don't believe it.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
