
   
   
      
         
            Net Gains
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Joe</ENAMEX>,

            I am glad you bit my well-baited hook about the impact of the Internet,
since it has become one of our most frothy debates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. In fact, I just
got back from a book tour with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, one of whom held
your exact sentiments about the current development of the Web. He and I
debated intensely over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> and we never really changed each
other's mind. I ended up calling him a whiney <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luddite</ENAMEX> and he said I was
Web-addled. In any case, you hit all the high points of the arguments pro and
con that are taking place, so let me address them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            First, you are right that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is being used--and aggressively--by
fomenters of hate who are spewing their poisonous attitudes out to the wider
world using these powerful new technologies. My general attitude is still that
this is probably a good thing, because I've always held the position that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sunlight</ENAMEX> is the best disinfectant and all speech needs to be spoken. All these
sites are surely loathsome to see, but haven't these attitudes been in
existence since the dawn of time? Frankly, I would rather be able to more
clearly see exactly what these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are spouting than to have them hide away
dangerously in dark corners, ready to pounce. For the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
being able to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dreck</ENAMEX> tends to remove its mystery and points out its
idiocy only more clearly. When you know that the Internet seems to bring out
the worst in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, I think your problem may be with the darker side of
humanity more than anything else.

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, you are right that it is unlikely that the Internet will live up to
its potential. But what does really? Not me and not you and not television and
not anything else. Some of what is on the Web right now is silly, some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">depressing</ENAMEX>, some crazy, and some just plain stupid. A lot of what is being
created now is aimed only at getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to buy more stuff they probably
don't need. And <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-click shopping, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Buddy List</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>'s
bidding frenzies are not going to change the world for the better.

            But I firmly posit that the increasingly free flow of information that the
Internet allows can only benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the long run by educating them on
the wider world outside their windows. What is undeniably powerful is the
ability to self-publish for low cost. I can't own a telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or a
television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, or even a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> like the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , but I can put up anything I want to on the Web. To me, it doesn't
really matter if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go there or not. Perhaps all this communication will
only result in pointless cacophony, but I like the noise.

            I am troubled by the kind of behavior that the Internet seems to engender
and am often offended by the cruel and mindless blather that is too easy to
find. The stock chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> are a good example, since most of them have turned
into places of little value. But I encounter rage and misbehavior when I drive
to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every morning</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to have lost a lot of the civility that
used to rule. But again, I don't think the Internet is to blame for this. It's
just a fact of life that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can be beastly.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Kara

         
      
   
