
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contenders</ENAMEX> and Pretenders
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw poll results--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>' on-air reactions to
them--are Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. (Unfortunately, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the chat shows were taped before
the vote.) The teaching of evolution in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is a distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>.

            The straw-poll verdict by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> is largely unanimous: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> proved they can compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>. All the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> proved they can't. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> seem to agree with this
verdict--even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>. On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> all but bows out of the race. Later in the program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>
hints at bolting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> asks, "Will you pledge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that you
will support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> if he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> responds, "No--let
me say this--uh, I don't know where I'm going to be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> of the year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.") The only straw-poll loser determined to stay in is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>, who received fewer votes than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits pronounce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> the biggest winners. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>--with
little money and a weak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>--had the most to lose, her third-place
finish gives her campaign a big boost (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right</ENAMEX>, say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>
News 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> ) argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> still has
to draw social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> to be truly competitive.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> appear <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after the other, and
the contrast is instructive. Asked about abortion and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
controversy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> waffles on both--giving nervous, have-it-both-ways responses.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> says confidently and directly that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> should answer the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> question
and that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> he would pose a litmus test for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> on abortion.)

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX>, and Late

               Edition's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>--predict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> will leave the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> "a cocked gun" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.)
Everyone agrees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> are toast, and some--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>--point out the irony that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> are relatively
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inexperienced</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> are political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>.

            The commentariat expresses surprise at the straw poll's growth in
importance. Some--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>--attribute it to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">front-loaded</ENAMEX> primary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> hunger. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill O'Reilly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> say the media attention it has
generated makes it important regardless. (In other words, it's important
because we say it is.)

            A few programs touch on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> decision not to require the
teaching of evolution in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX> and Late 
               Edition's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> think the decision is not that unreasonable, since it doesn't
give either creationism or evolution exclusivity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> sees it as proof that
the "purist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is gaining strength, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> points out
that, at the straw poll, none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> would go near the topic (save
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>).

Know <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Rights</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> plugs what it claims to be a scoop on the campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> scandal. In an interview to be aired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX> tells the
news program The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Reilly Factor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>) that during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmental Reform Committee</ENAMEX> hearings into campaign finance (the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>
hearings"), a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>'s
unsolicited documents detailing how to go about taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth</ENAMEX>
Amendment.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX> Report
Talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Blitzer</ENAMEX> in the Late Edition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> shows
the ravages of her <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Parkinson's Disease</ENAMEX>. Her mind is obviously as sharp as ever,
but her arms shake uncontrollably throughout the interview and the microphone
picks up her hands <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">spasmodically</ENAMEX> rustling against her papers on the interview
table. As they talk about gun control, both she and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blitzer</ENAMEX> keep stealing
glances at her hands' distracting gyrations.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bad Boy</ENAMEX>, Georgie!
Asked on Late Edition about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s repeated use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-</ENAMEX>word in
his Talk magazine interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> quips, "I found that article
surprising--[although] I'll leave it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to talk with his mom
about the language he uses."

         
      
   
