
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>?

            
               
                  For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>, click here.
               
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, as the saying goes, are like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX>: They sting and then they
die. Independent presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> succeed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> not by winning
elections but by influencing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to adopt their positions.
Thus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, who lost the election of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progressive</ENAMEX>, was
nonetheless effective in the sense that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
borrowed his policies. Another example of this phenomenon is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> presidential bid, which encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> to woo disenchanted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> conforms to this pattern as well. His big issue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> was the
budget deficit. By raising the topic relentlessly, he encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> to address it during the campaign. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> received
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX> of the vote was an inducement to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to stick with deficit
reduction once in office. For this reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perot</ENAMEX> deserves a share of the credit
for the healthy condition of the economy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> chose not to declare victory and go home. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, he ran again,
this time putting his opposition to free-trade agreements front and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. As
a result of his strong performance in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'92</TIMEX>, he was eligible to receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in public financing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> did far less well the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time around,
getting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 8.5 percent</NUMEX> of the vote. But that percentage still entitles the
Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> to a federal subsidy of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12.6 million</NUMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
election.

            "It's a huge pot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX> that's going to attract a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ</ENAMEX>
Verney, the outgoing national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>. Among those
buzzing around recently have been political oddballs who seem to hail from
altogether different planets: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell</ENAMEX>
Weicker, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>.

            If none of them has yet taken the plunge, it may be because there's a small
catch to the cash, namely the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> itself, which has come to resemble
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Monster Raving Loony Party</ENAMEX> without the self-conscious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theatricality</ENAMEX>. Reports from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>'s recent convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dearborn</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, conveyed a fragrant whiff of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bedlam</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> included
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lenora Fulani</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriot</ENAMEX>
Party, no-tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX>, and other miscellaneous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> and wackos.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman-elect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gargan</ENAMEX>, is stockpiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in a remote part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Keys</ENAMEX>
in anticipation of the global depression he thinks will result from a Y2K
catastrophe. In short, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> is both run and overrun by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> look sane and rational.

            As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verney</ENAMEX> says, it's unlikely that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX> will be left on the
table. But in this unstable environment, no one can predict whether that stake
will be used to whack the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> from the left or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> from the
right--or to squeeze a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weicker</ENAMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist</ENAMEX> into the narrow space between an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. For potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, the only vague
requirements are a commitment to political reforms like term limits, a belief
in fiscal discipline, and skepticism about free trade. Even these points may be
negotiable.

            At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dearborn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> lost control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and
thus the implied power to be or choose its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gargan</ENAMEX>, who encouraged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> to enter the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and subsequently fell out
with him, defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Perot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Benjamin</ENAMEX>, to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verney</ENAMEX> as party
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairperson</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gargan</ENAMEX> won with the endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX>
Party's only elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX> as unofficial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s
interest is in keeping a seat warm until he's ready to run for president
himself. To stand as an independent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, he needs to make sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX>
Party gets <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 5 percent</NUMEX> of the vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, which would entitle it to a
public subsidy once again.

            Press reports have portrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gargan</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Body</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah Sifry</ENAMEX>, who
is writing a book on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, tells me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gargan</ENAMEX> isn't simply a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shill</ENAMEX>. This means that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> probably won't be able to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the results of
the nominating process as he did against former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lamm</ENAMEX> last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> around, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> isn't automatically the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kingmaker</ENAMEX> either. What's likely is
a bitter battle between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>, conducted through proxies, their
respective stand-ins for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> at the moment appears to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who has
made noises about bolting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> and joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> was
the hit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">United We Stand Convention</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and enjoys good relations
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> also traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> to kiss <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>.
The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> said nice things about each other after their session, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>
didn't win <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s blessing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> is a libertarian on social issues. He's
not only strongly pro-choice on abortion and sympathetic to drug legalization
but has come out in favor of gay marriage, which would seem to rule out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. He has since criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> directly and
encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weicker</ENAMEX> to run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX>'s nomination.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weicker</ENAMEX> has yet to declare his intentions. In the meantime, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> is
pursuing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> option. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> knowledgeable about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform</ENAMEX>
Party tells me that media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Hillsman</ENAMEX>, who made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>'s clever
TV spots in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, is meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>. It's a
savvy choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissary</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillsman</ENAMEX>, who made ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
Wellstone before signing on with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX>, is even closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s
liberal-populist politics than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> is. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillsman</ENAMEX> couldn't be reached for
comment. But I'd wager he's telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> about how the disaffected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who
turned out to elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura</ENAMEX> might be mobilized in a national campaign.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> successfully woos <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ventura convinces Beatty</ENAMEX> to run,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> nominating convention might be the most entertaining
sideshow of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign. How do you describe the ideology of people
trying to decide whether they want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>? I'd call them mad as hell--in more senses that one.

         
      
   
