
   
   
      
         
            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone Rocked</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN</ENAMEX>:

            Well, that's a lot to chew on. I'm not convinced by your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nation</ENAMEX> -like
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is basically being run by global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>" rap. That's too
easy. If what you say is true, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wouldn't have been able to pass his
huge tax increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'93</TIMEX>. If what you say is true, the estate tax (an absurd
violation of "family values") wouldn't exist, and capital gains taxes would be
slashed. I agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has less to do with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> than is believed, and what they take credit for when things are going
well, but I don't believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX>, etc. "run" the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. If
that were true, the crazy amount of entitlements, handouts, and obscene
regulations on business wouldn't exist.

            I'm with you on most social issues: pro-choice, obviously pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
Amendment, pro-gay rights, etc. Legalize pot? It wouldn't bother me, and would
be an economic boon to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. I am in favor of capital punishment and
think all this nonsense about "hate" crimes is just that: nonsense. Rhetoric
that obscures the debate. Any crime is hateful, whether it's committed
against a white, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, black, gay, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientologist</ENAMEX>.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>, I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, especially television, behaved
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disgracefully</ENAMEX>. It was all about ratings (just as the intrusive coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s tragic death) and selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. End of story, so to speak. And
it simply encourages copycat crimes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> had the great hook: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>,
especially the unfortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who professed her belief in God and became an
instant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>. It's no surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> (the prime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX>) didn't spend
one-tenth the time on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> massacre. After all, those murders were
carried out in a financial work setting; it didn't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> of a high
school for TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>. Never mind that the kook killed his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, a
truly horrendous event.

            Magazines. I agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> , although it was far
more vital in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of the '70s</TIMEX>; after the move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> things
went downhill. My framework also includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that era</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early '70s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '80s</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> usually bores me; it seems like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Fallows</ENAMEX> mix. I
read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchens</ENAMEX> (he's been great on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>; if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wins
I'm sure we'll be on opposite sides), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cockburn</ENAMEX> (although he's far better in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPress</ENAMEX> ) and, just to be irritated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Alterman</ENAMEX>. I
didn't like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue of Talk at all; whatever you feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> (and I admired much of her work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> and the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ) she's clearly lost any sense of vision.

            That's it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> on-line, via the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> or directly at nypress.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RUSS</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
