
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            Who even knew that anyone still cared about things like trade deficits? I
mean, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has been borrowing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of billions of dollars</NUMEX> every
month from foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> for so long that I thought it was just something
everyone--with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> looking for reasons to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">bash China</ENAMEX>--accepted. But apparently there are still some numbers that can
scare even the most dedicated stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>, so that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s news that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> deficit soared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24 billion</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> sent stock prices tumbling
(well, relatively speaking).

            Concerns about the suddenly weak dollar, worries about the trade deficit,
rumblings that defaults on high-yield bonds are rising: What <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> is this,
again? And where's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>? Just kidding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>. The truth is that a lot
of these anxieties feel like just that: anxieties without any real object.
After all, bond yields fell by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a quarter</NUMEX> point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, assuaging a
lot of concerns about the impact of rising interest rates on stock prices. So
all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the fears of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> just had to find something new to fret
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>.

            A bit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollyanna</ENAMEX>-ish? No doubt. But something real has got to change before
all this talk about a suddenly fragile economy will make any sense. So go buy
something and keep the boom going. Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chatter</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDC Asia-Pacific</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800,000</NUMEX> home PCs were sold in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. At that rate, it will take a mere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">500 years</TIMEX> until every
family in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has a PC."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "In a week in which bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> after bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> filed for bankruptcy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX>-phone company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iridium</ENAMEX> also filed for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 11</ENAMEX> , which it had
insisted it would never do. Let's see: Its huge, clunky, hard-to-operate phones
cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX>. It cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> a minute to use the phones. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> often
didn't work. How could they have missed?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> is abandoning its 'Come see the softer side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX>' slogan, in
favor of a campaign that focuses more on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX>' strength as an affordable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mid</ENAMEX>-tier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailer</ENAMEX> . Among possible slogans that were considered: 'We're not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergdorf Goodman</ENAMEX>, but hell, we're not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Store</ENAMEX>, either'; 'We sold
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">washboards</ENAMEX> to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX>: That's gotta count for something'; and
'Come for the batteries, stay for the home furnishings.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> announced that it had doubled its earnings
in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most recent quarter</TIMEX>. Who would have thought that letting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris Rock</ENAMEX>
write the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Laughter Is the Best Medicine</ENAMEX>' column would have made such a
dramatic difference?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "Rather remarkably, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> yen just keeps getting stronger
despite the fact that interest rates there remain at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about zero</NUMEX>. That means
that even though there's no demand for money in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> , which in turn
means that it's hard to see how economic growth is going to be sustained there,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are wagering that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy is coming back. Or it could
mean that ... Actually, the whole thing is probably just a conspiracy. Just
like everything else."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Pacific Group</ENAMEX>--it's just a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--is on the verge
of spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$650 million</NUMEX> to acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piaggio Veicoli</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> company
that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vespas</ENAMEX>. Why? Listen, if you have to ask, then you'll never
understand."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "Planet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> at long last has filed for bankruptcy , and has
apparently negotiated a refinancing deal that will wipe out the value of all
its current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> and trade <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the equity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for
a measly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 million</NUMEX>. Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is now and will forever be
effectively worthless. So on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 million</NUMEX> is probably
overpaying."

         
      
   
