
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rise; Hillary's Fall</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN</ENAMEX>:

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and I returned <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> from a week in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>, where I managed
to pick up a bad sunburn, watch my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boogie-board</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, and
make sure my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> didn't get swallowed by the undertow. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I
managed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, going to a country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> dinner with my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, which was remarkable only for the dazzling array of
photos on the walls. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> in particular, of a (undoubtedly re-touched) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>
when he visited the (mostly) golfing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '50s</TIMEX>, was very
striking.

            Another change of pace for me was the lack of cable TV, save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, and the
stateside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> not being delivered until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 5 in the afternoon</TIMEX>. Which was
kind of cool: You'd get the meaningless Times fax with breakfast, but
then read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> before falling asleep. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> in the sun, and the
arduous exercise of building <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand castles</ENAMEX> and going swimming, it made me less
angry at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">morons</ENAMEX> who staff the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>.

            But here's a question: Where have all the fact-checkers gone? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hobbyhorses</ENAMEX> is that the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are overstaffed
by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 50 percent</NUMEX>--there's a problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> for you--and still the
quality, overall, is poor, especially in comparison with the upmarket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dailies</ENAMEX>. For example, in a sidebar to the letters section in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> wrote: "Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pointed out that while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> uttered the phrase ["Ask not what you can do ..."] in his
Inaugural Address in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> ..." Now, of course, the date was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'61</NUMEX> and you'd think
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> and assistants to
editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> could've snared that mistake. We run a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPress</ENAMEX> , and make mistakes, as every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> does, but I find it
inexcusable that large media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are rife with errors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> has a teaser on the front page, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">With Straw</ENAMEX>
Vote <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In, Some Hint of a Race</ENAMEX>," that says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> really has a
contest on his hands. You don't have to guess who wrote the story
inside: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Berke</ENAMEX>, perhaps the most biased beat political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. In fact, it was a decisive win for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>,
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outspent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> considerably, was privately disappointed by the outcome,
hoping to either defeat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> or come within a few percentage points.
Unless some catastrophic scandal is revealed--and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use doesn't come close
to alleged rape and illegal campaign contributions, but don't get me
started--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , which must be apoplectic
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is on the ropes, will do everything in its power, from pictures to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">captions</ENAMEX> to editorials, to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. Which is fine; I just wish they'd declare
themselves as partisan, as say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> do.

            I may be going on too long, but one more thought. I read in the New York
Post <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>-hunting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westchester</ENAMEX>.
I don't believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> will wind up running. She'll be creamed
(meaning by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> points) by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, and I suspect she'll end the campaign
sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. I think the final blow, ironically, was the tragic death
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> It pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>, and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> would've far preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. I think
eventually <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RFK Jr.</ENAMEX>, a solid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cuomo</ENAMEX> will run.
Personally, I'd love to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rangel</ENAMEX> go against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX>: That would be
entertaining politics. More later.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RUSS</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
