
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorry State of International Disaster Relief</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> earthquake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 17</TIMEX> and its disastrously bungled relief
effort--the official death toll now stands at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,997</NUMEX> --is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">depressingly</ENAMEX> familiar story. Why is the world unable to create an international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manpower</ENAMEX> and equipment to assist in the aftermath of huge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">natural</ENAMEX> and manmade disasters (which seem to occur pretty reliably at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>)? This extremely sensible idea was floated by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , which attached to the hypothetical force the memorable
name "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griefbusters</ENAMEX>," in a series of editorials from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX> to the early
1990s. But for some mysterious reason, nobody seemed terribly interested.

            According to an editorial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Science Monitor</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> is doing a
better job of coordinating the grab-bag of relief efforts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private,
from all over the world, than it used to, thanks to its new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> for the
Coordination of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humanitarian Affairs</ENAMEX> (OCHA), which apparently took over
many duties of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the United Nations Disaster Relief Coordinator</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNDRO</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNDRO</ENAMEX>'s record wasn't especially good. According to the
Monitor , "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> has learned from past attempts that its best role in
disaster scenes is to pool the efforts of national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, not to do the
work itself." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCHA</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Monitor</ENAMEX> , has a "realistic mandate." But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> isn't aware that the creation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Griefbusters</ENAMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> has ever
been tried. Clearly, whatever small improvements the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> has made in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX> coordination didn't prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> from telling
many foreign rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to leave; even before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismail Cimen</ENAMEX> was
pulled out, alive, from under a collapsed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">balcony</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuers</ENAMEX> had gone home. Meanwhile (according to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toronto Globe and Mail</ENAMEX> ), a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> was
being told by some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that the field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and
water-purification systems it had brought were needed, and by other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that they were not. Exaggerated deference to an incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX>
government doesn't strike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> as the way to go.

            The original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Republic Griefbusters</ENAMEX> editorial, published after
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX>'s disastrous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> earthquake, said:

            

               
                  A flexible rapid deployment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> would report to a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. More
important, it would know what each kind of disaster called for, and would
either possess or have immediate access to the basic required equipment. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> could employ a semi-military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>, with reservists from member
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> who could be called up at a moment's notice ... If we made a prior
agreement with other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, promising to help each other in case of disaster,
the burden would be to refuse aid rather than to ask for it.
               

            

            The editorial expressed a preference for limiting the disaster-relief force
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, working under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> control. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a later</TIMEX> editorial, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> control, rightly pointing out that "however
problematic the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> remains politically, it ought to be able to function on a
humanitarian level." Either way is fine with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>.

            The pathetic state of international disaster relief--arguably the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> is better at peacekeeping , which isn't saying much--calls to
mind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lytton Strachey</ENAMEX>'s description, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eminent Victorians</ENAMEX> , of the anarchy with which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence Nightingale</ENAMEX> was confronted when she set out to help wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crimea</ENAMEX>. (As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strachey</ENAMEX> makes clear, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nightingale</ENAMEX>'s fake "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> with the
lamp" image as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of modern nursing completely obscures her real
significance, which was as a ruthlessly effective administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a single military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and later of the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
military-hospital system.) But in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nightingale</ENAMEX>'s time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> military at
least had the excuse that the age of modern medicine, with its emphasis on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sterility</ENAMEX> and proper ventilation of hospital <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, was only just dawning.
What's our excuse?

         
      
   
