
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fear of Teen-agers</ENAMEX>
            

            This is my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> schedule, which is basically no schedule at all ... my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, who's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>, is away at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>; the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us are rattling around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> with no classes, meetings, etc., to worry about ... closest thing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nirvana</ENAMEX> except for places like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDowell Colony</ENAMEX>, where they give you meals
and bring lunch to your studio door.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>, before I forget: I don't, in general, buy as a sufficient
explanation for media obsessions that "it's all about ratings and selling
papers," for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. First, because you have to ask why huge numbers of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so interested that they watch the TV shows and buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. And
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, because the money explanation assumes a detached cynicism--or a totally
mechanical subservience to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX>--on the part of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, etc., who are responsible for the actual
coverage, when in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are caught up in the same fears and
fantasies as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. As I see it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> hit more of a cultural
chord than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> murders because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are in turmoil about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>: On the one hand, everyone's political agenda is rationalized as
protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, whether it's censorship and drug testing or welfare and
gun control; on the other, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are fearful of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, feel that
they're out of control, and at the same time guilty about the many ways kids
are being shortchanged in this enormously pressured, work-obsessed, and uptight
environment.

            Speaking of drug testing, according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> has
taken on the case of high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in a "small rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> who
are forced to take urine tests if they want to participate in extracurricular
activities or take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> that are, in some cases, connected with these
activities. Aside from the travesty against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fourth Amendment</ENAMEX>, this is just
another example of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> and contempt aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>. Treat them
all like presumptive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who deserve no autonomy and respect, and then
wonder why some actually fulfill your expectations.

            On the hate-crime issue, it's true you can't execute someone twice; but most
such crimes are assault or rape or lesser degrees of homicide--not capital
crimes. For the record, I'm basically against the death penalty on the grounds
that its application is discriminatory, mistaken executions of innocent people
are inevitable, keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> during the appeal process
amounts to cruel and unusual punishment, yet limiting appeals is even worse,
there's no evidence that executions have any practical deterrent effect, and
emotional catharsis is not a good enough reason for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
But I'm not an absolutist on the subject. For instance, there's a legitimate
question to be raised about what you do about someone who's already serving
life without parole who kills an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>; how to deter a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> who
shoots the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> trying to arrest him, figuring he has nothing to lose; and other
such situations. And then there's the issue of whether politically motivated
mass murder, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing, should be in a special category.
Which leads back to the issue of why we ought to create a special category for
what I'm calling intimidation or political terrorism: because these crimes are
more deleterious to the social fabric than ordinary crimes. I disagree with you
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX>. I believe it was a lynching. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were out to
teach him--and by extension all gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--a lesson.

            This is already too long, so later for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>. What do you think of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> redesign? And what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPress</ENAMEX> in-house
culture like?

         
      
   
