
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica Stonewalls About Plagiarism</ENAMEX>!

            It's never good to get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX> caught in the cookie jar. But if caught you
must be, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> recommends that you arrange for it to happen during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month of August</TIMEX>, when the media get lazy and inattentive. The latest
illustration of this principle is the lack of publicity surrounding some
apparent plagiarism committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Crowley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s former
editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> and research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, now a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> titillating books dishing "candid commentary" from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> Off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Record</ENAMEX> , which had a splashy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-bashing excerpt in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> From Beyond the
Grave: His Thoughts on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Impeachment, The War</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter Craze</ENAMEX> , coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.)

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 9</TIMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">25th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s presidential
resignation--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>'s editorial page published a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixon</ENAMEX>
apologia by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Day Nixon Said Goodbye</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four days later</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ran an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s note that read as follows: "There are
striking similarities in phraseology between "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day Richard Nixon Said</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodbye</ENAMEX>," an editorial feature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Crowley</ENAMEX>, and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> article by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commentary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> ... Had we known of the parallels,
we would not have published the article." Pretty interesting, no? Yet a Nexis
search conducted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier today</TIMEX> turned up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> other references to this
incident--one in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> gossip column that appeared the same
day the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ran its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s note, and one brief item that ran in
the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>' business section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days later</TIMEX>.

            Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> item, which appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full week ago</TIMEX> (and which
Chatterbox happened to spot while he was vacationing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX>), nothing
further appears to have been written or uttered on TV about this. That's
especially striking in view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>'s flagrant (oh, let's just say it,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nixonian</ENAMEX> ) stonewalling on the matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> was quoted by the
Times' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity Barringer</ENAMEX> as saying that "there are clear similarities
in the language. I have wracked my brain, and I can honestly tell you that I
have not read" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s article. I am not a plagiarist!
            

            Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has read both, and it just isn't possible for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>
not to have read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s article. (It is possible, of course,
that she has a photographic memory and repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
not-particularly-memorable phrases unconsciously; though if she had a
photographic memory, wouldn't she remember reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> piece?)

            Let's proceed to the evidence:

            
               From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Praise</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Commentary</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1988</TIMEX>:
            

            "There was none of the personal corruption which had marked the rule of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX>, let alone the gross immoralities and security risks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>."

            
               From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Day Nixon Said Goodbye</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 9, 1999</TIMEX>:
            

            "There was none of the personal corruption that had marked the rule of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> or the base immoralities and outrageous security risks of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Houses</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>:
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> ... consistently underestimated the unscrupulousness of his media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> and their willingness to sacrifice the national interest in the pursuit
of their institutional vendetta."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>:
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>, though always suspicious of his political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>, consistently
underestimated their ruthlessness and willingness to sacrifice the national
interest in the pursuit of their institutional vendetta."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>:
            

            "So great was the inequity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s downfall that future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> may
well conclude he would have been justified in allowing events to take their
course and in subjecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> to the prolonged paralysis of a public
impeachment, which at least would have given him the opportunity to defend
himself by due process of law. But once again his patriotism took precedence
over his self-interest ..."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>:
            

            "Given the inequity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s downfall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> may yet determine that
he would have been justified in allowing events to take their course and
subjecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to a prolonged process of impeachment, which would have
given him the chance to defend himself by due process of law. His allegiance to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, however, overrode his political self-interest."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>:
            

            Characterizes the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> election as "one of the most corrupt elections of
modern times."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>:
            

            Characterizes the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> election as "one of the most corrupt elections of
modern times."

            [This assertion, unlike the others, has some merit, and it's possible the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> arrived at the phrase independent of one another; but given the other
examples cited here, that likelihood is not great.]

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>:
            

            "By a curious paradox <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> was one of the very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
emerged from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> affair with credit."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>:
            

            "Ironically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> was one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who emerged from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> with
credit ..."

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley American</ENAMEX>; why would she, on her own, use a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Britishism</ENAMEX> like "with credit"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>]

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> left phone and e-mail messages with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>, but received no
response. It's possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>, like many of the more attentive members
of the news media, is on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation this week</TIMEX>. Or perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX>'s closeted in
order to finish a Talk magazine profile she's reportedly writing about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana Milbank</ENAMEX> recently quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowley</ENAMEX> saying she's trying "to humanize another
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>.")

             

         
      
   
