
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underhyped</ENAMEX> Internet
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Joe</ENAMEX>,

            First, I wanted to assure you that I never discriminate against straight
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. In fact, some of my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are of your ilk.

            Thanks for the good wishes about the wedding. I had no idea that it had
become an important <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> event--it had fewer Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moguls</ENAMEX> who
could give out lucrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>-and-family stock than it had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. For the
record, I didn't take any stock as a wedding gift. Frankly, I think all the
hubbub about the event was due to the fact that few have seen an actual
same-sex marriage up close and would not want to miss the opportunity. After
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">123rd</NUMEX> one, I am sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will become as thrilled about
going to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> as they are about heterosexual nuptials. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, not another
lesbian wedding? We're going to go broke buying all these power tools.")

            I hope so, although I was not heartened by an article I read <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> about the fact that despite numerous hate crimes
laws on the books, few are being implemented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, who appear to decline
to report obvious hate crimes as such. The first example, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West African</ENAMEX> man
being beaten up by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skinhead</ENAMEX> who didn't like the color of his skin, was only
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eclipsed</ENAMEX> in horror by the story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had his head split in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and was
"roasted" by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who claimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> had made a pass at him. I am not sure
when a simple "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, thanks" fell out of a favor for more brutal solutions. Both
crimes, shockingly, were not reported as hate crimes.

            It is certainly disheartening, but I have hope--which brings me to the
Internet, which I am thrilled to talk about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and night. In fact, I do,
since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PlanetOut</ENAMEX>, which is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the largest gay and lesbian sites on the Web. I report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> about the
Internet, and then go home and talk about it even more. Perhaps you could call
me a loser, but I have never been so captivated by a medium in my life. I think
I have become so obsessive about the advent of the Internet because I have long
believed that it will turn out to be the most powerful communications medium of
all time. To me, it has the potential to sweep away ignorance about such topics
as gay and racial hatred and empower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to take more control of their
lives. The idea of a fully interactive medium that only becomes more powerful
by its exponential growth, that gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the tools to instantly publish,
that allows for a freer and even chaotic flow of information, is a gigantic
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            I know I sound like those demented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">digerati</ENAMEX> who have spent too much time in
the insular world of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>, but I firmly believe that the Internet is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underhyped</ENAMEX>. I almost cringe when I write this because some of what is going on
here has been underwhelming and derivative of the old world. For all the
attention given to electronic commerce of late, and the incredibly high
valuation being given to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that lose scads of money, some of the
business on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is little more than a glorified version of selling crap on
the Internet. Not very exciting to be sure, and a little unnerving to me since
fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> I see these days are as concerned with building a real business
as they are in popping out an IPO, taking the money, and hoping to the heavens
to figure out what to do next. This makes me very nervous and it should make a
lot of others nervous, too.

            In fact, what disturbs me most is the lack of information individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are using to make their decisions, despite the flood of good data
available. It's more than a little ironic that the Internet is a place of
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">endless</TIMEX> information and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are buying up stock in Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have
little knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> they are betting on. It seems to have become
a big guessing game in which a few will end up with the right answers. In fact,
since this medium is built from the ground up, no one is entirely sure what the
right answers may be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> to come. Thus, the theme of my coverage of
this interesting time in business history, which was also the theme of my book
on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX>: Nobody knows. More on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> in my next missive.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: the little league story, I am never surprised by the lengths we go in
the name of sports, which I do not follow closely, making me a bad lesbian, I
guess.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Kara

            P.S. I am on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Zephyr</ENAMEX> with my lovely nephews, who are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 and 6</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX>, traveling east. We are taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two days</TIMEX> off, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> that we are,
for our honeymoon, since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> is in the throes of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round of
financing for her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. It's one Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> I don't cover, for
obvious reasons, but we're planning a trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later in the fall</TIMEX>--pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX>--to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
