
   
   
      
         
            Beyond Fact-Checking
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Russ</ENAMEX>,

            While you've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> getting sunburned, I've been up in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mountains</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catskills</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all summer</TIMEX>, which has been great for getting away but
also leaves me somewhat media-challenged--I get the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> but don't
have cable or any TV, and even the radio reception is terrible. For any
magazine less popular than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , the nearest venue is that great
metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woodstock</ENAMEX>, which is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 miles</NUMEX> away. Courtesy of a traveling
family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> I did get hold of the first Talk issue, speaking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. The profile was terrible--it must be really difficult to write with
your nose so far up someone's ass.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> needs a great popular novel to do her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. She's in some ways
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poignant</ENAMEX>, in some ways horrifying, and an ur-representation of all our cultural
contradictions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and power. I'm no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of her politics--on the
evidence, her left-wing reputation is entirely undeserved, she's a
pro-corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> (that health plan should have been called the
Insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Company Protection Act</ENAMEX>), a pious communitarian (against divorce--!!),
no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of civil liberties, feminism <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">half a millimeter</NUMEX> deep. I would vote for
her for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, because I can't stand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and don't want to see the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> votes, but not with any enthusiasm. She's a vulnerable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, not because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> thing but because she's arrogant, hates
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are tired of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. (Though if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> is stupid
enough to release his report right before the election, she's in.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>
is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoo-in</ENAMEX>: A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> and even suburbanites are turned off by his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authoritarianism</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX> will continue to undermine him,
endorsement or no; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX> probably won't endorse him unless
he makes some gestures to the right, which will not help him with his New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York/</ENAMEX>suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>.

            I do think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> will run, short of some major negative groundswell, which
I don't detect so far. I hope she does, since it would at least be an exciting
and unpredictable race, unlike (so far) the presidential yawn. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RFK Jr.</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cuomo</ENAMEX>?? Excuse me while I take a nap. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rangel</ENAMEX>? Maybe. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nita Lowey</ENAMEX> would
have been the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, actually, but at this point she could never
escape the comparisons and the celebrity gap.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>' casual attitude toward facts: If news stories get the dates
wrong, the "facts" purveyed by what passes for news analysis and commentary
make me feel like I'm living in an alternate universe. From what I read, we're
in the middle of an endless euphoric economic boom and lots of jobs at rising
wages, while what I see is a shaky stock market, technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> unable to
unload their overstock of computers, continuing layoffs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> losing good
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX> and getting part-time, lower-paid, benefitless jobs instead, etc., etc.
And then I keep reading that the culture war is over--so what do you call it
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> has decided evolution doesn't have to be
taught?

         
      
   
