
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gotcha</ENAMEX>!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the arrests of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 60</NUMEX>
airport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> on charges related to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> trafficking
(the other papers all front this story). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads
with a widening investigation of money laundering in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The amounts
involved may top <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 billion</NUMEX>, and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> could be implicated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s backing down from their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year</TIMEX> denial that incendiary
devices were used during the siege of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Davidian</ENAMEX> compound, a story
that's fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, and the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> front the capture of a high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> military
official by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>.

            A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> sting operation nabbed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> ramp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky Chef</ENAMEX> (a food catering service used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>), and a handful
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> and customs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> used their security clearance and
free flight privileges to smuggle fake <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">grenades</ENAMEX> for undercover
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> different incidents. The arrests may be related to last
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>'s arrests of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cali</ENAMEX> who were also using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> to smuggle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The papers suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> has proven
particularly prone to smuggling problems because it has the most service to
drug-exporting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> plays up an
interesting safety angle: Not only is smuggling laughably easy, it's
potentially very dangerous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Smugglers</ENAMEX> often stashed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contraband</ENAMEX> close to
sensitive equipment, or among the in-flight <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authorities</ENAMEX> were tipped off
to the smuggling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> complained of weak in-flight <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>--it had
been accidentally laced with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>.

            Various organized crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> and politicos are being scrutinized by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. At least <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> was filtered through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> owned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semion Mogilevich</ENAMEX>, an alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s largest crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX>. Along
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tatyana Dyachenko</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy prime minister</ENAMEX> are under investigation.
Interestingly, not all of the money laundered was ill-gotten, as is usually the
case. In addition to revenues from prostitution and contract killings, as much
as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> of the money in question may have come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> loans.

            A former senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> told reporters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> that tear gas
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">canisters</ENAMEX> used on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Davidians</ENAMEX> could have started the fire that
destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>. Until now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has insisted that the tear
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> fired at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> had no incendiary potential. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> director
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> have ordered a renewed inquiry into the events,
they still deny that the tear gas canisters could have caused the blaze--they
were fired, apparently to no effect, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> before the fire began. The WP
explains why all this is coming to light now: further investigation by a
documentary filmmaker and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> for siege <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX> also
claims to have footage demonstrating that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> helicopter fired on the
compound, another action that has been repeatedly denied.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Momir Talic</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>, is the highest
ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to be seized by the war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>. During <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>'s civil
war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talic</ENAMEX> was part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> "crisis <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>" formed to carry out ethnic
cleansing in northwestern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>. Mass graves containing over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1500</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Croat corpses</ENAMEX> have been uncovered in the territories he controlled during the
conflict. Thus far, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apprehended</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> points out this irony: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talic</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> to
attend a conference on cooperation between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Croat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">federation</ENAMEX> when he was arrested.

            According to a front page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>'s investigation of an
openly gay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> who was also in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> Reserves has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-ignited debate over the armed forces' "don't ask, don't tell" policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
May was "outed" in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona State Senate</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
investigation began only after he spoke out against antigay cuts in health care
benefits. The story notes an interesting fact: Since its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> inception, the
number of armed forces personnel discharged for homosexuality has actually
increased steadily. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 yearly</TIMEX> tally (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,145</NUMEX> discharged) is nearly double
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> count. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> that it will revise
its guidelines for carrying out the policy.

         
      
   
