
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kool-Aid Test</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Kara</ENAMEX>,

            Sorry to get such a late start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I find when I'm starting out on a new
story--as has been the case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of days</TIMEX>--I have a hard time even
reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, much less absorbing the information contained within.
I'm too preoccupied, too panicked. I always feel as though I'm starting way too
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late</TIMEX>, and I'll never be able to pull it off, and that this will be the story
that finally exposes me for the fraud that I really am. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> thinks this is
an utterly absurd way to go through life, for which I can offer no defense but
a helpless shrug. I used to think that I would get over this feeling; now I
know better.

            Anyway ... I did want to pick up on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> threads from your message this
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. First, on the question of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, it strikes me as completely
unarguable that his "living icon" status has been a tremendous asset to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--or at least it did until the antitrust trial began. First, he's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> who is much more a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technologist</ENAMEX>--he doesn't like to
hear that, but it's true--so he gets to command the respect that founders
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">command</ENAMEX> within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, while also having the set of skills, rarely seen in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">founders</ENAMEX>, that are required to manage very big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. It helps--a lot--that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> will follow him over a cliff. The classic example was when he
woke up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> needed to devote all its energies to
the Internet. The entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had to shift on a dime and promising projects,
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had devoted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to, were scrapped because they didn't relate to
the Internet. At a typical big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, there would have been enormous
resistance. But at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, there wasn't so much as a whisper of complaint.
Everybody simply got with the program, because, by God, that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
wanted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Competitors</ENAMEX> like to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> "take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kool-Aid</ENAMEX>,"
but they probably all wish they had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least a little</NUMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kool</ENAMEX>-Aid
themselves.

            During the antitrust trial, though, you could see the problem with that lack
of independent thinking. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' deposition was a true abomination--he was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">churlish</ENAMEX> and evasive--and precisely because he is so clearly the embodiment of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, he hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s cause a great deal. But no one at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
could admit that obvious truth. (Instead, they blamed it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feds</ENAMEX> for asking
"bad" questions, and the press for writing stories that simply said out loud
what we were seeing with our own eyes.) And most of the subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> brought to the trial the same set of characteristics that were so
vividly on display during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> deposition: defensiveness, arrogance, an
unwillingness to say anything straightforwardly. Fairly or not, they all looked
as though they had something to hide, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> had. It's such an insular
culture, ultimately, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have trouble even grasping questions
that are posed from a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> point of view. The great virtue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auletta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> piece on the trial is that it really illustrated
that point wonderfully. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX> would constantly ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> simple, sensible
questions--and would get an uncomprehending rant from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> in return.
Sigh.

            Speaking of abominations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco</ENAMEX> disclosure certainly ranks as one, on so
many levels. Not long after the event, an old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick J.</ENAMEX>
Reavis, went to work on a book about it. He was convinced that the government
had behaved badly--an attitude I foolish wrote off as part of his generally
anti-government bias. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, was I ever wrong, and was he ever right. Over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, it has become increasingly clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waco</ENAMEX> was a disaster that should
never have happened. It gives solace to the "off the grid" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. It's scary
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> will tell lies for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>!--before someone with
firsthand knowledge is willing to tell the truth. I can't stand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who play
to those who view the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>, secret conspiracy (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>,
for instance). But at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> like this one, it is hard to argue with them.

            Oh, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other thing: Isn't this just another reminder that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>
ranks among the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> of all time? Sure seems that way to
me.

         
      
   
