
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubles</ENAMEX> and Rubble

            The death toll in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> rose past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> by press time, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17,000</NUMEX> reported
injured and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> more still missing. Rescue and relief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> from all
over--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>--flocked to western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
where domestic efforts were faltering or nonexistent.  Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads
with post-quake events. The fire in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">refinery</ENAMEX> continued to
blaze out of control, threatening to blow up a nearby fertilizer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and
forcing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> to flee. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead
reports that law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have discovered <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobsters</ENAMEX> may
have used accounts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> to launder <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $10 billion</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post lead, dwarfed by the quake headline below it, carries <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
warning by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> that a fractured response
to the drought by regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> could impede effective conservation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with results of the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Household Survey on Drug Abuse</ENAMEX>. 

            Finger-pointing over western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s ill preparedness for the quake began
in some places before rescue and relief efforts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Survivors</ENAMEX> interviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for not conducting
adequate building inspections, failing to create food reserves, and failing to
equip them for emergencies. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story cites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>' complaints in
Izmit that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> slapped together many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> with greater concern for
cutting costs than risk. Only the LAT mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s top-heavy
government leaves regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> without the resources to cultivate local
civil defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. Earthquake <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> that strict
building codes make the city better prepared for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.4</NUMEX> (it's official) temblor
than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, despite similarities in their fault systems.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-column <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> exclusive reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> may have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> say that a notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> figure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Semyon Yukovich</ENAMEX>
Mogilevich, may have filtered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 billion</NUMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1998</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> suspended <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>, both
of whom are married to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have been on
the lookout for suspicious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economic activity since the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX>
ruble crash sent money flying out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> even more furiously than
usual. Money sifted through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> account may have gone to pay
contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drug lords</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports. 

            The federal survey reveals that teen use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, marijuana, and other
illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> fell to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.9 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11.4 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead.  The overall level of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use stayed about
the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> said they see the drop in use among <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-to-17-year-olds</TIMEX> as
an indication that messages from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are
getting through. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, which also fronts the story, says that young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18-to-25</NUMEX> saw an increase in both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use and smoking. A substance
abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that results in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12-to-17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> may be
flawed because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> must consent to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s interview and tend to
stick relatively close.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a response from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX> to charges that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of unfair racial targetting.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notra Trulock</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, deflated the accusation,
saying that of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> initially brought to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s attention, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and the rest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasians</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s decision to leave his post as independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> before his
final report is complete raises a thorny issue: Do the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who sit on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> that appointed him have the right to name a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> now that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> statute has expired? A new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointee</ENAMEX> might face legal roadblocks
from any of a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX> does not ask this question yet solves it anyway: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX> ask
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> stay on, dot his i's and cross his t's.

            Long-awaited economic recovery in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> may cause some strain in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, according to Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front-pagers. Increased production abroad
may make resources more scarce and finally tug prices upward at home. With
other places in the world to invest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> may pull money from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> stocks.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> expect that interest rates will head north to attract foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> also sees a global recovery as a turning point that
would solve minor problems at home: "In order to save the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>
pushed their own savings rate into negative territory."

            
               
                  Yes, the drug surveys were anonymous:
                On the
Post op-ed page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> speaks with candor of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
magazine-inspired conversion to the belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> should
answer rumors that he has used illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>:  "I happen to think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX> cokehead. If he had not used the stuff, he would certainly say
so. After all ... he has told us much about his past--his drinking, his
carousing, his lost youth, his meandering career path and how he gave up <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX>
and found God. This is a stirring tale, and I am moved every time I hear it."


         
      
   
