
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s Hypocrisy
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jim</ENAMEX>:

            Can it be that our exercise in stunt online writing is nearing its
conclusion already? And just now when we'd gotten to the topic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s sex life, a subject that surely deserves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full week</TIMEX> of breakfasts,
if anyone can stomach it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s hypocrisy is truly flabbergasting. But the thing that always kills me
about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dallies</NUMEX>-with-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">comely</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> stories isn't the adultery
or even the hypocrisy, it's how these affairs undermine the work of the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>) who hold the same jobs as the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>' paramours.

            I'm still waiting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> interns to file some
kind of class action lawsuit. Couldn't they get damages for their lost future
earnings? After all, their once prestigious job title--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> intern--has
been transformed into the world's easiest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">liner</ENAMEX>. It's got to be no fun
having a lurid joke embedded in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">résumé</ENAMEX>.

            A final note on the dim fate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Examiner</ENAMEX> . A column
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s soon-to-be-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> suggests that
we shouldn't be digging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX>'s grave so fast. But
the same story fails to unearth a single credible potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>. As you asked
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: Isn't there someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> who has the cash and hubris to
lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year after year</TIMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>?

            How about one of those IPO'd cyber-moguls? After all, they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> in
losing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>. But here's how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS MarketWatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Kramer</ENAMEX>,
reacted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>'s suggestion that he should buy the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX> : "How stupid do I look? I reach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> times that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now."
Sigh. So much for cross-media synergies.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, I've enjoyed your musings about murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>,
deceased cooking show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, and dying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. I wish you luck in all
future <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> games, and many newsy breakfasts.

            Yours,
Katharine

         
      
   
