
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hollywood Grabs Blair Witch</ENAMEX>'s Coattails
            

            Judging from the fervent response to my 
piece on The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project , the role played by the Internet in
the success of this movie is not a myth. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the surprising things about the
response, though, was how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hated the film. In part, it did
sound like a classic case of a movie that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> went from being a
sleeper to being overhyped, so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> after,
say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6</TIMEX> were led to believe they were about to see the greatest horror
film ever made. But I was still surprised, since I thought that the quality of
the film was not something <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would contest.

            In any case, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other interesting points to make about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Witch</ENAMEX> as a marketing/economic phenomenon. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that the film's
mainstream success--it's now grossed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $108 million</NUMEX>--speaks to the
tremendous flexibility of even as hidebound an industry as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Witch</ENAMEX> is owned, after all, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artisan Entertainment</ENAMEX>, a small independent
distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that specializes in true art-house films like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wim Wenders</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Social Club</ENAMEX> (which you should, by the way, see at all
costs). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artisan</ENAMEX> was able to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> all
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in the space of just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> was obviously heavily hyped, and the buzz on the film was
good, which undoubtedly made selling the film to theater <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> easier than it
would otherwise have been. But there's still something wonderful about the
speed with which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> that normally would have had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> screens showing
Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Sea</ENAMEX> adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> instead. It's an excellent
example of how quickly supply rises to meet demand with no planning involved at
all.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> point is more mundane, but also more curious, and it has to do
with a weird new trend in movie advertising in which one film tries to take
advantage of the buzz surrounding another film, even though the two movies have
absolutely nothing in common. This strategy was used to great effect by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Spy Who Shagged Me</ENAMEX> , which ran ads saying, "If you see
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> movie <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, see Star Wars . If you see two movies, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> ..." That, though, was a clever acknowledgement of
reality. What has followed seems more like a not very well-thought-out
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gimmick</ENAMEX>.

            First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> mimicked the ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Daddy</ENAMEX> , with Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mini-Me</ENAMEX> urinating on a wall (in place of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX> and that little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kid</ENAMEX>). Then, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, nascent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-in-the-making <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit Rock City</ENAMEX> has
run ads featuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, with the tagline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October of 1978</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> disappeared outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years later</TIMEX>, their footage was found."

            This is, of course, a rip-off of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> (whose ads featured
similar language). But what's puzzling is the point of the rip-off. Is it that
we're supposed to think the movie was made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Witch</ENAMEX> ? Or are we supposed to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit Rock City</ENAMEX> is somehow
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> ? Or, alternatively, are we just supposed to be amazed
by the cleverness of the ad<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-makers</ENAMEX>, and be inspired by that cleverness to see
the movie?

            The answer, I think, is none of the above. Instead, with the buzz on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit Rock City</ENAMEX> as bad as it's been, the marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> essentially
threw up their hands and decided that there was no point in selling the film as
what it is. Instead, they wanted to see if they could catch a little halo
effect from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, even as I write this down, it
still doesn't really make sense. Who would ever go see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie because its ad
campaign consisted of an homage to another? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit Rock City</ENAMEX> : "We're
not a sequel to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> , but oh, how we wish we were."

         
      
   
