
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apotheosis of the CB Radio</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Joe</ENAMEX>,

            Well, I am sorry you were much maligned by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motley Fool</ENAMEX>,
which was one of the first really successful online communities to take off.
But the kind of response you are getting is just the kind of thing I like about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>. Remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> we used to sit on high at elite media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
and broadcast down our words to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> below? No more. And I could not be
more thrilled to hear back from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> since it only makes us better at our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jobs</ENAMEX>, despite the agony of having to listen to the wackos that always accompany
the good comments.

            In fact, I really like this part of the Internet most of all, the ability of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to bypass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gatekeepers</ENAMEX> and perhaps even flex their minds a bit. I am
certain that there will be plenty of fraud and hucksters--there was a good
story in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on that lovely trend--but that, once again,
is another thing that seems to be a human perennial no matter the medium. It is
true though that the Internet is well-suited to these nefarious tasks with its
ability to reach out to more easy marks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, for example, has always been
plagued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> posing as customer-service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reps</ENAMEX>, who somehow manage to get a
lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to hand over the most intimate of information.

            But you are right, there are limits to technology. Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX>.

            I am riding the train right now toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and have been trying to file
my electronic letters to you while traveling. But there are no phones on this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">train</ENAMEX>, and definitely no data <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> to plug my nifty micro-laptop computer
into. So I have been calling in to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> very patient 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">editors</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to read--yes, I am actually giving dictation--my text in order to
have it posted. That has worked fine until I passed through a particularly
large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of buttes or canyons. Stupendous as they are from a nature point of
view, they utterly block my cell phone transmissions and I am left completely
without any useful technology. Imagine, a butte trumps all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
innovations.

            Nonetheless, since nothing works in this situation, I would like to take up
your notion that the Internet is not as impactful as communications mediums
before it, like the printing press, the telegraph, the telephone, and, finally,
television. While I think all these mediums are momentous, I feel that they
have all been steps to where we are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with the Internet. At its very best,
the Internet combines all of these inventions--it is the printed word that can
be instantly telegraphed anywhere that adds on the interactivity of the
telephone. Soon more advanced audio and video will be part of the daily picture
on the Web. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> that links up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all over the world is one that is
clearly going to be more important than all others, if you really have to
choose.

            I think the big question is how does society give everyone a seat at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> table. As far as I am concerned, the Internet is still a conversation
among the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>, a woeful trend that I see only getting worse. So I
perk up every time the notion of a free PC or free Internet access is brought
up. I was pleased to see an article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> about how
venture-capital money is now being spent in areas other than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>. Right now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of the cash
has headed to the peninsula south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. The joke we make there is
that there is so much money for Internet venturers available to entrepreneurs
located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> that there are not enough rat holes to shove it down.
Combined with the giant amounts of money these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are getting from Wall
Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> via IPOs--an that is real cash they are receiving, no matter
how high their stock prices are--there is too much money going to too few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and too few new ideas. I think there has to be more branching out with
these investment dollars, especially if they're going to help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> people
get connected as possible.

            The real question is, of course, will these already questionable Web
business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> ever make enough money to pay back all this funding? I don't
know if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> can ever make the kind of money that will justify its lofty
stock price, although it certainly seems adept at spending cash. I have heard
all the comparisons to the tulip mania of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland</ENAMEX> and the stock speculation of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1920s</NUMEX>, and this current craze is nothing new. But it should not blind us to
the fact that some very real and significant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are being built
here.

            I didn't see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> story in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , but I have been
constantly fascinated by his desire to paint himself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, especially in
the Internet age. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Auletta</ENAMEX> piece in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> was
fascinating to me because it painted an awfully childish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoon</ENAMEX> who doesn't
seem to like the way he world is changing. Nonetheless, notice that most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Electric</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>--are
riveted by the Internet, as well they should be. As the song from my favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">musical, West Side Story</ENAMEX> , goes, "Something's coming, I don't know what
it is, but it's going to be great." In other words, this ain't no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">radio</ENAMEX>, the
much maligned craze that the Internet was often compared to in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early days</TIMEX>.
But consider the parallels--handles were nothing more than screen names, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">banter</ENAMEX> was a version of chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, and instant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> was created from
nothing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, maybe it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> radio that is more important than the printing
press.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-4</NUMEX>, good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>,
Kara

         
      
   
