
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back-Slapping Media Elite</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN</ENAMEX>:

            We are on opposite schedules. While you were writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dispatch</ENAMEX>, I was eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">noodles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steamed vegetables</ENAMEX> from a palatable take-out
joint in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tribeca</ENAMEX>, watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hardball</ENAMEX> , and preparing to tuck my
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost-5-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> into bed. His birthday is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> (ironically, on the
same date as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, who passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years ago</TIMEX>) and that's all he can
talk about.

            You didn't respond to my take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX>.

            On "hate" crimes, I see your point, but I think the media and
attention-starved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have trivialized the issue. The most publicized
"hate" crime in recent memory was the sad death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX>, the gay man
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>. I don't believe that was a "hate" crime designed to send a message
to a whole class of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. It was the case of a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> who were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drunk</ENAMEX>, homophobic, and out of control. It doesn't compare to abortion-clinic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombings</ENAMEX>. In any case, my point remains: What's the point of "hate crime"
legislation other than to assuage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>? For example, I hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> are fried, but they can't be killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice</NUMEX>, right?

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> comes close, perhaps subconsciously,
to endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. She writes about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> question, as every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pundit</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, and chastises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for not answering that query when he's
stated that he's been faithful to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. Yet she closes the piece: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> seems
to have good instincts, and he knows how to get good advice. But does that
qualify him to lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>? That's the substance abuse we should worry
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> is an odd <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>: Most often she writes about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, fashion,
everything trivial, while wrapping it up in some political context. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s column about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>'s running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (which would be a
lot of fun, no?) was typical: She said he won't because as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carly Simon</ENAMEX> sang so
long ago, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">He's So Vain</ENAMEX>." She certainly didn't deserve the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> (even
though it's a bogus award, an example of the media elite slapping each other on
the back), especially when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Hentoff</ENAMEX>, now one of the few reasons to read the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> , was her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>.

            But I'm behind in my work. The classified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> has
just moved over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPress</ENAMEX> and she starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. She'll need a quick
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPress</ENAMEX> in-house culture, which I guarantee you is far
different from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>'s.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RUSS</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
