
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Man</ENAMEX> Theory
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Joe</ENAMEX>,

            It's nice to know that reporting does not change. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the first lessons I
learned in journalism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was the old phrase "there is nothing new under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX>," and I suspect that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> an exciting new topic will be
fascinating us in the same way that the Internet is now and the takeovers of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> did then. I too was riveted by leveraged buyout stories in that time
and great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. Boone Pickens</ENAMEX>.

            I was particularly struck by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie Bruck</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Predator</ENAMEX>'s Ball
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about this time</TIMEX> period, which I liked because of just what you were talking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. Business was dramatic, made up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and not just numbers. I was
very cognizant of this when I was writing my book on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. It was clear quickly
that all the successes and failures there over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> were due more to a
particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> than to larger market forces. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, born under some kind of
lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, was able to attract the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> at the right time to cause it
to be able to get to the next level. In its earliest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, it needed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">craziness</ENAMEX> provided by a enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Von Meister</ENAMEX>. But
it was a diligent and totally focused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> who was able
to take his ideas and make them real. And Case needed a lot of help too--often
company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mythologies</ENAMEX> focus on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>--from the loud entrance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Leonsis</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> to provide the spice and media savvy that Case lacked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Pittman</ENAMEX>'s
entry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, which gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> the world-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> who would turn the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> into a "real" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            The situation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> is a case in point, with its current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Armstrong</ENAMEX>. Whatever you think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s strategy to converge its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX>, telephone, and Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> to achieve some iron lock on the
consumer, it is clearly being driven by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armstrong</ENAMEX>. The same is true of most
every Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> I have written about--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bezos</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Yang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Filo</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX>. It's good, I think, in this speedy and
complex age to see that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> still can make a difference. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>, along with its struggles with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>, is in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, no matter how big that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has become, still hangs over
it like a living icon. I wonder if that is a good thing or a bad one as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> grow?

            In a completely unrelated topic, were you are disturbed as I was about the
stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> about
how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has reversed its stance on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waco</ENAMEX> incident in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>? Oops, it
did fire in incendiary devices, despite its denials. I swear, I am
still so surprised when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> lie like that. Does that make me
hopelessly naive? I should remember another old j-school maxim--if your mother
says she loves you, check it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
Kara

         
      
   
