
   
   
      
         
            Voice Over
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ</ENAMEX>,

            Bust the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, indeed! I'm for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> on principle--and in practical,
self-interested terms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> was what allowed me to make some semblance of
a decent living when I worked there, not to mention its role in representing a
militant staff culture and defending the autonomy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>,
especially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> era--but all that aside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> has nothing to do
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX>'s editorial problems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> was much better in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'80s</NUMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> was stronger, relatively speaking--not that it was ever
really strong, but it seems totally toothless now. On the contrary, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> has been done in by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'90s</TIMEX> corporate culture with its emphasis on
cost-cutting, its cult of efficiency, and its deep distrust of creative work
because it's ultimately unquantifiable and resistant to control from the top.
If a publication is built around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> with strong, individual views and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">identities</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> because of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, it gives the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> a lot of power; and I think it has suited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Stern</ENAMEX>'s
business agenda (I'm not suggesting it's a conscious conspiracy) for the
Voice to stop being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s paper. Free distribution also changes the
nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> and the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't shelling out money to read particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, and it's
harder for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> to tell who their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is.

            A while ago I had a conversation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX>'s managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in
which he said I was one in a long line of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Embittered Alumni</ENAMEX>. I thought that was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">witty</ENAMEX>, and briefly considered making up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice Embittered</ENAMEX>
Alumni button. But in fact I'm not bitter--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> was where I really
developed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, and I'm grateful to it, on the whole--I'm
just frustrated: I think the paper served a crucial function as a space for
cultural reporting and analysis and culturally radical ideas that were censored
elsewhere, and it isn't serving that function anymore, nor has any other
publication come close to replacing it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> was the first
publication to give a forum to pro-sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>, the first so far as I know to
blow the whistle on the "ritual sex abuse" day-care trials. There was a time
when something like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal would have prompted an
outpouring of debate and analysis from all angles. If something like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>
happened, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> would have sent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> out there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>
and would have had the best story on what was really going on there. And so on.
Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R.I.</ENAMEX>P.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>'s up. See you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
