
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekend Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
            

            To the chagrin of many and the joy of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a few</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cocktail Chatter</ENAMEX>
returns after a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-week</TIMEX> absence, which God knows I hope made your hearts grow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fonder</ENAMEX>. Not coincidentally, perhaps, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">recaps</ENAMEX> that went unwritten
would have had to detail a stock market tumbling steadily downhill, a Net
sector in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> appeared to have lost all faith, and interest rates
that had reached a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> high. (Though it's always worth remembering that
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.25 percent</NUMEX> is not exactly usurious.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, things brightened slightly,
for no obvious reason aside from excellent earnings from bellwethers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco</ENAMEX> (a
holding of mine) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> (which I don't own but probably should) and a
general sense that the market was "oversold."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oversold</ENAMEX>" doesn't mean anything, of course. It just means that prices have
dropped pretty far pretty quickly. Unfortunately, sometimes prices drop far and
quickly for good reasons. This wasn't one of those times, I think, but
"oversold" is not a label that helps you tell the difference. But it's a good
word to use at cocktail parties if you want everyone to know you're in the
know. Actually, it's a good word to use if you want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to think you're a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crackpot</ENAMEX>. But that can be fun, too. And so, once more into the breach.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "This from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomberg News</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Microsoft Corp.</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AvantGo Inc.</ENAMEX>, which
delivers customized information to handheld computers, will offer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in a bid to widen distribution of
the highbrow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> publication ... The push to broaden 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s
distribution is part of a sweeping effort by the world's biggest software maker
to strengthen its Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> and better compete with No. 1 online
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">service America Online, Inc.</ENAMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, which is based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, fell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 5/16 to 83 13/16</NUMEX>.' Next we'll be blamed for the fact that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Allen</ENAMEX> is selling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> shares ."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Kelleher</ENAMEX> announced that he would be
undergoing treatment for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">prostate cancer</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> praised his
openness as evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> were no longer as quick to hide potential
problems from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Meyers</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMC</ENAMEX>, told the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , 'It's like erectile dysfunction . Who would talk
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about that six months ago</TIMEX>?' ... So <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> are now going to tell us when they're
erectilely dysfunctional? Can we pass on that?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General American Life Insurance</ENAMEX> said that it would be unable to
redeem <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> of withdrawals from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who had entered
into so-called 'short-term funding agreements' with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Although
credit-ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> had always frowned on these agreements , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> always claimed they were a good business to be in. Oh yeah. It's a
great business when you can borrow money with no intention of paying it
back."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports, as evidence of tight labor
markets , that roofing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jude Laperouse</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, has
to turn down jobs because he can't find enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, despite offering a
starting wage of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> an hour . Damn! He can't get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to work tarring a
roof for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> an hour? What the hell is wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>! How spoiled have we
become?!"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "Perennial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">also-ran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advanced Micro Devices</ENAMEX>, which practically every year
comes out with a new product that it says will challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s
domination of the microprocessor market and practically every year has a
new explanation for why <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>'s product failed, released the Athlon
chip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. It's faster and more powerful than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pentium III</ENAMEX> ,
yadda yadda yadda. You gotta wonder if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that wrote the press release
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">touting Athlon</ENAMEX> wasn't tempted to add: 'No, really. This time we mean it.'"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> is introducing self-serve <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kiosks</ENAMEX> in certain test
locations. Someone tell me again: Why did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Automats</ENAMEX> go out of business?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster Video</ENAMEX> went public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, and saw its shares budge not
at all from their offering price . The headline in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> ? 'First
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day of Trading</ENAMEX> Hardly a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blockbuster</ENAMEX>.' It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, I tell you! Pure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genius</ENAMEX>!"

         
      
   
