
   
   
      
         
            The Internet As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Fight</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Kara</ENAMEX>,

            Should we, too, agree to disagree? Oh, I suppose. It's unsatisfying, but
you're probably right that we're not going to change each other's mind.
Debating the Internet has become a lot like debating politics in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>:
Nobody talks to each other; they talk past each other. They're not trying to
persuade; they're just trying to stake out claims. (You and I, of course, are
the rare exception.) "Stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hucksters Thrive</ENAMEX> on the Web," said the front page
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. No doubt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of that dispatch
received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> e-mail flames in response.

            I've been involved in a few spats with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Motley Fools</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>,
writing stories that I thought were models of judicious balance, only to have
all manner of insult hurled upon me, so I guess I'm particularly sensitized to
the food-fight aspect of the Internet. (To give them their due, they are firmly
convinced that I'm out to get them. Sigh.) Still and all, I concede that it's
amazing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can have such heated and passionate feelings about this
technology. Was there the same debate over the telephone? Over the automobile?
I'm just wondering.

            It is also possible that my general grouchiness on the subject of the
Internet has to do with the fact that I've expended a lot of energy these past
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> claiming that the valuations of Internet stocks make no sense, and
that, in general, what I've come to think of as the Internet stock
market--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> using the Internet to "learn" about Internet stocks, when they
then trade via an Internet site--is insane. To me, it's the latest sign that
the end is near, or at least the end of the bull market. There is a new book
out that catalogues all sorts of financial manias over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>; you can't
read it without seeing the obvious parallels to the Internet mania. But of
course, every time I say that out loud, the stocks keep going up, and I look
like an idiot. And the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> has a grand old time mocking me.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, you may have noticed, the market rose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close to 200</NUMEX> points. Yahoo was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up over 7</NUMEX> points etc., etc. It's tough to be an old fashioned market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in
this age.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oops</ENAMEX>--gotta run to a lunch date with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>. Before I go, I want to draw
your attention to the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> cover package in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . He's
giving away another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> or so; reveling in being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>; feeling
victimized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feds</ENAMEX>; and worried about the threat posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. Hmmm? ...
Perhaps a subject for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX>?

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
