
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-Word Litmus Test</ENAMEX>
            

            It's not that I'm uninterested in electoral politics. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing
elections are an important form of popular culture; they always have something
to say about what's going on with us. But my view of the electoral scene is
always filtered through a layer of irony since there's almost never anyone I'm
really for, and it's usually an issue of who I'm more afraid of. Even
third-party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are generally <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>. I did vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, but as
a protest against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policies, not because I like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>
running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would be fun, but on the other hand he blew it by
crossing the picket line at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that PEN</TIMEX> event at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cipriani's</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s column on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
missed the point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has every right not to talk about his past <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. In
fact, silence is a lot more seemly than all the blather he would feel forced to
put out if he owned up, to the effect of what a terrible mistake he had made in
the feckless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of his youth. No, what's truly objectionable is his
declaration of fidelity to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. Enough, already, with monogamy-mongering.
Even more ridiculous is the controversy over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> saying "fuck," apropos of
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>, in the course of defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX>
column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, saw fit to lay on us the information that he himself never uses
the word. What's next? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Zion</ENAMEX> confessing that he himself doesn't do oral
sex?

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lars Erik Nelson</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> column
suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> should come clean about whether she believes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">creationism</ENAMEX>. Since she is "seeking to lead this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> into the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st century</TIMEX>," we need to know. Well, OK, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>,
with their usual respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, may nominate her as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> on the
theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will vote for any warm female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. (Not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> seems to
have gender-gap problems so far, at least vis-à-vis <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.) But does she say
"fuck"? And was she ever unfaithful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> in those dark times before
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>?

            I notice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, also according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> , has declined to
backtrack on his opposition to a law banning so-called "partial birth"
abortion. Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX> swallow that and his position on gay
rights? And if they don't--do you really think he can win a three-way race?

         
      
   
