
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Comical Revolution</ENAMEX>

            In an unusual turn, foreign policy leads at all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes with an
exclusive report that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in public funds and international aid has been
stolen by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croatian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herzegovina</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post leads with its exclusive interview of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of
counterintelligence at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos National Laboratory</ENAMEX>, who says that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> did not steal nuclear information from any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> and that the investigation of alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> is racist. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Duma</ENAMEX>'s confirmation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>--an odd choice considering the
confirmation was a fait accompli . (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s confirmation was reefered
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts atop its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box a powerful
earthquake in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, which killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 286</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and injured
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,500</NUMEX>. The quake--which was reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> --was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.8</NUMEX>, or nearly as
powerful as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> quake. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with a
dispatch from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> describing the de facto ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">partition</ENAMEX> forming in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serbs</ENAMEX>, fearing widespread revenge killings, have fled to a northern,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosovska Mitrovika</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are
cleansed from north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and south <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, respectively, they flee to their
own racial ghettos, despite the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-led anti-fraud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>--part of a civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> set up by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX> peace accords--says that most of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in stolen aid was
funneled to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalist parties</ENAMEX> that govern the partitioned state of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnia-Herzegovina</ENAMEX>. The report, which was leaked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , says that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>-created civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> have each lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions of dollars</NUMEX>.
The missing funds--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a fifth</NUMEX> of the total aid received by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> since the
end of the war in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>--were to have gone to infrastructure repair and
municipal services.

            Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert S. Vrooman</ENAMEX>--whom <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> recently targeted for punishment--says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> is being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scapegoated</ENAMEX> because of his race. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vrooman</ENAMEX>--a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> operative--says there is
not a "shred of evidence" against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s stolen nuclear secrets
could have come from any of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and defense
contractors outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vrooman</ENAMEX> says the Taiwan-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> has
been singled out because he attended <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> physics conferences in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, but that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> who went to the same
conferences have never been investigated. (To read 
                  Sleate
               's take
on racism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-DNC campaign-finance scandal, check out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> article "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slanted</ENAMEX>.")

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> analyzes the finances of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, it turns out,
is rich but not very liquid. He has been cutting down on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s more
lavish expenses--such as his famous "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capitalist Tool</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>--and is even selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>'s island in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fiji</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> valued it at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 million</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> is selling it for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX>.) To match <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s
campaign spending, the article concludes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> may have to sell part of the
family business, liquidate real estate in his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, or go
heavily into debt.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living outside the farming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>
included--enjoy a good laugh every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> when presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> go
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disciples</ENAMEX> of farm subsidies. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' promises
may not be entirely cynical, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>' pain is real. Fresh evidence:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reports that calls to mental-health clinics
and hotlines in farming areas have soared with the recent decline in commodity
prices. Calls in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, for example, have risen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are known to get <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ulcers</ENAMEX> worrying about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' fate. But wait!
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week</ENAMEX>" also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> retraining programs at community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
are swelling, and state-subsidized retraining can often be had for less money
than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>'s annual subsidy.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" feature takes note of the latest youth fashion
trend: bra-strap flaunting. Many young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> now purchase bras not as underwear
but as fashion accessories--even choosing bras to match their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>, or
sporting bras with patterns and prints. Some wear headbands made of faux bra
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strap</ENAMEX>. "Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mennonite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are wearing it at church functions," sighs the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apparel Industry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. A textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> pins down
the appeal: "You can peek but not touch. It's sexually baiting but not in a
conscious way. It's just naughty enough to get away with."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China</ENAMEX> correspondent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Faison</ENAMEX>, notes the appearance in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> of government-sponsored comic books <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defaming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Hongzhi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the
banned sect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> comic book, with the subtle title <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Hongzhi</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man and His Evil Deeds</ENAMEX> , proclaims that "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hongzhi</ENAMEX>'s] illegal doings
seriously disrupted the normal order of society, causing chaos in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> and moral principles." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faison</ENAMEX> notes that the propaganda comics are
reminiscent of those circulated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gang of Four</ENAMEX>--the
leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> arrested after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>. The comic
books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faison</ENAMEX> says, "drip with so much political venom that they capture the
labored nature of the campaign [against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hongzhi</ENAMEX>] in a way that verges on
parody."

         
      
   
