
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reefer Madness</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN</ENAMEX>:

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last day</TIMEX> for us on 
                  Slate
               , so let's do some housekeeping. My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend Al From Baltimore</ENAMEX>, who was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore</ENAMEX> 
               City
Paper , and more conservative than me, has enjoyed our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. Although he
thinks I should be more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MUGGERish</ENAMEX> and call you a commie or something.

            I don't think there will be a three-way race in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. As I've stated
before, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> will not run and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> will win. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservative Party</ENAMEX>,
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> doesn't adhere to their pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX>, will huff and puff, and follow
the dictates of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Republican Party</ENAMEX>. None of these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> GOPers
wants to incur the wrath of a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, there's no way she'll be the veep. The choice will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, a pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> with a military record
who's from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rustbelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. That's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> needs. Don't get me
started with that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Neanderthal</ENAMEX> creationism jazz in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>. What nonsense.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX>
will have a story saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, coyly, has said he hasn't used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past seven years</TIMEX>, the amount of time necessary for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> OK at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> I hope he sticks to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> question. His "I won't play
the gotcha game" answers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> have shown the most passion in his
speeches so far, recalling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s spontaneous, and successful, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> [or
whoever that was], I'm paying for this microphone!" blast in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> back
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'80</TIMEX>. Frankly, I don't give a shit if he did snort coke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, although
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> say he didn't. So what? One thing that bugs me the most
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, who are truly an odious lot, is their namby-pamby position
on pot. Obviously, this wasn't a problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, but now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boomers</ENAMEX> and
Gen-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Xers</ENAMEX> are running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, they have to answer and inevitably, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazio</ENAMEX>, that little shit, they say something like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, as a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> I
tried marijuana <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times, but it was foolish." I'd love, just once,
for a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to say: "Yes, I smoked pot a lot and really enjoyed it.
Just like I enjoyed having several <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> at a dance. I was alive at a time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pot</ENAMEX> was part of the culture, I was curious, and you know what, it was pretty
damn cool. Made me think in a different way. But I don't smoke anymore."

            That would satisfy me. I smoked pot for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and don't regret it a bit. I
mean, who didn't? I did coke, but didn't like it. It made me feel like such a
whore: Since I didn't have much money, you'd always have to schmooze the person
who had the stash, even if you didn't like him or her. That made me feel cheap.
Also, coke didn't last long enough. Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal meth</ENAMEX>, that was an excellent
drug that I used a lot in college. I would snort it to pull all-nighters
putting out my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college paper</ENAMEX>, chasing it with Squirt <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX>, and then have a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beers</ENAMEX> to calm down. I remember one final exam where I was totally fried, and I
just undid my aluminum packet of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal</ENAMEX> and snorted right on the desk in the
exam <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> was oblivious. I got an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX>

            I don't do <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> now, but it certainly was part of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20s</TIMEX>. I wish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> could be honest about it.

            Next installment: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> .

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RUSS</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
