
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springsteen</ENAMEX>, and Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosses</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN</ENAMEX>:

            Still on the possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, I'm not
sure why you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nita Lowey</ENAMEX>, should the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> drop out, would be the
best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. Perhaps she best represent your politics, and those
of many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>, but she certainly doesn't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> to defeat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who gives most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the creeps. But that's why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> will probably win: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> know he's mean, that he grandstands, that
he's a control freak. So he's somewhat immunized against such lapses in a
campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowey</ENAMEX> wouldn't stand a chance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RFK Jr.</ENAMEX> would win going away; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuomo</ENAMEX> would have an even shot.

            Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX>. Any report he issues will have
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> news cycle life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, whom I believe is a decent, courageous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
was one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. He ended up as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot</ENAMEX>, unprepared to deal
with the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>. He had a terrible sense
of public relations, and was demonized successfully by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spin
machine. However, he wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. That honor goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. I assume you won't be voting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>; do you prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>? Or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>?

            You may be correct, but where do you get your information that the stock
market is "shaky"? It certainly was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last October</TIMEX>, with a recession looming, but
the rapid communications system in place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> alerted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could do
something about it, unlike the recession of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'90-'91</ENAMEX>.

            Back to your old turf. I don't know if you read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> today, but
there was an unspeakably awful article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Strauss</ENAMEX> about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springsteen</ENAMEX> concert in the arts section. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who's written memorable
rock criticism, what do you think of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strauss</ENAMEX>' worship of
Springsteen was very hard to read. Only at the end of the piece does he
acknowledge the pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>'s vast wealth, but still gives him a bye. He writes:
"But at the same time he has gotten more than he wanted only to discover that a
dream fulfilled is no longer a dream; it is a new and heavier weight." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yikes</ENAMEX>.
I'll bet the unemployed blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Springsteen</ENAMEX> sings about so
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mournfully</ENAMEX> would trade places with him in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>.

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RUSS</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
