
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> Up

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> interest-rate hike of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s news on the front page, but leads instead with
a possible link between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> laundering
scandal.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> give the same lowdown on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s decision. The federal
funds rate (that is, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> charge each another for overnight borrowing)
was lifted from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.25 percent</NUMEX>, reversing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s cuts. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s announcement was characteristically opaque. The stories follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s
lead, hedging their bets as to whether this will be the last hike of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> run helpful explanations of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hike</ENAMEX>'s repercussions. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> already announced
increases in their prime lending rates to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.25 percent</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX>. Since
many credit-card balances, home-equity loans, small business bank loans, and
some personal loans are tied directly to the prime rate, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of consumers
will see their monthy payments swell soon. A piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
warns the higher cost of borrowing may keep funds away from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that need the cash badly.

            Meanwhile, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> has become so
effective that he's ineffective. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> raises rates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are
assured by what they interpret as a wise, pre-emptive strike against inflation.
If he doesn't, they are emboldened by what can only be a sure sign of economic
health. So even though the rate hike might stave off consumer inflation,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> is inevitably contributing to stock price inflation.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reported that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of millions of dollars</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> may have been illegally diverted through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX>
via the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> USAT adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Konstantin Kagalovsky</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> and a close crony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>, is
now under scrutiny. He is married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who is also
being investigated. The scoop certainly sounds like a potentially juicy one.
But it lists no allegations against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kagalovskys</ENAMEX>, and doesn't surmise about
how they might have fit into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia-Bank</ENAMEX> triangle.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will prosecute the most
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX>--and only the most senior ones. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> order
excused most of the sect's adherents as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> who didn't know they were
joining a subversive political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, on the other
hand, will almost certainly be sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for life--just in time, says the
Times , for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50th</NUMEX> birthday bash.

            According to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
Health has traced an outbreak of syphilis to an <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX> chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. At
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have contracted syphilis from sexual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> they met at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Men</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX>, a chat room hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. Citing privacy concerns,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX> would not divulge the real names of the chat room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to the
health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Planet Out</ENAMEX>, a gay online
service based in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, which pelted the denizens of local gay chat rooms
with e-mailed and instant-messengered warnings.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Sheinbein</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> who set off an extradition battle when he fled to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> after
allegedly committing murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, has accepted a plea bargain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> had refused extradition on the controversial grounds
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheinbein</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> (his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> was
founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>). He will serve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years</TIMEX>--a heavy sentence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, but <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a light one</NUMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> standards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> from both countries
decried the way he manipulated the discrepancies between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager provides welcome perspective on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas School</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX>'s recent decision to excise evolution from its official curriculum. Most
science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> will continue to teach evolution. Moreover, "there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">304</NUMEX>
locally elected school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> who have the option to tell the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to go
jump in the lake," said an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Graves</ENAMEX>. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> is confident the overwhelming number will."

         
      
   
