
   
   
      
         
            Secrets and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spies</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , and the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> lead with follow-ups on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">day-care</ENAMEX> shootings.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes with anonymously sourced reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military
plotting against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, a story fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> places atop its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX>'s decision to seek punishment in a botched nuclear-espionage
investigation, a story fronted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . All the
papers front countdown stories to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw poll.

            Follow-up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> shooting takes different forms. In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-column headline reveals that suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buford Furrow</ENAMEX> had
considered unloading his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> prominent local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Tolerance</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Skirball Cultural Center</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also mentions that he scouted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> locations.) But
after finding security there too tight, he stumbled upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Valley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Community Center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>'s follow-up focuses on proposals by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> for more federal gun regulation. The story fails to
define clearly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> actually proposed (it summarizes one of her proposals
as simply, "federal limits on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">handgun</ENAMEX> purchases") and never mentions what laws
are on the books already. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> details how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are taking
elaborate precautions against shootings, despite federal reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gun-carrying</ENAMEX> and violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have actually declined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
Simulated shootings in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, for instance, have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">featured SWAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>, ersatz pipe bombs, and drama students
sporting fake wounds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superintendents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby group</ENAMEX> sums up
the mood nicely when he tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> : "Everyone feels the need to do
something, even though no one agrees on what that should be."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese Embassy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and
visiting military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> have hinted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> government
is considering a blockade of some small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>-controlled islands, a small air
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battle</ENAMEX>, or perhaps an incursion into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> to punish the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> for
its recent talk of independence. Both stories, sourced to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>," assert that the threat is unlikely but
nonetheless real. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says any action would likely occur after an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX>. "We have some time to play
with, but we're not out of the woods," an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> intones
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ominously</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> report <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Richardson</ENAMEX>'s
recommendation that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> be punished for their failure to
properly investigate espionage allegations against fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>.
(Since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> is run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> can only
recommend disciplinary action.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, fingered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector general</ENAMEX>, were not named, but a "department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>" tells
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> that one of them is former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> (now senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegfried Hecker</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson</ENAMEX>
will make amends with several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX> whistle-blowers in the espionage scandal who
had been punished rather than rewarded for speaking up. "There was a total
breakdown of the system and there's plenty of blame to go around," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>
said.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> publishes a below-the-fold headline that almost reads like
a satirical teaser in The
Onion : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Intense but Little-Noticed Fight, Allies Have Bombed Iraq</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All Year</TIMEX>." It seems that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last eight months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> have fired on more than triple the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> attacked in last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>'s highly publicized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> attack and have flown <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> as many
missions as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> flew against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78 days</TIMEX>. This is a curious
story: It is hard news reported almost as if it were a trend, and it is pegged
partly to its own absence in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in which it now appears.

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" story describes how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> of nearly every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> was pulled along reluctantly, albeit willingly:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gung-Ho; McCain</ENAMEX> is Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stay-At-Home; Quayle</ENAMEX> is Mrs.
Experience<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-With-Gritted-Teeth</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Traditional-Yet-Cautious</ENAMEX>; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modern</ENAMEX>-But-Naïve-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX>-Politics." And the one male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>? "Dole
is Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foot</ENAMEX>-In-The-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouth</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
