
   
   
      
         
            Where <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Were Eichmann's Memoirs for 37 Years</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> published <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolf Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s memoirs. The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">127</NUMEX>-page document in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s handwriting was recently uncovered in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s
Holocaust archives. No one knows how it got there.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> believe the recently published document is just an outline to the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX>-page memoir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eichmann</ENAMEX> wrote during his captivity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960-62</TIMEX>). A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> article briefly mentions that the longer document is
currently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and will be released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has had
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s complete memoirs for over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>, why are they being
published only now?

            The answer is that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eichmann</ENAMEX> was hanged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1962</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Gurion</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>--decreed that the memoir should be hidden
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s state archives. He believed the document was full of lies, the most
important being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s claim that he played only a small role in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.

            Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX> also made this claim in open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> during the trial.
(His arguments were most famously recounted in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Arendt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. ) So what's the harm in releasing memoirs that repeat it?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben-Gurion</ENAMEX> felt that releasing the document after the trial would distract
attention from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s verdict--an explicit rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s claims.
He was worried that publishing the memoir would give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> the impression
that there was still some controversy over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s guilt.

            The memoir's existence came to light only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, when it was
mentioned in another memoir, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> argued that there was no harm in not releasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">memoir</ENAMEX>, since he had already been given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            Spurred by this revelation, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segev</ENAMEX> took up the cause, arguing that the document is stolen property and
belongs rightfully to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> filed suit.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> agreed to release the document to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> for
publication. (It is not yet clear whether this will satisfy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichmann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.)
The document will be released in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, with commentary pointing out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrative</ENAMEX>'s many inaccuracies.

            Is it coincidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> released the
shorter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">127</NUMEX>-page memoir <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just days</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> announced plans to release the
longer version? It's possible--but unlikely. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX>
surely knew their document would be worthless if released after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
document, and it's reasonable to assume they sped up their editorial process to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">scoop Israel</ENAMEX>'s release.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Gottlieb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Explainer</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>, is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> to start law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
            

         
      
   
