
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speeches</ENAMEX>

            Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> addressed the audience
for a maximum of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX>. No one was brilliant, and several were actively
terrible. Here's my estimation of how they stacked up. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to see the results
and 
here to find out what a straw poll is.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> here who
really knows how to give a rousing speech. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> loved him, though few would
ever vote for him. Memorable line: "If I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, I'm the chief law
enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, right? ... The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thing I'd do is
turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and say you have the right to remain silent."
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer Soft-spoken</ENAMEX> but effective. His
tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> to its feet. The best of social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. "Campaigns aren't supposed to be about how much one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> has
raised and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> has inherited. Campaigns are supposed to be about our
futures."
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> Much less impressive in an
arena setting. His lines were elegant (who writes them?) but he made no real
connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> is not found in
our wallets. It is found in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>."
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX> Ever competent, never
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thrilling</ENAMEX>. "We need a contest because this is not a horse race. This is not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game. This is the biggest job in the world."
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle Emphasis</ENAMEX> on family values. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton-Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> started off as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Woodstock of 1969</ENAMEX> ... It ended
up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, trashing our values, trashing our ideas and
trashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> which is not theirs to trash."
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole Miss Perfect Platitude</ENAMEX>. Her
speech takes the daring position that telling the truth is good. "Integrity
never goes out of style. It never goes out of style."
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX> Despite his rhetorical gifts,
the weakest of the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>. The consensus is that he's lost his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marbles</ENAMEX>--his microphone was cut off when he didn't stop at the end of his
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">allotted ten minutes</TIMEX>. "We are coming to the end of the most disgraceful and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immoral</ENAMEX> presidency in the history of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orrin Hatch Senate</ENAMEX> oratory doesn't carry
across a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. He sounds hoarse and is barely audible. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> ... climbed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> foot <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Ranier</ENAMEX>, right to the top. He carried <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">65 pounds</NUMEX> of gear on his
back. If he thought that was heavy, wait until he campaigns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> carrying
a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">230-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on his back."
               

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes Fiasco</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> starts with
terrifying indoor fireworks and a release of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of balloons. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX>
of opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> pop them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half</TIMEX> of his speech, making it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inaudible</ENAMEX>. Lesson: Next time, release balloons at the end. "The power of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> won't be tamed, bent or broken by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who relies on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> and tutors to tell him what to think. Only an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>
can break the selfish grip that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has on our national life."
               

            

         
      
   
