
   
   
      
         
            What's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrong With the Neighbors</ENAMEX>?

            Your next-door <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> just shot up a school/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>/day-care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. Any
comment?

            
               "I thought he was pretty nice ... But then again, I knew that his
beliefs were way out of line. They were good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, but, well, I got blue
eyes, so I guess that helps."
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meda VanDyke</ENAMEX> on her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>, neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> Buford
Furrow
               
            

            
               "He used to say, 'They're watching me, through your satellite
dish.' I'd tell him, 'No, no, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rusty</ENAMEX>, no, they aren't watching you.' I tried to
convince him, but it made no difference ... He was just a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> when he
didn't have this problem. Everybody said, 'He's harmless.' "
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Moore</ENAMEX>, on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> Russell
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weston</ENAMEX>
               
            

            
               "We figured they would have questioned him and let him go and
eventually we forgot about it."
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta</ENAMEX> mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Barton</ENAMEX>, on the
murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> several years
earlier
               
            

            Pretty nice? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harmless</ENAMEX>? Forgot about it? Why, oh why, do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> feel
this compulsion to brush aside the dark side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> next door? If you
just found out that nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> you saw trimming his lawn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> just mowed
down some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, your first reaction would not be to relive the sweet memory
of a friendly hello. Yet in that mass-murder ritual known as knocking on doors,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> never seem to get the gory quote. Instead, the next-door
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> go on the record with comments that are naïve, foolish, and odd.

            It may be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> are simply following the script. Thanks to
television news culture, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> have undoubtedly memorized what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> are supposed to say, (nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, kept to himself) and dredge that from
the subconscious once they hear the knock.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, for example, told reporters: "He was shy, a
little withdrawn. But not real bizarre," and that, "he never bothered anyone."
(Anyone? What about all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he killed?) According to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Columbine killer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Harris</ENAMEX> was "a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. Shy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, didn't say much" and
"a very nice, polite, clean-cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furrow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> called him, "a very
pleasant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> saw him as "a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," "a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>" who "kept to himself."

            The most generous explanation is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> are demonstrating a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warmhearted American</ENAMEX> optimism. They want to believe the best about the members
of their imagined community. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> knew he was suspected of
savagely murdering his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, but they blocked that out. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furrow</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> knew that he was a neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aryan Nations</ENAMEX>, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife-beater</ENAMEX>, but they still considered him a "nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonesboro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Golden</ENAMEX> wrote off the threats he made to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>,
the shots he fired at their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, and the punches he threw at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> as just
youthful high-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spirits</ENAMEX>: After all, "He was a quick-to-wave, friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>' comments may also represent a kind of cover-your-ass legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">defensiveness</ENAMEX>. No one wants to be blamed for not reporting a mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>. So
even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> are as peculiar as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furrow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmer</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> make a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Herculean</ENAMEX> effort to present their homicidal acquaintance as
banal. Then they won't seem like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> for not noticing his villainy.

            This reached new and astonishing heights with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vernell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pamela</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bass</ENAMEX> lived in next door to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmer</ENAMEX>. As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reported, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Both Vernell</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> often. He always kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> [and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">closets</ENAMEX>] locked. He had a video camera attached to the ceiling, which recorded
every move. Otherwise there was nothing strange, they said." There wasn't? They
also noticed the stench of rotting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and they "heard
sounds of sawing from his apartment day and night." Downstairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whiteheard</ENAMEX> said, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, I heard what sounded like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> ... He was crying
like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had just walloped him. I heard a big falling sound ... like he
was being hurt." Yet even after admitting all this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> insisted
there was nothing odd about him, that he joined in neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">barbecues</ENAMEX>, that
he was "like the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabomber</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaczynski</ENAMEX> was hardly odd enough to worry
them: "We've got other ones around here that act a lot farther out than he ever
was."

            But don't blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> too much. Their trite comments say a lot more
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> neighborliness than they do about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> themselves. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> to flesh out the characters
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>, but what, really, do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> know? Ask yourself: What could you
say about your closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>?

            Some may blame neighborly ignorance on soulless, anomic suburbs, and indeed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Klebold</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> were ciphers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> across the lawn. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmer</ENAMEX> was a mystery to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in his downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment building</ENAMEX>, and
Kaczynski was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enigma</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            No, the ignorance stems more from the very nature of neighborliness.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neighbors</ENAMEX> attribute decency to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> next door because the standard of
behavior required for being a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> is so extremely low. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> managed
to wave hello from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmer</ENAMEX> went a few times to apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cookouts</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furrow</ENAMEX> once helped someone park a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. Almost anyone, even the most sociopathic
of sociopaths, can get through the occasional interaction like that without
seeming malevolent.

            Of course, not everyone fails to understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> in their midst.
Those who genuinely knew <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mass murderers</ENAMEX> have supplied the insight the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neighbors</ENAMEX> missed. Even as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood were remembering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden</ENAMEX> as "a beautiful young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who played with him were
describing his viciousness and rage. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> and Klebold
smiled on them as clean-cut polite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and assumed they were shattering glass
for "some kind of art project," their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolmates</ENAMEX> knew they were into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazism</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">idolized Hitler</ENAMEX>, and played with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. They were rightly scared of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klebold</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris</ENAMEX>: "They're really really creepy."

            Why did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> see what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> didn't? Because you can fake
your way through a neighborly hello, but you can't fake your way through
life.

            
               
                  --This piece was written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanna Rosin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>.
               
            

         
      
   
