
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hypocrisy</ENAMEX>; the Punditocracy
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN</ENAMEX>:

            You lost me on your techno explanation, but my thanks for trying. In your
opinion, what exactly is the "counterculture" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? If it's Fatboy
Slim, and the others, and confined to that, I don't see the counterculture.
Where does <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> stand on politics, for example? Besides the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> breakthrough, what's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s equivalent of the sexual
revolution, the feminist movement, etc.? Besides the tattoos and piercings,
which are pretty standard, I don't see much that separates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s 25-year-old
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-year-old</TIMEX>. Please inform me, with a touch less of Greil
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX>.

            I love e-mail too. It's so much more convenient than the phone, when you're
not sure if someone's in and you trade voice mail. Also, in reporting, if your
subject is willing, you can reproduce exactly what they've said, on
record, so there's no dispute on misquotes. Although when I was sifting through
some storage at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moishe's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island City</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, I came across a trunk
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and high-school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. It's a cliche, but
when was the last time you got a real letter? I know I never write them
anymore. They're relics now, and will make for fascinating reading in future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>.

            On Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> there's a priceless photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saratoga</ENAMEX>. He's wearing shades, with a too-wide tie, grinning, with
a flack by his side, looking for all the world like a don out of the opening
scene in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Godfather II</ENAMEX> , when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Corleone</ENAMEX> coughs up some dough for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> and then has that immortal conversation with the shady
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>.

            I don't agree with your point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> himself is messing up his
campaign. Yes, he's made a lot of dumb moves and gaffes and is spending money
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>. And hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter Eskew</ENAMEX> was positively Clintonian: After
moving all those union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> to tears with his speech about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX>, it was an unbelievably hypocritical hire. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> clearly doesn't want
to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and he's done his best to (I'm being charitable here)
subconsciously sabotage his loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>'s campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> herself is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fucking</ENAMEX> (figuratively, I assume) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, too. She'd be a far better asset being
on the stump for him and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, rather than sucking up money,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> attention, and organizational skills for herself. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> who was
responsible for re-electing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>; a plus for you, I'm sure,
a nightmare for me.

            I love your idea of combining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsleys</ENAMEX> of the world into one
awful outlet for conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> wisdom. It would save so much time. An
example is here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>-leaning of
course, predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Lazio</ENAMEX> would run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, thus bloodying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> for
his slugfest with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. That was stupid thinking. I don't care about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato/Pataki</ENAMEX> feud with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>; there was simply no way they'd resist the
pressure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to unite behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>. With a united
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is going to actually have to spend time in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> (same in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>) instead of thinking of it as a gimme <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            I read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>' column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, and as usual he had
some good points. He wrote that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is lucky to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> as his chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>, because the publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">scion</ENAMEX> is too dorky to win, an assessment I
agree with, although I'm a fan of his economic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> (although his pandering
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> is just shameless). The problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is that you can't
believe a word he says.

            I also read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> will unveil a new design <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Forst</ENAMEX> was smart, he'd unveil new content as well. But I'll get to
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. I'll be curious about your Voice nostalgia. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more
question: What are your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>? I'm sure you'll be horrified,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> .

            Best,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RUSS</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
