
   
   
      
         
             I, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antichrist</ENAMEX>?

            Early one shiny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">autumn</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, I got in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and
drove to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynchburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, in order to find out whether or not I am the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>. You know: the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beast, the Worthless Shepherd</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Little Horn</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abomination</ENAMEX>, the linchpin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diabolical Trinity</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>.

            I had my suspicions. Nowhere on my body could I
find the mark of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Beast--666</ENAMEX>--but I do have a freckle that's shaped like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX>. And though I have never been seized by a desire to lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">armies</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> in a final, bloody confrontation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of God on the plain of
Armageddon, I do suffer from aggravated dyspepsia, as well as chronic malaise,
conditions that I'm sure afflict the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>.

            The surest suspicion I
had about my pivotal role in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> eschatology grew from the fact that I am
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>, and alive. These are the qualifications for the job of Antichrist
as specified by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lynchburg</ENAMEX>'s most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>, in a speech he
made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>.

            I was actually going to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> on a different
matter, the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, but I thought I might just slip this
question--the one about me maybe being the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>--into the stream of the
interview. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>, I guessed, wouldn't be happy to discuss his views on the
identity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>--he had apologized for the remark but took quite a
load of grief for it anyway.

            As it turned out, though,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> was eager to talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>. And, as it also turned out, he
didn't really feel bad for saying what he said. In fact, he was more convinced
than ever that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> who walks among us.

            Let me pause for a moment to give <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> concise reasons why
I'm so curious about the identity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) I think I speak for all the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 4.5</NUMEX>
million adult male <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in the world when I say that we get a little antsy when
Christians start looking at us like we're the devil. This is on account of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> behavior over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 2,000 years</TIMEX>, by which I mean blood libels and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pogroms</ENAMEX> and inquisitions, those sorts of things.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) I've always been possessed by the delusional
notion that I am to play a major role in world history, so why not a role in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of Days</ENAMEX>? And I don't mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> movie.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Now that we stand on
the lip of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the millennium</TIMEX>, much of the evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> world is in the
grip of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Armageddon fever</ENAMEX>, and, according to the evangelical interpretation of
the books of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Revelation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will make his appearance
before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> makes his, and his is looking kinda imminent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>, in
this reading, will be a world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who strikes a peace deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, only
to betray the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and make war on it, until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> comes to the rescue.
The thankful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, those who are still alive, will then become <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and
live happily ever after. These beliefs, held by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>
are, journalistically speaking, worthy of note.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> before my visit with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>, I had just
finished reading a novelistic treatment of these events, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assassins</ENAMEX> ,
which is subtitled Assignment: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assassins</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> book in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Left Behind</ENAMEX>" series, "left behind"
referring to those unfortunate nonevangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> who are not taken up
to heaven in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapture</ENAMEX>--the opening act in God's end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> plan--and are
forced to contend with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>'s evil reign on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Left Behind</ENAMEX>"
series, co-written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim LaHaye</ENAMEX>, the prominent right-wing screwball and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly LaHaye</ENAMEX>, the even more prominent right-wing screwball, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry B. Jenkins</ENAMEX>, who, his biography <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX> books, which
is a lot of books for one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to write, is a phenomenon. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten million</NUMEX> copies of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX> have sold already--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> in my local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PriceClub</ENAMEX> alone. "Left
Behind" is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> set.

            The notable thing for me
about the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Left Behind</ENAMEX>" series--beside the fact that few in the secular media
have noticed that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are busy reading books warning about
the imminence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, mass death, and the return of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messiah</ENAMEX>, is that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaHaye</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX>
are both active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the absurd and feverish campaign by some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">evangelical Christians</ENAMEX> to redefine Judaism in a way that allows for belief in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> (and again, I feel comfortable speaking for all of us
here) find this sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> imperialism just a wee bit offensive. Just
imagine if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> began an official campaign calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muhammad</ENAMEX> irrelevant to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX>--can you imagine the fatwas that would produce?

            But evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, who are, in my experience,
uniformly kind and generous in their personal relations, can also be terribly
obnoxious in their relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

            There is only one road
to salvation for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and that road runs through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaHaye</ENAMEX> told me. To his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX>, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaHaye</ENAMEX> doesn't believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. He
will be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> gentile, who will kill lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> will be
forced to accept the idolatry of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> or be beheaded," he said. This
will take place during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribulation</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> suffering, though, is divinely ordained. Even though
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will not be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are still capable of great evil and
have often been punished for their evil, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaHaye</ENAMEX> explained. "Some of the
greatest evil in the history of the world was concocted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> mind,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaHaye</ENAMEX> told me, for reasons that aren't entirely clear--he knew what the name
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>" generally signifies. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigmund Freud</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>, these were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> minds
that were infected with atheism."

            I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaHaye</ENAMEX> to tell me more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
mind.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> brain also has the capacity for great
good," he explained. "God gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> great intelligence. He didn't give them
great size or physical power--you don't see too many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>--but he
gave them great minds."

            Of all the evangelical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> I have interviewed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaHaye</ENAMEX> is capable of some of the most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">utterances</ENAMEX>, which is troublesome, because he is also the most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> in
the evangelical world.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> is smoother than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaHaye</ENAMEX>. He acknowledges
"where the sensitivity comes from," though he shows no understanding of the
role the myth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> played in the history of anti-Semitism, and he
refuses to back away from his opinion that somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Neck</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West L.A.</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shaker Heights</ENAMEX> is living <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.

            "In my opinion," he told me, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will
be a counterfeit of the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, which means that he will be male and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was male and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>."

            I asked him if he understood that such statements
strip <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of their humanity, which is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Semites</ENAMEX> take before
they kill them. He responded, "All the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we do business with on a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis, not one has ever got upset over this." It is not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> who picked
this most recent fight, he said, it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX> made the
same statement <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, but there was no comment about that,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> said. "But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Graham</ENAMEX> was not calling for the resignation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>, you'll recall, is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s; he has even peddled
a video accusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of murder.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> is right: <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Evangelical preachers</ENAMEX> are constantly
accusing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of harboring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>.

            I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> if he knew the actual identity of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>. No, he said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> might say, it's a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>, like that, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> does not let us know that."

            So there's a chance, then, that I'm the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> chuckled a condescending chuckle. "It's
almost amusing, that question. Of course not. I know that you're not."

            Why?

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will be a world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, he'll have
supernatural powers," he said.

            He got me there--I have no supernatural powers. I
can't even drive a stick shift.

            I pressed him further on
the identity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> wouldn't play. "We'll know the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> when he arrives," he said.

            Most evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, in fact, refuse to publicly guess
the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>--though, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX> suggests, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> is a
perennial favorite, at least among those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelicals</ENAMEX> who believe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>. For most of their history, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> had
been content to ascribe the characteristics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as a whole. "Ever since the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> nd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CE</ENAMEX>, the very
beginning of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Antichrist</ENAMEX> legend, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> have associated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> with
everything unholy," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Gow</ENAMEX>, who teaches <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> history at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alberta</ENAMEX>, told me. In the minds of early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>; God's covenant with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> was obsolete. Therefore, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
who remained on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> were there to serve devilish purposes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gow</ENAMEX> explained.

            There are plenty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelical thinkers</ENAMEX> who differ with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>, who believe, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaHaye</ENAMEX>, that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will be a gentile who rises out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is
supposed to make a peace treaty with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Hindson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of Is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Antichrist Alive and Well</ENAMEX>? , explained. "Why would a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> make a peace
treaty with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>?"

            Hindson suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> will make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>--the revived <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Empire</ENAMEX>, eternal enemy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>--though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindson</ENAMEX> disputed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> popular idea advocated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monte Judah</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>-based prophecy-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>.

            "There's no way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindson</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Satan</ENAMEX> can do better than that."

            In his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindson</ENAMEX> runs through a list of
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is there, of course, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Wilson Reagan</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> letters in each of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> names. Get
it?).

            Of course, none of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are gay.

            "It says in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> will have 'no regard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,' and so many evangelicals
interpret that to mean that he will be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hindson</ENAMEX> said, though he
added that he's not entirely convinced.

            This idea--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> as gay--strikes a chord with many
evangelicals, just as the idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> strikes a
chord.

            I gradually came to see how far-fetched it was to
think that I might be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>. I'm not gay, I'm not famous, I wouldn't
know a euro if I found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in my wallet.

            Then it struck me: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Diller</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX>.

            There's no way to know for sure. But if you wake up
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> to read that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Diller</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> (and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX> is his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy</ENAMEX>), well, remember where you read it first.

         
      
   
