
   
   
      
         
            Febreze, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Take Me Away</ENAMEX>!

            
               
                  Please
send your questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to prudence@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.
               
            

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               Why do advice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> speak of themselves in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>? There is an air of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>-ism about the whole thing. Should I, in polite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, be referring to
myself the same way?
            

            
               --Please sign
me,
            

            

               All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doled Out</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear All,

            There is no protocol
mandating the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for advice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> does so because it
feels comfortable, and she has tired of the "I" word. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> agrees with you,
though, about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> thing ... so if you run for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, by all means use
the first-person pronoun so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't make fun of you. As for polite
company (the only kind to be in) follow the above suggestion, and speak as
though you were running for office.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-personally

            
               
                  Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I recently renovated a fabulous
condo <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX> in a historic downtown area. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> immediately below us has been
rented out as a live/work space to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> with a video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. Here's the
thing: They are both heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> and have managed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> to smell up
the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Recently the ashtray smell has begun to permeate our
apartment--I presume through the wooden floors.
            

            
               I am a nonsmoker and
allergic to cigarette smoke. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entreaties</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> have gone
nowhere. I am not an intolerant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, having grown up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, where
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s ceiling is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s floor. I am not an anti-smoking nut either,
just as long as I can stay away from it. What can I do? I don't feel it's
appropriate to try and dictate someone's behavior in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, but
the smell drives me nuts.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smokeless</ENAMEX> in Savannah
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Smoke</ENAMEX>,

            You do, indeed, have a problem. It sounds as though
you have purchased your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">loft</ENAMEX>, but the nicotine-addicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> is renting. And
you are correct that you cannot dictate private activities in someone else's
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, unless body parts are sailing by your window.

            Because you report that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is unwilling to support you, you have limited options. Short of
selling your fabulous renovated condo, you can stock up on neutral-smelling air
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freshener</ENAMEX> or make a plea to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> themselves. Prudie, by the way, is
sympathetic, because she has marveled that cigar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> can stink up the
outdoors . And just a little P.S., because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> senses you are in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of mind: In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> everywhere in the world, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s ceiling is
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s floor.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, odorously

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>,
               
            

            
               In reference to the
, etc., I am LEFT-handed and therefore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left-footed</ENAMEX>, but I don't think that
affects my ability to be honest. Really tired of the LEFT jokes, insults,
etc.
            

            

               --Sue
            

            Oh my, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has found
yet another way to be politically incorrect. How's this for making amends?
Prudie was not in her RIGHT mind when she wrote that answer. Feel better?

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, adroitly

            
               
                  Dear
Prudie,
               
            

            
               In your response to "" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks ago</TIMEX>, you
said that "Sometimes an inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--a young one--will be turned off
when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is too nice." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who is about my age, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, said the
same thing recently. She just isn't attracted to nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> but can't really
explain why.
            

            
               Being a much more
eloquent and mature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> yourself, do you think you could explain "Immature
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Woman Syndrome</ENAMEX>" to me so that I can understand the many wonderful, but immature
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> I know? Or, if you think it would be easier, you could just elope
with me so that I wouldn't have to face the thankless but highly entertaining
task of dealing with them.
            

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happily Confused</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Hap</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> thinks you have a darling sense of humor and
thanks you for the offer of marriage. As for your question, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> did not say
all young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are unresponsive to nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> ... just some. Proof of
this is the numerous older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who picked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who were nice and who
are still married! All you need to know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.Y.W.</ENAMEX> syndrome is that a
grounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--someone you would want--will not be looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who is
trouble or Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bad Behavior</ENAMEX>. The babes with radar for difficult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have the
idea that they can "fix" a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> or tame him. It gives them a feeling of power
and danger. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> has long felt, however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are not reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            You will be fine, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dear</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudie</ENAMEX> just knows it.

            
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, maturely

            

               
                  Pru,
               
            

            
               My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> has three
adorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>. I do not yet have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of
my own, so I visit my nieces as often as possible. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">occassion</TIMEX>, my oldest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">niece</ENAMEX> will  spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> with me. My problem is with how my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> treats
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>--she screams, "Shut up!" at them constantly and also hassles the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> about her weight. (She's a bit chunky, but not obese, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pete</ENAMEX>'s
sake.) Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> certainly never treated us this way, and it makes cringe to
think of what these comments might be doing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. Can I say something
to her? How?
            

            

               --mm
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear m,</ENAMEX>

            It sounds as though your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is overwhelmed by
the responsibilities and obligations of raising young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> ... and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>
can be a special strain, trust me. You don't say what your relationship is with
her, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX> suggests you arrange to have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and a chat, during which
you can tell her that you are aware of her short fuse with her adorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>,
you understand the many demands on her, and that there is help for the
situation. Pass on the name of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> like her: It is Parents
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anonymous</ENAMEX>, and it helps stressed out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who fear they might escalate from
yelling to actual physical abuse. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, so chances are good
she's near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Even the knowledge of such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> will reassure her that her
problem is by no means unique to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and that she's definitely not
alone.

            You might also point out
that harping at the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> about her weight is psychologically
counterproductive. Suggest that she choose the household food with nutrition in
mind so that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> cannot dive into a bag of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheetos</ENAMEX>. (Overeating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, however, can find ways of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">filching chocolate</ENAMEX>, etc., when they're out
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.) You could also say, more importantly, that some unhappiness may
be making the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> cling to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. Good luck in your mission to help your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nieces</ENAMEX>--and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>.

            --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudie</ENAMEX>, supportively

         
      
   
