
   
   
      
         
            Crash Course

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were killed in two workplace shootings. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> allegedly killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A day</TIMEX> later, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shipyard</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX> suspect has been
arrested, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter remains</ENAMEX> at large. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> has some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s strictest firearm regulations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>'s spin: See, gun laws
don't stop bullets. The gun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX>' spin: That's because the laws
aren't strict enough . Everyone else's spin: Who's next?

            

               A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was convicted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Shepard</ENAMEX> killing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron McKinney</ENAMEX> was sentenced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> life terms for second-degree murder. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> prohibited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> from using the "gay panic" defense, which
attributes violent acts to an unconscious reaction to homosexual advances.
Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>' spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s rejection of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-degree murder shows they
were sympathetic
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> . Gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>' spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s rejection of "gay panic"
means that hate crimes won't be excused .

            

               Weather is hampering the investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">EgyptAir</ENAMEX> crash.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> located Flight 990's "black boxes," but high winds will delay
recovery until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>. New radar data indicate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> did not fall
directly to the ocean, but dived and recovered, eventually breaking up at
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10,000 feet</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> cautioned that they had few clues to go on, but
early speculation focused on: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the thrust reverser flaw that downed a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
recent threats of terrorist attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) inconsistent
regulation of foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>' safety. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hager</ENAMEX> said the new radar evidence reduced the
likelihood that thrust reversers caused the accident.

            

               Feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> has been outed as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s
campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>, whose controversial work has focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as sex
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objects</ENAMEX>, has reportedly advised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) to speak from the heart; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) to dress
in more reassuring earth tones; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) to change his image from "beta male" to
"alpha male." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s spin: She's a "valued
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>" who helps him connect with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX>' spin: She's
a liability whose presence proves that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is no alpha male (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>). (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi Kantor</ENAMEX> asks, "How did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>
start out as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Friedan</ENAMEX> and end up as ?" But 
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> argues that the complaints about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> are .)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> transplanted hair from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to
another. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, who are married to each other, performed
the experiment on themselves. They took follicles from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and
grafted them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s forearm. She grew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> hairs and did not experience
immune-system rejection of the foreign tissue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> said the research
held promise for more successful organ
transplants and a cure for baldness .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is campaigning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>. After missing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> made numerous appearances and
delivered key policy speeches in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> retains his lead in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> has gained ground. The dismal spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> looks
less confident  and more desperate for votes. The rosy spin:
That's exactly the image he needs.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> participated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> to begin designing the "framework" for peace, which
they've agreed to complete by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>. A final pact is scheduled for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. The primary issues are: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the creation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">settlements</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the governance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
the status of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s spin: The peace process is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revitalized</ENAMEX> . The cautious spin: The tough part is
still ahead.

            
               A
federal judge ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> to restore funding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> had withdrawn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.2 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> opened its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensation</ENAMEX>" show, which included a depiction of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgin Mary</ENAMEX> adorned with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant dung</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> said it would appeal the
decision, which held that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s actions violated the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX>. The

                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
                reported that the exhibit had been
largely funded by those with financial interests in the artwork. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s
spin: They're using the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> to "put money
in the pockets of multimillionaires." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s spin: No, we're
using it to thwart censors like you .

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX> legend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Payton</ENAMEX> died at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> of complications from liver
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. He holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> rushing record (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">16,726 yards</NUMEX>). He was
remembered as one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>'s funniest and most generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, and his
nickname, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweetness</ENAMEX>, "was a tribute to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> more than his running
style" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bears</ENAMEX> Assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred O'Connor</ENAMEX>,
who believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payton</ENAMEX> was destined to be a legend from the outset, said, "God
must have taken a chisel and said, 'I'm going to make me a halfback.' "
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> ).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>
               he online auction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> may be a
fraud. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> have already dropped out, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who tried to place bids received no response. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietors</ENAMEX>'
explanation: We're inundated with responses and will be up and running shortly.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>' explanation: The site is a sham, intended only to drive
traffic to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s porn sites. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX> dissects the ethics of the
sale in ".")

         
      
   
