
   
   
      
         
            Obstacles to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-Voting</ENAMEX>

            

               This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part series about Internet voting. To read Part
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>, click .
            

            Every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> around this time, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> lament our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">low voter</ENAMEX> turnout rate--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44.9</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, putting us <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">138 th</NUMEX> in a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> voting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.
This explains the growing interest in Internet voting, which promises to do for
democracy what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> did for books. Aside from making voting vastly more
convenient, say its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, click 'n' pick elections could theoretically
eliminate fraud, allow instant recounts, and save pots of money.

            Buoyed
by these hopes, election <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have begun to take tentative
steps toward wired elections (many private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>--most notably
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>--already conduct internal elections online). State
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
are all examining online voting. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital</ENAMEX>
Democracy is collecting digital petitions for a ballot initiative that would
legalize Internet voting--though virtual signatures aren't legally valid, at
least not yet. Software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> eager to showcase their e-voting wares have
held mock online elections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, under
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> project run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Voting Assistance</ENAMEX>
Program, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> posted overseas will vote online. If the test
goes well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FVAP</ENAMEX> will consider eventually making online voting available for
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> living abroad.

            
E-voting isn't nearly as radical as it sounds, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> reasons. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, a
large and growing proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX>--already mail in their votes
via absentee ballot. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, the most aggressive remote-vote <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, has
abolished polling places entirely and now conducts elections exclusively by
mail. Local jurisdictions in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have conducted all-mail elections
too. While online elections would use fancier technology, they're based on the
same premise--that you can send polling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> a document that will serve
as your proxy.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, as pointed out in this space <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have already been
voting by computer for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Most polling places use one of three
computer-based technologies: punch cards, optical scans ,
or electronic
recording . (Less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fifth</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> uses old-fashioned
mechanical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lever</ENAMEX> machines , which aren't even being made anymore.) Most experts
expect the next generation of voting technology to be Internet-based. And once
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> start using Internet terminals at polling places, it's a short step to
using the same technology from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or work.

            But
for this to happen, software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> will have to devise voting systems that are
demonstrably secure. All of those currently being developed employ digital
signature technology--a cryptographic alternative to traditional signatures
that identifies a document's origin and verifies that it hasn't been altered
while being transmitted (click here for a primer). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> and insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> already use
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digital</ENAMEX> signatures to transfer large sums of money online.

            Here's
how it might work: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks</TIMEX> before the election, you visit your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>'s Web
site and print out a form declaring that you'd like to vote online. You sign it
and send it--via <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snail</ENAMEX> mail--to your local election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. The
authorities verify that your signature matches the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on your original
registration form at the county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> and also record the digital identity
of the computer from which you've downloaded the form. You're then sent a PIN
that will work only from that computer. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>, you log onto the site
using your PIN and check off your choices on a Web-based ballot. Once you're
done voting, your ballot is encrypted--transformed into an unintelligible
mathematical code using an elaborate algorithm--so that it can't be read during
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transmission</ENAMEX>. When it arrives, a central computer records both that your ballot
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> and the contents of the ballot, but in two separate places. Keeping
this information separate means that election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> can verify that you
voted without seeing how you voted. Another copy of the data is burned into a
CD as a backup.

            On an
individual level, the system is about as secure as an absentee ballot. Just as
you could sign an absentee ballot but let someone else fill it out, there's
little to stop you from allowing someone to vote with your computer and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PIN</ENAMEX>--or
to stop someone else from forcing you to turn yours over. But an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interloper</ENAMEX>
would have to obtain <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PINs</ENAMEX> and computers to influence any election.
And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> online voting may be far more secure than absentee voting. Software
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> hope eventually to use biometrics--voice and fingerprint
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX>--to check each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>'s identity.

            
Election <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are far more worried about mass cheating. Since regular
polling places are scattered in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of locations around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
large-scale fraud is almost impossible. But if a federal election was run from
a central server, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX> could flood it with activity or jam phone lines,
preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from logging on to vote. Software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> say they'll address
that problem by using multiple servers and telephone lines. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Voting Integrity</ENAMEX>
Project--a nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that monitors election soundness--calls
nationwide Internet voting "a large, non-moving, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> to potential vote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX>."

            Any
state that implements online voting may also have to contend with legal issues
of representation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Voting Rights Act</ENAMEX>, passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> to end discrimination
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, prohibits several (mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> from
making any change in voting procedures without federal approval. This clause
applies to even minor changes that could reduce minority participation. Given
the "digital divide" between well-wired white and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> on the one hand
and less technology-equipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latinos</ENAMEX> on the other, online elections
could be seen as an infringement on voting rights. (For more on Internet use
among different socio-economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Age</ENAMEX>: Falling
Through the Net .")

            But the most formidable
obstacle to online voting may be entrenched interests threatened by change. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>, vote-by-mail took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> to go from proposal to implementation
because of skepticism by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. "It's like campaign-finance
reform--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who control it are products of the system," says online
voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Strassman</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strassman</ENAMEX> is in charge of business
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development for Votation</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, an Internet voting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and is also the founder
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Democracy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ballot
initiative.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Keisling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> of
vote-by-mail, agrees, "The question behind closed doors is, 'Will this help our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>?' There's clearly a strain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who hope for low turnout."

         
      
   
