
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chechnya: The New Nightmare</ENAMEX>

            "More
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> slurry," the headline over an editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, neatly linked the scandal over what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX> feeds its <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> with
another mess that has forced the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Finance Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dominique Strauss-Kahn</ENAMEX>. The departure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strauss-Kahn</ENAMEX> amid corruption and
forgery allegations led the front pages of both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>
and was described by Die
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welt</ENAMEX> as a "disaster" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Socialist-led</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lionel Jospin</ENAMEX>.

            Many
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> agreed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial said, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firmament</ENAMEX> ... has abruptly darkened with sinister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">portents</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jospin</ENAMEX> "owes his
popularity in large part to his image as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M Propre</ENAMEX> , a decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX> a break with the permeating sleaze of the long <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitterrand</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>," it
said. "But the scandal in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M Strauss-Kahn</ENAMEX> is embroiled, the allegedly
illegal use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MNEF</ENAMEX>, a student health insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>, to channel illicit funds
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Party</ENAMEX> coffers, involves a host of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M Jospin</ENAMEX>'s close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX>.
... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> could be in for a period of weakened, indecisive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> . "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jospin</ENAMEX> would be weakened, but in an editorial congratulated
both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strauss-Kahn</ENAMEX> on his "panache" in resigning so quickly, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on their desire "that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> societies behave more and more like
Anglo-Saxon ones in demanding responsibility and probity from their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> said
in an editorial that with the departure of the euro-zone's most influential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>, it isn't clear who will provide leadership for the European
currency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bloc</ENAMEX>. In an op-ed piece, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> said that "abroad he was the
most important symbol of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jospin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s credibility and its
willingness to modernise the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> by reducing the overbearing role of the
public sector." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX> reported, with apparent
surprise, that the euro, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strauss-Kahn</ENAMEX> helped bring into being in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>,
has hardly moved on the foreign exchange markets. "Perhaps as a reflection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s relatively smaller economic role, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strauss-Kahn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX> appeared to
create little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> and have much less impact internationally than the
resignation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> for political reasons of his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German Social Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oskar Lafontaine</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> led mainly on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> described as an
"astonishing climbdown" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad Cow</ENAMEX> trade war with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. Despite a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> is as safe as
any in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, which has been accused of putting human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excrement</ENAMEX> in its cattle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX>, should lift its unilateral ban on it, the papers
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> yielded to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> demands for further safety checks. The
Independent
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, however, fronted a gruesome eyewitness report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ingushetia</ENAMEX>, a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> bordering
Chechnya, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 193,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chechen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> are believed to have fled.
Describing the terrible injuries inflicted on some of them by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s "massive
and indiscriminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">artillery</ENAMEX> and air bombardment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>" in
Chechnya, its correspondent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Cockburn</ENAMEX>, wrote that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one third</NUMEX> of the
Chechen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, numbering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, is now in flight. "What
is happening is a tragedy equal to anything witnessed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>
earlier in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>," he claimed.

            In an
editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> called the near-silence of Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> on the matter shameful. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
'expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>,' diplo-speak for doing as little as possible," it said.
"This do-nothing policy is lethal. Here, unlike the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>,
military intervention is neither necessary nor practicable. Tough diplomacy and
economic threats are, however, essential if the lunacy is to be reversed."

            In a
bitter editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moscow Times</ENAMEX> compared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s behavior in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, in which each argued vainly to the other that there could be
no military solution. "Now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> is de facto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partitioned</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> won't let
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian KFOR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> take up their positions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> is as mighty as
ever, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX> has yet to disarm; while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is weeding
out terrorism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chechnya</ENAMEX> by herding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> under carpet bombing," it said.
"And wherever <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> looks, there is the illusion of victory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> play the role of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s grave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statesmen</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> sacrifice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> to the
greater good. But the horrors are not exorcised, only deferred to future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">administrations</ENAMEX>."

            After
the controversy surrounding his visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> had a very easy week in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, where the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq al-Awsat</ENAMEX> even congratulated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> on its resistance to political
reform. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abderrahman al-Rashed</ENAMEX>, wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> column
that "fortunately for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>--and for the rest of us--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> did not go the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX> collapsed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>. It
did not take a sudden lurch to the right, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> did to their peril."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asharq al-Awsat</ENAMEX> was euphoric about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> as a potential market for its
oil and as "an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' paradise" of which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> wanted a part. The
paper also talked up the "spiritual" side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> relationship:
"Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> faith, and the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pilgrims</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> holy sites is set to increase, thus helping to further common
understanding between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX>'s most famous
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, came out firmly for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> in an interview
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> . He said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> would
suffer a "loss of self-respect" if it decided to retain the monarchy in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s referendum. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> monarchy has become irrelevant to this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX>," he said. "It's not just a question of the monarchy,
it's a question of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> has any self-confidence." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>, who is
now an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard</ENAMEX> for
opposing a republic and said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> was generally too "timid" in his reforms.
"I know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> is conservative and has resisted change, but the
radical policies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> brought in are now bearing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>," he
said. "Those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>] are leading the
world in gains in productivity and a higher living standard."

         
      
   
