
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia Bows</ENAMEX> to the Queen

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, which were mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">pro-republican</ENAMEX> in the campaign to
abolish the monarchy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, reacted huffily to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monarchists</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX>
percent to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX> victory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s referendum. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> bows to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Majesty</ENAMEX>" was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning Herald</ENAMEX> 's
contemptuous headline <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s prediction
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that rejection of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> in the referendum would provoke a
political backlash against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s monarchist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>, who had skillfully divided the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">pro-republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Howard</ENAMEX>
should reflect on his place in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> history," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syndey Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> said in an editorial. "He must know that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s referendum
settled nothing." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> warned that because <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> want
a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>, the debate will continue. "But it will remain confused, bitter and
divisive until another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> steps forward to bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> together. …
The deep division between direct-election and parliamentary-election
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republicans</ENAMEX> which Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> and the monarchists exploited in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s
election will not continue."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> , which also supports a republic, summed up the divisiveness
of the referendum, in which the monarchy's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> came mainly from
lower-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Queen</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> said the referendum has also widened divisions within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>'s
government and generated "serious fears for its chances at the next election."
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth II</ENAMEX> marked her triumph <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> by presenting
the rugby <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> championship trophy to the staunchly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Eales</ENAMEX>, after its win against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, there was talk
of subjecting the monarchy to a referendum by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> as well.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mass-circulation Sun</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> paper, claimed in a front-page splash that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> throne, is eager to have such a
referendum, believing the monarchy would prevail. But in an editorial, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> came close to advocating a republic for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, too. "We doubt
that, eventually, a monarchy can exist as part of a democracy," it said.
"Anyone who has spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has experienced
at first hand what it is like to be in a TRULY free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. … There is no us
and them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. … <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Great families</ENAMEX> come and go--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefellers</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearsts</ENAMEX>. ...We see this even now as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' gigantic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> looks threatened by his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> noted
in an editorial that "democracy seems to like monarchy" and that the queen "is,
more than ever, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the antipodean state not by grace of God but thanks to
a popular vote." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> sounded a similar note. "The tempering of the
hereditary principle by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> has produced a curious constitutional
hybrid," it said in an editorial. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> we now have elected hereditary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> they have what is, in effect, an elected hereditary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monarch</ENAMEX>. ... Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> is not in favour of the
hereditary principle, but if it happens to coincide with the popular will, then
who can argue with it?"

            Judge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>'s finding in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antitrust case was a huge
story around the world both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, leading the front pages of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Die Welt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> , which also devoted an editorial and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
inside pages to it. In its editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FT</ENAMEX> praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> for his
"sophisticated grasp of the workings of the computer industry" and said he had
successfully demolished most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>' arguments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates "</ENAMEX>must know that
the chances of a drastic remedy--such as the breakup of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> he founded
are no longer negligible," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said. "Though this would probably not be
the best outcome, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s findings demonstrate that, if it were to happen,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> would only have itself to blame."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> in an editorial said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> would be remembered in history for
recalling "a basic principle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> system, one of the principles
which assure the vitality and dynamism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> economy: the
struggle against monopoly situations and respect for competition." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in
effect told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, "You may represent the industry of the future, but you are
no less a monopolist than those who came into being at the beginning of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>." An editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX>, however, was more sympathetic to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>.
It said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> has made his fortune primarily through his own ingenuity and that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> antitrust law should not be used solely to rein in large and
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and keep more complacent alternatives in business." The paper
added, "The fundamental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> must be whether or not it is actually true that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> can command this market in a fashion that will frustrate
innovation."

            

               Libération of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, which led its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Setback for the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Master</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universe</ENAMEX>," said that it was "the Internet, more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, that is making his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> tremble." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, in an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furio Colombo</ENAMEX>, said that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, who with his
image and his self-promotion has become a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao Zedong</ENAMEX> of the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>, evidently considers that there is no difference between the good
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and the good of all." The case against him began when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> became convinced that the interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> "had been violated,
and therefore humiliated, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conquering</ENAMEX> ride of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and by the
personality cult of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> from the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orissa</ENAMEX> that receding
waters after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s cyclone disaster have revealed mounds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> in
almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX>. It said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> believe that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have died in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> alone, compared to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">765</NUMEX> deaths in the entire
region. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> complained in an editorial
that "the corrosive tawdriness of political populism" was delaying relief
efforts, with government and opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> arguing about money and
whether there should be a formal declaration of a national calamity. In the
state of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andhra Pradesh</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deccan Chronicle</ENAMEX> had as its front-page lead
a report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> claiming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would only send
further help to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orissa</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> asked for it. "This stance has created ripples
of outrage among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> and pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressmen</ENAMEX> here who interpret these
signals as being a clear indicator from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> must hold out a
begging bowl to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>," it said. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> complained
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orissa</ENAMEX> was "but a drop in the ocean" compared to the
"astronomical" amounts it sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> following the earthquake there.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> daily
Dawn put a positive spin
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s failure to name the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s new military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. "General
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pevez Musharraf</ENAMEX> has suddenly become an overnight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> and a 'yardstick' of
general knowledge for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and may well become the factor to decide who
will be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,"  began a front-page
report from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Musharraf</ENAMEX> quiz craze, as many are
calling it, has stormed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> with everyone asking everyone else: 'Who is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>?' If you don't know the answer, you are considered dumb,
like presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>. … His flunking of the pop quiz test is
snowballing into a major political threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> as their top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, who has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>, appears increasingly like a dumb
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duffer</ENAMEX> who cannot make out whether a 'military coup' is a good thing or
bad."

         
      
   
