
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Breach</ENAMEX>

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> for selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> urged
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> to stop delivery of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX> airborne radar system that may be
based on advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> technology. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> has reportedly sold <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 billion</NUMEX> in military equipment to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 20 years</TIMEX>. The nervous
spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> may have obtained our most valuable secrets . The relaxed spin: They still don't
have the technology to make those secrets useful . The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> spin: If this
was such a problem, what took you so long to complain ?

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> will bar non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> from using their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATMs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells Fargo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>,
adopted the policy in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s ban on ATM surcharges. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> are
suing to block a similar law in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX>' spin: We need the fees to
maintain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATMs</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX>' spin: You need the fees to
pad your wallets . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX>' counterspin: Either way, pricing
decisions should be left up to us.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> rated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> unfit for battle. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divisions</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, reportedly have insufficient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>, and training for a "major regional war." The evaluations, based on
new, stricter standards, resulted in the lowest ratings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> said the findings proved that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">underfunds</ENAMEX> and overextends <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. Skeptics
countered that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> underrated itself in order to get more money.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UnitedHealth Group</ENAMEX> will stop pre-screening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' medical
decisions. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> would no
longer need prior authorization for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> admissions, tests, or minor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surgeries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will monitor and issue "report cards" on individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>' cost-quality performance. Consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> said the change was: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
an admission that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> make better decisions than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> must compete on quality, not just price. The industry
countered that the move will: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) save the company money ; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) reduce
momentum for political reforms of health care.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> won the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of its antitrust suit against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. In his "findings of fact," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>
ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is a monopoly, has abused its monopoly power, and has
harmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> said the opinion was such a slam-dunk for the
government that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> couldn't spin it. Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> dismissed the
ruling as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round of a long fight. (
                  Slate
               's
"" explains how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> are spinning the decision to maximize the
damage; and "" tells what was the real surprise of the trial.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> are protesting the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dogma</ENAMEX> . The film
features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX> as fallen angels who attempt to re-enter
heaven using a loophole in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> doctrine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> dropped the comedy last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> because of the controversy, but it was picked up by an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distributor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>' spin: It's blasphemous "hate mail" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX>'s spin: It's a comic ode to religious faith. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>'
spin: In either case, it's a great film. (
                  Slate
               's "" assesses
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>' reactions and read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edestein</ENAMEX>'s review .)

            

               A "black box" from EgyptAir Flight 990 was recovered
               .
Information from the flight data recorder shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s fall began as
a "controlled descent" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> still in command. The new data
eliminate the possibility that a faulty thrust
reverser induced the crash, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> say that they must recover the
cockpit voice recorder to determine the cause. They continue to consider as
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">possibilities: 1</ENAMEX>) hijacking; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) bombing; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cabin depressurization</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
mechanical failure.

            
               The
"Bubbleboy" e-mail virus is spreading. The virus--which places
Seinfeld references on a computer's hard drive--is able to infect
machines without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> opening an e-mailed attachment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Users</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Express</ENAMEX> can get it simply by highlighting the message's subject line.
The optimistic spin: The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> is "more playful than destructive ." The pessimistic spin: Now
"simply reading e-mails can be dangerous ."

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> is resigning.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frenchman Michel Camdessus</ENAMEX> will step down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX> as head of
the multinational lending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> charged with ensuring global economic
stability. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> has been criticized for its role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic
crisis and the bailout of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX>' spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camdessus</ENAMEX> was
too liberal in disbursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX>' spin:
Camdessus was too strict  in forcing economic austerity. Camdessus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boosters</ENAMEX>'
spin: Criticism from both sides means he did his job just right.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> celebrated the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> anniversary of the fall of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Gorbachev</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>
participated in the commemoration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called it "one of
history's most remarkable triumphs of human freedom." Some former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Germans</ENAMEX>,
however, complained of ongoing economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inequities</ENAMEX> and the "wall in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>" that still divides the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> observed that despite unification's difficulties,
"few wish to go back."

         
      
   
