
   
   
      
         
             Fight Clubbed

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> , a movie about a fictional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who strip down and beat each other to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pulp</ENAMEX>, has provoked
more than its share of media hand-wringing, particularly diatribes about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s infatuation with violence and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Faludi</ENAMEX>-esque ruminations about the
emasculated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fight Club</ENAMEX> , however, has not sparked an
iota of interest in a real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who strip down and beat each
other to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pulp</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ultimate Fighting Championship</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>'s flameout from national
sensation to total irrelevance is a tragedy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> sports, a cautionary
tale of prudishness, heavy-handed politics, and cultural myopia.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> as a
locker-room fantasy. What would happen if a kickboxer fought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX>? A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">karate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> fought a sumo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Promoters</ENAMEX> built an octagonal chain-link
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cage</ENAMEX>, invited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> top martial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, and set them loose in no-holds-barred,
bare-knuckles fights. "There are no rules!" bragged an early press release.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contestants</ENAMEX> would fight till "knockout, submission, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s intervention, or
death." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> allowed, even promoted, all notions of bad sportsmanship: kicking a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> when he's down, hitting him in the groin, choking. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX><NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-hundred-pound</NUMEX> men
were sent into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Octagon</ENAMEX> to maul <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> half their size. Only biting and
eye-gouging were forbidden.

            The gimmick entranced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>). What
happens when a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">620-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sumo champion</ENAMEX> fights a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200-pound</NUMEX> kickboxer? Answer:
The kickboxer knocks him silly in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">35 seconds</TIMEX>. They tuned in for bloodshed--"the
damage," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> like to call it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> fights could be horrifying. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tank Abbott</ENAMEX>,
an ill-tempered, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">270-pound</NUMEX> street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>, knocks out hapless opponent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matua</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 seconds</TIMEX>. Then, before the ref can intervene, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX> belts the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unconscious Matua</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, sending him into a fit, limbs quivering
uncontrollably, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood spurting</ENAMEX> from his mouth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX>, naturally, became a cult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and won a guest spot on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matua</ENAMEX> walked out of the ring.)
Soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> was selling out huge <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">arenas</ENAMEX> and drawing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> pay-per-view
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> for its quarterly competitions.

            But a subtle sport was
emerging from the gimmicks and carnage. My passion for ultimate fighting (which
is also called "extreme" or "no-holds-barred" fighting) began when I saw the
finals of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Royce Gracie</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">180-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> jujitsu <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX>, was
matched against a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">275-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Severn</ENAMEX>, one of the top heavyweight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestlers</ENAMEX> in the world and a national champion many times over. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Severn</ENAMEX> had grabbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gracie</ENAMEX>, flung him to the canvas, and mounted him. For the
next <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Severn</ENAMEX> pummeled and elbowed and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-butted the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gracie</ENAMEX>'s face grew drawn, and he squirmed wildly to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Severn</ENAMEX>'s bombardment.
Then, all of sudden, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gracie</ENAMEX>, still lying on his back, saw an opening, wrapped
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and legs around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Severn</ENAMEX> like a python and choked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> into
submission.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>'s caged matches revolutionized the idea of fighting.
Nursed on <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> imagine fights as choreography, a
dance of elegant combinations, roundhouse kicks, clean knockouts. The UFC
punctured this. Boxers floundered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> in striking martial arts such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">karate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tae kwon</ENAMEX> do, who fancied themselves the world's greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>,
found themselves pretzeled by jujitsu <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>, who pulled them to the ground
and slowly choked or leg-locked them. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> immediately debunked a lot of myths
of fighting, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX>, karate, kung fu. It showed the reality of what works in
an actual fight," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Meltzer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wrestling Observer</ENAMEX> .

            Instead of being
carnivals of gore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> fights looked strangely like ... sex. Almost all fights
ended on the ground, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> mounting the other in missionary position, the
pair of them wiggling mysteriously along the canvas for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>, even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. There were few spectacular knockouts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX>--yes, there was
always a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX>--stopped many bouts, and in most others, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>
"tapped out," surrendering to mild-looking but agonizing chokes and joint
locks. It was not barbarism. It was science.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> spawned a new breed of "mixed martial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>."
World-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestlers</ENAMEX> learned to kickbox. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champion</ENAMEX> kickboxers learned to
grapple. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">karate experts</ENAMEX> learned to stay home.) They became, without doubt,
the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> in the world. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX>
wouldn't last <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX> in an ultimate fighting match. When <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> gold medal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wrestler Kevin Jackson</ENAMEX> came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>, a fighter named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Shamrock KO</ENAMEX>'d him
with a submission hold in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 seconds</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate</ENAMEX> fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> began sprouting
up all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, replacing the stylized gestures of the Eastern martial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arts</ENAMEX> with techniques that actually work.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> predicted
that it would supplant <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s martial art. Instead, it fell apart.
The collapse began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, saw a UFC tape.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, a lifelong boxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, was horrified at the ground fighting, kicks, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head butts</ENAMEX>. It was "barbaric," he said. It was "not a sport." He sent letters
to all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> asking them to ban ultimate fighting. The outcry against
"human cockfighting" became a crusade, and like many crusades, it was founded
on misunderstanding.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> fell victim to cultural determinism about what a fight
is. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, where no-holds-barred fighting has a
long history, it is popular and uncontroversial. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> adhere to the
Marquis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queensbury</ENAMEX> rules. A fight consists of an exchange of upper-body
blows that halts when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> falls.

            Any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> sport can be barbaric, whether it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> or wrestling or ultimate fighting. It is impossible to draw a bright
line between ultimate fighting and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX>. If anything, ultimate fighting is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">safer</ENAMEX> and less cruel than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s blood sport. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> pilloried
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> fighting because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> fought with bare knuckles: To a nation
accustomed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> gloves, this seemed revolting, an invitation to brain
damage. But it's just the reverse: The purpose of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> gloves is not to
cushion the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> but to shield the knuckles. Without gloves, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX> would
break his hands after a couple of punches to the skull. That's why ultimate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> won't throw multiple skull punches. As a result, they avoid the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">concussive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> wounds that kill boxers--and the long-term neurological damage
that cripples them.

            Similarly, the
chain-link <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX> surrounding the octagon looks grotesque. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have demanded
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> install ropes instead. But ropes are a major cause of death and injury
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fighters</ENAMEX> hyperextend their necks when they are punched against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ropes</ENAMEX>, because nothing stops their heads from snapping back. The chain-link
fence prevents hyperextension.

            When I tell people I'm an ultimate fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, they
invariably respond: "Don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get killed all the time doing that?" But no
one has ever been killed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>--though boxers are killed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. No
one has even been seriously injured at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>. On the rare occasions when a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bout</ENAMEX> has ended with a bloody knockout, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loser</ENAMEX> has always walked out of the
ring.

            But this does not impress
boxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, who are the most vigorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of extreme fighting. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">McCain</ENAMEX>
sat ringside at a boxing match where a fighter was killed. When I asked him to
explain the moral distinction between <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> and ultimate fighting, he exploded
at me, "If you can't see the moral distinction, then we have nothing to talk
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about</NUMEX>!" Then he cut our interview short and stormed out of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            But logic has not served the UFC well. Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> led, a
prudish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> followed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> opined against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> recommended a ban. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state outlawed ultimate fighting, as
did other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nevada Athletic Commission</ENAMEX> refused to sanction UFC bouts,
barring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> from the lucrative casino market. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> public TV station
refused a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> sponsorship ad. The only other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> ever
rejected was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX>.) Lawsuits blocked or delayed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> events all over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, forcing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> in legal fees. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> was
exiled from mega-arenas to ever-smaller venues in ever more out-of-the-way
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>. The match I attended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1997</TIMEX> was
held in the parking lot of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>.

            The cable TV industry struck the fatal blow. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commerce committee</ENAMEX>, which oversees
the cable industry. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1997</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Cable</ENAMEX>
Television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> warned that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> broadcasts could jeopardize the cable
industry's influence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Request</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cablevision</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Systems, Viewer's Choice</ENAMEX>, and other major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> stopped airing UFC events,
saying they were too violent for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Never mind that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> only aired on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pay-per-view</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> could not see it unless their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> paid for it;
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the same cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX> carried boxing matches, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">NC-17</ENAMEX> movies, and
professional wrestling shows far more violent than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>'s "addressable
audience"--the potential number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PPV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>--shrank from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">35 million</NUMEX> at
its peak to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            "It was a very cheap way
for the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to portray themselves as anti-violence. It did not cost
them much and it made them look good in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Klenfner</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>'s parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEG</ENAMEX>.

            The ultimate fighting industry did little to help its own
cause. The UFC promoted itself less as a serious sport than as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circus</ENAMEX> of
carnage. Its early ads emphasized extreme fighting's potential for death. UFC
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, without any evidence, of opposing the sport as a favor to
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. Extreme fighting was tarnished when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> from the
other ultimate fighting operation, the now-defunct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battlecade</ENAMEX>, were arrested
for violating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> prizefighting laws when they fought on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an Indian</TIMEX>
reservation outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montreal</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, an
increasingly desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> has been trying to assuage its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. The
competition, which had been gradually adding safety rules since the first
fight, imposed even more. It institued rounds and a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-point must" scoring
system. It banned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> butts and groin strikes. You can no longer kick a downed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or elbow someone in the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fighters</ENAMEX> are required to wear
thin martial arts gloves (a purely cosmetic change). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> imposed weight
classes, ending the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">David</ENAMEX>-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goliath</ENAMEX> mismatches that made early fights so
compelling.

            None of this soothed the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operators</ENAMEX>, who have kept UFC
off the air. The pay-per-view <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> has plunged from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">300,000</NUMEX> per show to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> can no longer afford its best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>: Some are fighting overseas.
Others, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Shamrock</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>), have become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro wrestlers</ENAMEX>.
Fights have deteriorated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> is limping along, but it has been reduced to
scheduling events in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> want to grow with the sport," says
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">UFC</ENAMEX> fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Beneteau</ENAMEX>. "They want to recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>. They
want to see the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> come back. When you compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX> now to what it
was, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> are not the same, the rules are not the same. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> have
no story to follow."

            Even as it disappears from public view, ultimate
fighting is returning to its roots. Away from the scrutiny of the major media,
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are still learning mixed martial-arts
techniques, and small-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> are quietly staging events. You can see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kage Kombat</ENAMEX> competitions at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dancing Waters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Pedro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX> You
can watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warrior</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Challenge</ENAMEX> at a small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> compete in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dungal All Styles Fighting Championship</ENAMEX>. Tribal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Idaho</ENAMEX> are hosting small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pankration</ENAMEX> tournaments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extreme</ENAMEX>
Fighting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenge</ENAMEX> is popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. The money is low; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> are small;
and there's not a TV camera in sight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate</ENAMEX> fighting should have become
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX>. Instead it has gone underground. It has become Fight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
