
   
   
      
         
             My <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder Suspect</ENAMEX>

            I like to think of myself as a responsible,
upstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> (even though I sell advertising for 
                  Slate
               ). So it
was a bit of a shock <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to find myself detained as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> during a
manhunt for a killer.

            My troubles started on a flight home to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> I wanted to check in on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX>--who lives in
a sailboat on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Union</ENAMEX>--so I tried to call him from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. Over
the phone, I got word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX> had sailed out from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX> around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night before</TIMEX>, and nobody had seen or heard from him since. This is unlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX>--or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Krohn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, for that matter. We're the sort who will let
someone know if we think we're going to be late for work, much less out on an
all-night boat ride.

            Things got worse after I landed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. At the
airport I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on television saying something about senseless
acts of violence, and I assumed he was referring to the shootings in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX>--until he mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>. I made a few calls and learned that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had been shot at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northlake Shipyard</ENAMEX>, which is less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> blocks
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX> where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> keeps his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> (and where I dock my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">houseboat</ENAMEX>). What if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX> has been shot? I thought.

            I took a cab toward the
scene of the crime. As we pulled up, I saw that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> had blocked off the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> near the marinas. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> told me that we couldn't drive any farther,
although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedestrians</ENAMEX> were allowed in the area, and I was free to walk home. It
did strike me as strange that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> would grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> access to the area
where a lunatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> was still on the loose. But the place looked pretty
safe--it was crawling with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SWAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX>-toting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, police <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, and armored <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>--and I needed to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and search
for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, so I started walking.

            Not far down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> stopped me and, to my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amazement</ENAMEX>, got ready to draw his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>. "You've got the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>," I said.
"I'm just coming home from a business trip." "Shut up," he said. As he barked
instructions--keep your hands in the air, spread your legs -- I felt
helpless. I was just an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. But I'm a
twentysomething white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> I happened to be unshaven and wearing
a trench coat, so I fit the description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>--though I didn't know it
at the time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX> interrogated, thumb-cuffed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>-searched me. I was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">patted</ENAMEX> in places I've never been patted before. "I'm not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>," I said
again. "For your protection and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>, stop talking and let me finish my job,"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> replied.

            Once he'd checked the address on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s
license, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> realized that my story made sense. He let me go and
suggested I proceed with caution: "You fit the description of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>."
When I told him I was trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to find my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, who'd gone
missing, we started all over again. "What does he look like?" he asked,
apparently now wondering whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX> might be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>. "He looks just
like me," I said, "but he's probably drowning if I can't get him some help."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> started asking questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh</ENAMEX>: Does he do <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>? No. Is he
mentally stable? I think so. Did he ever serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>? Well, yes--he
attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merchant Marine Academy</ENAMEX> and was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Reserves</ENAMEX>, which (as
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> pointed out) meant he had experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. But apparently I
said something that eased their minds about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX>; they told me I could go,
and they'd get in touch with me if necessary.

            Once I got home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
told me that the engine on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> had died <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night before</TIMEX>, that he'd
been rescued by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX>, and that he was sailing his boat
in instead of letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> tow him. Several <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> later we watched
with relief as he sailed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">marina</ENAMEX>. Not a bad alibi.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX>'s Note: At
the time of posting, no arrests had been made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> shooting. Check
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>'s news page for
updates.
            

         
      
   
