
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ox</ENAMEX>

            Ever
since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> woke up and opened fire on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has vacillated
between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> lines of attack. One is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is a big-spending liberal. The
other is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is a closet <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> who voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
budget cuts and promoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> vouchers. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s debate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
finally demonstrated how he plans to unite these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> indictments. He will tell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s big spending threatens middle-class entitlements.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
message reflects a cynical lesson of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past six years</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> wins. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pursued a bold liberal idea: mandating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> health insurance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> thwarted them and captured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
by convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that the plan threatened existing health benefits,
particularly the right of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to choose their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 and 1996</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> pursued a bold conservative idea: reducing the size
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to liberate the economy and to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> keep more of their
money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> thwarted them and defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> by convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> budget cuts threatened <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. To cynics, the lesson of these
wars is that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't care about liberal or conservative principles.
What they care about is losing the benefits they have.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has proposed to extend health insurance to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
through subsidies and tax credits. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Ten minutes</TIMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s debate, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">librarian</ENAMEX> asked him how much the plan would cost and how he would pay for it.
would be funded either "from the surplus" or "through the enormous savings that
we can get through the application of technology to the medical system," such
as "moving things from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> to Internet."

            
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> got his next chance to speak-in response to a different question-he
turned back to the cost issue. He said his own health insurance plan, which
would ostensibly cover "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" and "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of
all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>," would cost "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$146 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>," plus "a prescription
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug benefit …</ENAMEX> under Medicare for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$118 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>." Citing an
analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emory University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s plan "costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 trillion</NUMEX>.
That is more than the entire surplus over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 10 years</TIMEX>. We have to look
ahead and save some of that surplus for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>. If we wipe out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> and
wipe out the chance to save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>" by funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health insurance
plan, we would "shred the social safety net" and "give <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the money
to those who already have health insurance."

            The
next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">questioner</ENAMEX> asked about campaign reform, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> refused to let go of the
health-care dispute. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> cannot be an afterthought," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. "The only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to fix <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> fairly is to set aside <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 to 16 percent</NUMEX> of the surplus to
do it now. Otherwise, you're putting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> at risk. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> said in an
interview that he would speak to this issue later on, but if you spend the
entire surplus on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> campaign proposal, then that does not leave money
that should be allocated for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few minutes</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> steered a
question about education back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> health plan. "If the entire
surplus is spent, then there is no money left over for new initiatives on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>," he argued.

            From
one perspective, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s attack is conservative. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals habitually</ENAMEX> champion
new programs and entitlements without explaining what they would cost.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> habitually expose and exaggerate the cost of these programs,
which they translate into tax increases. On health care, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is championing
an entitlement, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is exposing-and, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>,
exaggerating-its cost.

            From
another perspective, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s attack is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> habitually
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champion</ENAMEX> smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and tax cuts without explaining which programs
would be reduced and which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> would suffer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> habitually
expose and exaggerate the suffering caused by these reductions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> isn't
suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health insurance plan will force a tax increase. He's
suggesting that in order to fund that plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> will have to cut other
programs, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and education.

            The
advantage of this critique is that because it is conservative as well as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can use it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> primary and then build on it in the
general election. In the primary, he can tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal voters</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s
health insurance plan would suck up all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX> in the budget, thereby
suffocating the left's favorite programs. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> were to complain that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s plan required a tax increase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> would shrug and vote for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>. By confronting them with budget cuts instead of tax increases-claiming
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> would "shred the social safety net" and stifle "new initiatives on
education" in order to "give <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the money to those who already have
health insurance"-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> gives them pause.

            In the
general election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can hold the same ground against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>.
He can tell moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s "risky tax scheme" (translation: tax
cuts) would eat up the surplus and force deep cuts in-remember this?-"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, education, and the environment." And now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is in
sufficiently good shape to stop borrowing from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can tell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that he would protect that trust fund, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> tax cuts
would force the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to "raid" it again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> also gets the benefit of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triangulation</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> as an arrogant
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who won't give back the tax money you overpaid the
government, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that he defended "fiscal responsibility"
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s reckless spending as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s reckless tax cuts.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
accuracy can certainly be disputed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has already accused him of
exaggerating the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s health-care plan. Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> can
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuse Gore</ENAMEX> of overestimating the cost of their tax cut and underestimating the
projected budget surplus. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> can question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s inference that any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who fails to reserve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of the surplus for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> is
putting the program "at risk" and "wiping out" the chance to "save" it.

            But as a political
strategy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s position has an unbeaten record. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> messed with
health insurance and went down in flames. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> messed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
and went down in flames. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> offered more spending and lost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> offered tax cuts and nearly lost it back. The only thing still
standing is the entitlements middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> feared they might lose to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visionaries</ENAMEX> on the right or the left. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> has stayed
alive by clinging to those entitlements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> could do worse.

         
      
   
