
   
   
      
         
            Will <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Windows Crash</ENAMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
fact in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antitrust case. He ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is a monopoly,
that it has abused its monopoly power, and that this abuse has harmed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. "For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s image, the damage is incalculable," said the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . "It's hard to imagine how the findings … could have
been worse news for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>," added the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The media,
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> itself, seem crippled by a failure of imagination. Things can
get worse for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. Much worse.

            From
the outset, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> (which owns 
                  Slate
               ) and the press corps have
treated the case as a bipolar debate: Either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has engaged in illegal
business practices, or it hasn't. Among other things, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>
accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of stifling competition by requiring business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> to
sign exclusionary contracts, colluding with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> to divide the browser
market, and eventually bundling Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer with Windows</ENAMEX> to wrest control
of that market. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> could have conceded some of these issues--for
example, that its contracts were unnecessarily exclusive--or it could have
denied that any of its practices were illegal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> chose the latter
course.

            In a
bipolar world, that calculation made sense: At best, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> would get to run
its business as usual, and at worst, rather than surrender prematurely, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would be ordered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to change some of its practices. What the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> failed to grasp is that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-sided clash in the courtroom left open
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> possibility in the financial press and the stock market. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> says
none of its practices are illegal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> says
some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s practices are illegal. But a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, led by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>, says all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s practices are
illegal--and if that perception prevails, true or not, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> may conclude
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> can't thrive once it is stripped of those practices by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> or by a settlement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> can only hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. The
stock market can kill it.

            Until
now, the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> owes all its success to ruthless marketing
rather than technical ingenuity has been a fringe view. But that view gained
momentum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s declaration that "it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s corporate
practice to pressure other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to halt software development that either shows
the potential to weaken the applications barrier to entry or competes directly
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s most cherished software products." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>
antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Klein</ENAMEX> underscored that sentence in a press conference
after the ruling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nightline</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and other media
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outlets</ENAMEX> followed suit. On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> called the case "a story of
predation, of anti-competitive behavior, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">monopolistic</ENAMEX> abuse. … It's a
mighty powerful story about consumer harm and predatory practices."

            
Discussing the ruling on television over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> repeatedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">distinguished Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s "predatory" practices from its "innovations," which
he praised. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> aren't interested in this
distinction. They want to convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, and the financial
markets that the "corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>" cited in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s opinion isn't just
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s bad habit, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>. They want to equate the "story" of
the trial--predation--with the story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            
Immediately after the opinion was released, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Black</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> antagonist
in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>: "The behavior they [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>] are accused of,
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> seems to be finding in fact that they did, is not behavior off
to the side of their business. It reflects a fundamental approach of the core
business strategy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which is to leverage and utilize their
monopoly to expand into neighboring markets, and to use that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> as a
critical tool of leverage with all of their business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. Because it is so central to the way they do business … it will be
very hard for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to make slight adjustments to their behavior and in
any way comply with the spirit of the antitrust law." <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossfire</ENAMEX> that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> really was created" from "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">old IBM</ENAMEX> monopoly" and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> relied not on "innovation" but on
illegal strong-arm tactics, like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Godfather</ENAMEX> . Crossfire
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">co-host David Corn</ENAMEX> joked that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> even "stole the operating system from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>."

            By
itself, this account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s livelihood is a mere insult. Combined with
the antitrust case, however, it threatens mortal injury. The combined message
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> will now be forced to fight fairly--and that it
can't. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> "will have to compete on the merits of their products," Corel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin McNeil</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is
"not an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innovator</ENAMEX> but a fast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follower</ENAMEX>," anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">futurist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Saffo</ENAMEX> told
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . In a press release, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Microsystems</ENAMEX> argued,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> should be prohibited from buying the distribution channels of the
future (e.g., cable and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wireless</ENAMEX>) and from buying rather than inventing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">technologies</ENAMEX>"--a constraint designed to handcuff <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in a high-tech
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> driven by timely acquisitions.

            The
image of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> as a crippled and helpless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> is increasingly penetrating
the mainstream media. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Courtroom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Software King</ENAMEX> Is at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risk</ENAMEX>,"
warned the front page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times published a virtual obituary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>: "Its strategy of buying up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> to absorb their technology no longer works as well as it has in the
past, in part because of the greater likelihood of firmer antitrust scrutiny of
such deals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">… Jackson</ENAMEX>'s finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> commanded a monopoly--and the
implication that he will rule shortly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> broke the law--may well
hobble its efforts to meet [new] challenges. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">…</ENAMEX> [A]s much as [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> is
widely viewed as a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is seen as technologically
mediocre."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has understood all along that its business image is as important as
its political image. At every opportunity, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> have reiterated their
commitment to quality and innovation. But they have failed to foresee a
collision between this message and their defiance in the antitrust case. By
insisting that everything <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has done is fair competition, they risk the
possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, if it accepts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s finding to the contrary,
will conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> doesn't know the difference. The ultimate danger
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> will conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, stripped of its ability to
exploit its monopoly power, doesn't know how to "compete."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has stuck to this all-or-nothing strategy even in the wake of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s findings. "The American legal system ultimately will affirm that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s actions and innovations were fair and legal," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> declared.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Neukom</ENAMEX> added, "We've always competed
fairly, and we will continue to do that. … We think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s actions
have been entirely normal competitive behavior." At the end of a conference
call with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> asked, "Does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> plan to
change any of its practices based on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s findings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Operating Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Herbold</ENAMEX> replied, "The answer to that question is
no."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> may be right in
claiming that it has done nothing wrong. Even if it isn't, it may succeed in
selling that argument to the public. But if it fails, the stakes are enormous.
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>, the worst that can happen is an array of sanctions--possibly
even a corporate breakup--designed to force <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to compete "on the
merits." In the stock market, however, the damage can get much worse. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX>
can decide not only that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> owes its success to the abuse of monopoly
power, and not only that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> will strip the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of this ability, but
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> doesn't know any other way to survive.

         
      
   
