
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain Vanishes</ENAMEX></SPAN>

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story celebrates the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 th</NUMEX> anniversary
of the fall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin Wall</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have sprouted out of the
former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">bloc</ENAMEX>, and ethnicity has replaced ideology as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s primary
source of friction. Despite the growing pains of economic reform, including
income contraction and worsening public health, a "free-market consensus" has
emerged in the ex-Communist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. ... A survey argues
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> is dematerializing. Power is being passed upward to the European
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> and downward to new parliaments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX>.
... A column claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has gone too far in its war
against "the new evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. Anti-smoking billboards clog the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">streets</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> are ostracized.

            
               
                  New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story claims that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reform Party</ENAMEX> is kaput.
After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> run, the mainstream parties assimilated his
deficit-reduction platform. Campaign-finance reform was also co-opted. Without
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cogent contrarian platform</ENAMEX>, a protest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is doomed. ... A
piece declares <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> debate. His congeniality made him look presidential next to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loony Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>. The piece also argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s draft-dodging,
triangulating, and poll-tracking allow his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> to tar him as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's of the debates.)

            
               
                  
                     
                        New
                     
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Magazine</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 7</TIMEX>
            

            A
cover package on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> after revolution. A
profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Michnik</ENAMEX> traces how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity</ENAMEX>'s key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX> steered <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>
through "a reasonable revolution." Michnik forged the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker-intellectual</ENAMEX>-church <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX> that peacefully overturned <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. As the "conscience of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of a
successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michnik</ENAMEX> rationalizes economic growing pains as "the
inevitable cost of joining the West" and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> reconciliation with former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>. ... In an interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solidarity</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lech Walesa</ENAMEX>
faults the West for not doing enough to rebuild <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>'s economy and complains
that ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> have prospered. ... An article argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
are pessimistic, despite plummeting crime and unemployment rates, because the
ideologically entrenched will not accept that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> can thrive without
religion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> or a paleoliberal in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospect</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 23</TIMEX>
            

            The
liberal policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> switches from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> to a glossy biweekly. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> will not be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">affable</ENAMEX>, backslapping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> is too much like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Voters</ENAMEX>
disillusioned with the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will elect the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>. ... A piece argues that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> presidency would
dramatically alter constitutional law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurists</ENAMEX> who are on deck
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> nominations--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Michael Luttig</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emilio M. Garza</ENAMEX>--are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultraconservative</ENAMEX>. A rightward tilt in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> could jeopardize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essay</ENAMEX> argues that television has reversed childhood and adulthood. Shows such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson's Creek</ENAMEX> feature <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> who act like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, while shows such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ally McBeal</ENAMEX> portray adulthood as "an extended adolescence."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov. 8</ENAMEX>
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> special issues about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 st century</TIMEX> imagines health
and environment in the future. An item speculates that sex "will be more for recreation than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">procreation</ENAMEX>," because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will choose to clone themselves or genetically
engineer "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer babies</ENAMEX>." ... A piece predicts that microscopic sensors in everything from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toilets</ENAMEX> to toothbrushes will provide "automated checkups" and enable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>
to consult with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> through the Web. ... An exclusive report
reveals that controversial feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> is advising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign on
how to win the women's vote. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>, whose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> per month retainer was just
cut to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>, urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for his sexual foibles
and to become an "alpha male." ... An article reports that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five tits-and-</NUMEX>action TV shows are
following in the profitable footsteps of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Anderson Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.I.P.</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Relic Hunter</ENAMEX> , starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tia Carrere</ENAMEX> as a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indiana Jones</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, featuring former model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Carol Alt</ENAMEX> as a babe in the
jungle.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov. 8</ENAMEX>
            

            The
cover story journeys to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> hell." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> are raising their
rates, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are trimming health benefits. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Sixty percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
are "frustrated and angry" with the health-care system, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> favor
federal intervention. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' bill of rights might soothe them, though it
would do nothing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">44 million</NUMEX> uninsured. ... An
accompanying survey ranks the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> biggest health plans: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX> comes out on top. ... A piece cites new evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigmund Freud</ENAMEX> was right about
dreams expressing unconscious desires. Neurological studies find that areas of
the brain associated with visual imagery and emotion are particularly active
during dream <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story forecasts a space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> race. The availability of
high-quality satellite imagery has prompted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> to develop a plan to
dominate space, a scheme that includes the deployment of space-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lasers</ENAMEX>.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> want to create a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Space</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX>. ... A piece ponders the fate of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is unlikely to welcome
their return, but permanently settling them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> could cost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billions</ENAMEX> and derail the peace talks. ... An article says it is harder for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to control their weight
because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> predispose adolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> toward weight gain and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> store
more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX>
            

            "Talk
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Town</ENAMEX>" publishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> report card. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> had a C
average. His lowest grades were in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics, astronomy, economics,
international relations, and sociology. ... An article describes the
pleasures of sleeping with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. Parenting books warn that co-sleeping
endangers an infant and makes it more difficult for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> to learn
independence. The author argues, based on his own experience as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-sleeping creates a deep bond between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. (For

                  Slate
               'stake, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wright</ENAMEX>'s ".") ... A piece marvels
at the coming wave of young, democracy-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has
doubled since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1979 revolution</ENAMEX>, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> will
constitute the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. Frustrated young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> challenge the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mullahs</ENAMEX> to allow more democracy, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> sport goatees to identify
themselves with reform.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story applauds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> for its populist programming. The
network has become "an intellectual counterculture." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Lamb</ENAMEX>'s objective
interviewing style is a pleasant contrast to cable's screaming matches.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>'s factual focus and lack of visual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">razzle-dazzle</ENAMEX> are a welcome relief
from postmodern infotainment programs. ... The editorial tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> to stop handcuffing
the payment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> dues to pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">codicils</ENAMEX>. Otherwise, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are in
danger of appearing isolationist.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15</TIMEX>
            

            An
editorial penned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Davis</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> pleads for the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mumia Abu-Jamal</ENAMEX>. They write that the man
convicted of murdering a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>: "ennobles the rest of us to deepen,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enlarge</ENAMEX>, and improve our political opposition to a state gone mad." ...
The cover story condemns suppression of minority voting through
selective and unwarranted prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> fraud. In a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> investigation
of absentee ballot forgery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> questioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabamians</ENAMEX> in
predominantly black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. Numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> have been prosecuted, but only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has been--and she was charged with helping an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
to vote.

         
      
   
