
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=350300619-12101999><SPAN class=350300619-12101999><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peak</ENAMEX></SPAN></SPAN>

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Films</ENAMEX>). Uninhibited raves
for the feature-film debut of music video and TV commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonze</ENAMEX>. The surrealist fantasy follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Diaz</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who discover how to enter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>'s brain though a miniature
door in an office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> trip over themselves with praise:
"deliciously one-of-a-kind" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ) ... "brilliantly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inventive</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desson Howe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ) ... "clever and
outrageous" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ) ... "either Being
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> gets nominated for best picture, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> need portals into their brains" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). (The film's official site includes an excellent selection of strange,
candid shots <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonze</ENAMEX> took of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> during filming.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess Mononoke</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
second-highest box office draw of all time (beaten only by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> ) is
this animated feature directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayao Miyazaki</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s undisputed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of anime. The complicated plot deals with conflict between man and
nature in an imagined <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">14 th -century</NUMEX> forest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are quick to note
that despite being distributed by an arm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>, the film is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> as different from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Little Mermaid</ENAMEX> as you can get, and it "makes
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s homiletic, follow-your-dream fables look even more solipsistic"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
               ). Most impressive is the "exotically
beautiful" artwork (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ); the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> is
reported to have personally retouched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 80,000</NUMEX> of the film's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4 million</NUMEX>
cells. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to watch the trailer; click to read the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music of the Heart</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). Horror director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Craven</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scream , A</ENAMEX> 
               Nightmare on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Elm Street</ENAMEX> ) branches
out and tackles the true story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roberta Guaspari</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Harlem</ENAMEX> violin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are evenly divided. Some declare the film "a sugary paean
to the violin as a tool for improved self-esteem" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ), while others are touched: "thoroughly
appealing ... Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guaspari</ENAMEX>'s story has been given a blunt, no-nonsense tone
that works" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to bone up on
A Nightmare on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Elm Street</ENAMEX> .)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lo's Diary</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pia Pera</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foxrock</ENAMEX>). This retelling of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lolita</ENAMEX> from the point of view of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> has
taken quite a beating. First it got dumped by its original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>, Farrar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s estate sued for copyright infringement
(they settled). Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are assaulting it in print. Michiko Kakutani
neatly sums up most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' thoughts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : "The
problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lo's Diary</ENAMEX> isn't that it's derivative. The problem is that
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pera</ENAMEX> seems to have no understanding whatsoever of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nabokov</ENAMEX> was up to in
Lolita , and so cannot begin to re-imagine his story in any meaningful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>." In this version, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lolita</ENAMEX> is a knowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seductress</ENAMEX> who tortures her pet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hamster</ENAMEX> and feels no sadness at her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s death. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> slam her voice as
"false and ungainly" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Levi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ) and complain
that her diary is tainted by ideas and language that sound awkwardly mature.
Among a scattering of positive reviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> calls the book
"a compelling novel in its own right." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               
                  Thumbsucker
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadway Books</ENAMEX>). Mainly
negative takes on book reviewer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirn</ENAMEX>'s coming-of-age novel about a troubled
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who tries to replace his thumb-sucking habit with various other
crutches, including smoking, drinking, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ritalin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX> writes in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> that though "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirn</ENAMEX> is a frequently sparkling
tour guide" through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>'s life, "[w]e get no sense ... that any of
this is real; not even comically real." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> call it a "largely episodic
collection of great moments that aren't all causally linked in that comforting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> we're used to" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahlin Chang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Wolfe</ENAMEX>, who attacked the
book in the literary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biblio</ENAMEX> on the basis of its title--without
having read a word of the manuscript--draws a stinging retort from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirn</ENAMEX> in the
latest issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tin House</ENAMEX> , in which he writes a lovely parody of a
negative review for his own book: "I consider it my duty as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of this
offensive work, to carry even further <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolfe</ENAMEX>'s condemnation in hopes of
neutralizing, from the start, a potentially harmful literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contagion</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

         
      
   
