
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">331</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">&quot</NUMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">'Twixt</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 and 20&quot</TIMEX>;

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> share an idea about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> held
by no other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. What idea?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               Note: Because of demands from a meddlesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX>,
we were obliged to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> retrofitting

                  Slate
               's coal furnaces to burn pandas. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News Quiz</ENAMEX> will
resume in a special pollution-free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> edition.

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 330</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Down, 94 To Go":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
                  On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
signed a joint declaration, resolving a conflict that began exactly 482 years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. It turns out that, on this point, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> believe the same thing.
What?
               
            

            
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> is still the perfect time for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> because there's nothing
good to watch on television."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrill Markoe</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>,
and more specifically <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alicia Silverstone</ENAMEX>, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">henchmen</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Hotchkiss</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
whole thing about it being easier for a camel to pass through the eye of a
needle than for a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to get into heaven? The rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> could buy his own
giant needle."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Reynolds</ENAMEX>
            

            
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter Meets Charles Darwin</ENAMEX> should be banned from public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shulman</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Episcopalians</ENAMEX> are all going to hell."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Heaney</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            It is so delightfully
dark ages to see this kind of mumbo jumbo reported right next to the real news.
But of course we live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where religious belief is not merely
tolerated, it is required of anyone seeking high office. Where do they get this
stuff? They learn it in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>; that's what social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Eve</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> say. In a national survey of high-school life-science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> (reported
in the terrific book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How To Think About Weird Things</ENAMEX> ), they found:

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> thought the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark</ENAMEX> was definitely or probably
true

               <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> believed in communication with the dead

               <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX> felt <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> lived at the same time

               <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> believed in ghosts

            

            Should you wish a more
passionate embrace of the irrational, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1996</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
reported that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> believe in a literal hell, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX>
believe the world was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78 percent</NUMEX> believe in angels.
It's amazing our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> get off the ground. Well, maybe not so amazing: We've
got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Della Reese</ENAMEX> holding them aloft.

            
               Good Deeds Are for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suckers Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> agreed on the doctrine of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">justification</ENAMEX>, declaring that salvation could be achieved by faith alone; no
good works required. This assertion, one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther</ENAMEX> posted
on the door of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wittenberg Cathedral</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 31, 1517</TIMEX>, contrary to church
teachings of that time, helped kick off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reformation</ENAMEX>.

            No consensus has been
reached concerning the buying and selling of indulgences online at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Touting Scouting</ENAMEX>
Extra
            

            It's not all gay-bashing and religious mania;
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s scouting encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to learn many useful skills through its system
of merit badges. Which of the following are actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> merit badges?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Agribusiness

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Business</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atomic Energy</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Consumer Buying

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Entrepreneurship

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Family Life

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Fingerprinting

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. Genealogy

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">10 Personal Management</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. Salesmanship

            
               Answers
            

            All are actual merit
badges that can be earned by any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troop Willie Loman</ENAMEX>, should such a
troop actually exist. Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safety and Sports</ENAMEX> have been dropped from the list
of merit badges required to become an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Scout</ENAMEX>. They have been replaced by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Marketeering</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learjet Leasing</ENAMEX>, but only in my feverish khaki-clad
imagination.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>: bad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
