
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>

            
               For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>, see the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 4</TIMEX> "."
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> begins <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Beauty Myth</ENAMEX> , her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>
treatise on how the beauty industry thwarts female progress, with a bitter
salvo against image <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>. As proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> value looks
over capabilities, she cites the then-growing ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> hired by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to polish their professional appeal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> ends the book with a call to
reject "the insistence that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s appearance is her speech" and "political
manipulation" based on looks.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eight years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> has become an image
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> herself. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> a month for advice on presentation, from
the tones of his speeches to the color tones of his wardrobe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post relayed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> "has long contended that earth tones are more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'reassuring</ENAMEX>' to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>' " and that she is "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s recent
wardrobe change."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s non-sartorial
advice to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>--and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> before him, as an unpaid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>--is
even stranger. She coached each to emphasize his manly strengths, relying on
hoary, tired gender stereotypes. She reportedly told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> that he is the "beta
male" who must fight <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "alpha male" for dominance. And as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, she informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> was
searching for a "good-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> role model" to "build a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. "I
will not let anyone or anything touch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> wrote in one memo for
him. "I will DEFEND/PROTECT the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>." This came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only three years</TIMEX> after
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of her book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire With Fire</ENAMEX> , in which she savaged
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> for positioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> as "the reassuring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arch</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> are not her only charges. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is
now a full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, she and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> other "remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>"
founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodhull Institute for Ethical Leadership</ENAMEX>, devoted to training
twentysomething <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> "to assume positions of power and influence." But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institute</ENAMEX>'s programs don't cover political, economic, or legal issues. Instead,
the short retreats teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> "how to be financially literate; how to
speak and present; how to write a business plan; fundraise; and run for
elective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>; how to write a book or magazine article proposal; how to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mentor</ENAMEX> and be mentored; how to start a community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>; and how to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philanthropist</ENAMEX>."

            How did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> start out as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Friedan</ENAMEX> and end up as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> wasn't as long or twisted as
it might seem. In fact, the advice she dispensed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>--safe, poll-tested
ideas mixed in with a few fancifully nutty ones--is remarkably similar to the
instructions she's been giving to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> has never been a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wonk</ENAMEX> or an ideologue. While she's dabbled in journalism and teaching, she isn't
really a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> or an academic either. She began her career by being a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rhodes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> with a splashy book--and has been tutoring others in
how to succeed ever since. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is a master cheerleader, and she acts like one:
upbeat, entertaining, sweetly sexy, sharply aware of image, and endlessly
trilling about victory.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> books are breathless, hyperbolic tracts on
What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holds Women Back</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beauty Myth</ENAMEX> , written while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> was at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>, is an angry protest at how the cosmetics, plastic surgery, and magazine
industries have sabotaged feminism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> holds the beauty biz accountable--at
least in part--for the pay gap, female poverty, censorship in the free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>,
fear of aging, sexual unhappiness, rape, and eating disorders. But she doesn't
suggest abandoning the visuals; she wants them to be more attainable and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uplifting</ENAMEX>. "Our movement forward as individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> together ...
depend now on what we decide to see when we look in the mirror," she writes. No
wonder she has spent so much time thinking about what color <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s suits
should be.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire With</ENAMEX>
Fire , as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> settles into her persona as pep-talker, she tells women
essentially the same thing she told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: Drop the victim-loser image, stop
playing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> fiddle, and use romantic archetypes to visualize the path to
glory. "To imagine and enjoy winning ... had long been alien to female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consciousness</ENAMEX>," she writes. Because "history moves in response to narratives,
dream images, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, heroines, and myths," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> need to think of themselves
as latter-day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incarnations</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, avenger of insult; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheba</ENAMEX>, a responsible,
politically influential sovereign; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>, the feminine spirit of victory."
In other words, as alpha <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>.

            Even before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, she was coaching
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> on how to save the women's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX>-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triangulation</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire With Fire</ENAMEX> , she argues for editing the stridency
out of feminism and emerging with a vaguely uplifting, centrist message. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX>, she is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Feminist</ENAMEX>. "Many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> don't think
[feminism] addresses their concerns, or don't like images of it that they see,"
she announces. In order to accommodate them, the women's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> should
de-emphasize specific political causes--abortion, rape, homosexual
rights--because they're "issues that may or may not include [some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>],
rather than a theory of self-worth that applies to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s life." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wolf</ENAMEX>
wants to expand the size of the feminist tent, and she wants to do so by
redefining its ideology as the simple pursuit of success for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> first began advising
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> when her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shipley</ENAMEX>, worked as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> speechwriter.
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> troubles started, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> hit the spin circuit. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair was a tricky issue for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal feminists</ENAMEX>, who were caught
between protesting sexual harassment and supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> they had
elected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> did both, by turning the issue into an object lesson on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s
professional success. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who should be looking into these allegations
is not a partisan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EEOC</ENAMEX>," she opined on the talk-show
circuit. "What is clear is that when there is a situation where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> is
advanced as allegedly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was with special help, getting jobs, it goes to
a sex discrimination situation in the workplace--were the other interns and the
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>, who may have been at the
copy machine, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>, trying to raise their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and move up to
that job that was allegedly offered to Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> sees the telling of her own personal experiences as a
triumph for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Promiscuities</ENAMEX> , is a memoir in
which she single-handedly "retrieve[s] [the] secret struggle for womanhood" by
narrating her own sexual coming of age. "By telling my story and asking other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to tell theirs, I wanted to elucidate the emotional truths that emerge
from a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s erotic memory," she explains. She bills her
stories as tough to tell: In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tikkun</ENAMEX> magazine piece on her coming out
as a spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, she testifies that "it's taken me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> to build up
enough credibility in the analytic/linear world that I can now speak and have
some expectation of being heard to a certain degree. It's been a long haul, and
very much a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gendered</ENAMEX> haul." This from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose first book was a best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seller</ENAMEX>, published in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> often expounds on the trauma--and the
necessity--of expressing herself in public. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of her books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>
demands the need for positive role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> in the media--of which, naturally,
she is one. It's a brilliantly self-justifying line of reasoning: I am on
television because I am a role model, and I am a role model because I am on
television. And a great marketing strategy: Buy my books, because they're good
for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>.

            It's no wonder that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> has become a well-paid
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>. Who better to help a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> extract weighty lessons
from his personal history, to teach him to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that their own successes
depend on his own? At last, it seems, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> has found a forum where the personal
really is as political as she thinks it is.

         
      
   
