
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Insiders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Way Insiders</ENAMEX>

            
               
                  Being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Malkovich</ENAMEX>
                is everything I've ever dreamed of in a crazy comedy. It's
close to pure farce, yet its laughs are grounded in loneliness, impotence,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">self-loathing</ENAMEX>, and that most discomfiting of vices to dramatize: envy. The
action is surreal, the emotions are violently real. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> at finding slapstick correlatives for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s nebulous
sense--or non-sense--of themselves. It's possible that no one has ever come up
with a more absurdly perfect metaphor for our longing to be
someone--anyone--other than who we are than a portal into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Schwartz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX>), is a soulfully unkempt puppeteer whose wildly
ambitious work is ignored while his gimmicky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX> thrive. When he reports for
a drudge job as a file <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is between the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>
floors of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX>--it's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-and<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-halfth</ENAMEX> floor, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walk stooped and make feeble jokes about the "low overhead." That low
ceiling--a constant reminder of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> has been stunted--is the first sign
of the movie's comic astuteness, of its knack for devising sight gags with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sting</ENAMEX>. When a sleek and derisive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Keener</ENAMEX>)
rebuffs his advances and mocks his art, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> argues passionately on behalf of
his puppets: He says that everyone longs to be inside someone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. On
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cue</ENAMEX>, he discovers a passageway behind a file <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> that whooshes him into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> and then disgorges him, after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>, into a ditch beside
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Jersey Turnpike</ENAMEX>. The poor sap can't keep his secret. He tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>,
who is soon selling tickets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> experience. The biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX> turns out to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>'s nerdily frazzled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lotte</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Diaz</ENAMEX>), who
sums up the thrill for the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. "Being inside did something
to me," she says. "I knew who I was."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Jonze</ENAMEX> (he played the skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">redneck</ENAMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX> ), comes to Being 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> from music
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">videos</ENAMEX>, but the movie isn't a digitized bag of tricks like Fight

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonze</ENAMEX> is never in your face: His instincts must have told him that
hyping gags this outlandish would turn the picture into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. He keeps the
action slightly remote and the jokes deadpan, and the upshot is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> almost never stops giggling. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">first hour</TIMEX> and change has a magical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fluidity</ENAMEX>. The scenes between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cusack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keener</ENAMEX> boast the best emasculating
banter since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Durang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyond Therapy</ENAMEX> , and when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lotte</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxine</ENAMEX> begin to communicate erotically through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, the film
becomes a transsexual (and transcendental) screwball comedy. The script has a
free-association quality that turns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> on--they love not knowing where
they're going. I wonder if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX>, when he started writing, even knew that the
protagonist would stumble on that portal, or what he'd find when he went
through. (The head of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>??!!??)

            That the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> might be the movie's most brilliantly unsettling touch, since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>--although undeniably great--is one of our most distant and weirdly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insular</ENAMEX>. You can understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> fantasizing about being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> or
being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>, but being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>? What's lodged under that thick brow
is anybody's guess. Evidently quite the heterosexual, he still courts sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambiguity</ENAMEX>: He speaks in querulous tones and bats the most insolently feminine
lashes this side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny</ENAMEX>. Weird or not, though, he's a celebrity: He
exists. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> makes a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> sends up his own
preening aloofness, and he has never been more emotionally exposed than when it
dawns on him that his smug façade has been literally penetrated. When he
attempts to fathom what's happening to him, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonze</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> deliver a coup
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">de</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> --a vision of hell that isn't, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">à la Sartre</ENAMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but
oneself ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infinitum</ENAMEX>.

            B eing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX> should have ended right there,
since the filmmakers never top that hysterical sequence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> seems to have
written himself into a corner. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last half-hour</TIMEX> he ties things up too
neatly and the craziness--and some of the helium--goes out of the movie. Why do
crazy comedies need closure? As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cusack</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> becomes more twisted, he
loses his stature (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s good will), and the climax has too many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dissonances</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jonze</ENAMEX> end up sentimentalizing the longing for a
collective consciousness in a way I found creepy: Do they mean to be retelling
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Invasion of the Body Snatchers</ENAMEX> from the body-snatchers' point of view?
(If so, the film is even darker than I think it is.)

            The last part diminishes
the movie, but not enough to wreck it: It's still an amazing piece of work.
What other madcap farce would dare to have a score--it's by the superb Carter
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burwell</ENAMEX>--so plangent and melancholy? Or to cast that sunny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Diaz</ENAMEX>
as a nerd? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> retains her essential sweetness, but the transformation
is otherwise remarkable<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: Her Lotte</ENAMEX> is such a mouth breather that she nearly
drools, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> manages to look estranged from that lovely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. Even more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dazzling</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keener</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> who has lately been stuck playing nice, sensible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but who here is all silken curves and withering putdowns--she greets
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>'s declaration of love with a pitying sigh that brings the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keener</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxine</ENAMEX> is so glamorously, tantalizingly self-contained that you can
almost believe she never dreams of being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>
                  he Insider
                is a big, overlong, and rather
unwieldy piece of storytelling, but the story it has to tell is so vital that
it cuts through all the dramaturgical muddiness. It's a terrific muckraking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">melodrama</ENAMEX>--it will get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fuming. It's about big-business mendacity and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who do its bidding, and about what happens to corporate whistle-blowers
in a society where the mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are also in the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>.
The movie tells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two interlocking</NUMEX> stories: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Wigand</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Crowe</ENAMEX>), former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> for research and development at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown & Williamson</ENAMEX> tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, who is persuaded to go public with
revelations about how cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> manipulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> in their
product for maximum addictiveness. (Despite their testimonies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wigand</ENAMEX> says, tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> regard cigarettes as "a nicotine delivery
system.") The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> story concerns the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lowell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Pacino</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who persuaded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX> to come forward. Bergman
watches in horror as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, backs away from the story under pressure
from the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>--which fears, at a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> is on the block, the
impact of a major lawsuit on its value. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oddly</ENAMEX> unmentioned in the film is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">then-owner Lawrence Tisch</ENAMEX> had his own tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorillard</ENAMEX>, and had
separate dealings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown & Williamson</ENAMEX>.)

            We're used to hearing
tales of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, informants, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whistle-blowers</ENAMEX> who are urged to come
forward and then, after they do, are "hung out to dry"--i.e., left unprotected
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who approached and exploited them. What gives this version its
kick--and what has made it fodder for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost six months</TIMEX>--is that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who betray the whistle-blower are among the most famous and powerful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX>, the co-anchor and the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> . If they could be pressured to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">spike</ENAMEX>"
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segment</ENAMEX> that they knew to be true, the film implicitly asks, how much chance
do others have of breaking stories about corporate wrongdoing? And what about
news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> with a financial stake in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>? Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> known for their integrity tend to look the other way at their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' malfeasances when they hear words like "stock options" and
"IPO."

            But the movie's emotional hook isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> infighting or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX>'s quest to get the story. It's the fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowe</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prickly</ENAMEX>, blockish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> with no social skills--an edgy wonk. Already isolated
by temperament, he seems more vulnerable than a conventionally nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX> appears to have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (a nearly unrecognizable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venora</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> debutante type who clearly didn't bargain for a life of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> and financial ostracization, is on the verge of bailing out on him even
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> start appearing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s mailbox and the death
threats on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX>'s computer. You can't always tell what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowe</ENAMEX> is doing--his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opacity</ENAMEX> is sometimes a little too opaque. What's plain, though, is that Wigand
doesn't want to have this role, didn't ask for it, and has no support system to
get him through it. He's entirely dependent on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX>, with whom he mostly
communicates by cell phone and fax.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>, has never tried to tell a story as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> (or nonviolent) as The
Insider , and he and his co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Roth</ENAMEX>, don't shape their
narrative very satisfyingly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX> are both "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>," and both,
ultimately, whistle-blowers. (It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergman</ENAMEX>'s spilling his guts to the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> that finally shamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> into running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX> interview.) But
although the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> is played by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> (Pacino
grandstands, but not to the point of distraction), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX>'s story doesn't have
the same primal force. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dark night</TIMEX> of the soul is in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, indicted,
financially ruined, threatened with death, minus his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman's</ENAMEX> is in an expensive-looking beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with his warmly supportive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spouse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay Crouse</ENAMEX>).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> seem to be bending over backward--even
now--to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX> from appearing to have disclosed what he disclosed too
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX>. I admire their consideration for their subject, but in its wake come all
kinds of narrative fuzziness. The movie isn't clear on where the secret report
that kicked off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergman</ENAMEX>'s interest in tobacco came from, or who in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
thought it was a good idea to turn him onto <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wigand</ENAMEX>. It's left vague just when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX> decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wigand</ENAMEX> was important not for what he might say about that
report but about the industry as a whole. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> must have had legal constraints
that rivaled those at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, which responds to a death
threat, carries off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wigand</ENAMEX>'s computer while he sputters that it contains all
his important data. The implication is that the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is in cahoots
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown & Williamson</ENAMEX>, but we hear no more about it; we never even know
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wigand</ENAMEX> got his computer back. And there's no dramatic payoff with the
chillingly satanic tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Gambon</ENAMEX>) whose threats
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX> think about going public. Given how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> must have
vetted this thing, it's probably an achievement that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> got as much as he did
on the screen.

            Should <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX> be pissed off? Depends what
really happened. In a delicious turn, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Plummer</ENAMEX> makes the co-anchor
less a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> than a pompous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">prima donna</ENAMEX>, but he also gives him a bullying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> and real charisma. It's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caving</ENAMEX>-in to the
network--"I'm with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> on this," he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX>--that does him the most
damage. It's the scene in a posh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> regards the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigands</ENAMEX>' paroxysms of fear over the coming <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> interview with
aristocratic contempt. He says, "Who are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?"--which opens the
door for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman</ENAMEX>'s too-pat rebuke: "Ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> under extraordinary
circumstances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>. What do you expect? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">consistency?</ENAMEX>" It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s
lack of interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wigand</ENAMEX>'s story--the movie's most powerful--that damns him
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s eyes.

            
               The Insider
doesn't note a couple of key, maybe hopeful ironies. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s
"spiking" of the interview turned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX> into an even bigger story than he
would have been otherwise. And in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where</ENAMEX> are they now?" titles at the end,
the filmmakers omit the most important detail of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bergman's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wigand</ENAMEX>'s current
lives: that they're being played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Pacino</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Crowe</ENAMEX> in a major
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movie, and that they're big news again.

            Is there a less savory subgenre than the hardcore forensics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thriller</ENAMEX>? A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpse</ENAMEX> is discovered in a grotesque state of mutilation, then the
scene shifts to an autopsy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where skulls are popped off and innards held up
for inspection. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">short time</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> pore over glossies of fatal
wounds. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yummy</ENAMEX>. In 
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bone Collector</ENAMEX>
               , the wily serial killer
leaves clues for the brainy forensics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--clues that amount to a forensics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jigsaw</ENAMEX> puzzle. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
solves the puzzle fast enough, he has a shot at saving the latest manacled and
tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>; if not, he has to scour the gore-drenched death scene for
clues to the next murder. Yummy yummy. One fact quickly becomes apparent: "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">perp</ENAMEX> knows forensics," murmurs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Yummy yummy yummy.

            The rub is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is a quadriplegic. He
can't "walk the grid"--he needs a pair of eyes as sensitive as his but attached
to a good pair of legs. As luck would have it, they're attached to a very good
pair of legs and a great pair of breasts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelina Jolie</ENAMEX> plays the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> who
discovers a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and snaps some photos that convince <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> she has a
"gift" for forensics. He dispatches his new protégé to grisly crime scenes,
purring into her headphones and demanding to know what she sees. Better than
phone sex! He says, "I want to know what you feel in the deepest recesses of
your senses," and "Follow the instincts you were born with. ... Process the
body." I was thinking that she could process my body anytime, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolie</ENAMEX> rises
above such adolescent spasms. Well, almost. She's a thoughtful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>, but she
wasn't born to play a beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>. Those tire-tread lips are model lips; those
exquisitely chiseled cheekbones, model cheekbones. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> scans her file on
his fancy bedside computer: Guess what? She was a teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">model</ENAMEX>! Clever
save!

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bone Collector</ENAMEX> is less rancid than the
last big serial-killer-fetishist picture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copycat</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), and it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expertly</ENAMEX> shot and edited. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Noyce</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Semler</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cinematographer</ENAMEX>, cook up some eerily muzzy images inside the brackish <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX>
and abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> where the fiend does his/her demented surgery. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> is still a piece of exploitive schlock. A mediocre mystery, too: It never
approaches the ingenuity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Harris</ENAMEX>, still the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maestro</ENAMEX> of forensic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">porn</ENAMEX>.
For some reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noyce</ENAMEX> telegraphs the identity of the killer halfway through
(does he mean to? Or does the hammy framing give it away by accident?), but
it's left to the laughably garish climax for the wacko to spell out his/her
arbitrary motive. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>'s lines are on the level of: "You think I'm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">m-m</ENAMEX>-mad, don't you?") The only aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Bone Collector</ENAMEX> that can't
be derided is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. The option of walking through the part clearly not
available to him, he doesn't sleep through it either: Every muscle in this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s ruined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> seems to strain against his fate while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> in his
brain grind fiercely. He deserves a smarter psycho--a smarter movie, too.

         
      
   
