
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Matters</ENAMEX>

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Le Monde</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> devoted its front-page lead and its editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to the continuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of November</TIMEX>. It dwelt on their
different attitudes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> wanting it to lift more trade barriers,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> wanting it to act as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arbiter</ENAMEX> of trade disputes--and noted that last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s meeting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and Romano
differences. "The discussions will therefore continue to prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
conference being devoid of all content," it said. In its editorial, Le
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monde</ENAMEX> defended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> against its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, saying it is much better
to negotiate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in a multilateral framework than to let the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> exercise its power in bilateral deals with other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            In a
long piece for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South China Morning Post</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the
paper's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> wrote that early <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> was
now impossible and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> would be shut out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX> negotiations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX>, now touring <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, derailed the plan of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhu Rongji</ENAMEX> to cut <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and privatize its state-owned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprises</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, the article said. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> issued
proclamations keeping foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s Internet and
telecommunications industries. He also failed to soften his positions on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>, and human rights, which might have been one way of wooing
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>.

            
"Instead, the opposite happened. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few days</TIMEX>, harsh sentences were
handed out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hangzhou</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> and there
were further arrests of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun Gong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>," the SCMP
said. "In the past, Mr <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> always timed the release of prominent political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> to smooth relations and give his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> some face so they could claim
credit for improving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s record. This time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was confident that such
gestures, which border on the insulting, were not necessary for the banquets at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buckingham Palace</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Elysee</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX>. The praise and support Mr
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> gave over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX>
has not been withdrawn."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCMP</ENAMEX> also reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Klosson</ENAMEX>, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consul-general</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>, was rebuked by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for a speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in
which he attacked a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> proposal to establish a press <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
as a threat to media freedom and criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>'s decision to prevent the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pope</ENAMEX> visiting the territory. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> called the speech meddlesome and
irresponsible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s proposed new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adm.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Prueher</ENAMEX>, had delighted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.C.</ENAMEX>, during a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, by stating that human rights will be at the heart of his mission
there.

            
Already criticized for its tough crackdown on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>'s recent visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> came under renewed attack
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> for overprotecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. Libération of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> said that the police deployment bore no
relation to the size of the threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khatami</ENAMEX> by mujahadeen exiles and "could
have given the impression that certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> were under siege."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Monde</ENAMEX> reported special indignation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Party</ENAMEX>, one of whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Chirac</ENAMEX> of "making our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a
prostitute" by offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> his bed. It was "a black week for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of
the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parliamentarian</ENAMEX> said. In an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Figaro</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henri Leclerc</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Rights League</ENAMEX>, said it was a sad time for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
democracy and that arresting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> was "no way of persuading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to respect the rights of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Süddeutsche Zeitung</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> reported that after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">II</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> had not been put on trial in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> because
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> fears that such actions would sour its postwar relationship with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> were killed during the German
occupation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1943 to 1945</TIMEX>, and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> of
inquiry passed on the names of many of the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. But "after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Democrat</ENAMEX>
government in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> didn't want to ruin its relationship with its new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> by
holding embarrassing trials," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            The
Times of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 12</TIMEX> military coup in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> had
been predicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days earlier</TIMEX> on an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> Web site. The message, posted by
an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>, said: "There is going to be a coup in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> very
soon democratic rule will be over for good.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chiina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> know." Soon
afterward, mediaibc.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, a site for "media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>," was hacked into and
put out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> for some time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said.

            
Opinions varied on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> debate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> won; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corriere della Sera</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> won; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boredom</ENAMEX> won.

         
      
   
