
   
   
      
         
            Is  Everybody Happy?

            Here's the least controversial principle in all
statecraft: Never pass up an opportunity to make everyone happier at the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>. Admittedly, opportunities like that are vanishingly rare--almost anything
you propose is likely to make someone unhappy--so the principle is as
useless in practice as it is compelling in theory. But if you want to talk
about the difference between good and bad policy, it helps to have an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncontroversial</ENAMEX> starting point.

            This particular starting
point has proved useful enough to earn a proper name. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> call it the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pareto Principle</ENAMEX>, in honor of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vilfredo</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pareto</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> line among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> is that although we disagree about a
myriad of issues, at least we're all good Paretians: If you can think of a way
to make everyone happier, we're behind you all the way.

            How disturbing, then, to realize that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pareto Principle</ENAMEX>
conflicts with another value that some of us hold at least equally dear--the
right of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to make free choices. Here's a stylized example: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suppose</ENAMEX>
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (call them the "prudes") cherish their freedom of religion, but not
half so much as they would cherish a general ban on pornography. Others (call
them the "lewds") cherish their right to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Chatterley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lover</ENAMEX>
but not half so much as they would cherish a general ban on religion. Then if
you outlawed both pornography and religion, you'd make everyone happier,
while simultaneously making everyone less free.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pareto Principle</ENAMEX>
demands that we embrace such a law while the fundamental precepts of liberalism
demand that we recoil from it. As <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amartya Sen</ENAMEX> pointed out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, there's no such thing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paretian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>. When some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get
pleasure from controlling other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paretians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> must
part ways.

            That's no problem in practice, because in practice there
will always be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> who are offended by book-banning--and the very
existence of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paretian</ENAMEX> to withdraw his endorsement of
the ban. (Remember, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pareto Principle</ENAMEX> endorses only changes that make
everyone happier, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>.) But in practice, nobody is
guided solely by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pareto Principle</ENAMEX> anyway. Instead, we're guided by more
flexible criteria such as the cost-benefit principle: A policy is good when its
benefits exceed its costs, with benefits (or costs) measured by what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> (or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>) would be willing to pay to see the policy enacted (or
defeated).

            Under quite general circumstances, it can be proved
(though not in the space of a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> column) that free markets yield
exactly those outcomes the cost-benefit principle recommends. That makes it
easy to reconcile a taste for economic welfare with a taste for individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberty</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Usually</ENAMEX>, markets deliver both at once.

            Usually, but not always. With just a slight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">modification</ENAMEX>, the paradox of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paretian</ENAMEX> liberal reasserts itself in the
cost-benefit context. Suppose I'm willing to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> to read the subversive
works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Krugman</ENAMEX> and you're willing to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> to stop me. A strict
cost-benefit analysis suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX>'s writing should be banned.

            (There's no need for a
ban if you can locate me and offer me, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> to change my reading
habits--and if you can be assured that I won't just take the money and run. But
let's suppose the impracticality of such arrangements leaves book-banning as
the only realistic alternative.)

            That's a conclusion we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> find repugnant, and it
would be nice to avoid it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way out is simply to declare that "psychic costs
don't count." If you don't like getting your nose punched, your aversion goes
into the cost-benefit calculus and inspires us to write laws that discourage
nose-punching. But if you don't like knowing I read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krugman</ENAMEX>, that's your own
problem.

            Appealing as that
position might sound, it's also suspiciously incoherent. If my habit of reading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krugman</ENAMEX> and my habit of punching your nose are equally painful to you, why
should public policy discourage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and not the other?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> answer is that psychic costs shouldn't count because
they're too easy to exaggerate. Anyone can claim to have suffered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>
worth of emotional distress, but we have no way of knowing which claims are
simply fabricated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amazingly</ENAMEX>, though, this seemingly insurmountable problem can
be surmounted. A sufficiently clever system of taxes and subsidies can induce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to make accurate reports of their own emotional distress. (I look
forward to explaining how such systems work in a forthcoming column.)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> argument against counting psychic harm
is that once you start counting it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> train themselves to start feeling
it. That one, I suspect, is harder to refute.

            The mirror image of a
psychic cost is a psychic benefit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Corps of Engineers</ENAMEX>, charged with executing a
cost-benefit analysis of un-damming the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snake River</ENAMEX> in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, plan
to factor in something they call "existence value"--the value of the psychic
benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get from knowing the river is running wild.

            In principle, existence value makes perfect sense. If your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Agnes</ENAMEX> just can't stand the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> damming the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snake River</ENAMEX>, her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anguish</ENAMEX> is a real cost of maintaining the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX>. Of course, it's also true that
if your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Agnes</ENAMEX> just can't stand the idea of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> reading the New York
Times , her anguish is a real cost of allowing freedom of the press. If
we're intellectually consistent, we'll cater either to both those preferences
or to neither.

            Not that everyone values intellectual consistency.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stevens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Massachusetts</ENAMEX> is identified in the
Times as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist</ENAMEX> who is skeptical of the concept of
existence value. The source of his skepticism: "What if you add up all these
numbers and they don't come out in our favor?" So much for statecraft as a
dispassionate attempt to balance competing interests. If the goal is simply to
make the numbers come out the way you want them to, you're not a policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>; you're just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
