
   
   
      
         
            Machines in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garden</ENAMEX>

            In the animated ecological
epic 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess Mononoke</ENAMEX>
               , the camera travels over landscapes with a
clear, steady gaze, like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zen</ENAMEX> hang glider. The images have none of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comin</ENAMEX>'-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-ya pop-surrealism of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cartoons, many of which have characters
that spring out of the frame like jack-in-the-boxes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayao Miyazaki</ENAMEX>, who spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess Mononoke</ENAMEX> and is
reported to have done <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of its paintings himself, seems to work from
the outside in: to begin with the curve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, then the mossy hills, the
watercolor foliage, the nubby <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>, the whorls on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, the meticulous
carvings on a teacup. He captures the texture of light and the currents of air.
You could almost settle down in this landscape. A view of nature that some
would call "<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>-hugging" doesn't feel softheaded when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> are rendered
in such brilliant and robust detail.

            But then, "soft" is not
a word you can apply to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mononoke</ENAMEX> , however pantheistic its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worldview</ENAMEX>. The film, which is rated PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>, is full of splattery carnage. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyazaki</ENAMEX> in long shot is contemplative, in close-up he's ferocious. He's both
inside and outside the action: He knows when to rock your world and when to
induce a state of sorrowful detachment. According to the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toy Story animators</ENAMEX> screened reels of his work when their
imaginations flagged, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> named an alien species
after one of his features. Watching <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mononoke</ENAMEX> --which has
been dubbed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney/Miramax</ENAMEX> specifications by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> but
retains its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX>-plus length, its gory beheadings, and its grim,
near-apocalyptic finale--you can understand their worship. It isn't that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyazaki</ENAMEX>'s work is technically so dazzling in this age of digitized miracles;
it's that everything is sublimely in proportion.

            The movie has a scope that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s homiletic,
follow-your-dream fables look even more solipsistic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyazaki</ENAMEX> is after nothing
less than the moment in our history (the film is set in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14 th</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>) when the power shifted from a "natural" world to one
shaped by human technology. It's the beginning of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McKibben</ENAMEX> called
"the end of nature"--that is, when nature became no longer an autonomous,
self-regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> but one touched (and, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miyazaki</ENAMEX>'s view, poisoned) by
human industry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ashitaka</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">warrior</ENAMEX> from the isolationist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emishi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clan</ENAMEX>, is forced in the first scene to kill
a marauding boar--a god turned into a demon (covered in roiling, corrosive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX>) by an iron ball lodged in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. Infected, destined to be consumed
by--and to die of--rage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashitaka</ENAMEX> leaves his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> in search of the iron
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ball</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. He discovers a fortress-cum-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>-manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> called
Irontown, presided over by one of the most complex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> in modern film: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">regal Lady Eboshi</ENAMEX>. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, she's a benevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX> who presides
over a warmly matriarchal society; on the other, she wants to destroy the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forest</ENAMEX>, harness its resources, and exterminate its animal deities--chiefly the
Spirit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forest</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">magnificent deer god</ENAMEX> whose touch brings instant life or
death, and who transforms at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX> into the towering <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night Walker</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P rincess Mononoke</ENAMEX> builds to a full-scale war between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and the animal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>--which does not, by the way, consist of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critters</ENAMEX>. In fact, the boars and apes have little patience
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashitaka</ENAMEX>'s call for nature and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX> to live together in harmony; they'd
like to eat him. The wolf god, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moro</ENAMEX>, is slightly more sympathetic, but that's
because her adopted "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX> (a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mononoke</ENAMEX>), is human. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX> is
first seen sucking a wound of her huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wolf mother</ENAMEX>, then, as the gore drips
from her mouth, training her dark eyes on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashitaka</ENAMEX> with feral hatred. Her
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> appearance--a lone attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irontown</ENAMEX> to assassinate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Eboshi</ENAMEX>--is one
of the movie's high points. It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyazaki</ENAMEX>'s use of sound--and silence--that
takes your breath away: the determined tap of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wolf princess</ENAMEX>'s shoes as she
scuttles over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fortress</ENAMEX>'s rooftops; the silence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eboshi</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> as
they stare at this tiny yet formidable tomboy against the black sky. Their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battle</ENAMEX> is so furious that the blades streak and lose definition--it's almost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subliminal</ENAMEX>.

            It's a shame that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wolf princess</ENAMEX> warms up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashitaka</ENAMEX> and spends the rest of the film either
saving him or being saved by him. She loses that punk-bitch allure. The voice
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Danes</ENAMEX> doesn't help. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danes</ENAMEX> says, "I'd do anything to get you
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> out of my forest," she sounds like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> peeved over lack of
parking spaces at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX> needs a more ragged voice--I'd be interested
to hear the original <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crudup</ENAMEX> is just as Disneyfied
(Miramaxed?), but that doesn't hurt as much because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashitaka</ENAMEX> is conceived from
the start as a rather bland ingénu. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gillian Anderson</ENAMEX>'s growling Moro sounds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">silly</ENAMEX> (she doesn't have the breath control), and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fey-hick</ENAMEX> tones of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Thornton</ENAMEX> are too recognizable as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akim Tamiroff</ENAMEX>-like mercenary, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jigo</ENAMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Driver</ENAMEX>--coming off a triumphantly dizzy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarzan</ENAMEX> --once
again provides a voice that the animators deserve. "Bring the strange-ah to me
late-ah," she commands in sexy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martian Queen</ENAMEX> cadences that will stir the loins
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flash Gordon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> everywhere. "I would like to thank him
puh-sonally."

            The overfamiliar voices nudge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mononoke</ENAMEX>
closer to its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>--but not by a lot. There's always something
wondrously strange. The "kodamas" are little tree spirits on doughboy bodies.
They cock their trapezoidal dice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> and emit a series of clicks; then their
heads pop back with a conclusive rattle. Something about them seems just right;
I could watch them for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. (Miyazaki limits their appearances to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>--he
doesn't wear out their mystery the way that, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas</ENAMEX> would.) And no
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> animated feature would end with such a powerful vision of apocalypse,
as the land is bestridden by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colossus</ENAMEX> dropping a thick, caustic, tarlike gel
that recalls the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX> "black <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>." Can you take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>? I think
so. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyazaki</ENAMEX> said at a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">New York Film Festival</ENAMEX> press conference, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Children</ENAMEX>
understand intuitively that the world they have been born into is not a blessed
world." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess Mononoke</ENAMEX> , at least, can tell them why.

            "A special smile ... a
certain touch ..." So begins the elevator-music theme song of 
                  Music of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX>
                ... "I never had a lot that I loved so much." The credits had
just started and I was already looking for a barf bag. Did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> and director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Craven</ENAMEX> have to work so hard to schlockify the story of Roberta Guaspari
(played here by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>), whose violin courses in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Harlem</ENAMEX> elementary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have become a beacon for such programs nationwide? A fabled taskmaster
(her story was told in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> documentary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Wonders</ENAMEX> ), Guaspari
used music as a way to teach self-discipline--along with the healthy
self-respect that follows in its wake. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> cut the
funding for her program, she proved a marvel of self-promotion, attracting
features in all the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> and ending up along with her best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Hall</ENAMEX> for a benefit "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fiddlefest</ENAMEX>"--along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itzhak Perlman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>, and other legendary "fiddlers."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX> has said that she spent so much of the time on the
set learning the violin (she doesn't play any instruments) that she didn't
bring the full force of her acting technique to bear on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roberta</ENAMEX>. Maybe that's
why the performance seems so natural. Let her always learn an instrument on the
set! Still, she doesn't make much sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guaspari</ENAMEX>. The script, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pamela Gray</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Walk on the Moon</ENAMEX> ), has her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> complain of her nastiness and
perfectionism, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX>--who has made herself look dumpy, thick-waisted, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bedraggled</ENAMEX>--is so busy telegraphing her vulnerability that all we get is dippy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">niceness</ENAMEX>. Instead of a monument to an individual's iron will, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX> of the
Heart becomes the story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> so helpless that she arouses the
kindness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX> of violent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genre</ENAMEX> pieces like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craven</ENAMEX> (who got this mainstream gig in return for doing the
Scream sequels) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Franklin</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Raimi</ENAMEX> sometimes want so badly to
belong to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Establishment Hollywood</ENAMEX>--to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>--that they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neuter</ENAMEX> themselves. Bending over backward to show how sensitive they can be,
they forget that violence--even if it's just emotional violence--belongs in
"ordinary" dramas, too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craven</ENAMEX> does good work with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> in the
classroom scenes, but the film has a reticence common to most biopics and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mushy</ENAMEX>, TV-movie humanism that blands out its texture. OK, I was a puddle after
some scenes, like the one where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guaspari</ENAMEX> pushes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to get her to improve
her posture and discovers that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is wearing a leg brace. But how much
more emotional the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Hall</ENAMEX> climax would have been if instead of suddenly
seeing these <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Harlem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on stage with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perlman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Bell</ENAMEX>, etc.,
we'd seen them rehearsing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and struggling to keep up. There's too
much music of the heart and not enough music of the callused fingers.

            In outline, 
                  The Limey 
                is a lean little
B-movie revenge melodrama about a felonious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terence Stamp</ENAMEX>) who's newly
sprung from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and flies to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> to get to the bottom of his
beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s death: "My name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> ... Who dunnit?" The film,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Soderbergh</ENAMEX>, would be worth seeing just for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stamp</ENAMEX>'s
performance, at once rock-hard and goofily blinkered, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Fonda</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">wittily</ENAMEX> self-parodic turn as the suspected killer, a music <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> who coasts
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'60s</TIMEX> counterculture easiness while his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">lackeys</ENAMEX> do the dirty work. ("Oh,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," he says, the fear finally seeping through the ether. "This is getting all
too close to me.")

            But the picture's glory is its layered and intricate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">syntax</ENAMEX>. The dialogue moves ahead--there are great gobs of exposition--but the
images continually double back: to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stamp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lesley Ann Warren</ENAMEX>, as his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, simply gazing at each other; or to Stamp sitting on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, remembering his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> on the beach, the lens of his home
movie camera creating an eerily bright--almost supernatural--spot that dances
over her face. The film's most violent act happens well off screen. (You hear
the distant "pop-pop-pop-pop-pop" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>.) The rest is only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-glimpsed, fantasized, or saturated by memory--or is the present the
memory? Is all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Limey</ENAMEX> a temporal hiccup?

            Some, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , have
questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soderbergh</ENAMEX>'s sanity. (But of course--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soderbergh</ENAMEX> flouts time!) I see
a method to his madness. Less grandiosely than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harmony Korine</ENAMEX> in Julien
Donkey-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy , Soderbergh</ENAMEX> pores over every scene in search of its essential
dramatic gesture. He's saying: This --not all that other stuff--is what's
important. He telegraphs the ending--you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limey</ENAMEX> will somehow be at the
root of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s death--but it's still an emotional wow. The climax
justifies the technique. It says the point of this odyssey isn't revenge but
regret--for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">irredeemably</ENAMEX> blown chances and a tragic waste of love.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soderbergh</ENAMEX> is one of those rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">filmmakers</ENAMEX> who learn
on the job. Working within a tight genre structure, he's discovering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of ways of editing a given scene that can give it the richness of a novel. Is
he totally successful? No; he misses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX>, which is why the technique
sticks out. But what a fantastic effort. See it and weep for what's missing in
most other movies.

         
      
   
