
   
   
      
         
            Was It Witchcraft? The Mystery of Flight 990

            
Despite the initial lack of any evidence of foul play in the crash of EgyptAir
Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">990</NUMEX> off the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> clung hopefully
to that possibility <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> were particularly interested
in the mystery of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano Porcari</ENAMEX>," which, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Aviation</ENAMEX>
Administration, is the signature on a letter it received in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, warning
that a bomb might be placed aboard an airliner departing from either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> noted that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano Porcari</ENAMEX> hijacked a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> and was sent briefly to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for it. But, according to
Corriere della
Sera of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> "seems not to know" that the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porcari</ENAMEX>, now
aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>, is currently in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Naples</ENAMEX> for a different crime. He was
arrested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> for stabbing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> to death in the central Italian
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orvieto</ENAMEX>. "But if it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porcari</ENAMEX>, who is hiding behind his identity<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> asked. "It is a mystery within a mystery."

            
Another common urge was to associate the crash with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repubblica of Rome</ENAMEX> began an overblown front-page article as follows:
"On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witches</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>--right in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witches</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>--the spell that swallowed up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> aircraft in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
in the same stretch of sky and sea seems to have been beating its wings and to
have consumed another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">217</NUMEX> lives flying on an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>." He said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s media now regard that stretch of sky and sea as "cursed"--"another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda Triangle</ENAMEX> ready for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new millennium</TIMEX>"--but he went on to explain
prosaically that the flight paths up the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are in
fact neither "bewitched nor cursed, but simply the busiest in the world."

            As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> began talks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha'aretz</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> still has no united policy on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> peace settlement. In a front-page report,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud Barak</ENAMEX> will offer statehood to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> in the "framework agreement" they are due to sign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next February</TIMEX>
and in exchange will demand that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Jerusalem</ENAMEX> as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>; but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> said in an editorial
that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have yet to deal with the heart of the conflict."
International confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> was restored following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>'s defeat of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> in the general election, but "[c]onfidence-building measures
can no longer suffice at this stage," it said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oslo</ENAMEX> summit, therefore, is
an important reminder of decisions yet to be made, without which the summit
will remain only a ceremony, without any of the requisite diplomatic content to
advance the process."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> marked the departure of the last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>
by describing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year</TIMEX> war to keep control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> as "an
historic error." But in an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the paper was optimistic about the
future. "With the kind of wise and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that now exists in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jakarta</ENAMEX>--and hopefully in the near future also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dili</ENAMEX>--there is every reason
to believe that a rapprochement is possible." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jakarta Post</ENAMEX> also
quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">East Timorese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Peace Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Ramos-Horta</ENAMEX> as ridiculing
claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX> would not be viable as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on its own: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> does
not have to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> to do slightly better than those incompetent, lazy,
corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bastards</ENAMEX> who managed our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years</TIMEX>. Sometimes I find it
laughable that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>] keep telling us that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>
cannot manage without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Morning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herald</ENAMEX> , which reported the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> evacuation under the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Timor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tormentors Slink Away</ENAMEX>," ran a long editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> extolling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s peacekeeping role and
expressing the hope that it might eventually lead to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Asian Nations</ENAMEX> adopting a collective security role in the region. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMH</ENAMEX> , which has been campaigning for a republican victory in this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s referendum to rid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> monarchy, published a
pro-monarchy article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Slezak</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New South Wales</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slezak</ENAMEX>'s argument is that without the queen,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australia</ENAMEX> "would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of jingoistic, sentimental flag-wavers. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t
may be the very irrelevance of royalty which has helped protect us from
excesses of patriotic fervor," he wrote--comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> favorably with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, who "have a cloying sentimentality about their history, their flag,
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and their system." An opinion poll published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian of London</ENAMEX>
found, surprisingly, that a large proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britons</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> should
ditch the monarchy: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty</NUMEX> percent said it should become a republic and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX>
percent that it should keep the queen as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX>
said its poll "could provide a much-needed boost" to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>'s republican
campaigners, who have been running slightly behind the monarchists in the
latest polls.

            The
cyclone disaster in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orissa</ENAMEX> on the east coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> prompted a breast-beating
editorial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of India</ENAMEX> . "Just what is it about us that we feel
so helpless before a natural disaster?" it asked. "Our achievements are
obviously world class in many spheres, science and technology and computers
being among them. We have the almighty nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> and, yet, we despair when
it comes to floods, droughts, cyclones and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">communicable diseases</ENAMEX>, many of them
entirely avoidable man-made disasters. ... It used to be said of the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> that while it excelled in such complicated endeavours as space
exploration, the smallest things would fox it--the tap would leak and the flush
would not work. Perhaps because we modelled ourselves after that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, we
seem to be affected by the same disregard for the smaller details, which, for
all their apparent insignificance, matter the most in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">press</ENAMEX> recovered
from its gloom over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> ruling against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> in its <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mad Cow War</ENAMEX> with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and found something to celebrate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s astounding semifinal
victory over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Blacks</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rugby World Cup</ENAMEX>
tournament in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blues flatten the Blacks</ENAMEX>" was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-column
front-page headline in Le
Figaro of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> press was generous. "All Blacks
humbled by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> tour de force" said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Telegraph</ENAMEX> , calling it
"the biggest upset in the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rugby World Cup</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> called it
"a blaze of gloire " and added: "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of remarkable sporting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">finishes</ENAMEX>, here was the most unexpected of victories for the most enchanting of
underdogs over the most intimidating of favorites. And what, now, will they do
for an encore<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> in the final of the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">cup</NUMEX> in
Cardiff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Saturday</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
