
   
   
      
         
            Beta <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>

            

               For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>, see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s "."
            

            Just
when it looked like this was going to be the most substantive presidential
election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, along comes the brouhaha over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This weekend</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign has been paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>, a feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> (recently reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>) to transform <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> from a
weak "beta" male into a strong "alpha" male. The media seized on the story
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Secret Guru</ENAMEX>," shouted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) as a fresh source of groans and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">titters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> agree that by hiring such a "controversial feminist," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embarrassed</ENAMEX> himself and exposed his personal and political "confusion." The
real confusion, however, seems to be over why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is controversial or
embarrassing.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
She's too radical. The prevailing complaint against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is that she's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">permissive</ENAMEX>, condom-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> who pushes sex on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Every news story
mentions her latest book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promiscuities</ENAMEX> (which, as every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> notes,
is written in "the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> sexual"), in which she reportedly "urges the
teaching of sexual techniques" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>--specifically, "instructing teenagers
how to masturbate and perform oral sex." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s idea was to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> satisfy
themselves without resorting to intercourse, but never mind.) Critics also
point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> has defended former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surgeon General Joycelyn Elders</ENAMEX>, who
lost her job in part for advocating similar ideas about masturbation.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are having a field day with naughty quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s book,
reading them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and faxing them to conservative talk shows. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
favorite quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is, "I want to explore the shadow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slut</ENAMEX> who walks
alongside us as we grow up, sometimes jeopardizing us and sometimes presenting
us with a new sense of authentic identity." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>
has issued a press release playing up the "shadow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">slut</ENAMEX>" quote and suggesting
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> should "run like crazy" from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> because he's "married." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
have even equated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s naughty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s adultery. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Tumulty</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> article, quipped,
"With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> you get a sex scandal, and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> it's a sex-education
scandal."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
She's too retro. Having branded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> a "controversial feminist," the media
turn around and deride her hierarchy of "alpha" and "beta" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> as a macho
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">throwback</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> snickers that she has counseled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to "bare his teeth"
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> and "take on the 'Alpha <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>' " in order to become "the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>."
Other reports say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is trying to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> "aggressive" and "dominating."
"growl," "sniff" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and "challenge him to arm wrestle. ... This will
surely win <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> the respect, admiration and sighs of countless <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>." RNC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chair Patricia Harrison</ENAMEX> mocks the insecurity of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice Presidents</ENAMEX> who worry
about their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alpha Male Status</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
She's too powerful. While poking fun at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s obsession with male power,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> insinuate that she's accumulating undue influence in the campaign. In a
front-page report on her "behind-the-scenes influence," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> cites
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> who say "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s tentacles stretch far beyond" the project to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
assigned her. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX> call her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mastermind</ENAMEX>." "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMINIST WEARS</ENAMEX>
THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PANTS ON TEAM GORE</ENAMEX>," screams the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> . The RNC headlines a
news release, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> & the Big Bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
She's overpaid. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> is somehow wielding all this
undue power without earning her consulting fee. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> who wonders "why there's a premium on her advice." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
"spends money" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> "like a drunken sailor in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX>." Conservative satirist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Buckley</ENAMEX> advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to hire other ineffectual literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>
at absurd rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>, gasping at the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s retainer--"for what?" he
asks--adds, "Who else is on the payroll, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Simmons</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Snow</ENAMEX> voices dismay that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> was "making more money from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> was making as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>"--a status that
surely no male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> could have achieved on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>
campaign.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
She's dangerous. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> may not be doing anything for her paycheck, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> conclude, but she's planting plenty of crazy ideas in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> calls her a "mad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says she
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demonstrates Gore</ENAMEX>'s "weird" taste in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX> calls her a "kook."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brit Hume</ENAMEX> warns that her "strange" advice is
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of "psychobabble." Fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX> calls her a "wild
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cannon</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.
She's frivolous. When they're not fretting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> has too many
pernicious ideas, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> scoff that she has none. They dismiss her as a
mere "wardrobe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>" who has shuffled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s "shirt-and-tie combination,"
instructed him to wear "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">brown</ENAMEX>, olive, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tan</ENAMEX>," and told him "to wear different
colored suits and all that"--evidently to no effect, since, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> dryly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observes</ENAMEX>, "polls have yet to record the difference."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>.
She's a crutch. Having declared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> insubstantial and impotent, her
detractors again reverse course, accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> of relying too heavily on her
for guidance and a definition of himself. "An alpha <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> would not need
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> at all. He would not have to be told who he is," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>. The RNC
jokes that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Real Alpha Males</ENAMEX>" don't have to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> "to learn how to
be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpha</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Males</ENAMEX>."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>.
She's a dirty little secret. Unable to agree on why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> should be
embarrassing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> have fallen back on the implication that she must
be embarrassing, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has been employing her "secretly," "funneling her
payments through other consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>," and conspiring to "conceal her from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> likens her to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s own once secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>" and suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> may have been keeping her under "deep
cover." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's front-page story notes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has gone to
great lengths to conceal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>'s role." And what exactly is the scandal about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is covering up? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have no answer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evidently</ENAMEX>, it's their
little secret.

         
      
   
