
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">333</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In No Sense</ENAMEX>" 

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Nelson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, has announced the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> release of a book with
the working title <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Death of Innocence</ENAMEX> . Name the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and subject.
( Question courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX>.)
               
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 332</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Believe It or Else":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               In a TV commercial debuting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> says: "It made
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe again, feel free again." Who's pitching what?
            

            "Does
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cher</ENAMEX> really need to publicize that song anymore? It's a hit, a triumphant
comeback, we get it."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Sullivan</ENAMEX>
            

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> : now with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> percent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Rosenthal</ENAMEX>!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radosh</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Carvell</ENAMEX> had a similar answer.)

            "At
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX>, they've published the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Singer</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Songwriters of the '70s Almost-Rhyming</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary</ENAMEX> !"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Delfin</ENAMEX>
            

            
"Whatever it is, if that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Jones</ENAMEX> doing the voice-over, I'm
buying!"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lofquist</ENAMEX>
            

            "I
don't know all the answers, fella. But I do know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> over there, in charge, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> ... his name is ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>. No
... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang</ENAMEX> ... No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>... either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang or Wong</ENAMEX>. Did I say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>? I meant to
say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wong</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris W. Kelly</ENAMEX>
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> conflated feeling free and feeling
fresh. The distinction between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is apparent in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King Jr.</ENAMEX>'s
eloquent and moving, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Have a Dream</ENAMEX>" speech, which would have been much less
effective had he concluded, "Fresh at last, fresh at last, thank God almighty,
I'm fresh at last."

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history, "feeling free" refers to
ridding the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of an oppressive monarch, a view expressed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Declaration of Independence</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> advertising, "feeling fresh" refers to
ridding oneself of vaginal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">odor</ENAMEX>, a view expressed by a fashion model clad in
white who has plucked every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX> from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and then painted in some
artificial eyebrows and perhaps drawn a silhouette of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> to
replace her pubic hair.

            It's like aromatherapy
as political expression: "We have nothing to fear but … is there a funny smell
in here? Is it me?" That's the slogan <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> was paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> to
provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. Or was it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sweet Smell of No Sex</ENAMEX>!" Or the rule-of-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Odorless, Colorless, Tasteless</ENAMEX>!" Or perhaps it was alpha-malevolent: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now With</ENAMEX>
Real <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beef Aroma</ENAMEX>." Somebody stop me. Was it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scents and Fiscal Sensibility"</ENAMEX>?
Hang on. Do I smell smoke? Yes, it's me. I'm hot! And menstrual. Somebody turn
a hose on me!

            
               Little Me
Answer
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX> is pitching
himself.

            In a spot running only in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> is particularly popular with those who've never lived where he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">governs</ENAMEX>--he touts his economic policies. Just before he delivers his toothy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slogan</ENAMEX>, the narrator says: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> got to work, creating a record
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">341,000</NUMEX> new jobs. Cutting taxes over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX>. Leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off welfare and
requiring those on it to work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> has made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> the safest large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>."

            What the narrator does
not say is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> live below the poverty line, a
number that has not improved under this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, even after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> of
economic expansion. But maybe that will be on the bumper stickers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B&N Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            Below, excerpts from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnes & Nobel</ENAMEX> ad describing books whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> will be appearing at
various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. Can you identify each book and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>?

            
               Ad Copy
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "insights on the power of music from a wide
swath of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry David Thoreau</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX>"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "reams of astute and acerbic correspondence"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "a stirring look at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> unafraid to stir
things up"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "entertainment for your whole mouth"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "a tender look at childhood"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. "a father-son bond involving a majestic
tree"

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super rich</ENAMEX> gel
that will give you the most comfortable shave ever"

            
               Answers
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Spirit <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Into Sound</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Hart</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Rooney</ENAMEX>
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Kaplan</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Not actually a book; this is the tag line from a
pack of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pop Rocks</ENAMEX> which also includes the sub-head, "more action" neither of
which would be an entirely inaccurate blurb for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vidal</ENAMEX> biography.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Spruce</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuomo</ENAMEX> book again. And I'm sure writing it
was much more rewarding than being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. More father-son
bonding from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX>? No. A tender passage from the back of a can of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edge</ENAMEX>
Pro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gel</ENAMEX>.

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Fire down below.

         
      
   
