
   
   
      
         
             Party at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>!

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> recently pointed out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX> has
paid relatively scant attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX> story, a failing of
which she's well aware. It's not that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> coverage of the 6-year-old
beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>'s murder has been anything less than scintillating. (A recent
highlight was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> 's astonishingly detailed painting of
the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s lifeless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, bloodied garrote and all.) But following the
story's back-and-forth arc can induce such a maddening case of whiplash that
it's been hard to find the proper moment to pause and reflect. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>'s
recent failure to return any indictments in the case seems an appropriate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juncture</ENAMEX>, although any hopes that the story might fade away were dashed by this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> cover, which shows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">JonBenet</ENAMEX> with the words "IT'S NOT OVER"
printed menacingly across her forehead.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX>, one
could almost hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ramsey</ENAMEX> machine kick into high gear as each
magazine tried to make sure it would be on record as having outguessed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>. (Although after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly three years</TIMEX> on the case, it's probably safe
to assume that they've all accused the correct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> at some point.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> forecast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> "bombshells" and
pointed fingers in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy Ramsey</ENAMEX>'s general direction. But more intriguing was
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's report on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX>'s grooming habits: With her marriage
"wrecked" by the strain, she reportedly slipped away to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,300-</NUMEX>a<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">-week Georgia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spa</ENAMEX>, where, because she "is always concerned about her upper lip getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hairy</ENAMEX>," she had a much-needed lip wax "to clear away the dark bristles."

            Not to be outdone by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's hairy-lip scoop,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> ran <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon Loughrin</ENAMEX>'s undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expos√</ENAMEX>© on the
"shocking sex and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, where JonBenet
was killed. Posing as a partygoer at a bash thrown by the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loughrin</ENAMEX> writes as if she were on a pilgrimage to
some sacred mountain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andes</ENAMEX>. The occupants, she writes, "hold regular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> ... drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, listening to loud music and"--please <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shannon</ENAMEX>, tell
us it's not so--"playing games like foosball into the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning hours</TIMEX>
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramseys</ENAMEX> once lived." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loughrin</ENAMEX>'s insights run from
the profound ("I realized how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX>'s frilly, feminine decorative taste
clashed with that of the young college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>") to the truly anguished ("I
passed a spiral staircase on my right, shuddering as I realized these were the
same stairs where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patsy</ENAMEX> claimed to have found the ransom note that fateful
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>").

            Perhaps sensing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loughrin</ENAMEX> could use a little time away from the story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> hired
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo Dietl</ENAMEX> to investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JonBenet</ENAMEX>'s death.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dietl</ENAMEX>'s first dispatch from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, the no-nonsense ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> claimed to have
already zeroed in on the "real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>," claiming that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> had
been "going after the wrong suspects since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day One</ENAMEX>." And while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dietl</ENAMEX> stopped
short of actually naming anyone, a teaser assured us that the following week
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> would reveal "who really killed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">JonBenet</ENAMEX> and why." And sure
enough, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next week</TIMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dietl</ENAMEX> peeling away even more tantalizing layers:
JonBenet, he stated definitively, was not murdered by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>,
although he accused them of lying and hiding information that would solve the
crime. And what of the promised revelation? A breathless Keeping Tabs made it
all the way to the end of the story, only to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dietl</ENAMEX>, citing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>'
advice, wimp out without naming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>--a decision that instantly shot him to
the top of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keeping Tabs</ENAMEX>' public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> list.

            If they are indeed as "close to a divorce" as the
Star claims, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramseys</ENAMEX> might take comfort in the fact that they're in
good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. In fact, we'd be hard pressed to find a celebrity marriage that
didn't go under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>. Wandering eyes seem to be behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share
of splits, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo Rivera</ENAMEX>--who the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> says "sneaked a sexy young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on board his luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sailboat</ENAMEX> for steamy lovemaking sessions while his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>"--to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s Most Wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Walsh</ENAMEX>,
who was "caught in the arms of a sexy blonde," per the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> . But the
tabs can't agree on what caused shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>'s recent split with his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> claims that she lost it when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> "cheated on
her--with a porn tape!" while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> points to the radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>'s
"increasingly out of control partying," including "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">wild nights</TIMEX> with strippers."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enquirer</ENAMEX> confidently sums it all up in "one word: obsession."
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>'s lifestyle was dictated by his obsession with his career," explains a
source.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX> wandering eye, however, still belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, who
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> tardily reports) hit on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper Gore</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1992</TIMEX> campaign.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gores</ENAMEX>' marriage has apparently withstood the challenge, however; the
Star claims that they are planning to have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. (The couple
reportedly acknowledges that since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tipper</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>, "natural conception is a long
shot.") But other problems seem to be looming for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enquirer</ENAMEX> maintains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s adherence to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atkins</ENAMEX> diet has "dumbed
him down" and "impacted his thought processes": The avowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist</ENAMEX> is
eating steak and recently approved a resumption of whaling.

            Perhaps the only celebrity divorce where stepping out was
not a factor was that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie Rowe</ENAMEX>, a parting
that even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> had a hard time trying to instill with the slightest
hint of dramatic tension. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> actually trumpeted: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exposed</ENAMEX>!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s marriage was a sham." We wondered where on earth there might be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to whom this shocking secret would have to be "exposed"--until the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> reminded us of that remote research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX> from
which cancer-stricken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerri Nielsen</ENAMEX> had to be evacuated. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX>, who has universally been lauded as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, is
actually a "sad, selfish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>" who cheated on her ex-husband and deserted her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> might be heartened to learn that
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , his first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Marie Presley</ENAMEX>, is "still
nuts" about him, even though she's seriously involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oszajca</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> took what has to be the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'90s</ENAMEX> devotional step by investing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> in computer-generated photos
of what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would look like. In a similar vein, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presley</ENAMEX> might want
to check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's computer simulation of what her ex might look
like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> without plastic surgery. Which leads us to the only real bombshell
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of pop, it turns out, is actually an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
