
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">329</NUMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies Foist</ENAMEX>"

            
               "Please be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lady</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> chided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Woolsey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing
room <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. Then he sicced the cops on her. What had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolsey</ENAMEX>
done?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Question
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 328</ENAMEX>)--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hello, Wieners":</ENAMEX>
            

            

               
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times as likely to do it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> as on any other
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. Do what?
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Turn</ENAMEX>
off the television and go outside."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Pollack</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carlin</ENAMEX>
had a similar answer.)

            
"Strangle another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gummy worm</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nell Scovell</ENAMEX>
            

            "Pick
up a bacterial infection from hanging around the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">undead</ENAMEX>."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>
Markoe
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can I</ENAMEX>
give a shout out to my peeps? Yo, yo, what up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shacky and T</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keepin</ENAMEX>' it real in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da H</ENAMEX>-town."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon W. Davis</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trick</ENAMEX>
or treat. And frankly, the number seems a tad low to me."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Carvell
            

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            Many responses remark on our sedentary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>,
barely able to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>, let alone the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, sedated by the television,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX>, the ennui, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quaaludes</ENAMEX>. Budget cuts have eliminated sports
programs in many urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX>, once the vigorous instruments of
suburban freedom, are rarely spotted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> fear for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in heavy suburban traffic. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> are now sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, all too
often wearing ill-advised spandex pants.

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> study cites
the immobilizing effect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. A report on the increased rate of obesity
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> (from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991 to 1</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>) shows the biggest
increase--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">67.2 percent</NUMEX>--in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, with a hefty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">101.8 percent</NUMEX> gain in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>. The cause: not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>'s sprawl keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sitting in
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, encouraging them to eat fatty fast food and run down kids
who, bloated and logy from their indoor lifestyle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX>-less and slow,
staggering along on foot, slowed by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35-pound</NUMEX> backpacks, make easy targets and a
sickening sort of "squish" sound. It's like dodge ball, but with an actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX>.

            
               Screech of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bats</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brakes Answer</ENAMEX>
            

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times as likely to be fatally struck by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. Trick? Treat? The study is
a little vague in its conclusions.

            
               Get It off Your
Chest Extra
            

            I give the expression of
dismay; you give its object.

            
               Dismay
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. "Shock, horror, disappointment."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. "There are phenomenal shenanigans and
accusations."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. "They're full of blackish, horizontal lines and
some have worms in them."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. "So fat and windy that they sit, with some
exceptions, like hefty neglected lumps."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. "It's another reason
to move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>."

            
               Object
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Johnson</ENAMEX>, amateur <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pinball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX>, reacts
to the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WMS Industries</ENAMEX> is shutting down its assembly line, leaving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern Pinball</ENAMEX> as the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> of the beloved game. (But go ahead and
make up an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta Braves</ENAMEX> joke if you like.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bohdan Krawchenko</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> democratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>, is dismayed at his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s rigged presidential elections. (Note to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">translator</ENAMEX>: What is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> for "shenanigans"?)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> is disappointed with the way
their new shows look on television. No, wait. I'm wrong. It's a letter-writer
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> who's having trouble with his organic carrots.
(Probable cause: The "wonderful world of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">carrot rust fly</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Prognosis:</ENAMEX>
excellent.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> is disgusted by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>.
Or perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Arnold</ENAMEX> thinks a lot of books are just
too darned big. (And on a personal note, it's just so sad when any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> is
neglected. I think that's the message of that new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX> movie where she
plays a heroic violin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>.)

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> has
had it with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>. Or an unnamed beverage industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> hates
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>'s plan to put temperature sensors in its vending machines to
automatically raise the price of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> on hot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. (But he wasn't so snippy
about my plan to affix temperature sensors to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Common
Denominator
            

            Razor blades.

         
      
   
