
   
   
      
         
             <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX>

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s Bringing
Out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX> are the latest evidence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s status as a critical
favorite. This is not because the notices have been uniformly glowing--it's
been some time since a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> picture won unanimous praise from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reviewers</ENAMEX>--but because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> remains, almost uniquely among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX>, an embodiment of the beleaguered idea that filmmaking, and therefore
film criticism, can be a serious, important, life-and-death matter. Here, for
instance, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>, all thumbs:

            
               To look at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bringing Out the Dead</ENAMEX> --to look, indeed, at almost
any <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> film--is to be reminded that film can touch us urgently and
deeply. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> is never on autopilot, never panders, never sells out, always
goes for broke; to watch his films is to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> risking his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, not
simply exercising it. He makes movies as well as they can be made.
            

            Never? Always? This is pure ideology--which is not
to say that it isn't, to some extent, true. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s weaker films
bristle with energy and intelligence. But look closely at what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX> says: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
be reminded of the power of film as a medium is not quite the same as being
moved by a particular film, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bringing Out the Dead</ENAMEX> is, for all its
hectic pacing and breakneck intensity, an oddly unmoving experience. Yes, you
think, movies can touch us urgently and deeply. Why doesn't this one? If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> makes movies as well as they can be made, why does one so often feel
that his movies--especially over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade or so</TIMEX>--could have been
better?

            Above all, to look at
Bringing Out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX> is to be reminded of a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>
films. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have noted its similarities with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Driver</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Schrader</ENAMEX> (who also wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Temptation of Christ</ENAMEX> and the later drafts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> ). Both
movies feature a disturbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX> cruising the nightmarish,
as-yet-ungentrified <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> in search of redemption. In place of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sport</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX>'s suave, vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimp</ENAMEX> in the earlier film, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bringing Out</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dead features Cy</ENAMEX>, a suave, vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Curtis</ENAMEX>.
The mood here is a good deal softer: The scabrous nihilism of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driver</ENAMEX> is no longer as palatable--or, perhaps, as accurate in its response
to the flavor of the times or the mood of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX>--as it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Pierce</ENAMEX> saves <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cy</ENAMEX> from a death as gruesome as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travis Bickle</ENAMEX> visited on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sport</ENAMEX>, and when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> does take a life (in the
movie's best, most understated scene), it's an act of mercy.

            Aside from these parallels and variations, there's plenty
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bringing Out the Dead</ENAMEX> to remind you that you're watching a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>
picture. There's voice-over narration. There's an eclectic, relentless rock 'n'
roll score and a directorial cameo--this time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> provides the disembodied
voice of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ambulance dispatcher</ENAMEX>. There are jarring, anti-realist effects
embedded in an overall mise en scène of harsh verisimilitude. And, of
course, there is the obligatory religious imagery--the final frames present a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic Pietà</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Arquette</ENAMEX> (whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>) cradling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of sorrows, in her arms. To survey <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s oeuvre is to
find such echoings and prefigurations in abundance. Look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boxcar</ENAMEX>
Bertha , a throwaway piece of apprentice-work he made for schlock impresario
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Corman</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX> (if you've never seen it, imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX> and
Clyde remade as an episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kung Fu</ENAMEX> ), and then look at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Temptation of Christ</ENAMEX> , the controversial, deeply personal rendering of Nikos
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kazantzakis</ENAMEX>' novel which infuriated some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half</TIMEX> later.
Different as they are, both films prominently feature <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a crucifixion and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Hershey</ENAMEX> naked.

            Well, that may be a coincidence. But it's hard to
think of an active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> who has produced such an emphatically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-referenced body of work who seems not so much to repeat himself (though
he does some of that) as to make movies by recombining a recognizable and
fairly stable set of narrative, thematic, and stylistic elements. In other
words, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> is the last living incarnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">la politique des</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">auteurs</ENAMEX>.
            

            That old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">politique</ENAMEX> --the auteur theory, in plain <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>--was first articulated in
the 1950s by a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, many of whom went on to become, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directors</ENAMEX>, fixtures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nouvelle Vague</ENAMEX> . In a nutshell, the
theory--brought to these shores in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> film critic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sarris</ENAMEX>--held that, like any work of art, a film represents the vision of
an individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, almost always the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who populated the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">auterist canon</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hawks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Ford</ENAMEX>, pre-eminently--had labored within
the constraints of the studio system. But even their lesser films, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">auterist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, could be distinguished from mere studio hackwork by the
reiteration of a unique cinematic vocabulary and by an implicit but
unmistakable sense of solitary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> in conflict with bureaucratic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">philistinism</ENAMEX>.

            The auteur theory was quickly challenged, most notably by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kael</ENAMEX>, who shredded <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sarris in the pages of Film Quarterly</ENAMEX> . But
the "new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>--with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kael</ENAMEX> as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX>, scold, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassandra</ENAMEX>--was dominated by young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> who attained, thanks to the
collapse of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>, an unprecedented degree of creative autonomy, and
who thought of themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. What resulted, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Biskind</ENAMEX> shows in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Hollywood dish bible Easy Riders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bulls</ENAMEX> , was an epidemic
of megalomania, sexual libertinism, money-wasting, and drug abuse--as well as a
few dozen classics of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>.

            The avatars of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> were mostly "movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brats</ENAMEX>"--socially maladroit, nerdy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (and
they were, to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>) who shared a fervid, almost religious devotion to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cinema</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>, a runty, asthmatic altar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> who traded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> seminary for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX> film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, was
arguably the purest in his faith. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford Coppola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lucas</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St. Martin"</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biskind</ENAMEX> calls him) did not see directing as
a route to world domination but as a priestly avocation, a set of spiritual
exercises embedded in technical problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s technical proficiency won
him some early breaks. While <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">making Who's That Knocking at My Door</ENAMEX> , his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">earnest</ENAMEX>, autobiographical first feature, independently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> was hired to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">edit Woodstock</ENAMEX> into a coherent film. His success (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more or less</NUMEX>) led to
more rock 'n' roll editing assignments--a traveling sub-Woodstock "festival"
called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine Ball Caravan</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tour</ENAMEX> --and then to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boxcar Bertha</ENAMEX> , which allowed him to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directors Guild</ENAMEX> and gave
him the chance to make <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mean Streets</ENAMEX> . That movie helped launch the
careers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX>, and taught generations of would-be
tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> the meaning of the word "mook."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kael</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mean Streets</ENAMEX> "a triumph of personal
film-making," and even though it may be the single most imitated movie of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 30 years</TIMEX>--cf The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greenwich Village</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of Grace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyz N the Hood</ENAMEX> , etc.--it has lost remarkably little of its freshness
and power. Watching it, you feel that you are seeing real life on the screen,
but real life heightened and shaped by absolute artistic self-assurance. Or, to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quote Kael</ENAMEX> again, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mean Streets</ENAMEX> never loses touch with the ordinary look
of things or with common experience. Rather, it puts us in closer touch with
the ordinary, the common, by turning a different light on them."

            This kind of realism
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> films, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alice Doesn't Live Here Anymore</ENAMEX> --his
best piece of directing-for-hire, and one of the half-forgotten gems of the
period--and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Driver</ENAMEX> , both of which were critically and commercially
successful. But the medium-budget, artisanal, personal filmmaking of the early
'70s soon gave way to grander visions. To be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> was to
flirt with hubris. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biskind</ENAMEX>'s book, accordingly, concludes with a litany of
spectacular flameouts: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coppola's Apocalypse Now and One From the</ENAMEX>
Heart, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Friedkin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorcerer</ENAMEX>, and, of
course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Cimino</ENAMEX>'s Heaven's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gate</ENAMEX> . According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mardik Martin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s erstwhile writing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> (as quoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biskind</ENAMEX>): "The auteur theory
killed all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> films, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> told them they were
geniuses, that they could do anything. They went completely <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX>. They
thought they were God." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Götterdämmerung</ENAMEX> came with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , a hugely ambitious jazz epic starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Niro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liza</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minelli</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> at the time), and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a series of flops
that continued with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy</ENAMEX> .

            Of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> has been singled out for
vindication. It's the highest-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">of the three Scorsese</ENAMEX> films on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Film Institute</ENAMEX>'s Top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> list, and it's widely considered to be his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterpiece</ENAMEX>. But it remains exceedingly hard to watch, not so much because of
the repulsiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake La Motta</ENAMEX> as because of its overall sense of
aesthetic claustrophobia. It's a movie lacquered by its own self-importance, so
bloated with the ambition to achieve greatness that it can barely move. If it
convinces you it's a masterpiece, it does so by sheer brute force.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> is
undone by its own perfectionism. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of
Comedy stand up rather better, in my opinion, in spite of their obvious
flaws. (So does <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Waltz</ENAMEX> , a documentary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band</ENAMEX>'s last concert
done simultaneously with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , thanks to the magic of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>.) For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is virtually the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> movie (aside from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Lessons</ENAMEX>," his crackerjack contribution to the
Coppola-produced anthology film <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New York Stories</ENAMEX> ) to have at its center
the relationship between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. For another, it ends with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liza</ENAMEX>
Minelli parading through a series of phantasmagoric stage sets singing a
pointedly ironic song called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Happy Endings"</ENAMEX>--a sequence every bit as dazzling
(and as mystifying) as the ballet from An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> . Just as
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mean Streets</ENAMEX> is an unparalleled demonstration of the power of film to
convey reality, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Endings</ENAMEX>" is a celebration of film's magical ability to
create it. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">moviegoer</ENAMEX>'s dream, but good luck seeing it on the big screen.

            For its part, The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy</ENAMEX> , a creepy reprise
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Driver</ENAMEX> --played, this time, for laughs--is a movie made before
its time, back when celebrity-stalking was a piquant metaphor for our cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ills</ENAMEX>, rather than the focus of our cultural life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Niro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Bernhard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kidnap Jerry Lewis</ENAMEX> (playing, brilliantly, a famous late-night talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernhard</ENAMEX> steals the movie, and the ending is guaranteed to provoke long,
excruciating arguments about the difference between fantasy and reality.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biskind</ENAMEX>'s account of the tragedy of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> is the villain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal Ashby</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scarred survivor</ENAMEX>. After the failures of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX>, he picked himself up
and made some more movies: the quirky, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">proto-Indie</ENAMEX> downtown comedy After
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Color of Money</ENAMEX> (a respectable sequel to The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> ), and his long dreamed of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Temptation of Christ</ENAMEX> . His
fortunes revived with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GoodFellas</ENAMEX> , which was hailed as a return to form,
and floundered again with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Age of Innocence</ENAMEX> , one of his periodic
attempts--like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Waltz , Temptation and</ENAMEX>, most recently,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kundun</ENAMEX> --to defy expectation. Next came <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX>, one of his
periodic attempts to defy the expectation that he would defy expectations.
Casino blends Raging 
               Bull with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GoodFellas</ENAMEX> and can
be interpreted as a wry allegory of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>--a time when "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
like us" (i.e., the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-lancing gangsters</ENAMEX> played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pesci</ENAMEX>)
were allowed to run things without interference. Of course, they got too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">greedy</ENAMEX>, screwed everything up, and the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> turned their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>
into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyland</ENAMEX>. At the end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, the scarred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX>, picks
himself up and goes back to work.

            Scorsese keeps working too--upcoming projects
include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gangs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> , with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean Martin</ENAMEX>
biopic starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>. His extracurricular good works--overseeing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-release of classics such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Cid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Belle de Jour</ENAMEX> ,
campaigning for film preservation, narrating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> documentary on his favorite
movies--are testament to his abiding faith. But his movies more often than not
feel cold and mechanical. They substitute intensity for emotion and give us
bombast when we want passion. Why do we go to the movies? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Kael</ENAMEX> used to
say it was to be caught up, swept away, surfeited by sensation, and confronted
by reality. Some of us keep going to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s movies because we still want to
believe in that, and we leave wondering whether he still does.

         
      
   
