
   
   
      
         
             White-on-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Crime</ENAMEX> 

            

               "Even if racism were to disappear <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>, this would do nothing to
improve black test scores, increase black entrepreneurship, strengthen black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, or reduce black-on-black crime. These problems have taken on a
cultural existence of their own and need to be confronted in their own terms."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinesh D'Souza</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX>

            A group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> is
mounting a behind-the-scenes campaign to persuade <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-runner George W. Bush</ENAMEX> to speak out on what one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> has called
"the unspoken domestic crisis of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next millennium</TIMEX>": White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> preying
on white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            These thinkers note that white sociopaths most
often prey on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of their own race, citing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High School</ENAMEX>
shootings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> massacre; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Trump</ENAMEX>'s presidential candidacy as examples.

            "It's white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
are suffering disproportionately yet no white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> want to talk about
it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Pepper</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eldridge Cleaver School of Law</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, who has written extensively on the roots of white crime. "A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is growing up in fear and the traditional white leadership
seems out of touch."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX>'s arguments, while controversial, are based on a
mixture of sociological data and political calculation that even his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> do
not entirely dismiss. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> study of crime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58 percent</NUMEX> of white crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> were victimized by fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. And while crime has been decreasing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX> notes that it is falling
most slowly among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Crime Victimization Survey</ENAMEX> reports
that while the number of violent crime victimizations per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fell
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49 to 42</TIMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>, it only fell from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38 to 36</TIMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX> is passionate that the issue must be
addressed.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fifteen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High</ENAMEX> shootings, all but one of them white," the genial, bearded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">academic</ENAMEX> said in a recent interview. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> want to blame <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. Traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> blame a decline in moral standards, which is more on the mark.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and bad values don't kill white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. White <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kill white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. "

            In a compilation of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> prominent violent incidents between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994 and 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Blanco</ENAMEX>, a criminal justice policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Institute</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reactionary Reform</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tank</ENAMEX>, noted that virtually all of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> were white.

            "From the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX>
bombing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>'s rampage, the pattern is clear," Blanco
wrote in a recent article for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page.
"The new cohort of amoral middle-class white male <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX> has a cultural
existence of its own. It must be confronted in its own terms. But virtually no
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> will admit it. That vacuum creates an opportunity
for real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blanco</ENAMEX> have conferred with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> twice since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-August</TIMEX> to discuss their ideas, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> on the campaign. While a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> declined to comment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX>
said that he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> used the meetings to advance two ideas.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>, we said the message needs to be that white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to pull themselves up by their bootstraps," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX> said.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> is not the solution. For example, the idea of putting the Ten
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commandments</ENAMEX> in every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> is attractive but, in the long run, federally
funded stone tablets will only breed dependency on the nanny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX>, we said that
government does have a limited role in addressing the problem. Maybe there
should be block grants to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that would enable them to give a tax break
to every white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> who buys a high-quality <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">handgun</ENAMEX>. That would
really deter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX> in the school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX>. At the same time it would
teach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> about the real-life value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Second Amendment</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blanco</ENAMEX> said he emphasized the political potential of the
white-on-white crime issue for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.

            "Fairly or unfairly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have been
pigeonholed as being soft on white lawbreakers, whether it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver North</ENAMEX> or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Posse Comitatus</ENAMEX>," he said in an interview in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talking</ENAMEX> candidly about white crime is a way to break that perception."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blanco</ENAMEX> said that while traditional interest groups
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> might be offended, the broader <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> would get the
message.

            "The issue is really
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compassion</ENAMEX>," he said. "After all, the vast majority of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't
deranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX>. They are hard working and pay their taxes too. They're the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> here."

            Already some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> are objecting. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Always Right</ENAMEX> wrote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX>'s argument amounted to "a blame-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>-type approach that only
serves to help those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> who want to avoid
sharing responsibility for getting at the root causes of what is really a
societywide problem."

            The larger issue, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwame Jackson</ENAMEX>, professor
emeritus at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morehouse College</ENAMEX>, is the culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Littleton</ENAMEX>,
Jonesboro, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Paducah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edenboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> where
the white-on-white crime epidemic is the worst.

            "Let's face it, the
pathologies are severe in these areas," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said. "Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> grow up
listening to country music lyrics that mock the sanctity of marital vows. The
dependency on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> for free medical care is widespread. And the
intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> who once defended standards have proved all too willing to
go silent in the face of deviant behavior like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s affair with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophisticates</ENAMEX> will sneer but these things have an effect."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, considered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX>
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>, introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blanco</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>. He said he was confident the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> would be
receptive to their thinking.

            "I get the sense of a magnificent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
Reagan-like intellect absorbing the best ideas of a generation while remaining
optimistic and inclusive," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> sought to distance his efforts from the
views of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray Charles</ENAMEX>, who holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elijah Muhammad Chair for the Study of</ENAMEX>
Racial Realism at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' recent monograph The Caucasian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coefficient</ENAMEX> has triggered a fierce debate in academic circles. Writing for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Statistical Science Association</ENAMEX>'s Web site (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASSAnine</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>) last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> marshaled an array of data to argue that the appropriate
response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> tragedy would be for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to fund a
study of the gene structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.

            "Is there a biologically
based explanation for the tendency of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> to slaughter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> in
public?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> asked. "We need to ask the hard questions and not shy away if
the answers are politically incorrect."

            In an accompanying editorial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASSAnine</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> said
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s views, "while offensive to some, deserve the utmost in thoughtful
discussion" and announced that the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> issues of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> would be
devoted entirely to debating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>' thesis.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> has some good ideas," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said, "but I
think he goes too far with the notion that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are biologically
disposed toward crime and violence. I mean, some of my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. We need a more compassionate approach to white-on-white crime."

         
      
   
