
   
   
      
         
            Poetic Juice

            
               Subject:
Poems That Satisfy

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Robert Pinsky in The Fray</ENAMEX>"

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristine Domingo</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>

            I doubt there are any more questions you have yet
to answer with regards to poets and poetry, you, or your poems, but for the
sake of obtaining a reply from you, here's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groupie</ENAMEX>'s question: What poem of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yours</ENAMEX> has satisfied you the most?

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poems That Satisfy</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Robert Pinsky in The Fray</ENAMEX>"

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>

            Kristine, this is like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> being asked to name
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite child</ENAMEX>. And to stretch that metaphor, the youngest one--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> just
finished--sometimes gives the greatest satisfaction.

            Once, when I visited a writing class in a
medium-security <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>, urged by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX>, recited by
memory my little poem "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exile</ENAMEX>." That was a satisfying moment. Entering another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s memory with your words, perhaps a person quite different from
yourself, is in certain ways more glorious than any prize or title.

            (To reply, click
here.)

            

               [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Poet Laureate</ENAMEX> 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s poetry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> .]
            

            
               Subject:
Starting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poetic Engine</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Robert Pinsky in The Fray</ENAMEX>"

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Kobielus</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>

            As a general habit, how do you personally start
writing a new poem? Do you start with an interesting title and then write
around it? Or an interesting <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> line? Or the kernel of a core
subject/message? Or simply an abstract rhythm, cadence, or melody to which you
must give voice?

            Once you start, how do you know you're done? When
does it feel complete?

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: Starting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poetic Engine</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Robert Pinsky in The Fray</ENAMEX>"

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Fri
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oct</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>

            A good question, but not only is everybody
different--many of us are different at different times of life, maybe even at
different times of day.

            The best I can describe the process for me is that
it resembles noodling on a piano: I run rhythms and sentences--or maybe not
even sentences, the shapes of sentences--across one another, trying out
their sounds, and sometimes I get a tune-like combination of sound and syntax
that makes me want to go on, extend and refine it, as it comes to dredge
sustenance from the great pool of feelings and ideas that accumulates in a
life.

            It's a physical process, because the voice is
physical. And everything I've said about germination applies to termination--a
silly rhyme I've just stumbled on--as well.

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aesthetic Genius</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon Warner</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Mon
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov 1</ENAMEX>

            I agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> is probably the most
important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but I find it less easy to pass
over his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> film The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age of Innocence</ENAMEX> [as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX> does]. I
completely disagree that this film substitutes intensity for emotion. The point
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> being difficult to watch many times is well made but
Age of Innocence improves with each viewing.

            The film is the most beautiful thing I can remember
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kundun</ENAMEX> comes close though). The subtlety of the direction is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breathtaking</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> moments standing out for me: the bursts of color
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploding</ENAMEX> onto the screen during the opera sequence; the steadicam shot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Day Lewis</ENAMEX> entering the post-opera ball (with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanne Woodward</ENAMEX>'s sublime
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice-over</ENAMEX>); and my favorite, one quick external shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>,
showing it seemingly in the middle of nowhere and saying more in a single shot
about her social exclusion than other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> could achieve in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pages of
dialogue. If you have not seem this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gem</ENAMEX> recently I urge you to revisit it, it's
fantastic.

            (To reply, click
here.)

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aesthetic Genius</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Mon
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov 1</ENAMEX>

            I can't speak for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX>, but I saw [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of
Innocence ] again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> and found the technique that you admire
a distraction. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> at the time described the movie admiringly as
"virile"--and I'm forced to agree. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> is working so hard to show that he
can make a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s picture" in a robust manner that he loses touch with his
supposed themes. And he doesn't begin to get inside his impotent male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">protagonist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. You're right the film is full of astonishing moments--stuff
as good on its own terms as anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> has done. But I wonder if anyone
even remembers what the film is supposed to be about.

            
               Kundun , on the other hand, really is a
triumphant merging of form and content. I'm less enchanted by the content than
many, but I certainly respect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s struggle to alter his directorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX> and usual amphetamine rhythms to portray the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>.

            (To reply, click
here.)

            

               [ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. ]
            

            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aesthetic Genius</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.O. Scott</ENAMEX>

            
               Date: Mon
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov 1</ENAMEX>

            I wish I'd had sufficient space to say more about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age of Innocence</ENAMEX> --not to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kundun</ENAMEX> , After
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodfellas</ENAMEX> --but I pretty much agree with [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s]
take on it. It does indeed have virtuosic moments, but the central love
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triangle</ENAMEX> is entirely inert. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> just doesn't do courtship as well as he
does male friendship. I think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> is a case, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX> , of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> overwhelming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> with technique, and producing
visceral effects rather than emotional responses. (This is true of
Goodfellas as well, in my view--a completely exhilarating movie that
nonetheless has a certain coldness at its heart.)

            Now, these effects are powerful, and the technical
command behind them is extraordinary--unparalleled, I'm willing to stipulate,
among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s generation. The argument of my piece is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> is often hailed as a visionary on the basis of his technical
discipline and formal panache, but that in too many cases the vision seems
tired or blurred. I wish I'd had space and time to examine each of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s
films more closely, and to contextualize them to everyone's satisfaction, but
I've enjoyed following this discussion so far and look forward to more.

            (To reply, click
here.)


            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox Lost in the Wilderness</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Lewis</ENAMEX>

            
               Date:
Tues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov 2</TIMEX>

            The account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Lee</ENAMEX>'s manservant [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wm</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mack Lee</ENAMEX>] seems to be made up of whole cloth, as he recounts how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marse Robert</ENAMEX>
got mad at him only once during the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>--on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3, 1863</TIMEX>, down in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wilderness</ENAMEX>. As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3rd</TIMEX> was in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>, it
seems unlikely.

            (To reply, click here.)

            

               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chatterbox Lost in the Wilderness</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>
Noah

            
               Date: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov 3</ENAMEX>

            Several <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buffs</ENAMEX> have written to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fray</ENAMEX> to
point out that in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s memoir snippet can't possibly be true because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Lee</ENAMEX> was at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stonewall Jackson</ENAMEX> was dead on the specific
date <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> mentions.

            My item correctly quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rev Lee</ENAMEX>'s book, but it
[the book] was written when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> was an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and is obviously faulty on
this point. It's also possible that the error lay with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> was quoting from in his book. (None of the above,
incidentally, has any bearing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s usage of the word "bumfuzzled.")

            (To reply, click
here.)


            
               Subject:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">O.J. the Alpha Male</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>:
""

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillis Heller</ENAMEX>

            
               Date:
Tues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov 2</TIMEX>

            The confluence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s attempt to become an alpha
male and the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Payton</ENAMEX> brings to mind the now-macabre episode of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>, the quintessential alpha. In
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> skit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> are watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> on TV and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Payton</ENAMEX> is
close to topping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>'s rushing record. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> tells his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> what a great
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">athlete Walter</ENAMEX> is and how he wishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> all the best. And then he goes to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> for a beer and sticks pins into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Payton</ENAMEX> voodoo doll.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payton</ENAMEX> is down, leg injury!" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sportscaster</ENAMEX> shouts.

            (To reply, click here.)

         
      
   
