
   
   
      
         
            <SPAN class=630250921-01071999>Surfing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Web</ENAMEX></SPAN>

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 29</TIMEX>
            

            A pair
of cover stories on campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece affectionately profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jester</ENAMEX>/press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Lehane</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehane</ENAMEX>'s greatest contribution to the campaign may be
a sense of humor: His pranks include ordering a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> to remove all furniture
from a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. … Another cover article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skewers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s communications
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Hughes</ENAMEX>, as too controlling. By tightly managing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
interactions with the press and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> "allows her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to peddle
his backslapping bonhomie" without revealing his lack of "basic knowledge and
experience." … An editorial condemns the bombardment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> as
"grudge genocide." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> offensive is "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>-like," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration won't intervene because it "does not defend human rights in big
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economist</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov.</TIMEX>
13
            

            The
cover editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> breaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> competing operating-system <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and an applications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
which would encourage innovation without harming interoperability.
... An article ridicules interplanetary plans for the
Internet. A consortium including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> is planning to create a separate Internet
to ease communication among <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spacecraft</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> interplanetary Net-equipped
craft won't launch till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. Spaceweb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> would have to use domain names
such as--no joke--<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slate</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sol</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story questions whether the conglomeration of media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> will corrupt journalism. Corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">honchos</ENAMEX> are "cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>" to
the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>, for example, believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> should not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cover Disney</ENAMEX>. Don't worry too much: The proliferation of news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> ensures
that media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">conglomerates</ENAMEX> will be covered aggressively. … An article
describes how presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> kowtow to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>'s press. The
campaigns lavish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manchester</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WMUR-TV</ENAMEX> with political ad buys and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> campaign calls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ahead</TIMEX> to secure an interview with a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> newspaper.

            
               
                  The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 14</TIMEX>
            

            A
special issue about what clothing reveals. A chronicle of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
flirtation with a personal shopper laments the decline of posse shopping.
Teen-age girls shop in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, but as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> slip into middle age, shopping
becomes a solo sport. Personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX> are a poor substitute for the communal
pleasure of hunting down the perfect sweater with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pals</ENAMEX>. ... An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> heralds the increasing importance of the department-store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> merge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saks</ENAMEX> change the course of fashion by
telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> what sells and demanding practical adjustments to runway
designs. … The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> solves some enduring fashion
mysteries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Guccione</ENAMEX>'s open-necked shirts are a reaction to his buttoned-up,
private-school youth. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> loved to knit him sweaters.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15</TIMEX>
            

            The newsweeklies agree
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is in big trouble. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's cover story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Penfield Jackson</ENAMEX>'s
findings of fact could not have been worse for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and could be used
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> in private antitrust actions. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News ' cover says the proliferation of small computer devices and the
ascendance of Web-based applications are eroding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s dominance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> 
               notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is no longer just a software business.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> branched out into e-mail services, an online broadcasting tool, and
a Web-based travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> "" for 
                  Slate
               's take
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>'s findings.)

            
               Time marvels at the growing popularity of
polyamory, openly maintaining multiple loving relationships. Polyamorists
maintain their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two annual</TIMEX> conferences, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
Now the practice has its own martyrs: a "triple"--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and her two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> was taken away because of their unusual living
arrangement.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
applauds the new trend of "green
hunting ": Rather than killing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> shoot big
mammals with anesthetizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">darts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservationists</ENAMEX> collect big licensing fees
for dart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">safaris</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> don't feel guilty.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>
are "hawking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s hottest commodity: the aura of authenticity." To sell
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> credentials, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> aired a commercial filmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> National
Cemetery, in violation of federal regulations forbidding partisan activities at
the site. … An article says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> prepared for his campaign by
pulling in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> on the lecture circuit and advising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.P. Morgan</ENAMEX>
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$327,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. … An assessment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> findings says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>
invariably cast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s action in the worst possible light, but the
"compelling litany of misdeeds will be difficult to refute."

            
               
                  The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15</TIMEX>
            

            An
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Independent Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> botched the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> could have destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> if he had gotten <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to
cooperate immediately. But because he wanted to squeeze <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> for more
damning evidence, he revoked his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s offer of immunity after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had
signed it, enraging several of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> testified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX>, but by then anger toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> had receded.
… An essay examines the shifting iconography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arc</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Front</ENAMEX> now reveres <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX> as a nativist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> embrace
her as a feminist icon. Most appallingly indicative of its age, the forthcoming
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Messenger</ENAMEX> depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX> as "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of post-traumatic stress
disorder."

            
               
                  National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is maniacally depressed.
Earth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balance</ENAMEX> demonstrates that its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> has a dangerously
diseased mind. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s central claim--that the environment is at risk of being
irrevocably despoiled--is merely a displacement of his personal despair.
… An article worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are caving in to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonism</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> is repudiating the goal of limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embracing Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s commitment to "government activism for the middle
class." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antistatism</ENAMEX> is conservatism's central message and should not be
abandoned.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22</TIMEX>
            

            The
cover story exposes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> money machine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX> uses direct mail to haul in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s presidential
runs. In between elections, she converts the campaign into a nonprofit so she
can keep dunning the same list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. She routinely sells their mailing
list to other direct-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">solicitors</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $360,000</NUMEX>.
… An article praises the wisdom of the right. Conservative think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> generously subsidize the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinesh D'Souza</ENAMEX>, who took
home <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$483,023</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise Institute</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1992 and 1994</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right-wingers</ENAMEX>' largesse has tilted the ideological marketplace toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>. Left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> should start doling out similar subsidies to
their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 15</TIMEX>
            

            A
cover story argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s temper is his
best asset. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> impresses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> with his passionate distaste for
pork-barrel politics and wows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> by answering every question with a
fulmination on campaign finance reform. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s tantrums crystallize
his reputation as a straight-talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX>, while relieving him of the need
to take specific positions.

         
      
   
