
   
   
      
         
            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">332</NUMEX>: " <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Believe It or Else</ENAMEX>"

            
               In a television
commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">debuting</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> says, "It made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe
again, feel free again." Who's pitching what?
            

             

            Send
your answer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m. ET</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to newsquiz@slate.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> .

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Question (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 331</ENAMEX>)--" 'Twixt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 and 20</TIMEX>":
            

            

               
                  
                     The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX> share an idea about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> held by no other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. What
idea?
                  
               
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
their taste alone should ultimately dictate what television shows, movies,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">albums</ENAMEX>, and shoe styles get produced."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merrill Markoe</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Hawk</ENAMEX>
had a similar answer.)

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
putting them to death is occasionally warranted. And yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britney Spears</ENAMEX> still
lives. What's up with that?"-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Radosh</ENAMEX>
            

            "I ran
this question by our teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babysitter</ENAMEX> and he said, 'What's "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>"?'
"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Macleay</ENAMEX>
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
they shouldn't have sex, except on television, where we can keep an eye on
it."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis "Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Werthmann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Show</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Tuesday</TIMEX>"
Heaney
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
they're just like those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quasi-people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> . Except in those
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the slutty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> get beaten to death."-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Shearer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gabel</ENAMEX> (similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Thomason</ENAMEX> )

            Click
for more answers.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>'s Wrap-Up
            

            "Why can't they dance like we danced? What's wrong
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Kaye</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sang Paul Lynde</ENAMEX> (and recalls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Milner</ENAMEX>--you know, in his
quiz response; he wasn't actually in the movie) in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bye Bye Birdie</ENAMEX> 's
show-stopping musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kids</ENAMEX>," a look at teen-age life every bit as
insightful as anything on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> (if you can accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Lynde</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann-Margret</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>). So you can imagine my surprise that the recent remake, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> ,
was not based on the song. It wasn't even a musical. Or a remake. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>
in that one were so much meaner than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann-Margret</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bobbie Rydell</ENAMEX>.
But that's what happens when you suppress the powerful erotic and aggressive
urges of youth. Remember: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo and Juliet</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 14</NUMEX> and, by the end of the
play, dead. (As I recall my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet</ENAMEX> refused to renounce her faith
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercutio</ENAMEX> shot her. In the musical remake. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynde</ENAMEX>.)

            But of course Bye Bye
Birdie was the product of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an era</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s way of dealing with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen-agers</ENAMEX> was to encase them in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX>-lined steel canisters, truck them to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>, and bury them <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several miles</NUMEX> underground in abandoned salt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>. Our
perhaps that was our way of dealing with nuclear waste. But either way, things
have changed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Lynde</ENAMEX> has been replaced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center square</ENAMEX> by Whoopie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>. And current social policy is to sublimate those disruptive teen
tendencies into shopping, and so I salute our many fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>--for seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> not as violent over-sexed
barbarians, but as a marketing opportunity.

            
               Hang 'Em High
Answer
            

            It may not be "cool" or "hip" or "the thing to do"
in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confreres</ENAMEX> all enjoy
executing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as young as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court turned down an appeal by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Domingues</ENAMEX>, sentenced to death for a
double murder he committed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 16</TIMEX>. He argued that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>
prohibits capital punishment for crimes committed before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 18</TIMEX>. Ah, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domingues</ENAMEX> didn't reckon on then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> who inserted language in the
treaty explicitly stating that here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> we love to execute
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. OK, maybe not "love to," but reserve the right to. This was,
presumably, before young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> concocted that whole "compassionate conservative"
thing and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> foreswore executions. Didn't it?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Store</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">= Fun Extra</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Night</TIMEX>
Live may be in the doldrums, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> may have outlived its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">usefulness</ENAMEX>, but parody thrives in the form of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> T-shirt. Some fine
examples can be found at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic Enterprises</ENAMEX>--A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Apparel Store</ENAMEX> &
More--including these tees from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerusso Activewear</ENAMEX>.

            

               "He <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saves: Taste and See</ENAMEX>
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> is Good"-- A 
                  parody of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hershey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> wrapper. This is
my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, This is my body, This is my body with almonds.
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus King</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kings--Sweet Savior"-- Bright</ENAMEX> orange, a parody of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter</ENAMEX> cup logo;
you know, because "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>" sounds a lot like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese</ENAMEX>'s" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">King of Kings</ENAMEX>"
sounds a lot like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peanut Butter Cup</ENAMEX>" if you say it in a frenzy of religious
mania.
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God's Way: The Best Way</ENAMEX>
is God's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Way"-- Plays</ENAMEX> off <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Subway</ENAMEX> logo. If I read this correctly, the
lunch <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> is salvation, the shredded <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> represents the apostles, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">provolone</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BVM</ENAMEX>, and the sliced tomatoes mean "Vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>."
               

               "In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All Thy Ways</ENAMEX>:
Acknowledge Him and He will direct thy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Proverbs 3:6</ENAMEX>"-- A parody of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> ad (picture the ALL and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WAYS</ENAMEX> really big.) These shirts tend to parody
sweet or fatty foods, perhaps explaining why we are a very religious and very
fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
               

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christ Whitens Hearts</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freshens</ENAMEX> Lives"-- A skillful parody of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crest</ENAMEX> toothpaste logo. I guess to
make up for all the sugary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>. There will be no cavities in heaven.
               

            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Denominator</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
