
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Problem</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> has an Internet problem. No, it's not that silly remark about him having
invented it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s real problem is that Net <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> apparently think his site
is too dull to visit.

            A
recent study by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> Hit, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that operates a
"popularity" search engine, revealed that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late October</TIMEX>, almost
no one searching the Web for information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> actually made their way to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s official Web site. By a large margin, Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> preferred going to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> parody site or an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> site to the real thing.

            Direct
Hit tracked the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">paths</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,400</NUMEX> Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> who entered the names <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> into search engines from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 22 to Oct. 27</TIMEX>. These were the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> leading up to the "town hall" meeting between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>. Direct Hit has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> with a large number of Web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Network</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lycos, InfoSpace, LookSmart</ENAMEX>, and others. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> claims that it tracks some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71 percent</NUMEX> of all Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> over the course
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>.

            The
good news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is that more Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> were looking for his name than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s, by a factor of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">793</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">597</ENAMEX>).

            The
bad news is that when the search results came up, there was no indication that
anyone during those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> used the results to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s authorized site .

            The
official site "didn't even make the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>" choices of those who searched for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s name, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> Hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>. Instead, Web surfers
presented with a variety of options were more likely to visit a joke or parody
site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s site in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> was among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> most often visited by those
searching for his name, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct Hit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> say that after the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>,
there's no significant traffic worth measuring.

            By
contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> was the most common destination of those who
entered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s name into a search engine, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> Hit. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign declined to comment on the study.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
Salazar, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign, says that he has not seen the
Direct Hit study. "It doesn't really surprise me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salazar</ENAMEX> says. "The vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is much better known than his opponent, and so it makes sense that
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be looking for first-time information that way." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salazar</ENAMEX> says
his campaign is focused on making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s site "as comprehensive and informative
as it can be" and estimates that the site attracts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several thousand</NUMEX> unique
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> per week.

            Direct
Hit says that while it cannot detect the identity of individual Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, it
can track their movements with unprecedented precision. "We process the data
from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Culliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> Hit's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX>. The process is similar to that used to track banner advertising
on the Web. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culliss</ENAMEX> added that the popularity rankings also take into
consideration the amount of time that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> spend on a given site.

            Some
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> Hit said were visited most by those
searching for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> material are out of date and thinly visited. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-most-visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> site, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> Hit, is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> joke
repository, posted on the home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GeoCities</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and sponsored by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripon College</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. The site is actually no longer at the address that
Direct Hit found to be most visited (a common problem with search engines). Now
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripod</ENAMEX> home page, the site itself claims to have been hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1,110</NUMEX> times
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1998</TIMEX>. (Nothing currently on the site is going to hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> very
much. Sample joke: "Topping the list of top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> shortest books of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild Years</ENAMEX> .")

            Of
course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> Hit study doesn't mean that no one is going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
site. Loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> probably already know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX> or have it bookmarked in
their Web browsers. And it's possible (though statistically unlikely) that
large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> using search engines not measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> Hit
were flocking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> site. Most important, with the first primaries still
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> away, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign hasn't advertised much to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> to the
site.

            It's also possible that
the problem is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s alone, but rather is common to front-runners.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Direct</ENAMEX> Hit has yet to produce a similar traffic study for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, a search on its Web site shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s
official site
is also not among the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> surfed by those entering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s name.
However, upstart <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>'s official site , like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s, is the most popular
destination for those who've entered his name into a search engine.

         
      
   
