
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woman</ENAMEX>'s voice TAPE <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDE A</ENAMEX> @ <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:20 minutes</TIMEX>
      
      
         Can you please share your name?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Adams</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And where are you from?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK, and your age?
      
      
         18.
      
      
         OK.
         And so what year does that make you, are you a--?
      
      
         I'm just finishing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my freshman year</TIMEX> in college.
      
      
         And did you find that to be kind of hard, or did, you know--?
      
      
         Wha, yeah, very hard compared to high school.
      
      
         It was?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, now why did you decide to stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> to go to school?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I wanted to be closer to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, number one, and, um, number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, I have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> coming here, which helped me a lot, and, um, I just liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNC Charlotte</ENAMEX> because I wanted to be a, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Do you still want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> or--?
      
      
         Not anymore, no.
         
      
      
         How come, just--
      
      
         It's just not me.
         I've, I've decided and it's very hard.
         The, um, curriculum here is very hard.
      
      
         Right.
         That's what I've heard, it's extremely hard.
         What have you decided, what are you going to do?
      
      
         I'm going to do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> now.
      
      
         Do you plan on staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yes.
      
      
         So you do feel like you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> as an area?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\Uh-huh</ENAMEX>, yes.
         \\
      
      
         \\And you'll stay here?
         \\
      
      
         Yes, definitely.
      
      
         For any particular reason or you just like the area?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I like this area a whole lot and it's, it's growing so much and I just want to be near my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so I can take care of them whenever they get older.
      
      
         What do your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> do?
      
      
         They're actually both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So are they happy that you're going to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>?
         Or do would they rather you have stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nursing</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         They would rather me stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nursing</ENAMEX> because they know that's where my heart is but, um, you know, they're behind me in whatever I decide to do.
      
      
         Do you feel like you did well this sem, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, or if you had to do it over what would you do differently?
      
      
         I wish I could take back my whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">freshman year</TIMEX>.
         I've done horrible, let's just say horrible
         really, really bad.
         In high school I was, you know, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.0</NUMEX>'s, you knows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>'s an occasional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C. Now</ENAMEX> here I'm lucky if I get a C on something.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         C's and D's, you know, and that's just not me.
         I wish if I could do it all over again I would stay home and study instead of going out with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, which has really hurt me a lot.
      
      
         Do you think that's what it was?
         Was it the freedom aspect of it or?
      
      
         Definitely the freedom, definitely the freedom.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Even though I had freedom when I was, you know, home, whatever, but I still had a curfew.
         But here in college you don't have, I mean you can do what you want to, come and go as you please.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, you don't have to answer to anybody except yourself.
         And I've learned, um, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this year</TIMEX> how to manage my time, which I hasn't helped me out very much.
      
      
         It hasn't?
      
      
         No it hasn't because my grades are still pretty bad.
      
      
         
         So do you plan on working on it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>?
      
      
         Oh definitely.
         I have to set some goals for myself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
         If I don't then I probably won't come back to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> anymore, which I don't want that because I love this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> I love the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that I've made here everything about this, this place I love.
      
      
         Are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> putting a lot of pressure on you?
      
      
         Definitely.
         Definitely, I'm feeling the pressure from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.
         He's, they're like, they're not disappointed but they just know that I could do a whole lot better.
         And it, it kind of makes me feel bad.
         I feel like I'm letting them down, so to, so to speak.
      
      
         Kind of letting them down.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         So you're just going to work a lot harder?
      
      
         Work a lot harder, um, take some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> that I think are going to interest me more.
         That's one thing about this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is they just give you like certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> to take and they don't let you pick and choose what you want to take and stuff.
         And, um, I just wish that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> would have been more helpful to me.
      
      
         So you felt like you didn't even have anybody there to guide you?
      
      
         I have nobody here to guide me.
         I was pretty much, you know, on my own and I'm not used to that because in high school--
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         --the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> were much more, I guess, I don't know�
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lenient SA</ENAMEX>: --lenient, you know.
      
      
         They would guide you and kind of show you what you need to do and stuff?
      
      
         Yeah.
         They were more like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and I wasn't like a number in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         Do you feel like that's just in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> that that's how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> are?
         Or do you feel like in general that's how high school is as opposed to college?
      
      
         I feel like it's that way everywhere.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Is there anything else you want to--?
         Oh no!
         Don't get nervous!
         Is there anything else you want to talk about or is that pretty much all you had to say?
      
      
         That's pretty much it.
         I'm just going to tell everybody that they need to study!
         Definitely study!
      
      
         And work hard.
      
      
         Work hard study balance your time, you know.
         You can go out on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> but during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> it, you know, it should be study time.
      
      
         Well thank you for sharing your experience with me.
      
      
         You're welcome.
      
      
         And it was nice talking to you.
      
      
         Nice talking to you.
      
   
