
   
   
      
         All right, this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elissa Adams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elissa</ENAMEX>, you've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> for--
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years</TIMEX>.
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> thing I want to ask is if you remember any books that you read as a child um, or either books that were read to you either by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> that you really remember enjoying.
         Is there anything in particular that comes to mind?
      
      
         No.
      
      
         Nothing.
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         How about stories, that uh, you didn't read or weren't read to you, but stories, you know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come up with stories, I mean, is there any, were there any particular stories that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> told you that you really liked hearing when you were growing up?
      
      
         
         Not that I can remember, no, uh uh.
      
      
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         How about when you were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>?
         Everybody has to read stuff in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         Do you remember anything that, um, I mean, there are always books that I liked, I always had to read everything but uh, there were certain things that I liked more than others, do remember anything you liked in particular, um, about stuff you had to read maybe in your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> class or um, things like that?
      
      
         Nothing.
         Nothing I re, that I recall.
         No.
         Not really.
      
      
         No?
      
      
         Not really.
      
      
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         Well, what about now, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>'s coming up, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> get together for that and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> when, when you are um, you know eating dinner, or you know, just talking and everything.
         Are there particular stories either, either family stories that you might tell or stories about, um, you know things that have happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>?
         Or maybe stories that, you know, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just make up stories to tell.
         Are there any particular stories that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> tells now?
      
      
         Oh.
         Lot of times we just sit around and just reminisce and go back to the time when we were growing up.
         
         Family, um.
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         Anything in particular?
      
      
         Well, do you remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those particular stories that um, might come up when you're just sitting around reminiscing?
      
      
         Well, a lot of times we had company over.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I guess the time when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>.
      
      
         Hum?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> took me for a it, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s visit uh, it was a physical.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> got, did some tests and uh, done some tests.
         He dia, diagnosed me as having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">acute leukemia</ENAMEX> and um, this was when I lived back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>.
         And uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Momma</ENAMEX> and I took trips back and forth to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX> and went through a couple of treatments and uh, you know, uh, ( ) uh, I had, had to have different shots each time I went back.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         It was, and the little I remember, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Momma</ENAMEX> telling me on the way, you know, just little things I don't know really, let me think now.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         
         I guess I was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in that whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, well, in that, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> and everybody went through the same treatments.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And uh.
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, let's see.
         Turned out after all the treatments were done, I was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivor</ENAMEX> in the particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.
         Well, you know, to this day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now and then</TIMEX> that particular story comes up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now and then</TIMEX>.
      
      
         So, when, when that comes up, does, is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> primarily the one who would tell it or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Both.
      
      
         Either?
      
      
         Actually, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> wrote a story on it.
      
      
         Oh really?
      
      
         And I have it back in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
         It's just one of those things that you know, you just don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to hear much about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.
         It's just one of those things, you know that happened.
         And it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one afternoon</TIMEX> I was out playing on the uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> was, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> doing something and I was, I guess pretending to act like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> and I went up to the front door and rang the doorbell.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> came to the door and uh, she saw like this glow of light all around me as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> had definitely cured me of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>.
         No more treatments, no more.
         
         What do you call it?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         
         Nothing more.
         Actually, I went back to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and when I, everything you know was fine.
         Nothing, you know, nothing more to do.
         He knew right then that it was a miracle, miracle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Would you say that um, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> or you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> or whoever is telling the story, tells that part of the story, the, the last part when you came to the door and she saw the glow of light, would you say that they tell that part of the story more than any other part or do they tell the whole thing from beginning to end?
      
      
         Beginning to end.
      
      
         OK.
         What, you said that you were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>?
      
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX>.
      
      
         And I'm sure you remember parts of it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, do you remember everything that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, like when she's telling the story, do you remember everything she tells or is some of it you remember and some of it you don't?
      
      
         I pretty much remember the whole thing.
      
      
         The whole thing?
      
      
         I was old enough at the time that I knew what was going on.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         And uh, I remember exactly going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and the uh, waiting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, but um, yeah, it's just something you don't know anybody goes through.
         It was a very interesting experience.
      
      
         Do you ever tell this story yourself?
         Obviously you're telling it to me.
      
      
         I have told it to several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> and to this day they can't believe it, they would have never known.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Well, you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't know unless I share it with them.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX> helped me for a reason.
         I was on this earth you know, I've lived on this earth for some reason, I just don't know what it is yet.
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-huh.</ENAMEX>
         
         Well, as far as being a story, this is not an ordinary story that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> tells, obviously some do, um, is it something that comes up a lot or is it you know, something that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> doesn't talk about a lot or is it something that comes up on a pretty regular basis?
      
      
         Maybe once in a while.
      
      
         Once in a while.
         OK, well um, are there any particular stories related to this or anything else you enjoy reading now or um, I mean, is there anything looking at what you experienced, is there anything, any type of stories that you like to read now or that you like to hear about now?
         Maybe other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who survived <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> that you know were life threatening like that or I mean, do you ever try to find out other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s experiences?
      
      
         I do enjoy reading the um, stories related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guideposts</ENAMEX> or uh, what's another, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX>, they come in.
         
         ( ) When cancer comes up I'm just pretty, pretty interested in it, to find out what they went through and I can relate to it.
         Other than that, I get more out of reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guide</ENAMEX>, Guideposts stories.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, OK.
         Well thank you very much and thank you for sharing your story with me.
      
      
         Oh, you're welcome.
      
   
