
   
   
      
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we're going to talk about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> childhood stories and what I'm wondering is what are the stories you remember as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I recall, a number of stories.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> read a great deal, to me.
         Ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Wiggly</ENAMEX> was a favorite.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Wiggly</ENAMEX>?
         What was that about?
      
      
         That's about a rabbit, and about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> that used to chase the rabbit out of his, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carrot patch</ENAMEX> and, uh, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> that were associated with that.
      
      
         Was that your favorite story?
      
      
         I think that's one I remember, a lot because when I was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1st</NUMEX> grade, I was sick a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, and I was out of school a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.
         And, uh, because of that, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> read to me a lot, you know, to help me, me feel better
         .
         So, she uh, she read a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Wiggly</ENAMEX> stories to me.
         But I think the story that was, was a favorite was one that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> made up herself, utilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> from, you know, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny</ENAMEX> and, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thumper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bambi</ENAMEX> and all that.
         And ah, she, she made it up, a story about a, me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>, ah, going on this trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canadian Northwest</ENAMEX> to hunt and meeting these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, uh, while we were there.
         Of course it can't be published because all those things are copyrighted, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> made up the story and I thought it was very nice and I still have it, uh, handwritten, uh, in our file here.
      
      
         OK, how about you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I remember, uhem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Cottontail</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> chasing him under the wire and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Cottontail</ENAMEX> getting out just in time.
         and I remember <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mickey Mouse</ENAMEX> stories.
         I liked those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> World things.
         Of course, who knew about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years ago</TIMEX> but, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mickey Mouse</ENAMEX> was a favorite.
         And, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um, Little Women</ENAMEX>, that was and, now I had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, and I always kind of envisioned us patterned after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Women</ENAMEX>, and, because
         there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and I loved that story; read it over and over again.
         I fact, I took you to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louisa May Alcott</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, and we, ah, umm--.
         Let's see, other stories.
         Oh I hated, I, well, I'll just tell you that later.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, uh, I, I, I just, um, I guess I'm drawing a blank here.
         I can't think anymore.
      
      
         Well, what was your favorite story?
         If you had to pick out of all of them?
      
      
         My favorite story, um, oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cinderella</ENAMEX>.
         I just loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX>
         .
         I also saw my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> as the wicked stepsisters sometimes
         , and I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX>, running around waiting on them.
         
      
      
         What, ah, story in your childhood had the most impact on you?
         I'll ask you first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh...um, most impact on me?
         
         I think, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oh Heidi</ENAMEX>!
         I loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX>, and that, in fact, I wanted to name one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX>
         because I loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, as far as having an impact on me, I guess, uh, being a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and doing all the right things.
         Those were the stories I read, OK <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, want to tell--
      
      
         What's your favorite?
      
      
         
         Well, I'll tell you there was a record, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy Rogers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabby Hayes</ENAMEX>, and I still quote it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> when I'm, when I'm being funny.
         And it had to do with the description of all the cowboy paraphernalia that was, ah, existent at the time.
         Like tapaderos that were on the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the</ENAMEX>, uh, place to protect your boots in the saddle [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laughs</ENAMEX> and reverts to `normal voice'] and all that sort of thing.
         So I remember silly things like that, that were a lot of fun
         .
         I read, uh, the story that, I don't, this isn't, ah, I think the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real story that I read was, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Red Badge of Courage</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, more serious, and that was, that was a very interesting story because it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I came upon a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who was real, who was afraid, who ran away who, uh, then came back and, uh, and conquered his fear which is something that we all have to do from time to time.
      
      
         What are your least favorite stories?
         When you're thinking of stories that affected you and really you abhorred.
         What are those stories?
      
      
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aladdin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lamp</ENAMEX>!
         That genie that came out of that lamp scared me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> to death!
      
      
         Was that told to you or did you read that?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, that was told to me and I saw that genie coming out of the bottle in the picture in the book was not about a kind and loving genie.
         It was kind of scary looking and I thought, "Ooh!
         I don't think I'd like to meet up with that genie!"
      
      
         Well, who told you that story?
      
      
         Ooh, one of my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>.
         Probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lois</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Lois</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I can't think of a story that, uh, had a real negative impact on me.
         Umm, I guess I'll leave it at that.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when you're talking about your favorite stories, what was your favorite part of the story?
      
      
         Remember I told you about the story my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> wrote and I can remember at the time and in some ways it's still true <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
         Ah, the favorite part of the story was the fact that I had somehow bought an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Model T Ford</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         How appropriate!
      
      
         
         That was the favorite part of the story!
      
      
         Well, I think all the happy endings we read as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollyanna</ENAMEX>, you know and, uh, everything always seemed to turn out right.
      
      
         \\So, these were your favorite parts?
         \\
      
      
         \\<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stories</ENAMEX> I liked, yeah.
         \\
      
      
         What were your least favorite parts of the story?
         What parts of the story were boring?
      
      
         Oh!
         In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Women</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg</ENAMEX> died, Oh dear!
         That was so traumatic and, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss Family Robinson</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I loved the part where they would, you know, make things out of nothing.
         They made a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> out of, out of things they found on the island, fashioned things, oh uh, implements, uh, out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coconut shells</ENAMEX> and whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> and whatever they could find.
         I liked that part.
      
      
         Did you identify with any of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>?
         And what's the one you identified with the most?
      
      
         Well, I think I identified with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jo</ENAMEX>.
         She was kind of headstrong and she was, um, kind of artistic maybe, and, uh, uh, liked to have a good sense of humor.
      
      
         Yeah, the main, I, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Red Badge of Courage</ENAMEX>, the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, at first I had never, you know, all of the cowboy stories that I saw or read, it was, uh, uh, you know, the good the bad and the good were very good and the bad were very bad.
         And this was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> occasion where the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> had some, some flaws.
         So I didn't like that at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, and then, of course, you know, as the story unfolded, you would, uh, relate that to your own experiences of being afraid and, and learning to conquer those fears and that kind of thing.
         So I thought it was, uh, uh, it was at first a part of the story I didn't like, but afterward, uh, you know, it certainly taught a lesson.
      
      
         We're talking a lot about childhood stories and stories that um, were read to you and what were the first what did you start reading when you were first allowed to choose what you read?
         What did you choose?
      
      
         Well, I chose to read the ones that had been read to me.
         We had a great big book of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grimm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairytales</ENAMEX>, and looking back on that they were grim!
         They were scary, throwing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the oven and all that sort of thing!
         However, it didn't seem to be so horrifying.
         It was a story and I, you know, you knew it was fiction, but I would go back and read, when I could read myself, I read everything.
         I read the backs of cereal boxes.
         I read everything I could get my hands on.
      
      
         I didn't do a lot of reading.
         I guess I read a lot of classic comics.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classic comics</ENAMEX>, yeah!
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, well yeah and I remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivanhoe</ENAMEX> and, uh, The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disinherited Knight</ENAMEX> and all that kind of thing.
         I was always into those kinds of heroic things, um, so I read a lot of those things.
      
      
         I forgot about comic books!
         Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archie</ENAMEX> and, oh I loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie comics</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh yeah, superheroes like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Captain Marvel, Superman, Batman</ENAMEX> and all of them.
      
      
         I'm talking to you as your you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> and, uh, what were, if you know, what were your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>'s favorite stories?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> read, uh, liked history and read, um, a lot of historical, uh, factual things, not into fiction at all.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was probably so busy running around taking care of all of us,
         I guess she read, um, I think she read biographical things rather than um, novels.
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> didn't read anything in terms of what you'd call a book, uh, but he was analytical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sport</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kings</ENAMEX>, and, so would peruse the paper to check on that
         .
         But, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, uh, you know, didn't read a whole lot, but spent a lot of time reading to me, uh, my being an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, so yeah, I took up a lot of her life and she read a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s stories to me as a result of that, but I don't believe she read a lot for her own amusement.
      
      
         At that time, and now later on she, she lives at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> just about.
      
      
         Absolutely does.
      
      
         So, it's like she, uh, and the education wasn't the same back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>.
         So um, you know, it was different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would read for different reasons and I think your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has, um, you know, she's educated herself at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah, that's true.
      
      
         We're talking a lot about stories and, um, novels and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books, was there any poetry that was your favorite?
      
      
         Golly, I never really got into poetry.
         Yeah I had to take it, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
         Or high school?
         I just really didn't ever love poetry for some reason.
      
      
         I still recall, and I'm sure your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> does too "Whose woods these are, I think I know His <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is in the village though;" and I won't go beyond that but, uh, you recall that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail</ENAMEX>, when we were, when I was in college and we were first dating that was a, a favorite poem of, uh, us and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Was that self-written?
      
      
         Oh no.
         That was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Frost</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK, I thought so.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and we're talking about childhood and middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, what about high school?
         What about high school into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> into adulthood what are some of the books that you read?
      
      
         Oh, gee.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um,</ENAMEX>
         Can we turn that off while I think?
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> in particular I read while in college that we just howled over and that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catcher</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rye</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peyton</ENAMEX> Place was, had, um, kind of a fascination because I was at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NH</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gilmanton Iron Works</ENAMEX>, where that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, lived.
         So, that was such a racy and shocking book at that time, and so, of course, we had to read it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I.</ENAMEX> I liked, uh, oh gosh, go ahead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> you've got--
      
      
         Well, I remember another book that you read that that I didn't read but that, uh, painting was made `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">84</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ayn Rand</ENAMEX>?
         Yeah, um--
      
      
         And I remember that being, appearing to be so far in the future.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atlas Shrugged</ENAMEX>.
         Oh yes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Orwell</ENAMEX> books I read, uh, uh, um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> and what's the other one?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Farm</ENAMEX> and they, yeah, it was so far in the future, and, my gosh, now it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX>.
         Whew!
      
      
         Into adulthood, what books do you like now?
      
      
         I like, uh, political non-fiction, and I've read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Making</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> series from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> on up.
         I, I like, uh, uh, those kinds of things that talk about why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do what they do when they're in positions of political power or aspiring to positions of political power.
         I also like to read things about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I've read all the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> books, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turow</ENAMEX> and a lot of the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, current, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, novelists.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, oh gosh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Shrever</ENAMEX> is one, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rosamunde Pilcher, Maeve Binchy</ENAMEX>, um, I like all of that type of reading.
      
      
         Have you ever read any books from foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>?
         Somebody who obviously that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> was not their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>, but they wrote a book?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I'm sure I have I just can't think of what.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I just can't think of what one.
         You know what?
         I should have remembered back as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX>, I read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An American Tragedy</ENAMEX>.
         And, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> we ended up living in the place where that took place and the, uh, and it was not something that was, uh, not a subject that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> liked to talk about because many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in town knew the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was charged with that murder.
         And so that was really interesting, uh, in retrospect.
      
      
         I can't remember reading anything, foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>.
         As I say, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political non-fiction doesn't exactly lend itself to that.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dostoevsky</ENAMEX>.
         I mean I'm sure I have read I just can't even remember what, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zhivago</ENAMEX>, I read that.
      
      
         Did you notice any differences between an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and someone of foreign descent?
      
      
         Oh well, the cultural differences would come through in the writing, yeah, sure.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I wish I could think more.
         I just can't remember.
         Go ahead.
      
      
         Well, I'm going to ask a final question that, um, I mean, you're my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, and you imparted a lot of, uh, a lot of the love of reading to me.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, how important it was to read and we're all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>, I think that has something to do with it; my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I are all, we're all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> in college.
         So, what I am going to ask you is what was your philosophy behind that?
         Why is reading so important?
      
      
         I can't imagine not reading.
         Reading is the basis of all learning.
         I can't imagine not reading and for pure enjoyment and, uh, for growth, broadening your knowledge base.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, reading is fundamental as they say and it truly is.
         What a sad thing if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't read!
         If I had, if I was retired, I would definitely be working in aliteracy, um, you know, volunteer literacy capacity.
         I think it's so important.
         It's such a handicap not to read.
      
      
         I think, uh, that intellectual stimulation is very important I think thinking is very important I think reading is a part of that.
         And I, uh, too often, much too often, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, um, feeling superior somehow because they don't read, they don't think, they don't experience other ideas.
         And so, uh, those things come about through the work of reading rather than through listening to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street corner</ENAMEX> or, uh, gazing on TV.
      
      
         Well, thank you for being part of this study
      
      
         Our pleasure!
      
      
         Thank you!
      
   
