
   
   
      
         Don't be nervous.
         OK.
         What's your name?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon Averitt</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And, how old are you?
      
      
         19.
      
      
         And where are you from?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West</ENAMEX> side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK.
         And how was growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
         Did you like it or?
      
      
         Yeah, I liked it a lot.
         When, um, I was little, I lived more, near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Norman</ENAMEX> side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         If you're not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, you're not going to know where that's at, but, um, it was really far away from everybody and behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> and stuff like that.
         And, um, my junior year of high sch, high school, we moved into like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the west side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, and I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Meck</ENAMEX>, and that was a, um, culture experience, \\ I guess <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\ How \\</ENAMEX>, how come?
      
      
         Because it was more diverse.
         Like in most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, if you go on other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>, it's like everybody's just white, but in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, there was every kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you could ever meet.
         So, I haven't met <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNC</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> that I didn't meet in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>.
         I can compare them to, like black, white, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>, whatever, grunge, redneck, it doesn't matter.
         
      
      
         Do you think that's a good thing that it helped culture you, or--
      
      
         Yeah, it did because I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> now that went to like, not to slam <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> because I like a lot of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but they like have like so many like stereotypes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because they don't know anybody.
         But then like, I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that and they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just like anybody else is.
      
      
         OK.
         And so is there anything in particular about growing up that you want to share that maybe changed you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>?
         Or made you the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that you are?
         Anything in particular?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Tough question.
      
      
         Yeah.
         OK.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, um, `cause I wasn't really like I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, I mean I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         I mean, like my junior year of high school the first dress I ever owned was my junior year prom dress!
         
            . Like because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> always treated me like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> because I was like I was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in like, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> or something like that.
         Like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da-da-da-da</ENAMEX> and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> were both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.
         And then there was never like any female <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood Averetts</ENAMEX> until like my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         But like, so I was always raised like a tomboy and everything like that and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> treated me like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> all the time.
         And that's like I can totally see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> in my personality.
         Like when I lived at home, we did not get along at all for anything in the world; we would fight all the time.
         I moved out and we get along perfect.
         `Cause we're like, now I can say this because I'm older or whatever and I can like deal with it, I'm exactly like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But, when I was younger, I would have shot myself before I would have admitted that me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> were the exact same!
      
      
         So you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> get along really well now?
      
      
         Yeah.
         Unless I'm like, when I go home for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> break, after being there for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>, it was like I'd never moved out and we get kind of like tense with each other.
         Basically because we both, um, always think we're right.
      
      
         I know about that!
         Now what about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>?
         Were you close with her when you were growing up?
      
      
         I was closer with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> when I was little, just because I did all the sports and everything like that and, I've always been close to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, it was never like I didn't like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, but, um, me my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and I never really fight or anything like that, but now me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> are a lot closer.
         When I started doing like the whole shopping thing, the make-up thing, everything like that, me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> got really, really close.
         And then, like now that I'm in college, like I call her, like all the time and it won't occur that I should talk to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, too!
         But, then like me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> will talk all the time and she'll come over here and she'll like have a beer and a cigarette with me and it doesn't matter anymore!
         
         Just because, you know, she knows how I am, I guess.
      
      
         Do you think that's hard for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> maybe that you're closer with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> now than you are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>?
         Or do you think he kind of understands that's just the way?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, it was hard for him at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, I think because, um, like all of a sudden I was like so into softball, so into sports and everything like that and I'm still like, I'm still like that.
         But it wasn't like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Daddy's Little Wannabe Tomboy</ENAMEX>," thing anymore, you know.
         Like, I started doing more things with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>: I started doing this and I started doing that.
         I think that was kind of hard for him, you know.
      
      
         Do you think he resents that now or--?
      
      
         I don't think he resents it, I think he kind of had to suck it up and get it over with, get over it.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Because like he saw that like, I think he saw that I was like him before I would admit that I was like him.
         Because he knew that I was going to do what I wanted to do without disrespecting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or do anything like that because I was still like not going to run out in a rampage and kind and be like a horrible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, but it was just like my life now and--
      
      
         And what's your major?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX>?
         How do they feel about your being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> major?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, funny.
         Actually my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first semester</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pre-Business</ENAMEX> major to go into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marketing and Advertising</ENAMEX>, because I did that in high school, too.
         But I never wanted to do that.
         I did that because that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> wanted me to do.
         And `cause I was really involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and stuff in high school and everything like that.
         And kind of like coming in to college or whatever, he kind of convinced me that what else am I going to do?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         If I, he's like, "You're not going to do anything, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da-da-da</ENAMEX>."
         He wasn't real supportive about it at all.
         But, um, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my first semester</TIMEX> was over with and I had like a real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, I knew that's what I still wanted to do.
      
      
         Really?
      
      
         And so I changed my major without telling my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh gosh!
      
      
         Then they got the whole schedule thing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> with the tuition bill on it and everything like that and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was reading it and it said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major THEA</ENAMEX>," and she was like, "What is this?"
         She knew I was going to do it, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> was pretty irate.
         Then I started paying him half the tuition bill.
         So--
      
      
         Really?
      
      
         Yeah.
         That was the deal for them to get off my back and let me do what I wanted to do.
         I pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of my, everything.
      
      
         Was that hard for you?
      
      
         Yeah.
         Because my whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX>, I didn't work.
         But then, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha, ha</NUMEX> that changed quickly.
         Well, actually when I went the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX>, the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first semester</TIMEX>, because I worked at the pool on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         That was horrible.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Because I'm like a lifeguard every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> I had to get a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter job all year</TIMEX>.
         And it's hard to go from having like your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">whole day</TIMEX> to go to classes and do whatever you want to do and space out everything then like having to like drive across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and go to work.
         Just to be able to have a job, because I'm not a big work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>.
         That's probably why I'm a theater major so I can kind of, you know, do what plays I want and then move on.
      
      
         Do you think they've become more ex, do you think they've accepted more what you've decided to do or that's going to take a while?
         Or if they ever will at all?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> has because she knows how important it is to me and everything like that and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> when I went home, I don't even remember why I went home, but I went home for something and he's like, he's still trying to convince me to double major.
         To have something to fall back on and everything like that.
         And I'm like, I'm trying to convince him to, you know, if I don't make it and there's a strong possibility I won't, I know that, I'm not stupid, I'm nor going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> and make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five million</NUMEX> or more than that--
      
      
         
            Right.
         
         
      
      
         And do all that, and I mean, if I don't make it, my life's not going to be over or something, like I can't go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So you'll go back to school if that doesn't work out?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Did you tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that?
      
      
         I think they know.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> knows.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> he, I don't know, he doesn't think I'm stupid, but he doesn't he wants better for me, than what he has.
         He thinks, you know, it's just kind of that whole thing, he wants me to get everything now, because he thinks once you're his age, it's too late.
         But he realizes it's not like that.
         He could go and make more his self if he would get off his butt and do it.
      
      
         What does he do?
         What does he do for a living?
      
      
         He's a brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mason</ENAMEX>, which he builds like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         And he's been doing that since he got out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.
         He went to college for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> and dropped out.
      
      
         Oh, you're kidding.
      
      
         Yeah.
         Like neither, like I'm the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to go to college on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side.
      
      
         That must be a really big deal.
      
      
         Yeah.
         It is.
         That's why it's such like a big thing, because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, he went, he went into the military and then came out.
         I don't know what, he sells like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> or something.
         
         And like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> like, one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>, he's just like slack; he dropped out of high school his senior year.
         
      
      
         So, I'm kind of like the hope, I guess.
      
      
         That's a little bit of pressure, though.
      
      
         I guess.
         I don't, I kind of don't think about that though, because I'm like my life is my life, you know?
         And like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s a big part of it.
         I love them all to death, but what they do, doesn't like reflect who I am--
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         --you know.
         And stuff like that.
         I'm kind of going to do what I'm going to do.
         That's why I stand out in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         I think that's why they expect so much more of me.
         It kind of gets tiring and that's what I don't like, you know, I don't like to talk about myself when I go around my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         You know they're all like, "Oh good!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Da-da-da-da-da</ENAMEX>."
         I'm like--
      
      
         Do they praise you a lot?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         And you don't like that?
         I love it!
      
      
         I do, but it gets to a point where like I feel like if I fail, it's just going to be like way too much for everybody.
         And, I don't know, it's like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>, I'm the youngest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         I'm the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, you know, besides my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who are like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         So nobody knows what they're going to be yet and considering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> is raising them, that doesn't, you know, say too much for them two little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         Whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s.
         
      
      
         Oh.
         Oh yeah.
      
      
         
         I'm making my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> sound really bad, but they're really not that bad!
      
      
         No!
         Everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is different.
         What does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> do?
      
      
         She's a, she works in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX> now, actually.
         She used to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> for the longest, longest time.
         Now she works at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Aid</ENAMEX>.
         She does packages like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Aid</ENAMEX> stuff.
      
      
         Does she like what she does?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, no.
         
         No she doesn't at all.
         She waits tables like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> at another job to help put me through and everything like that.
         So--
      
      
         What do you do?
         Where, where are you working now?
      
      
         Now I'm starting my whole lifeguard thing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.
         I'm opening up like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> and they're giving me a headache because they all turned green <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, so, that's like the most fun job for me.
         This is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth summer</TIMEX> I've done it.
         So now I'm going to run <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>.
      
      
         A big responsibility!
      
      
         Yeah, but I've done it for so long, I'm used to like lifeguard and like everything like that.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> I managed one pool and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> are kind of small and like a few of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> are working for me.
         So that'll-- TAPE <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDE B</ENAMEX>
      
      
         --work on stage and then go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> and work in movies to begin with, anyway.
      
      
         So you wouldn't stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
         Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will be sad!
      
      
         They know.
         I've told them.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> still doesn't believe me.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> believes me, because she knows I'll go.
         But, um, It's not like I'll never come back and visit or anything like that.
         Like, I mean, if let's say, I make it really big, you know, big, famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or whatever, I'll live here.
         And then I'll go and everything like that, when I'm big enough to make my decisions on, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are sending me scripts by then instead of me having to like audition and stuff.
      
      
         You have a good attitude about it, though!
         That's good, though, you need to, I guess.
      
      
         You can't go into it and be like, "Oh!
         I'm going to be a big movie star <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>!"
         and everything like that, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that are the ones that are disappointed the most and then like end up nowhere.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         You know, like I know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> I'll have to sit down and decide if I'm where I want to be in life or if I'm not.
         And if I'm not, I've got to do something about it.
      
      
         That's a good attitude!
         Well, I definitely think you're going to do something with it and I want to thank you for talking to us.
      
      
         No problem!
      
      
         Bye!
      
   
