
   
   
      
         Can I please have your name?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Blanchard</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And your age?
      
      
         19.
      
      
         Where are you from in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concord</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK.
         And is there anything in particular you want to talk about?
         Are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Freshman</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         OK.
         And did you like living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> all your life?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yeah.
         It's a nice place to grow up.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I don't think I'll be able to settle down here though, because most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> live up north.
         So when I graduate, more than likely I'll move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> has definitely been a nice place to live.
         I've never experienced any problems with crime or anything like that, and there's always been something for me to do, like in high school or in college, there's always things to go do, so it's been a nice place to grow up.
      
      
         Do you think it will be strange to move up north when you've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> all your life?
         Do you think there'll be a very big culture shock?
      
      
         I don't know that it will be a very big culture shock, because I've grown up going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> all the time.
         So it's almost like a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         It won't be too different, but the style of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is a little different, so--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-hmm.</ENAMEX>
         Why wouldn't you want to stay on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
         Is there any particular reason?
      
      
         I need a change.
         I've lived here all of my life.
         So I need a change and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s the place I've always looked to live at, so--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-hmm.</ENAMEX>
         Do you feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> has changed a lot since you were growing up here?
         Do feel like it's changed a lot?
      
      
         It's definitely grown.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And a lot more things have come up since then for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do.
         So, I don't know.
      
      
         If you want to move so bad, why did you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, the reason I choose to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here is because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> away, and I wanted to be away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, yet be able to go home, if I needed to, so--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         Are you close to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes.
         Very close to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         I usually go home once or twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Don't you think that will be hard if you move all the way up there, not seeing them as much?
         Or do you feel you're ready for the change?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I'll definitely be ready for the change.
         I've been going up as a progress in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, so I, it will be a good change for me.
      
      
         So you'll stay here for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and then move, or would you transfer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, if I was able to get educational opportunities in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, I would transfer, but I'm happy with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here, with my sorority, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, with, I mean I'm happy with the way things are right now, so probably when I graduate.
      
      
         And what is it you want to do when you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I would like to look for a job in education, possibly teaching elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, um, hopefully up north I would rather do that up north, so--
      
      
         How come?
         For any particular reason?
      
      
         I mean, just mostly because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lives up there and I enjoy being up there.
      
      
         It won't bother you, the cold weather and stuff?
         I can say that because I'm from there.
         That won't bother you?
      
      
         It would definitely be an adjustment, but I've been up there with the weather before, and, um, I'm not, it's not hard for me to adjust to things so--
      
      
         Do you like the weather in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
         Do you enjoy--?
      
      
         Oh, I definitely like the weather in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, so that would be kind of a shock for me to have those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX>, but I'll be able to adjust to it.
         Although I do enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> here.
         
      
      
         How was it going to high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
         Do you feel like, do you think it would have been different if you had gone to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> or someplace else up north?
      
      
         I guess, actually it would, because in high school, I was on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> cheerleading championship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX>, and they don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squads</ENAMEX> like that up north as much, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> tell me from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>.
         So I think it would definitely been different, just because of that.
      
      
         Do you feel like that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> thing or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> thing, or--
      
      
         Well, I actually kind of having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on a cheerleading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> in high school is more a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> thing, because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> had never heard of that before me, so--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         So you feel like it's a southern thing?
         Because in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, where I'm from, they do not, cheerleading and that stuff isn't as big as it is down here.
      
      
         Well, that was a big part for me in high school, so, I definitely think it would have made a difference it I had lived up there for high school.
      
      
         So was an important part of being in high school?
      
      
         Oh!
         That was my life!
         It truly was my life in high school.
      
      
         And it was an important aspect, was there a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> that hung out because of that?
      
      
         Oh yes.
         It was the little popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, you know, the little "we're better than everybody else" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>.
         I hate to say that, but it is true!
         
      
      
         What about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that didn't do that?
      
      
         I mean, I wasn't a particular snobby one, but there were some that were, so--
      
      
         So it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX> dated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah.
         
         It really was.
         It was the stereotypical high school.
      
      
         It was?
         And do you feel like it was a good thing to grow up around?
      
      
         No.
         I really don't.
         You should really give everybody a chance.
         Just because they don't have as much money as you, or they don't do the same things as you do, doesn't mean they're not a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> inside.
      
      
         The money aspect is that, in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>, did that affect stuff, how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> fit in or--?
      
      
         It really did, because a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were well off.
         They had awesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and they strutted around with their awesome clothes and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who didn't really didn't hang out with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Does that make for a lot of pressure to have a lot of money?
      
      
         It does!
         Because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is by no means rich, but we never had that much trouble, so--.
         You always wanted to have the update styles clothes and the updated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         You want to be down anymore than anybody else, so--
      
      
         Is there anything else you wanted to talk about?
         High <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I guess I want to say that it's been a real positive experience living here, because my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> really wants to move back up north because that's where she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from</TIMEX>.
         But my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> loves the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, so, I guess it would be an adjustment for him if they moved so--.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>'s a good <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, it's expanding and it's getting better.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNCC</ENAMEX> is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, it's probably the right size, I wouldn't want to go to a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so--.
         I enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNC</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Well, thank you for sharing your experiences with me and your time.
         I appreciate it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>.
      
   
