
   
   
      
         OK.
         If you could state your name and your um, date of birth your age and where you were born and where, just basically, just a brief sketch of all the places you've lived, real quickly if you can.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Borel Junior</ENAMEX>, born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 20th 1968</TIMEX>.
         They tell me at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside Memorial Hospital</ENAMEX> or something in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>.
         There I resided until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> um, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'70</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when we moved to northeastern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> more specifically a little squirt of a town called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Laceyville</ENAMEX> and there I lived until I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> and I moved here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belmont</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         And how, OK can you tell me any flood stories about growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Oh, we lived uh, not far from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Susquehanna River</ENAMEX> where our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was down that way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skinners Eddy United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> specifically and I don't know if it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> died there in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'77</NUMEX> or if it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'78</NUMEX>, but a flood came and course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were all you know told to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would come get you, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> ran special routes and so forth.
         I remember going down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and there was a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> there that were organizing an uh, evacuation of all the valuables of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, take them to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>.
         We had a large tractor-trailer parked out front and uh,
         these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> all assembled to take the pews out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.
         Well, of all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> there now.
         I'm maybe, I'm maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years old</TIMEX> and uh, of all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> assembled there not one of them had a pair of pliers or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a</NUMEX> wrench.
         I fortunately remembered when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and I left to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> to bring a wrench and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple</NUMEX> pairs of pliers because of course the pews were bolted to the floor.
         This as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> kind of stunned me you know that we're going to go evacuate pews from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and we're not going to bring any tools with us of course this was predating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Makita</ENAMEX> battery tools looking back in retrospect we could have used Makita tools would have been far more productive but carrying the pews out of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and loading them in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and by the time we got done the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer wheels</ENAMEX> were covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and uh, we just kind of made it by the skin of our teeth that we got everything out of there.
      
      
         Yeah, um, how about because I know weather always reeked uh, certainly during the wintertime and all of the snowstorms that would come uh.
         \\
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Ah</ENAMEX> yeah, fond, fond memories.
         \\
      
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my favorite,
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my favorite stories is the one about with you and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> that you went sledding.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sleigh</ENAMEX> riding down a uh, property line that divided our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, our land from another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> that was kind of a, a swell or a ditch if you will there and that would freeze the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> would freeze in that so you basically had a uh, like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">luge</ENAMEX>, is that what it is?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ice</ENAMEX> with a little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> on top of it and we were in a little toboggan sled there not the, not the kind roll up there like a plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet</ENAMEX>, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat sled</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         And uh, we, we were moving pretty quickly down through there and I happened to glance up the road and there was a car coming.
         So,
         I have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> here and I'm going to kill him underneath this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> shortly.
         
         So we uh, through tremendous diversionary tactics of dragging my leg and my elbow and so forth we managed to stop just at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX>, the edge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> after blistering my elbow on a big knot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> but uh, I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marsha</ENAMEX> knew about that until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> I guess I don't know it's been a while but uh, yeah the snow there in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> were exciting to say the least.
         I remember many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> walking down to the bus where you know whatever you had in your nose would freeze.
         It would just crunch and you went to blow your nose nothing liquid came out it was crystals and you'd get on the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> and it would be so damn cold that the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> would just be a solid sheet of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> you'd have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock salt</ENAMEX> scattered on the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> in order to keep some kind of traction and uh, had a couple of deviant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> there on the bus and one's name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robbie</ENAMEX> Share.
         He would pick chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> up off the floor and chew it disgusting things he was a deviant little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX>.
         And uh, I don't remember
         the specifics as to what he did, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louie</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four and a half feet</NUMEX> tall driving a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">72</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-passenger</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diesel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, he would, he would try to straighten out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robbie</ENAMEX>, so he would call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robbie</ENAMEX> up to the front of the bus and he'd tell him, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, I want you to sit there on that top step don't say a sound, don't make a sound, don't move, I don't want to even know you're there."
         And every stop we make, now you got to remember when those bus doors open what little heat that's in that bus goes out that door and the cold comes in.
         
         "Every time we stop I want you to get off and let whoever I'm letting on, in and then you get back in, sit on the step."
         All the way through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that hour and 15 minute</TIMEX> bus route old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robbie</ENAMEX> get off, he'd stand outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on and he'd get back in.
         I don't know whatever became of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robbie</ENAMEX>, not much I imagine.
         And then <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>, ice uh, I can remember me and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> once we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about sixth</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade we'd stop uh, you couldn't run with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> on state maintained <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>.
         You can do that on your, on your county <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and I think they call them a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">borough</ENAMEX> if I remember right up that way.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, you could run with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> on those secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads um</ENAMEX>, but once you got on a state road you couldn't, so it would be a point in our bus route that we would have to get out and it would be you know, I don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 degrees</NUMEX>, wind blowing and we'd help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louie</ENAMEX> get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>.
         That was you know, you kind of felt important at that point because you've, you've graduated to next level of adolescence, you're now helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>.
         We uh, we would run our safety drills at the elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         
         And uh, the elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, as you got to the high school, of course that was different than it is down here, our elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> only ran until <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade and we went to the high school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade so you had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX> all in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.
         Of course you only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> through all those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> grades.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         But once you got to that point you still stopped at the elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and we would help those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, we would have emergency drills and that sort of thing.
         You would open the back door and you felt like you were big stuff.
         We had one spot on our route at the top of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Browntown Mountain</ENAMEX> which was about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two mile</NUMEX> drag downhill which, you know could be deadly for large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> in any situation.
         I can remember sitting there and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louie</ENAMEX> saying, "Everybody be quiet, shut-up."
         It would be so damn foggy you could not see the yellow line on that divided <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> in front of you and we to turn left out onto this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>.
         We would all slide the windows down on the bus open the door, stick your head out the door, you couldn't hear anything coming that way, you couldn't hear anything coming the other way, and he'd just drop it in low and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> it, we would make it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another morning</TIMEX>.
         That seems like that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks</TIMEX> out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> especially that the fog would just be outrageous.
         We never had any uh,
         never had any problems.
         I can remember it being so cold again that uh, one circumstance coming from uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springhill</ENAMEX> where I live down into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> which was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laceyville</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> wouldn't run, it kept cutting off it was diesel.
         It was so cold that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> does what they call congeals, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> becomes like gelatin.
         We'd basically coasted down into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and got <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 50 gallons</NUMEX> of kerosene and pumped it in the fuel tank so that so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> would actually run through the fuel lines and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> would run.
         And you're going to school in those conditions.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         That was uh, that was the most exciting part of you know, most important, most exciting part of going to school was getting there for me.
         
         Alive.
      
      
         How about um, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yes y'all need to include that picture with my little dysentery here, uh disinter, I guess it is.
         
         
         I guess it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> bought me a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yamaha 80</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> I could cruise through the fields and dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and so forth which uh, I had real good luck with that I guess up until um, I don't know what year that was there.
         Groundhog hole found the front tire of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> and I managed to fly over the handlebars.
         I guess I lay there unconscious awhile.
         I don't remember, but only, only a fractured collarbone, which I recommend to anyone that needs to break a bone, break a collarbone.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         It's a relatively painless experience and not very cumbersome to deal with, not bad.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> reminds me of a story I told him or I think his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> told him.
         Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> had a pool and we were kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatfield</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCoy</ENAMEX>'s, they weren't very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they didn't like us.
         I guess I had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> staying <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>.
         We thought it would be cool to see just how far a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BB</ENAMEX> would shoot.
         
         
         Well we found out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days later</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> walked over and informed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> that he found <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BB</ENAMEX> in the filter pump of his swimming pool.
         So I guess they went that far.
         We lived in uh, in dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land country</ENAMEX> and uh, little things you missed which now I don't know if I like or not.
         We had a barn, a dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> that was maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">quarter of a mile</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama</ENAMEX> say, "We need <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>."
         Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three miles</NUMEX> away and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> was a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,000 feet</NUMEX>, so you grab your little stainless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> kettle with a lid on it and a handle.
         You'd walk down the road with a dollar bill in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX> now this is in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-seventies</TIMEX>, but still <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> was twice that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> I guess.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         You'd go down to this big stainless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> vat that was would hold <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a thousand gallons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> then you'll pull the lid of this vat and lower you're kettle down in to it.
         Ice cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and uh, pull it out of course it was whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> on top.
         If you forgot to shake it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> your cereal was kind of disgusting.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         It was kind of like eating it with whipping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX>.
         But I know uh, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> used to love it.
         You couldn't leave it if you didn't rinse your glass out after you got drinking after you got done drinking it would stick to the glass to the point where you'd have to scrape it.
         Now they tell you that's not good to do.
         You shouldn't drink that non-pasteurized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, but hey, it never hurt us.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, what other, now I know you worked with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> in the beginning there when you were quite younger.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 or 13</NUMEX>.
      
      
         Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is a, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Uh-hum.
      
      
         And, and you took up the trade too.
      
      
         Met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first girlfriend</ENAMEX> that way.
         Walked through her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> you know.
      
      
         Really?
      
      
         Yeah.
         We were putting siding on her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and beat on the door nobody comes to the door it's summertime everybody sleeping until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00</TIMEX>.
         We're there <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> to beat the heat.
         I got to get the windows open in order to pin, bend the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX> around them and so forth this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and I had always had a love hate relationship on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>,
         I love to hate her.
         And uh, me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> there we'd always sit together in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> seat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>.
         Well when she, we would pick her up on the route, she'd want to sit with us.
         It was the closest seat, she was only on the bus <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> and then we were dumping the elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we had plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> again.
         So she, we would always fuss about her sitting with us but anyway <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this one morning</TIMEX> I putting siding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and I are putting siding on her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and nobody come to the door.
         The door was unlocked and I had to get the windows open, so I just kind of go cruising through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house upstairs</ENAMEX> try to find my way to the window.
         Well that window happened to be through her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, so I just kind of walked on through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and she looked up at me and I said, "Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>," and she just screamed.
         I went on through, unlocked the window
         and left.
         Later we laughed about it, but wasn't really funny at the time for her I guess.
         
      
      
         
         Do you remember the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> jobs that you, that you did um, because, I, did you, I don't think you started working with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> did you?
         You got a job cutting siding wasn't it?
      
      
         Well that was for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>.
         Yeah, he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that would help him on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesdays</TIMEX>, it was the local barber.
         He was paying him <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five bucks an hour</TIMEX> and he would, he could work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and uh, but I believe it was on that job there, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kavalo</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> said, "Look <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you can read a tape measure better that this forty year old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can so I'll give you <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five bucks an hour</TIMEX> if you prove you can do it."
         Excuse me.
         "You can prove what you can do."
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         So after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three days</TIMEX> he called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Callgrove</ENAMEX> and said, "Don't bother coming in I found a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> better than you."
         Well when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callgrove</ENAMEX> found out it was me that, that kind of hurt his feelings a little you know, but ever since then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> and I worked all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every summer</TIMEX>, we did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kavalo</ENAMEX> job, then we built a barn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reamuses</ENAMEX> down on the river.
         I fell off that roof, there's a little miracle, I missed a boulder by <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about six inches</NUMEX> which would have probably shattered my spine when I fell off that, but you get, you're lucky, everybody's here for a reason just what condition you're in when you're still here.
         Fortunately I'm all in functioning.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         All my digits um, still work.
      
      
         Do you remember?
         
      
      
         I didn't, oh, I, when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> I don't even remember that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>,
         I only heard about it.
      
      
         Do you remember any stories or do you have any stories about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, not so much stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandmom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandpop</ENAMEX>, um--
      
      
         Because they were living in a, in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> basically.
      
      
         Yeah, when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 12</NUMEX>, I guess I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 or 12</NUMEX>.
         I went and stayed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandmom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpop Borel</ENAMEX> in their little <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom apartment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX> and uh, I guess I stayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six days</TIMEX>.
         Grandmom smoked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saratoga</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">120</ENAMEX> cigarettes which are <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about eight and a half inches</NUMEX> long.
         Grandpop was a very quiet, somber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> he wouldn't say much but uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gra</ENAMEX> ndmom was a little more boisterous.
         They had a small poodle named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fifi</ENAMEX>, it was disgusting,
         but I learned uh, you know how you learn respect for, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in, in, different ways um, for you know, for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpop</ENAMEX> didn't say much <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandpop</ENAMEX> had more love and affection for that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and showed it to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> probably more than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> show to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today.
         I mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had hip replacements and bad knees and everything else and he'd get on his knees and play with that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and give it it's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, put <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter</ENAMEX> on his finger and feed it to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> to keep that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> alive.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wouldn't, couldn't I mean and for him he wouldn't have bent down to pick up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> because it would have hurt him too much.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but he'd bend down and stay down to help that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.
         My grandmom was pretty much a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> smoker.
         She uh, she'd had laryngitis and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> told her if you don't quit smoking you'll never talk.
         She told him to shut-up and get her a pack of cigarettes.
         She got gangrene in her foot and he said if you don't quit smoking you're going to lose your foot.
         She said, "I'm going shoe shopping," and kept on smoking.
         Died with both feet and talking the whole way.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh, //</ENAMEX> she would have smoking all the whole way.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> Smoking the whole way.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Yeah.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And that time I spent with them was the coolest because grandmom would let me smoke and at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 13 years old</TIMEX>
         you know being able to
         sit there and smoke cigarettes with grandma.
      
      
         Do you smoke her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saratogas</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Oh yeah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they were good cigarettes.
         Now that was uh, man the most flavorful cigarette I'd ever smoked, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> what did you ever smoke you know?
         
         But uh, come mealtime boy this little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> with central air conditioning running, the smoke hung <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four and a half five feet</NUMEX> down from the ceiling.
         I mean literally you could just see it hang, it looked like a fire scene on the news it was awful.
         I mean you have smoked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> and smoked roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>, smoked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX>, smoked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">syrup</ENAMEX>, everything tasted like smoke.
         And clothes, everything just reeked of it especially if you went outside for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> and actually got huh, fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smog</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SF</ENAMEX>: Yeah.
      
      
         And then came back in oh my gosh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> hand smoke in there was enough to kill uh, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         Terrible.
      
      
         Well, I think what was worse about their place is not only the smoke hanging in the air, but they kept it at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// 80</ENAMEX> degrees.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Uh-hum.</ENAMEX>
         It was always warm.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> All the time.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> Even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the in</TIMEX>, I mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> are really cold but--
      
      
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpop</ENAMEX> would complain that it was still cold in there.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> he was still cold.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         He liked it a little warmer.
         Not too many stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandmom</ENAMEX> and Grandpop though they were pretty quiet.
      
      
         Do you remember any stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandma Mackton</ENAMEX>, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s a little bit?
      
      
         The only stories I remember about
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandmom Mackton</ENAMEX> would be uh, when uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpop Mackton</ENAMEX> uh, he was a watch repairman and so forth and this was even actually before my time, I remember this just being translated to me from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marsha</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rayona</ENAMEX> would be over there visiting with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpop</ENAMEX> would be working on a watch and he'd drop a part.
         Now you can picture the part out of a watch how small this is and for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that in his probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> at that point difficult for him to see, lighting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> and time not being what it is now, of course he'd lose his part and he'd say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tootles</ENAMEX>," well first he'd have his fit, "Nothing but damn junk, junk, junk!"
         He'd say about these watches he was fixing, "Nothing but a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GD</ENAMEX> junk."
         I can remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandmom</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen hollering</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Daddy, Daddy, Daddy</ENAMEX> I wish you wouldn't talk like that in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>."
         Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandpop</ENAMEX>, he'd calm down, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tootles</ENAMEX>, you see this part here.
         I dropped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of bitches on the floor again.
         
         Can you find one just like it for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Grandpa?</ENAMEX>"
         And he, they would get down there and they'd find it and find it for him.
         I remember too <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandmom</ENAMEX> would fuss at him for giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> money, I say I don't remember now how much it was but if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pack</ENAMEX> of cigarettes was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 cents</NUMEX> he'd give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Now this is going back to the fifties and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early sixties</TIMEX> when you could still do that but he'd send these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 or 11 years old</TIMEX> maybe, down to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and get him a pack of cigarettes well, with the change they could buy licorice and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX> and what not.
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Daddy, Daddy, Daddy</ENAMEX> send those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> to get those filthy cigarettes."
         "Well they get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>."
         
         You know that's how he justified it, they were getting something out of it.
         He wasn't sending them there for nothing.
         I'm told I'm a lot like him.
         Which I don't know I never met him, don't remember him.
      
      
         How about do remember any stories that, that you've been told by your, by your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> about them growing up or have they told stories about you growing up that you can remember?
      
      
         Well, some of them that uh, with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marsha</ENAMEX> uh, I she was, I believe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 18</TIMEX> when I was born.
         I was a mistake.
         An oops.
         And uh, everyone you know going out to eat or anything like that then uh, the waiter would say to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, "What would you like, what would you like?"
         and then they ask my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> what would she like for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.
         She'd go, "Oh no, he's not mine.
         He's their's."
         You know she wasn't going to claim me.
         
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> had uh, an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX> and I remember there was, she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> which hindsight is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20/20</NUMEX> she used to say she was going to kidnap in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX>, put me in bed with her.
         I would just scream and scream you know that, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, no, don't do that."
         But stories I remember hearing one of uh, I believe it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marsha</ENAMEX> uh, the wind caught the storm door there she was, she was uh, hanging on to the back storm door and I guess pulled it open a little bit to see what was going on and the wind caught it and threw her right out in the yard.
      
      
         Yard.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>.
         I don't know uh, any other fantastic tales that I have.
      
      
         How about um, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>?
         You've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now.
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         Yeah.
         
      
      
         Born and raised in, in uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// NC</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// NC</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> The fine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaston</ENAMEX>.
         Yeah, I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that uh, likes to relive the tragedy of his split lip.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, took a little spill and had to get a stitch, huh?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>, yeah.
         But uh, no they've had pretty uneventful childhoods, I think we've had our moments of comedy.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         We were helping my niece and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> paint a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that they bought and uh, he uh, little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX> was with us.
         He said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Daddy</ENAMEX> I have to go poo-poo."
         And I said, "Well son the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Port-o-john</ENAMEX> is way down there in the neighborhood.
         Hold it as long as you can.
         
         Tell me when you feel it peeping out and then we'll run like hell."
         
         And my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rayona</ENAMEX> she reminds me of that story and laughs every time we tell it.
         
         But you held it didn't you?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         I don't know, do I have any other fantastic stories I've told you?
      
      
         I'm trying to remember.
         I can, well you know we just relived the story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of when you built the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> over on um, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Songbird.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Songbird.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> We were there working.
      
      
         And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that you put the, the shower and the tub in.
         Do you remember that?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yeah when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> busted my ear because he stopped moving.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Yeah.
         And those moments of idiotic stupidity we uh, we put some scaffolding out on the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh, I just shot a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-by-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a couple of nails in it and got out there and climbed on top of it.
         There's, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> reminds me from time to time.
         What if those nails would have pulled out?
         But fortunately they didn't.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> story does come to my mind though where you painted the foundation coating on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and got tar all over you.
         
         Do you remember that?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         And you said, "How do I get this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tar</ENAMEX> off of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">me uncle?</ENAMEX>"
         I said, "Well you can use paint thinner or turpentine or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>."
         "Well what do you have?"
         I said, "Well we got some // <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>."
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Gasoline.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         So you.
      
      
         I thought it was lacquer thinner.
      
      
         No it was gas because you washed your legs all over because you did it in shorts.
      
      
         It was a hot day.
      
      
         Then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> I don't know if you weren't there.
      
      
         No, I worked.
         My ankle.
      
      
         But you ended up with blood poisoning from all the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah.
         Throwing up.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, the joys, joys and fun of construction.
      
      
         Construction.
      
      
         Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> came to help us there.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ninety</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> degrees outside I got nothing on but a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock strap</ENAMEX>,
         I'm still dying it's so hot.
         You're sweating.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpop</ENAMEX>'s drowning, I mean everything on him is soaking wet and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s got on a long, honest to God he had on a long sleeve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX> with the collar buttoned up.
      
      
         I know.
         I think he had on a short sleeve.
         I know he had on blue jeans.
      
      
         Yeah, I know he had on pants, he had on a long sleeve I think the cuffs were rolled up once or twice.
      
      
         Yeah.
         I couldn't have done it.
      
      
         I would have died.
         I'd a screamed.
      
      
         Because that was, we would wake up at, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six in the morning</TIMEX>.
      
      
         We'd be sitting there waiting on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight</TIMEX> to be able to go to work.
      
      
         Couldn't some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>, couldn't even see just hoping that it would be cooler.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         And the afternoon would come around around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
      
      
         Oh yeah, I want to quit early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      
      
         We would be there until <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// five, //</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock at night</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Five.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> Well it's starting to get cool now that's how you justify it.
      
      
         Go in for an extra long lunch.
         How about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that um, how about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that I would, to help you with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six</TIMEX>'s.
         Rafters out on the back porch and I went to reach a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to hand it you and another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> slipped.
         Do you remember that?
         It fell right across my foot.
      
      
         Oh yeah!
         Did a number on your toe didn't it?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> wasn't real happy about that.
      
      
         I think we hid it from her didn't we?
      
      
         Yeah, you didn't tell her too much about it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> that you smashed your foot up pretty bad.
         I forgot about that.
         Grandpop slipped through the floor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">joists</ENAMEX> there too.
      
      
         That's right.
         
      
      
         That did a number on the inside of his leg.
      
      
         That <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time you were trying to take that floor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">joist</ENAMEX>.
         You had put some type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> floor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">joists</ENAMEX> and you went to hit it with a hammer and you were hitting it backwards and it smacked it into your chest.
      
      
         Smacked my chest.
         Oh I've done that a number of times.
         Had my head up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between</NUMEX> ceiling joists nailing rafters glanced off the rafter and hit myself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with a hammer.
      
      
         How about um, how about this story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpop</ENAMEX> and his son, of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Oh yeah.
         That was when we first moved here to NC we uh, had a job across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from where we build him a house uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         And uh, we were borrowing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s saw, chop saw, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miter</ENAMEX> saw and um, I upstairs nailing down trim and I hear the saw every once in a while so I know he's down there working and all of a sudden don't hear the saw and I run out of new trim.
         "Are you down there?"
         I look nobody is standing at the saw.
         I look around well he was right here.
         I see a few drops of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> on the floor.
         I look out the window and there he's booking across the yard heading for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         I get over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         He said that saw drifted down and hit him right across the back of his thumb.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ouch</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah so he's kind of standing there at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> sink and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s running around like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> with her head cut off.
         
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Need a Band-Aid</ENAMEX>, need some gauze, need some tape."
         Well she can't find any of it.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s not real organized when it comes to things like that.
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band-Aids</ENAMEX> are at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> sink, the peroxide is in the basement you know, the gauze is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and the tape for that is upstairs.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         Oh lord, she's running around carrying on well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> makes the mistake of looking at his wound and his knees go out from under him.
         He buckles down onto the floor.
         I think uh-oh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 pounds</NUMEX> of mush going to be laying on the floor,
         I'll never get him up you know.
         
         So we quick think and I go, well grab a paper towel and wet it and throw a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cubes</ENAMEX> in and put it on his hand, get him up to his feet and haul him off to the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
         Well meantime my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> is running around she doesn't hardly know that we left.
         She's still looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Band-Aids</ENAMEX>.
         
         Take him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Med</ENAMEX> Place.
         They stitch him up good went back to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">later that afternoon</TIMEX>.
         He's a trooper that way he, that doesn't make any difference as far as him being hurt he'll work.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         He'll work it off.
         I remember um, one of the best trips we had, which was why we've since created the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borel Family Reunion</ENAMEX>, was a funeral we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpop Borel</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and I decided we would all ride up together in // the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">upchuck wagon</ENAMEX>.
         You were there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">upchuck wagon</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> I think yeah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> and I were there.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> Yeah now you have to explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">upchuck wagon</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I believe it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> wasn't it?
      
      
         If my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> bought it, it would have to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         Yes that's true.
      
      
         It was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Oh.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> It was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">conversion van</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70 miles an hour</NUMEX> would make the freakiest noises which would wake my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> up to prompt her to poke me and tell m e to slow down.
         
         And uh, somewhere in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VA.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Because we were driving from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">// NC</ENAMEX> all the way up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">// NC</ENAMEX> all the way up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NJ</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> Of course we had to do it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> because we couldn't take enough time everybody.
         Somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marsha</ENAMEX> sees a billboard for this restaurant to eat at.
         It's a very attractive billboard, but it was not anything franchised where you could actually say, "Oh yes I know that."
         So we took a chance on it and started following the billboards.
         I swear to God it must have been <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">17 miles</NUMEX> later, like on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, down a dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, at the end of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> was this nice kind of western looking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that we ended up eating at.
         I believe that there was a pond even that it kind of overlooked in the back.
         It was kind of, it was nice.
         But it kind of killed an hour out of our trip as far as time, but we had a lot of fun at that uh, that funeral.
         I had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> there that had a, he was I guess in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his twenties</TIMEX> and uh, he loaded the trunk of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and after the funeral we all kind of stood out in the parking lot drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, smoking cigarettes and it wasn't um, until after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandmom</ENAMEX> died and uh, we were sitting at uh, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, sitting in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> and um, his name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Ward</ENAMEX> and he was kind of hosting the post funeral procession there that goes on.
         And I said to some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> that I had only the last I had seen was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpop</ENAMEX>'s funeral.
         I said, "You know, this really sucks we all have a really good time and it's a really sad occasion.
         Why don't we do this in spite of not don't have a funeral let's just get together."
         And we were just sitting there and the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> at that point lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> and the rest of it lived here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> and sitting there with him we just kind of said, "You know we ought to find a place in the middle."
         And uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and I had stopped many times in a little town called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Market</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> which was just a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// little, //</ENAMEX> yeah it seemed like a halfway point.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Halfway.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And uh, so we uh, put some plans together.
         My older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rayona</ENAMEX> she put together that reunion.
         Turns out it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">226 miles</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Market</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">320 miles</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Market</ENAMEX>.
         And now we can sit around <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink beer</ENAMEX> by the pool, smoke cigarettes and tell stories without somebody dying.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         But I know, ironically I don't think, why in fact I know we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reunion and then we lost a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Ward</ENAMEX> that we met at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         Any more interesting stories you know that I tell?
      
      
         I was just, well I always thought the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with um, about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Ann</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Ann</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> that, that flew into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh well that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was gone.
         They lived across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from us in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PA.</ENAMEX>
         That's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and uh, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and um, one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> call over there and she says, "We got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> stuck in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and it won't get out."
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Ann</ENAMEX> has a lot of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">knick-knacks</NUMEX>.
      
      
         Uh-hum.
      
      
         A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal</ENAMEX> and plates and she had a plate rail in the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> that ran around, you know so far down from the ceiling and that damn little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> would walk behind those plates and you, you just knew he was going to knock a plate knock off, a plate off but he never did.
         Chased him all the way up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX>, I don't think the bird ever even pooped in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> not that we found--
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         Not that we found, but he got <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and we locked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and opened all the windows in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about half an hour</TIMEX> it kind of ran out, but I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Ann</ENAMEX> ever noticed that.
         I don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Ann</ENAMEX> noticed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> was ever in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         I won't tell.
         
         We won't let her see the tape.
      
      
         OK.
         
      
      
         Thank, thank you for your stories.
      
   
