
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elbert Branch</ENAMEX>.
         Elbert, I just want to ask you uh, some questions about your experience with uh, stories.
         The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> stories that you remember, um, stories that were read to you or told to you and who told them.
         What, what are some of the first stories you remember?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, the one that really sticks out a lot is uh, before my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had TV,
         their,
         I want to say it's their aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> who lived <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> up the dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> had the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> TV in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and so after all the farm work was taken care of and everybody had dinner and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX> everybody would walk up the dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         How far away?
      
      
         It was a pretty good distance.
         I would say about a mile.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         They were off up the hill a little ways.
         And in between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> you had this pasture where they kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bulls</ENAMEX>.
         And on this particular night, it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, they, they had a bull out there that was pretty mean and would charge the fence at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         And um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grandma</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, was walking with them that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
         She was going to watch TV.
         And uh, it was dark, they really couldn't see.
         And uh, they were walking up the path and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandma</ENAMEX> accidentally stepped in something
         that was really soft and her foot got to sinking and instead of her pulling that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> foot back out and shaking it off to keep going, she stuck both feet in there and she started to holler.
         
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> said all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> took off running and left her.
         Because they heard the bull coming.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bull</ENAMEX> start making his noises and all that other stuff.
         
         And they said somehow, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">someway</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandma</ENAMEX> was with them when they got to the aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">uncles house</ENAMEX>.
         So, but uh,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would always sit us around at home at the evenings, um, and tell us about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her days</TIMEX> growing up.
         They walking to school in the rain, sleet, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> and all this other crazy stuff--
      
      
         Uphill both ways.
      
      
         Yeah, uphill both ways.
         And how they use to take their lunches to school and some of the things they took for lunch like fatback <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat biscuits</ENAMEX> and--.
      
      
         I forgot to ask you.
         Where is, where was this?
         Where did they grow up?
      
      
         They grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, which is a little small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> it's
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east of Raleigh</ENAMEX>.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 40</NUMEX> miles east of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         On a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         On a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and uh, she has some wild and crazy stories that she sat and shared with us.
         And um, they talked about how a quarter could buy them so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX>, and that stuff, and talked about some of the things, wild things that went on, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, some of the ghost stories, the hankses they called them.
         They didn't call them ghosts.
         It was the hanks that they seen.
      
      
         These are dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are--
      
      
         I, at that time I,
         she just called them hanks.
         \\ They wasn't ghosts.
         Yeah.
         \\
      
      
         \\ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>, I never heard that.
         \\
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granddad</ENAMEX> had seen something <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>.
         It was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seven or eight feet</NUMEX> tall.
         He kept shining his light up.
         He never did see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of it before he took off running so
         and uh, something that jumped on the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>.
         She said it was a panther.
         You know, at that time I was like you, panther here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>?
         So jumped on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> back.
         But it was a bunch of wild and crazy stories.
      
      
         Now where did you, when you were hearing these stories, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was telling them to you, where were you living at the time?
      
      
         We were staying here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albemarle</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         We grew up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albemarle</ENAMEX>.
         Myself, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>.
         We moved from down there up here at a very young age and we don't remember a lot about the old as they call it their home.
         We call this our home because this is where we were raised at.
         But uh, we hear a lot about home and how it used to be and like I said walking <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> to school and--
      
      
         So don't complain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elbert</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah, don't complain.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, the first book I guess I really remember is she bought us a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible stories</ENAMEX>.
      
   
