
   
   
      
         OK.
         Umm, go ahead and tell me about a story.
      
      
         Well I can remember as a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of three and seven</TIMEX> going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Asheville</ENAMEX> and visiting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother umm</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> but he died when I was fairly young so I mostly remember visiting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         She lived in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Asheville</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, it was pretty much a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> a front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-bedroom house <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>.
         The uh neighborhood she lived in was very uh quiet mostly older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh we used to go around the neighborhood and visit a lot of her old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         Um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in particular the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blankenships</ENAMEX> had a apple <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> in their back yard and we would go and we would pick <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> and take them back to her place and make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apple pies</ENAMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blankenships</ENAMEX> were kind of an odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in that uh both of them chewed tobacco and spit into little spittoons.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, it's kind of weird talking to an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> spitting tobacco, especially because one of them was female and you always had that impression that chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> thing.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh,</ENAMEX>
         strange little memories like that about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         She had a washing machine but not, not a dryer so all the laundry get, got put hung out on the clothesline.
         Uh she had a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> that was separate from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and almost bigger than the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it was almost like it was a barn.
         And a bunch of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s old tools were in there odd things like, like scythes and things that you would find only on a farm even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> itself was not on farmland.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> had a `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nova</ENAMEX> which a most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would consider to be a muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but uh she only drove it maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three miles</NUMEX> at the most and it usually took the whole day to plan what would happen if she were to need to drive somewhere so this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> had very little mileage on it even though it was, at that point, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 20 years old</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, we used to sit on her back porch and uh snap uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> or what they called doing snap <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>, uh, which was really just taking green <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> and snapping them into smaller pieces.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I suppose it had some kind of great significance.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> seemed to get a good kick out of it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, we used to walk up to the local grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, uh, which was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three or four</NUMEX> blocks away.
         There was also a candy store <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three or four</NUMEX> blocks in the other direction called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pud's</ENAMEX> that we used to walk up to and across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pud's</ENAMEX> was the local fire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firemen</ENAMEX> used to let us play on the fire engines which is completely unheard of nowadays but they let us you know climb all over them, get inside and honk the horns you know put on fire jacket and boots or whatever we wanted to do and uh I guess there just weren't a lot of fires in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Asheville</ENAMEX> in that part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> because they never seemed to be concerned that we would be interfering with their preparedness.
         Um
         I don't know those are the, the sort of stick out in my mind about visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Asheville</ENAMEX>.
         Um we always tended to stop somewhere scenic either going to or coming from.
         We went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chimney Rock</ENAMEX> on a number of occasions.
         We went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linville Caverns</ENAMEX> once and we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sliding Rock and Biltmore House</ENAMEX> and some of the other attractions that are up that way in the western part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
         Uh I think we even went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tweetsie Railroad</ENAMEX> a couple of times so, uh, you know the sort of just wholesome, down home kind of memories
         about visiting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> before she got uh, unable to take care of herself and she ended up moving in with us.
         You know, but they're rather pleasant memories of childhood and I certainly wouldn't trade them for anything.
      
      
         Is there anything specific that, uh, you remember about your grandma?
      
      
         Mm.
      
      
         A specific story that she used to tell or?
      
      
         Not any stories that she used to tell.
         Um she was always a very active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
         Um she used to, she used to walk <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she had grown up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>.
         She had uh, I believe she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         And uh, they were all very active very strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and even though my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was a tiny little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5'2</NUMEX>", uh, she was pretty strong for her size and rugged and sturdy and that uh even carried over into her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> when mentally she wasn't all there but physically she was still extremely healthy and it was uh, kind of a strange kind of position to be in.
         Um I guess the thing I remember most about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX> is that she was extremely frugal.
         She would save everything.
         One thing in particular she used to save would be soup labels.
         I guess there was one particular program where you would returned so many soup labels and they gave you a rebate or something on collecting aluminum cans.
         And uh she had just cartons and cartons of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> labels that she had saved over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and redeem them you know I don't know
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> cents a bushel so she was very practical in that regard.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she always kept all her bills and expenses at an absolute minimum ran everything very efficiently kept an extremely tidy house uh.
      
      
         Is there anything your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> ever told you about her, stories that they ever did like when they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I guess when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, not too many stories about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s childhood.
         He spent most of his time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> learning things like how to work on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and how to build things paint things and that translates over cause my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> does just about everything; he can fix about anything and build just about anything and repair just about anything.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I guess the only story that they ever say a lot about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was the fact that she did not like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> when uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and she <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got together.
         And uh mostly because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptists</ENAMEX> from the mountains of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> which, oh, just scared everybody right there.
         So, before she even had the opportunity to meet my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> she had already decided that she was this, this evil heathen creature that was going to corrupt her beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy um</ENAMEX> and even wrote her a nasty letter to that effect.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she pretty much showed a lot of disinterest at best and, and outright hostility at worst towards my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> until we the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> came along.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, once uh she had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was all smiles to everybody which I think was kind of amusing.
         Um I guess at that point she figured it was too late so she might as well make the best of the situation.
      
      
         Anything else?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, not that I can really think of off the top of my head.
      
      
         What about when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandma</ENAMEX> moved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with you, were there any stories about her once she moved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?
         Anything you remember?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, not really anything unusual.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she uh, at that point, things were, she wasn't in the best of health so there weren't really any, any unusual anecdotes that weren't immediately or at least tangentially related to her health and the decline of her health, so no, no interesting anecdotes about her personality or really, or really anything that I could talk about at that point.
      
      
         OK.
         Well, thank you very much.
      
      
         You're welcome.
      
   
