
   
   
      
         You're not going to hear yourself on the tape.
      
      
         ( ) OK go ahead.
         OK <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX> is now going to talk
         about the music industry.
         Go ahead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         The music industry, well, you want more of the juicy, sordid details.
      
      
         Hold on.
         OK go ahead.
      
      
         The music industry.
         I had a dream once of becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>, most specifically, probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> slash rapper-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> extraordinaire in the music business and all of my hopes and dreams were shattered once I actually got involved in the music industry.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, specifically, I guess, more the recording aspect and dealing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you have to deal with in the music industry on a day-to-day basis in that supposedly creative environment, and, um, where to begin?
         Let's see I started in the music industry when I was very young, um, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> and--
      
      
         \\How old were you?
         \\
      
      
         \\My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> thought \\ how old was I?
         I was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 or 13 years old</TIMEX>.
         My, and I somehow managed to convince my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and stepfather, of the time, to uh get me a couple of turn tables and started mixing songs and scratching and doing all that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.J.</ENAMEX> stuff.
         And, uh, it was cool and it went on like that for a while.
         And, uh, as I continued, I got more into actually making the music that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would, I guess, rap over and from there I hooked up with a few different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were rappers, if you will, and, and, uh, kind of developed my own interests in actually writing words and that sort a thing.
         And this is, I guess, after, after high school, kind of right before college, actually, while I was in college, before I went away to school, while I was still in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>.
         And so I was working with a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> anyway, um, went away to school and got more into it and managed to do a little business deal with a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine that enabled me to get some equipment to actually produce music on a more professional level.
         And, anyway, uh, anyway, went on from there, started doing a lot of stuff in college working with um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> specifically.
      
      
         
         You can stop it.
      
      
         Anyways where was I from that interruption?
         Was working with somebody in college and, um, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> and, uh, you know, we put a few demo tapes together and that kind a thing.
         And he was more active in naturally shopping and, and some, some positive feedback.
         But really what we were, the subject matter and content probably was a bit far into the hip-hop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, it seemed like we were more interested in kind of promoting a level of consciousness, and most other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were interested in talking shit about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> banging, you know, the whole gangster rap thing, and that got really big.
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NWA</ENAMEX> and some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dre</ENAMEX>, and just some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were kind of involved in that.
         So anyway, so we, uh, got some response and, and kind of adjusted things, but after, uh, after a while we kind of went our separate ways.
         I, uh, went off to do my thing and he went off to, to some other things, and, uh, anyway, um, to make a long story fairly short, I got married, and being married gave me a little bit of freedom as far as what I need to do to make money because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was working and making enough to support us.
         So I was able to get out into the actual music industry the recording industry and, unfortunately, one aspect of the recording industry, when you get started, a lot of times you have to do either very low-paying or non-paying internships to get into the recording <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>.
         Specifically, I mean, if you want to work at, work at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these places, they, they, uh, generally have a lot of free help, so, uh, you're not going to make a whole lot of money doing this and they expect you to put in a full time schedule so you really can't work another job.
         But at any rate, I had this, this freedom and, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> had come into my life to, to go and pursue this dream, so, um, I started working at place called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D&D Studios</ENAMEX>, which was known for doing, um, a lot of hip hop music, kind of stuff similar to what I was interested in and I was hoping I'd be able to make some, some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> at least, maybe do a little bit of networking there, and, uh, I met some pretty cool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, did some really kind of really interesting projects, um, but--
      
      
         What kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well, let's see, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that I've met.
         A, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DJ</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Funk Master Flex</ENAMEX>, who put out a few albums and I don't even remember what they called.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mix Tape</ENAMEX> Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to whatever it is now, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D.J.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Premier</ENAMEX>, who worked with, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gangstar</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gangstar</ENAMEX>, and, uh, another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry O'Danagar</ENAMEX>, who also worked with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay-Z</ENAMEX>, who's pretty popular right now, um, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from out west named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exhibit</ENAMEX>, and, uh, basically a very a kind of a close knit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that did this professionally that, that really mostly came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> and a few other areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>.
         Anyway, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> itself was kind a dingy, it wasn't very professional.
         It was really dirty and had a reputation as being such, um, kind of a grungy atmosphere, environment, but where you could do what you wanted to do and get stuff done and what have you.
         From there that was kind of frustrating me a little bit, going into, um, sessions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> and having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around me smoking fat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">blunts</ENAMEX>, drinking forties of Old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, and really not getting a whole lot of stuff done that was, it was, it was just depressing.
         And, uh, seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with no real creative potential getting paid to do music wasn't very encouraging or inspiring to me.
         So I needed to get out of that environment.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so I began looking around for other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> that I thought might, uh, have a higher level of professionalism.
         From there I went to a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battery Studios</ENAMEX>, which had everything that, that I was looking for.
         It was, uh, a very established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> and had put out a lot of, um, I guess, well known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, and it was actually, it was affiliated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jive Records</ENAMEX>, um, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jive Records</ENAMEX>, I guess, at the time, had, their big act was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backstreet Boys</ENAMEX>, and they were recording the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Backstreet Boys</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> released album.
         So I got to work on that a little bit, um, and I actually met the whole, the whole other caliber of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>.
         But then, also a lot of the same, that, uh, that deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D&D</ENAMEX> and it was a much cleaner environment.
         They, they definitely had a lot of pride in, in the appearance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> and how well it was maintained, which was nice.
         It was nice to at least be working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who seemed to care about where they were and how things were handled.
         And I met some interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there, and, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Angelo</ENAMEX> was probably one of the most interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that I met there and just, just one of the most down to earth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> that I, I have met in the industry.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, also a pothead, but not really so consumed with it necessarily.
         Sort of, it was just kind of how he worked.
         He did things very slowly
         and I don't think that wasn't necessarily the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weed</ENAMEX> that he smoked, I think he just had a style of working and that was how he did it.
         I also worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Roots</ENAMEX> while I was there and their sessions were just hectic.
      
      
         You didn't like them?
      
      
         I liked them, but, yeah, no.
         I like them, but they, I think, which CD does shehave?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Things <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fall Apart</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I don't know.
         Black cover.
      
      
         Black cover?
      
      
         Black cover with white, black and white.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> and white yeah.
         I think I have credit on that CD actually.
      
      
         You do?
      
      
         Yeah on some of the songs yeah.
         If, if it's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Things Fall Apart</ENAMEX>, yeah my name is in the album binding as an assistant engineering credit on the creative cut track.
      
      
         So what did you actually do?
      
      
         I helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> put their music and their vocals to tape.
         Basically, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> is pretty much the one that, that mans the, the mixing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and adjusts all the volume levels and equalizes the, the different instruments and sounds and separates things and adds effects to it echoes and--
      
      
         So do they actually change the tone of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s voice?
      
      
         They can change the tone of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s voice yes.
      
      
         Do they do it a lot?
      
      
         They don't do it a lot but with, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, um, that really can't sing very well that are very big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> that they need to have a perfect sound on the recording, they do.
         There was one particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> I don't recall her name.
         I think her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>, and I don't really recall her last name, but she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>.
         They were comparing her to, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Mariah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> is actually what they described her as, and I, I never heard of her before being there, and haven't really heard anything of her since, but I remember they were doing an album of hers and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> after they would do it they would give a digital tape to a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> who would then take it in the back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and correct her voice.
         Basically if she couldn't hit a note he would digitize it so that she did.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And they did that a lot with her specifically.
      
      
         Don't they do that a lot with like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britney Spears</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that?
      
      
         Well with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittney Spears</ENAMEX> I think what they probably do is they, um, they've got a lot of back up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> that can sing, and they kind of blend her voice into theirs when she can't quite do it.
         And another, another technique that they kind a use is chorusing, where they will allow you to basically record your vocal the same, the same verse, or the same whatever, the same words, the same lyrics on a few different tracks, and they'll kind a blend it all together so that it, it almost sounds like one very full voice.
         They also have a lot of, uh, effects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processors</ENAMEX> that they can run it through that will add harmonics that will kind of smooth out the voice.
         You know, echoes and stuff like that.
         It just kind a fills it out a little bit makes it a little easier on the ear especially if they can't sing but.
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battery Studios</ENAMEX> was great, but it was just, uh, it was just hectic because once if, if they actually liked you and they liked how you worked there and you got along well with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> and stuff like that they would work you to death.
         I had, had put in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks</TIMEX> that were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 60 and 90 hours a week</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiring</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah, I mean, it was kind a it was rough especially on a young marriage when, when you go into work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six p.m.</TIMEX>
         , you know, basically crossing paths on the way out as, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> was coming in and get to work stay at work until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five a.m.</TIMEX>
         come home as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> was getting up and getting ready for work, go to sleep, she goes to work, I wake up, eat, shower and all that good stuff, and then, uh, she's coming home and I'm going out again.
         After doing that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> it's kind of like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damn</ENAMEX>," you know.
         We didn't get to spend any time with each other and just being married, and, you know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a year or so</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> it was, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> being unfamiliar with, with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and not really liking it very much.
         It was kind of, it's sort of, it seemed unfair to me to, um, to subject her to that, and plus, I mean, the schedule was just starting to take a toll on me as well, and you can only put in so many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">80 hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> before you kind of break down from it.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Plus, I really wasn't making the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> that I wanted to make.
         Unfortunately, um, at least like with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and, and other, I guess, industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> or industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that really could make decisions about things, when they're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> working with somebody else that's what they focus on.
         Plus being there and watching how they dealt with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you kind of pick on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s shadiness and, and bullshit so that they just, I mean you kind of see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for what they are when they don't have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> up as much and under those kind a those conditions they really don't have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> up that much they're just kind a relaxing and being themselves and it's kind of scary to see
         what some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are when they're being themselves.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         But, uh, I guess I did that for it must have been close to, um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and a half maybe, and then I decided not, and ended up leaving.
         I think, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> was my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'99</TIMEX>, but it was fun while it lasted, you know, it was a lot of cool experiences, got to meet a lot of interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, um, got exposed to what I thought I might want to do, it, and decided that I didn't really want to do it, so, I guess, uh, it was a learning experience and one I don't have any regrets about it, but it was a lot of fun and--
      
      
         You can stop.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         OK good.
      
      
         Thank you.
      
   
