
   
   
      
         OK.
      
      
         Am I sitting in the right spot?
      
      
         You're fine.
         What stories or books do you remember reading as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
         Was there a favorite?
         So that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions.
         What stories or books do you remember reading?
      
      
         My favorite books were all about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Boxcar Children</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK.
         Did you have a favorite?
         I mean, of any of those did you have a favorite?
      
      
         No.
         I just couldn't wait to get my hands on the next one that would come out.
         And, and now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, they have a lot more than they ever had available when I was little.
      
      
         Do you remember a particular color?
         Right now they're all beige--
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         --if I'm not mistaken.
      
      
         Seems to me like a lot of them were yellow.
         It was like a goldish-yellow.
         Not a bright, sunshine yellow, a warm gold looking--
      
      
         What age were you when you started reading those, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">approximately</NUMEX>?
      
      
         Those books?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         It would have been the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade.
      
      
         Did they have any illustrations?
         I don't think they have any illustrations, do they?
      
      
         No.
         Not many at all.
      
      
         All right.
         This might sound like a different kind of question, but is there a certain type of smell that they had to them?
      
      
         Just, um, just an old musty, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>-type smell, you know?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>.
         OK.
         Was there a particular place for reading that you had when you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I loved to go outside.
         Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> had a big pasture.
         So actually I'd go sit in the pasture and read.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> or freezing, I loved it!
      
      
         All right.
         What stories or books do you remember somebody reading to you?
      
      
         Well, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> helped me learn to read before I ever started school, and most of those were just your little, basic, I Can Read books.
         That's what they're called now, I don't, I don't know what they were called then, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX> type books.
      
      
         Yeah.
         See them run.
         
      
      
         Yeah.
         Exactly.
      
      
         All right.
         Did you have a favorite?
      
      
         Let me think
         .
         I can remember her helping me to read the, the books.
         The main ones were like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Emperor</ENAMEX> with no clothes--
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Yeah.
         You know, that type books.
         Absolutely.
      
      
         All right.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, are there any illustrations that you remember from books that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> read to you?
      
      
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, the one that stands out in my mind are the fables.
         I can remember as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> looking at all the fable pictures.
      
      
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, all right.
         Is there a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that you liked to, I mean, that read to you that you liked to hear?
      
      
         Yes, yes.
         My, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um, cousin Roseanne</ENAMEX>.
         She lived with us at the time.
         She's the one who got me interested in reading.
      
      
         How old was she?
      
      
         She was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> older than me.
         So
         you know, it was really a good age to--
      
      
         Is there a place that she read to you?
      
      
         We would sit on the living room <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>, by the lamp.
      
      
         What stories do you remember family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> telling you?
      
      
         Hmm
         .
         There again, a lot of them were the fables
         , mostly stories that had some type of moral or a catch to it, you know?
      
      
         Right.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, were there any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> with events, the stories that they told you, with anything that happened in real life?
         It doesn't have to be like stories from a book, any story.
      
      
         I had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> that would tell me like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX> stories and that type of thing, you know.
         And things that they remembered from you, uh, like from the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> or, you know, even though they weren't directly involved in that.
         That type thing.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, do you remember any of those?
         I mean, can you remember enough to tell any of it?
         If you can't, it's not a big deal.
      
      
         Well, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, she was just a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> when, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>.
         She told about how, you know, it was so hard for them to get anything.
         They had to grow everything they ate and they had nothing!
         And, of course, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> weren't one of these that had money in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> that they actually lost anything anyway.
         But of course when all the surrounding, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> or whatever, everybody had lost money and so the whole economy was totally poor whether they actually lost money or not.
      
      
         That's, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> talks about that, or used to talk about that.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         They had nothing and, of course, he looks like.
         ( ) All right.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, who is the best storyteller in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         The best storyteller in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>?
         I would have to say it would have been my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Lizzy</ENAMEX>, she's deceased now, but--
      
      
         Do you know why?
      
      
         She, I can remember as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, that in the, it was like she was ageless.
         And it was like she was old, but she was ageless.
         As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, she never changed.
         And she would like dance a little jig, you know, while she was telling stories.
         She was, oh!
         She was my favorite!
         That's who <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sara</ENAMEX>'s named after.
      
      
         Oh, OK.
         What kind of stories, um, did she tell?
      
      
         Just, a lot of times I think she would make up some of them, you know?
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Or just really embellish, you know?
         She would definitely add on.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But, uh, and, and there again, most of hers had morals, too.
         Like she would say, "Now what did we learn from that, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Debbie</ENAMEX>," you know?
         And I would say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uh...</ENAMEX>."
         And she would say, "Now that told you that...
         ," and she would go on.
         But she would, if she was talking about rabbits, she would jump around and she's up there and she's put socks on some kind of wires and made little rabbit ears out of them, and, you know?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         Just things that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would never have done!
      
      
         
         That's funny!
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Lizzy</ENAMEX> would always do it, so--
      
      
         
         So what kind of reaction would she get from you or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that heard her?
      
      
         
         Belly laughs!
         
         Roll on the floor laughing!
      
      
         Did they ever request for her to re-tell something?
      
      
         Oh yeah!
         Yeah.
         If we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion or something, a lot of us would get her to re-tell a story.
      
      
         Is there a particular story that you remember her telling?
      
      
         There was one about a rabbit and this, I can't remember all of it, and in fact, we were talking about it at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion not too awfully long ago, and a lot of them were adding bits and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> to it.
         Because I can just remember her getting up and jumping around and have you heard, uh, it's like a version of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Bunny Foo</ENAMEX>-foo."
      
      
         Uh huh.
      
      
         That type thing?
      
      
         
         OK.
         What stories do you tell yourself to keep going through hard times?
         Funny, sad, whatever.
      
      
         I guess it's, um, maybe a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> thing, just whatever, depending on whatever your mood is.
         If it's sad, you can always, you could always remember a story where, you know, somebody who has it a lot worse than you do!
         Or if it's happy, it's a, I don't know, it's just recalling memories.
         Yeah, I really like them.
         I can be reading a book and be totally lost in it and think, "Wow!
         I thought I was having <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad day</TIMEX>!"
         Or, you know, or you could be reading a really good book and thinking, "I wish my life were that easy," you know?
      
      
         Yes.
         Absolutely so.
         Is there one that, um, you've read lately that's like that you're kind of lost in it?
      
      
         Oh!
         The best books that I've read recently were the, uh, Left Behind series.
      
      
         Yeah.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy LaHaye</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jenkins</ENAMEX>
         .
         Yeah.
         Oh!
      
      
         I've only, we've only started the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> version of that, but, um, what, what I've had so far is good.
         It's absolutely a lesson for, you know--
      
      
         Oh absolutely
         .
         I'd like to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> version too, just to--
      
      
         Yeah, we need to read it.
         OK, well, I mean, can you sum up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those books or something that meant something to you in the book?
      
      
         Well, all of them.
         You know, of course, it's talking about being raptured and it's just such a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follower</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.
         I mean it, it follows really closely, and, um, you can't wait till the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> comes out.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I think one of my favorite parts is when the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> prophets, you know, they had the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>?
         You know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elijah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX> are at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wailing Wall</ENAMEX>?
         You know, if you haven't read it, I don't want to tell you about it yet, but oh!
         I mean it's, it's just, it's just wonderful!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         You know, it's, it's just like when the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> says it, says that they will be there and nothing.
         I mean if somebody threatens them or tries to harm them at all, they're immediately consumed in, uh, in uh burst of fire.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Well, you know, and then, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antichrist</ENAMEX> is trying to
         trying to say that well, you know, that they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX> hidden under their clothing, and, but they're, they're absolutely wearing their tattered, same tattered clothes that they would wear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.
         And it talks about them having the long scruffy beards, and they've been standing outside for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, and, um
         , you know, without bathing and without doing anything.
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         And, uh
         , of course, then, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> says, they're put to death again.
         But, I mean, it's, you know
         , God let's them, all of a sudden, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> they have no protection and, and they're killed.
         And then their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> are put out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and I mean everything is just as an example--
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         But then, you know, they come back to life again and God takes them up to heaven.
      
      
         Yeah, ( ).
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Is there a particular story you like from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Hmmm
         , I like a lot of them from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>.
         Umm, I think one of my favorite ones would have to be, oh goodness.
         I guess one of my favorite ones would have to be, uh, the one about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meshach, Shadrach</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abednego</ENAMEX>.
         I love that one.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, could you tell us why?
      
      
         Just the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the fire, you know!
         
      
      
         It's just cool to think that there's a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in there.
      
      
         Absolutely!
      
      
         OK, well, is there a story that you could tell us like, you know, from your life now?
         Something that isn't, doesn't have to be, you know, relevant.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I mean my favorite in the jalapeno story, but I don't think we'll put that on tape!
         [They both <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Laugh</ENAMEX>]
      
      
         
         Yeah.
         Really!
      
      
         
         For the whole world to know!
      
      
         I don't want them to know about the jalapeno story.
         OK
         , a favorite story.
         Hmmm.
         I'm trying to think
         .
         Oh I've got plenty of stories.
         You know, it's just a matter of thinking about one of them.
         
         Uh
         I can't think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
      
      
         
            It'd be easier if we were all sitting around--
      
      
         Oh absolutely.
         If somebody, if somebody brings up a topic, it's like well, "I can do better than that!"
         You know.
         "Let me tell you this!"
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Umm, well I could tell you that, you know, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is always saying that he thinks I'm a witch because I can say something and then it happens.
         You've probably heard that story before.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, we hadn't been married long and, and we were driving down the road <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>.
         I saw a box in the middle of the road, you know, and I looked over at him and, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> always automatically, you can just see them lining up like they're going to hit that, you know?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yep</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         Like it's a point system or something.
         I mean like they'll get some points for it.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And I said, "Don't hit the box."
         And he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Why?</ENAMEX>"
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, if it gets, if it doesn't come out from under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and it gets under the exhaust pipe and catch on fire."
         "OK," and I didn't say another word and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two miles</NUMEX> down the road, of course, you know, it was `fwapp, fwapp, fwapp,' you know?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About two</NUMEX> miles down the road he pulled over and I said, "What are you doing?"
         He said, "I've got to get out and get that stupid box.
         It's on fire!"
         And it was.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, just little things like that.
         So, to this day he'll, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three weeks ago</TIMEX> he called me and he said, "You'll never guess what happened to me now."
         And I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What?</ENAMEX>"
         He said, "I's driving down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>."
         And he said, "I saw this bag in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>."
         It wasn't even a box and he said, "I thought, `That's weird!
         ' And he said, "I couldn't, it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interstate</ENAMEX> and I couldn't, could not move over either way.
         I knew I was going to run over it."
         And he said, "I thought, `Now just wait and see if it does anything.
         '" And he said, he looked in his mirror and it didn't clear.
         And so he said, just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> later, he could smell something.
         He pulled over and it was hung on his exhaust pipe!
         
         
      
      
         Then.
         Just, just little things like that through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>.
         He, um, we were in CA, and we had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three days</TIMEX> and this is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip to CA.
         And I was just fascinated with the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> life, so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that we were going the shuttle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> was taking us back to um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAX</ENAMEX>.
         We were going to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Well</ENAMEX>, we got on the shuttle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> and it just dawned on me, you know.
         And I said, and I told him, "You know, I've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> as I've seen," I said, you know, "I've not seen a single accident."
         And he was like, "Oh, don't say that, don't say that.
         You'll jinx us!"
         I was like, you know.
         So we get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>.
         We fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> We rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and he decides he wants to take me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, drive down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rodeo Dr</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> because he's been there before.
         So I'm like, "OK," you know, "I'm all for it!"
         We get in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         We're headed down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">San Diego Freeway</ENAMEX>.
         Stop.
         Bap!
         
         And we get hit!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And he's like, you know, without saying, "Oh goodness," you know, "Are you all right?"
         His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> whips around and he says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How</ENAMEX>'s that?
         Is that a good enough accident for you?"
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And, of course, it was all my fault because I could have said something about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>.
         Of course I was in the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the um</ENAMEX>, the earthquake, the last earthquake from CA.
      
      
         Oh really?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         I didn't know that.
      
      
         Oh you didn't?
      
      
         No.
         I didn't know anything about that.
      
      
         I'm trying to remember what year that was.
         Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>?
         Was either `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">94</ENAMEX>?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ridgecrest</ENAMEX>?
         Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ridgecrest</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ridge</ENAMEX>, I can't remember the name of that.
         We were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX> when it happened.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northridge</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northridge</ENAMEX>.
         Yeah, um, and there again I'm such a sound sleeper that it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:30 in the morning</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> woke me up.
         He was saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Debbie, Debbie</ENAMEX>!
         Wake up!
         Wake up," you know, "It's an earthquake!"
         I'm like, "You would say anything to wake me up," you know?
      
      
         
      
      
         And then I, I realized that he's on his knees and the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is shaking.
         And I didn't know it at the time, but we were on the fifteenth story of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>-floor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.
         And I did not know it at the time, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> was built on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rollers</ENAMEX>.
         I mean it's built to sway and give.
      
      
         Yeah, but still.
      
      
         Yeah, but I mean the, the then that's another reason I know now that everything is bolted to the walls.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Everything, you know?
         Because you'd hear furniture crashing, but I can remember we went straight over to the window and we still had power, but we went straight to the window and it was just, I honestly, I think, thought we were going to die.
         All right, you could see transformers popping everywhere!
         Just looking, that's all you could see were lights.
         It looked like big flashes of light everywhere.
         And, uh, we immediately got on our knees and started praying, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>, because I knew we were goners!
      
      
         Yeah, I would.
      
      
         Absolutely.
         So--
      
      
         I didn't know you all were in that!
      
      
         Oh, yeah, yeah.
         It didn't really, it didn't really hit me, but later on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, we were flying to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And it didn't really hit me until we got to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>.
         Well, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle</ENAMEX>, the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle bus</ENAMEX>, took us to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, and on the way over there, I can remember he stayed on, on his little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> thing the entire time with the dispatcher.
         It was so foggy, or smoggy, probably fog, that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX>.
         It was so foggy you couldn't see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> feet in front of you, no more that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>.
         And he was like, "I'm heading down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura Blvd</ENAMEX>," or whatever.
         And she'd say, well, "Don't go past such and such because the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> is out."
         There were reports, and, and after I got home
         I'd see film clips on TV where like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> got killed.
         He was going across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> and, you know, it was so foggy he didn't know the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> was out and it was just there, you know, and the entire surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> around us was like that.
         There were <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> out, just, and not necessarily just a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>.
         Just, all of a sudden there would be a sinkhole in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were just going down into it, you know, that didn't know that it was there.
         So if it hadn't been for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and that radio, we would never have made it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>.
         But when we got to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, we were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> flight that they let leave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> and we were sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Air</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club lounge</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         There's other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming in and they were waiting on flights, and, you know--.
         We were all sitting there.
         Everybody was reliving their experiences and some talked about what happened to them.
         And they were talking about armoires that were falling across their bed that weren't, you know, bolted--
      
      
         Bolted
      
      
         --bolted down, and, all of the sudden I noticed that everybody, we were just all sitting there just like, like this right here, like we were old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> full of rocking chairs, you know?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ooh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And then I realized.
         I mean, that was that was just aftershocks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tremors</ENAMEX> from the, you know?
         And I thought, "What magnitude of power it would take to move the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LAX airport?</ENAMEX>"
         Here we were all sitting there, you know.
         And for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> we felt, we felt aftershocks and tremors.
         It's like a really bad case of vertigo, you know?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         And you just, just sitting there and you just get light-headed and you just think, "Oh it's my equilibrium that's all messed up."
         It was definitely an earthquake.
      
      
         Were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> with you?
      
      
         No.
         No, they were here with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.
         In fact, I had called my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and it's, it's lucky I called her as soon as I did because later on, the phones were down for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.
         But I called her and I said, "Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, I just wanted to let you know that we're all right," and she was like, "OK--"
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         "That's good."
         And I thought, you know, "We're <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> behind them out there," you know.
         She had no idea.
         And I was, "We just had an earthquake.
         I want you to know I'm fine."
         And she's like, "Oh my God."
      
      
         "Measured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> on the Richter Scale.
         It's all right."
         
      
      
         Absolutely.
         It's a good thing that I called her when I did, because later on when, if she had heard about it on the news, then she would have been, terribly upset.
         So--
      
      
         Yeah, bet so.
         I'm sure.
      
      
         But, yeah.
      
      
         You remember, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Hugo</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Oh yeah!
      
      
         You'd never forget it.
         Were you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> here?
      
      
         Yes, we'd been here since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July that year</TIMEX>, `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">89</NUMEX>.
      
      
         Welcome present.
      
      
         I was at work when it happened.
         It tore my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> all to pieces.
      
      
         Oh really?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         We had to stay in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, a ratty hotel at that, because there was no power, no--.
         The only place that was open in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hickory</ENAMEX> was, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domino</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX>.
         That was really scary!
      
      
         We only had power off for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> here.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         There were a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke Power</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who lived down here so, I think that kind of helped us a little bit, but, oh, my worse, I kept putting off the laundry, kept putting off the laundry and I said, "I can't take it anymore!"
         Drove it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">laundromat</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our</TIMEX> power came back on
         .
         You know, and, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>.
         I couldn't get any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>!
         I was dying for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>!
         That's all I wanted was <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But yeah, when <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hugo</ENAMEX> hit, I was at work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, and I worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">third</TIMEX> shift at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>.
         And, there was only, me and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.
         Of course, we were in the computer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And we had the generator.
         The rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> was totally out.
         She was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 months</TIMEX> pregnant.
         Had to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">restroom</ENAMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX>.
         Finally, I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>," you know, "we got to scrounge up the flashlight," because, you know, there were no lights in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>, no anything.
         And, and, you know, we had a pretty good walk, too.
         So I told her, I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>, we have the little area where we have all the supplies, that little computer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>?"
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, go up there.
         You can use the bathroom right there, instead of going," you know.
         And so that's what we did.
         And she said, "What if somebody drives by?"
         I'm like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, you know, who do you expect to drive by in the hurricane?"
      
      
         
         In the storm!
         
      
      
         That's right.
         And I thought, "No security patrol's going to be out here."
         But uh, you know, my and, and, when I got out there to where the little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> was at for the paper, I could see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>.
         I parked right beside this great big tree, and all that while I worried about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>, but not enough to where I was going to go out there and move it.
         You know?
      
      
         No!
      
      
         And the whole time we were in there, all you could hear was
         .
         That's all you can hear!
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And so, every little bit, I would go and stick my head out the door and, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>'s OK!"
         Well, of course I worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twelve hour</TIMEX> shift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days a week or three nights a week</TIMEX> and that, I guess <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about seven o'clock</TIMEX> was when the, the when the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were supposed to come in.
         It was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 7:30</TIMEX> and here come <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>.
         And that's, I'll never forget it.
         He came and then he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shh</ENAMEX>, what happened to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>?"
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         I'm like, "Nice try, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> is fine.
         I've been going over there <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> long."
      
      
         Been checking.
      
      
         He said, "No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, it's just awful!"
         I'm like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Right</ENAMEX>."
         Well I went out there and I looked and was like,
         ."
         You know?
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, or, uh, office up on the top floor was on the end, and, I don't know if you know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, but it's kind of, I don't know, like an oval and arc type shape.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Well, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> was like right here in the middle, like right here on the end, and the windows were blown out!
         All these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal aluminum blinds</ENAMEX> were wrapped around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         Oh my God!
         
      
      
         A piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet rock</ENAMEX>, I don't know how large this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet rock</ENAMEX> was, but it had blown around the curve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, like his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is here and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> was back here.
         It had blown around, slapped the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s window or my side.
         For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, every time I'd put my window down and come back up, you would see little slivers, little pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet rock</ENAMEX> on the side of my window.
         I mean it was awful!
         And I had pieces of it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s side door was all dented in.
         And, and little, later on, I didn't know it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> on that, uh, I guess, probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a year</TIMEX> after the hurricane hit, then you could start seeing little spots all over the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         That was glass.
         You know where it had just made little things that would--
      
      
         How weird!
      
      
         --that didn't show up immediately.
      
      
         Oh my gosh.
      
      
         Yeah!
         Oh yeah, it was like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1600.00</NUMEX> worth of damage to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Hugo</ENAMEX>.
         And then when uh, I ended up staying at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen hours that day</TIMEX> because, you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> were shut down and nobody was coming in.
         Finally, I got to come down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyvola</ENAMEX>; the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyvola</ENAMEX> above the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Coliseum</ENAMEX> was pretty new at that time.
         And I, I drove home that way and we'd only been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX>.
         I got all the way out here to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Rd</ENAMEX> at that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And there was a huge tree across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
         I couldn't make it any farther.
         And I didn't know any back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>.
         I didn't know how to go around and try and find.
         So I just pulled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> over and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> parking lot and I got out and started walking and I was just, I can remember live wires being everywhere, crackling and popping.
         And the first thing I saw when I got home, was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> over here, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> over.
         He was outside, he was, it was really funny.
         He was out and here I come walking up and looking like something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> drug in.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And he's like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie</ENAMEX>, Have you seen my shutters?"
         Every shutter on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> had blown away!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         He was like, "All of a sudden we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">KS</ENAMEX>!"
         And this was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX>!
         
         
      
      
         It was like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">No Jerry</ENAMEX>, I haven't."
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But it was it was really scary, the, just the scary, I mean I, I, it's weird, it's like I during the hurricane I really felt safe in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> but, driving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that were down.
         It was like I was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
         And when I finally got here, it's like, you know, just seeing everything, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>!
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the first things I noticed was, when I come up from the top of the hill, was my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, it looked like it had ivy growing all over it.
      
      
         Oh really?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Leaves from trees</ENAMEX> everywhere were up against the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
         Stuck on the--
      
      
         Yeah, I mean it was just like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">moss</ENAMEX> or something grown on everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> overnight.
         
         And all of these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> around here were new.
         And this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> right here was just being built and parts of the roof had blown off if it.
      
      
         I'm surprised it didn't damage this over here!
      
      
         I know!
         We were really, really lucky!
      
      
         Yeah.
         You all didn't have a lot of big <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, so that's good.
      
      
         No.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         No.
      
      
         We had, had, um, even our little peach <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, made it through everything.
         Everything that ever, we had a creek in the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and whenever it stormed, small storm or big storm, it just floods, come straight up.
      
      
         "Get under the bed!"
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> going to say, "Get under the bed!"
         
      
      
         Right.
         You know, I don't know why she did that.
         I think because we were all pretty fascinated with, um, storms outside of the window.
         We have sliding glass doors in our living room?
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         And we'd sit there and just watch.
         But now I wasn't stupid or nothing when the lights were going `shz, shz,' you know, but she's, "Get under the bed!"
         in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>.
         She's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those tall <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-poster beds, like that w as going to save us, but we had to get under there a lot when I was growing up, bad storms--
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         But, no, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hugo</ENAMEX>, we had to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Johnson</ENAMEX>'s or something.
         No the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hickory Motor Inn</ENAMEX>!
         
         To take a shower!
         
      
      
         I'll tell you what!
         I would have gone just to get a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>!
         
         
      
      
         That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of not taking a shower!
         
      
      
         Oh, I know!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Absolutely!
      
      
         That's funny!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         I'm trying to think, um, some stories that you told me that, you know, can be aired!
         
      
      
         Without offending any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>!
         
      
      
         That's right!
      
      
         Which is the most important thing here!
         I'm trying to think, because you're always telling stories and I just can't, my mind is gone, like your mind is gone on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.
         
         Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ida</ENAMEX> ever tell you any stories?
         Or was she not more--.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunts</ENAMEX> read to me in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         Not my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> a whole lot.
      
      
         Well, same here.
         I mean, it's, she would tell me stories about my early childhood.
         Things, you know, stories about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> died um, before I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>.
         So I didn't hardly--
      
      
         You don't remember anything, do you?
      
      
         And she would tell me a lot of stories about him and, you know--
      
      
         The kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that he was?
      
      
         Right.
         Just real stories, you know, things that
         .
         Like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> TV set, you know, when we used to have well water, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> had to be, you know, got out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every afternoon</TIMEX>.
         Just, you know--
      
      
         Yeah.
         The hard stuff.
      
      
         --that type of thing.
      
      
         What was your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> like?
      
      
         Well--
      
      
         That she told you.
      
      
         From stories that, from her and from, uh, other family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, I mean, everybody, they would always say that, that he would always be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to help you.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> always said that, that he would help a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>, you know, get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> out of a ditch or whatever.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And, and it would take her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> to get him to do something for her around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         You know, and like she say, "OK <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac</ENAMEX>," you know, "You need to, we've got a hole in the roof," and she would use that as an example.
         And, "I'll get to it.
         I'll get it fixed."
         And then, you know, get up at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> because somebody's called because somebody's in a ditch or something.
         You know?
         That type of thing.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And then, basically, everybody's always told me that he was a really big practical joker.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         But, uh, actually kind of a mean practical joker!
      
      
         You got some of that then!
         
         
      
      
         Yeah!
         Absolutely!
      
      
         And you help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah.
         And I would never do anything to hurt anybody or destroy property, you know.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But, um, I mean I wouldn't take a practical joke that far, but there's nothing funnier than a real good practical joke!
      
      
         Yeah.
         Do you have any?
         That you can share?
         
      
      
         Like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>, he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, and one of them was his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>.
         I mean, they all say, you know, that she was his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>, and she was telling about when
         it was so hard for her to get to go on a date because everybody was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>.
         Forget his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>!
         They were afraid of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>!
         And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them said that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> he walked out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and they got where they wouldn't come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and she had to walk down this long driveway to pick her up.
         And she said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> come over there and she said, "He was so nice to my date!"
         And her date stayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         And said, she said my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> was leaning in over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> side, like where she was sitting?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And she said, "He just kept talking to us and just telling us what a good movie was playing and all this type thing.
         And he was so nice!"
         She said they didn't realize it until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX> that even while he stood there talking to him, he had painted all up and down the side of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s car!
         
      
      
         Oh my goodness!
      
      
         That type thing, you know?
         That's--
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         --That's what I said, I don't destroy property, you know!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, she just built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and, you know back then, I mean, uh, she had, uh, she was probably one of the first ones in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that own a brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, you know?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had built a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> did a lot of the carpentry work.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, once it was built and they got moved in, she told everybody that as soon as they got in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to take their shoes off, well, from what I gather, it really made my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> mad because he had helped build it, and, you know.
         So he went and got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> and took the goat back down there with him into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>!
         
      
      
         You know, just things like that!
         I mean--
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         --I'm not malicious, so--
         
         
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>, well, he didn't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> riding in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and he made them duck down in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billing's Store</ENAMEX> and when they got there, he'd push them out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         [They both laugh]
      
      
         Because he was so embarrassed!
         But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time he ran over, they went to ( ) down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hickory</ENAMEX>.
         I don't know if you know where that is, but sort of near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Longview</ENAMEX>, actually.
         But they went to this snack bar <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, that's the kind of place where everybody pulled in and they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         And, uh, he ordered something and then he got out and he was cruising around, acting cool, and everything.
         But he almost killed this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>!
         
         He turned around the curve and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was holding the thing like this!
         
      
      
         He was holding, the drink he was holding was going, "shzzzz!"
         Sitting there holding--
         
         
      
      
         See, I love stuff like that!
         I love stuff like that!
         I mean, that's absolutely--
      
      
         Of course, he won't tell us anything, because he won't tell us much of anything about his past because he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohawk</ENAMEX> and he just--
      
      
         
            Yeah.
      
      
         He's real quiet about the things he had done.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         I think we don't want to know what he did.
      
      
         That's like you tell your stories to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and it's like, "Who did you date when you were growing up?"
         "I dated really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.
         You know, very clean-cut."
         Oh my God!
         If they'd seen some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> I used to date!
         
         "Oh really!
         They were all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>!"
      
      
         That's true.
      
      
         Oh!
         Absolutely!
      
      
         ( ) I went with him, but, I mean, you know--.
         But you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> aren't very opposite.
         I mean, not really.
      
      
         No, not, I mean, oh, I don't know.
         There's a lot of things we are opposites in, but it all evens out.
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Compliments</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah, all compliments each other.
         Like, he hates to read, you know.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> does, too.
      
      
         And I love to read.
      
      
         Everybody has their own.
      
      
         Absolutely.
         And I'm afraid that all of them are going to be like him in the area.
         I mean, at least it's not, nobody likes to read like I do.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         You know?
      
      
         Right.
         Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> like to read like you do?
      
      
         Who?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>?
         Do they, they're, are they kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         They've slowed down.
         They're were doing really good, but--
      
      
         Doing OK in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Absolutely!
         I think a lot of it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>.
         Yeah.
         I'm all for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>, but at the same time, like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>, I had this little thing that kind of upsets me.
         Like right now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> has to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>.
      
      
         On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AR</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         It's hard for her to read at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, it's hard for her to read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-point books.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX> it's--
      
      
         Exactly because it has to be done before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And if she reads a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-point book and takes a test on it, she misses a question, she gets point-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>.
         The reading another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point book, she's going to get, say she gets a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> on it, she's still only got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-point-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and she had to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points.
         So, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> it seems like I have to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and get these little point-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> books as, I call them "fillers," just to fill in.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And, and, and I think, to me, I'm afraid that I'm taking away the joy of reading.
      
      
         Exactly.
      
      
         If I said, "You've got to read this now!"
         You know?
      
      
         Exactly.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amanda</ENAMEX>, she gets to read self-selected books and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> starting to read self-selected books.
         But, um, I think it's important because not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like athletic books.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         I probably never read a sports book in my life!
      
      
         I don't think I ever have.
      
      
         As much as I like to read, sports just isn't one of the things that held any interest for me whatsoever.
         I always liked books about true stories, whether it was, it could be murders, you know, those always grabbed my attention, I guess because I knew it really happened.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         That's just like, historical places.
         I've been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo</ENAMEX>.
         I've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alcatraz</ENAMEX> like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times.
         It's like one of my favorite places in the world.
         I'd give anything if I could stay over there.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> on The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Actually, I was there before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Really?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         It's crying shame!
      
      
         The whole thing, you know!
         I could not get enough information about <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alcatraz</ENAMEX>!
         We got to meet one of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> over there and one of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>.
         Yeah, I`ve got a bunch of pictures with him, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         Actually, I bought one of his books
         , but, um, I mean, it's just fascinating to me, you know!
         To be on "the rock" and just--.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> was, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> was talking about, he said, you know, he said, "They think that it's not, we're not being punished enough.
         Like when we got to go outside to the exercise yard."
         He said, "But if you don't think that it's not punishment.
         He said, "I promise you that I could stand outside in this yard and look across the harbor where you can see the whole bay area," and he said, "If it was quiet enough, you could swear you could hear champagne glasses clinking together."
         Your, I guess your imagination, you know, what all going on there, you know.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         But I, oh!
         I just absolutely loved it!
         I mean, I wouldn't want to be incarcerated or anything.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         I would love, I would love to be able to stand right over there, you know?
         Just, just to see, oh!
         This is wonderful!
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         I would have liked to have been there when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were over there, you know?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Machinegun Kelly</ENAMEX> and--.
         Oh!
         I would have loved it!
         Love it!
      
      
         When did they close that place?
      
      
         Nineteen, I forget.
         Nineteen sixty something.
         Yeah, um--
      
      
         I mean a whole, is it an island?
      
      
         Absolutely.
      
      
         And the whole thing's a prison?
      
      
         Yeah.
         Absolutely!
         Well, they had warden's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>; they all lived there.
      
      
         Oh really?
      
      
         Yeah.
         But there's no fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
         I mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> they had to ferry a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> back and forth and bring fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
         You know, there's, because it's just right there in the middle, you know.
         There's no fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and no way of getting fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> over there, other than by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And so, um, of course everything that's over there, you know how <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX> damages, you know?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         So everything that's over there is such, just such a hard place to upkeep.
         And it was so cold and each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> was assigned a little light, almost like a cardigan type sweater--
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         --and a blanket.
         And that's what they had year `round.
         Of course, it's not supposed to be like, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn</ENAMEX> or anything.
      
      
         Yeah.
         I know.
      
      
         There are a lot of bad things about it, its location.
      
      
         That's wild.
         How far is it off the--
      
      
         It's like right.
         Here's the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden</ENAMEX>, you can stand right there and like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX>, you get under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisherman's Wharf</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX>'s right there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, you can see <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate Bridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alcatraz</ENAMEX>, there's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Oakland Bridge</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         --and it's just all right there together.
      
      
         Cool.
      
      
         If I had the, it's probably a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minute</TIMEX> ferry ride.
         But, I mean, that's just a little ferry.
         If I was on a motorboat, it would probably not take me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> to get over there.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         You know, I mean, it's, you can see it, it's just right there.
         It's beautiful and that's why it's called The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rock</ENAMEX>; it literally looks like a big rock just popped out of the ocean and just, you know, water all the way around it.
      
      
         I mean, I'd like to go sometime, but it's not on my "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great To-Do list"</ENAMEX> or anything.
      
      
         It's wonderful!
         Absolutely wonderful!
      
      
         I mean I'd like to go to CA and see the redwoods.
         That's really what I want to see.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Have you been to see the redwoods?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         We went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bear</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake</ENAMEX> and we stayed at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alberta</ENAMEX>?
         It's a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX>?
         It was a little bitty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, but it's ski <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and, um, they'd just finished filming a movie.
         And we were right beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>.
         Where, um, Back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future II</ENAMEX> had been filmed.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         We went panning for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and went horseback riding down there and, um, um, but when we went to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, there was one <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.
         I have pictures of this too.
         You just have to see it to believe it.
         I put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on it just so you could get an idea of about how large it was.
         But this tree, it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six years or five years</TIMEX>, so I don't remember the exact width or anything, but this tree was so large, and it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one that they had spotted, so they cut it down and there was--.
         OK, this is how big it was, this tree that when the trunk part, they holed it all out and made a bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> out if.
         I think like a four-lane bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         Ooh!
      
      
         A four-lane bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> out of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         God!
      
      
         And right behind it, the stump or whatever was leveled off and they made a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar room</ENAMEX> with a dance floor out of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>!
         I mean, it was so huge!
         It was unreal!
         Things like that, I mean, that stuff fascinates me!
         They had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> where you could literally drive through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> was kind of like sculpted out and big enough for you to drive through!
      
      
         How neat!
      
      
         I, I have pictures, like started taking a picture and I make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> stand like this, with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, you know, and still have tree on both sides of them, on either side of them.
         Just amazing!
         These huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>!
         And that doesn't begin to tell you how tall they were!
         I just couldn't get over it!
         It's just huge!
         I mean, it's just huge!
      
      
         That's cool.
         Was that your favorite vacation spot?
         CA?
      
      
         My favorite vacation spot?
         That would be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh really?
      
      
         It's just, I mean I wouldn't want to live there.
         Oh God!
         Just the bustle and the, well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> would be working, normally, when we were there.
         I've taken the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> once.
         The rest of the time it would be like, everywhere.
         I just couldn't wait for him to get up and go to work, wherever he had to go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>.
         I was hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wharf</ENAMEX>, you know, I mean, just everything from the sights, the sounds, the smells, the everything!
         I just loved it all!
         The cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, everything!
         I would stop on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wharf</ENAMEX> and get some, um, prawns for lunch or something, you know?
      
      
         That's kind of cool!
      
      
         It was just wonderful!
         I wouldn't want to live there!
         But it was just absolutely wonderful!
         Every time he goes back, he has to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, I always try to go.
         If we have enough points to go, I'll go.
      
      
         I'll have to go.
         Is the temperature really hot or cool?
      
      
         It's pretty, well, cool.
         But most of the time when I've been there, it's been around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> and it's not, it doesn't seem like it's as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX> as it is here, but it's always foggy and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>'s pretty rainy, too.
         But it's never so bad that it keeps me from doing anything, you know?
         I mean, I can still walk all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and I never remember having to walk with an umbrella.
         So, but, pretty often <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> is kind of cloudy and just--
      
      
         And you can shop a lot?
      
      
         Yeah.
         Yeah and there's, you know, in CA, it's unlike it is here, they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.
         You know, you go buy a loaf of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, it's like a loaf of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> stuck in one of the old paper popcorn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX>, you know.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         I mean it's not cellophane with a twist-tie, "There you go!"
         You know?
         It's like a loaf of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> that you can chew on while you're walking down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         So and, and, the things that, that are everywhere over there.
         You can literally just walk down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, you can get you a bowl of clam chowder in the scooped out <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, you know?
      
      
         Oh yeah.
      
      
         And I mean, just, just things that you don't get here, you know?
      
      
         We have a hot dog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> where they actually do that, put <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>, but it's expensive.
      
      
         Oh yeah!
         Absolutely!
         I think that, uh, where were we?
         Oh!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX>!
         They have it there, too.
         I was trying to think, the only other place I've seen it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carowinds</ENAMEX>, but no, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX>.
         But yeah, I mean, just everything about it was so complex.
         And then you had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, not just begging for money.
         It's not like they're just standing there asking for handouts like they do here.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing something for the money.
         And they take turns.
         Where the, I think it's Market and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Powel Streets</ENAMEX>?
         Market, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powel</ENAMEX>.
         Those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> all intersect somewhere where the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are running.
         And where they all come down and turn around, it's like these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all have scheduled show times, you know?
         Like at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one o'clock</TIMEX>, you have this Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> down there, they're playing a fiddle, and he'll play for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>, it's time for the next cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to come in and turn around, and everybody's just gathered around there.
         He passes his little hat around or his fiddle case or whatever and everybody throws money in it.
         Well, then next time, it's a juggler, and the next time it's a mime, and the next time it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who play guitars.
      
      
         Um-hum.
      
      
         But it's always something going on.
         And, you know, it's just the culture and I'm always thinking, you know, it's not, at least they're not expecting, they are providing you some type of entertainment; they're doing something, you know.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And uh, that's the type thing that you really--
      
      
         That's neat.
      
      
         Yeah, just, it's just really nice to see all those things going on.
         I can remember this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> standing there and he had this little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>.
         I don't know what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> it was, but it couldn't have been <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than a foot</NUMEX> tall standing on his little hind legs, and he also had a little hat and sunglasses and you could have your picture made with him for a dollar.
         
      
      
         Just things like that.
         Things that you do not see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>!
         It's almost like going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carowinds</ENAMEX> or someplace and seeing all these little, special little things, you know.
         But they're all over the place.
         All you have to do is open your eyes and you're there!
         You have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX> that, you know, are selling homemade jewelry and there's still a lot of the old hippies, and you'd see a lot of the old hippies, too.
         There's a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> like that in CA.
         That's my favorite!
         CA would have to be my favorite vacation spot!
      
      
         Sounds like the place to go!
         
      
      
         You got to go!
      
      
         I want to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX> and all that.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         See all that.
      
      
         Yeah.
         I'd like to do that, too.
         I haven't done that yet.
         There's a lot, in fact, telling about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> is my favorite spot, that's my problem, see.
         I get to travel so infrequently that when I do get to go, I'm always thinking, "Well maybe, I'd love to go do this and this and this."
         And I think, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, what if I go and I don't have as much fun as I would if I had gone to," you know?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         So, I know if I go here, I'll have fun if I go here!
         So I'll go back there, you know?
      
      
         That's what I tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>.
         I want to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>.
         I wouldn't live there.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         But, it is so awesome!
      
      
         That's another place I'd like to go.
      
      
         I mean, it is so busy but if you want to be alone, you can be alone.
         In one of the busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in the world!
      
      
         Absolutely!
      
      
         And nobody cares!
         And then you could walk down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pier</ENAMEX> and it must be a little bit like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> only they don't have, well, they do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down there making money, but they're mostly drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and stuff like that.
         It is beyond cool!
         And nobody but, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say they're indifferent or whatever, but not really, it's just that it's a whole different
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifestyle</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         Exactly!
         Absolutely.
      
      
         They don't, I don't, their driving is,
         my driving, I don't know, but,
         I was getting screamed at and everything else, but, it's just a different place.
         Now I like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schaumburg</ENAMEX>, it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX>, and there's not, you know, it would be like being here, you know.
         Or like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gastonia</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Blvd</ENAMEX>, stuff like that.
         You had everything you needed.
         You didn't have to go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         You could go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for something special, you know, that was just there, but everyday living, you could just stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Schaumburg</ENAMEX> and never to leave.
      
      
         That's one thing I liked about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>.
         When we stayed right there, right in the heart of it, I could walk anywhere I wanted to go.
         And we weren't, I could literally walk out of my hotel and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> blocks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisherman's Wharf</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">piers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pier 39</ENAMEX> is my favorite, it had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> on it and you know, and, and, these seals, and nobody knows why.
         And I mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of seals just started coming to this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX>.
         And they've got all the little boat slips, well, they're just covered with seals all the time!
         And nobody knows why, they just started coming up there, you know.
         But it's just wonderful!
         There's, there's so many things that you never get the chance to see anywhere else, but you can see it all just walking around.
         And then, of course, you have Lombard <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">St</ENAMEX>, the crookedest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in the world.
         I've walked down that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and it's amazing, you know!
      
      
         Just like those movie spots.
      
      
         Absolutely the crookedest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in the world, yeah.
         And all those are right there within walking distance.
         Then you take a cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And still that's not that far, but after walking up and down those hills!
         You are ready for bed when you go to bed that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But it is absolutely wonderful!
         There's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, there's um, all kinds of like comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and stuff.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, it's just a whole different world.
         I mean, everything that you can imagine seeing all at once, it's just--.
         And you can smell, you have to love <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX>, you can smell seafood all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and hot breads and go get you a bowl of chapino and a big old thing of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and just--
      
      
         What's chapino?
      
      
         It's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fisherman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stew</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         We make it here.
         In fact, I bought, I got the recipe from the little, where we went to eat at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fisherman's Wharf</ENAMEX>.
         At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grotto</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Got the recipe for chapino.
         It's got like a tomato-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX>, and then it's got uh, oysters, it's got, um, crab <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">claws</ENAMEX>, it's got shrimp, but nothing's peeled!
         So you have to have these big bibs on.
         It's not something you'd want to eat on a date, you know?
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Because it makes such a mess!
         But when we make it here at home, but, of course, we peel everything.
      
      
         Thank God!
      
      
         When we make it at home, we put like the whitefish in it, and like, uh, uh, tilapia.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, oysters and shrimp, you know.
         I don't know if I put any crab in it.
         But it's just wonderful!
         Wonderful!
      
      
         I think my favorite, um, food story from here is
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> putting
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork rinds</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>!
         
      
      
         Oh God!
         Absolutely!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atkins Diet</ENAMEX>!
         Yeah!
         Just crush up those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork rinds</ENAMEX> and roll your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> in it!
      
      
         It's much more creative really!
      
      
         Yep!
      
      
         That's when you get real desperate.
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>, again, somebody was asking me from church <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>, he recently went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s breakfast, the one they have once a month on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>?
         And, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> came back and said that, he said, "I had to fix <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gravy</ENAMEX> for them."
         And I'm like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uh oh</ENAMEX>!"
         He said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What?</ENAMEX>"
         I said, "I didn't know you knew how to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX>!"
         "But they've been asking me for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."
         And basically that's right, they have.
         But I told them, I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> is one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who could improvise."
         So I have learned after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 years</TIMEX> of marriage, I have learned, "If you don't want to know, don't ask."
      
      
         Don't ask!
      
      
         Because he won't lie to you.
         He will not lie to you.
         If he tells you something, it's the truth!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         I promise you, he will not lie to you!
         Like, for instance, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> there was a little gravy story.
         He had made <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gravy</ENAMEX>.
         As I sat down to eat it, I thought, "We don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>!"
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> likes powdered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, he grew up on that welfare-type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         
      
      
         Yuck!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         But anyway, with a clothespin on my nose, I was sitting there thinking, and it was white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gravy</ENAMEX>, it was not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water gravy</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>?
         How did you make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gravy</ENAMEX>?"
         No answer.
         So then I got to thinking, "We don't have any powdered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>--."
         "Yes we do!"
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>, look me straight in my eyes and tell me you did not put baby formula in this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gravy</ENAMEX>!"
         And he looked at me and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How's it taste?</ENAMEX>"
         I knew I was eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">baby formula gravy</ENAMEX>!
         
      
      
         
         Eeeww!
      
      
         So you know, hey!
         If I hadn't have known, I would have been fine, but knowing, it's like, "Ooh!"
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         I was glad I had quit nursing or he would have had breast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> in there!
         
      
      
         There's some things you don't want to know!
         
      
      
         Absolutely!
         I mean it's just like, like...I've learned, if you don't want to know don't ask him!
         Because he can, he can come up with stuff you wouldn't ever think about, you know?
      
      
         Was it OK?
      
      
         Yeah!
         I mean it tasted fine, but it was just knowing that it was in there.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Enfamil gravy</ENAMEX>, you know?
      
      
         That's hilarious!
         That's nasty, too!
      
      
         Absolute ly!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh-huh</ENAMEX>!
         Whew!
      
      
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>'s told me about some of his creative stuff, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>'s pretty creative, too.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Like the time he cooked, he left the--
      
      
         Red vinegar?
      
      
         Oh please!
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> says stuff about it too and I'm like ( ) and I'm, "No we can't!"
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         "Forget it!"
         
         But, no, he um, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time put, he said, "I'm going to marinate these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon steaks</ENAMEX>."
         Neither one of us had had it in our whole married life.
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Uh-huh</ENAMEX>, that would be nice."
         He's going to marinate it and cook it later, you know.
         And it ended up--, and oh God!
         It had the worst ( ).
         It was pretty--.
         I said, "What did you put in this?"
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red vinegar</ENAMEX>."
         Red <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vinegar</ENAMEX> and it ruined it.
         It had, oh God!
         It was awful!
         "I'm not going to do that again!"
         On <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">salmon steak</ENAMEX>, I know.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         It was nasty, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>!
         I don't think you put vinegar on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>.
         I don't really know.
      
      
         I don't think, no.
         HC: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vinegar</ENAMEX>'s too strong for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>.
         It'll go right through it.
         With <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> and stuff, maybe a little vinegar.
      
      
         We'll have to make a big pot of chapino and bring it out there.
      
      
         Oh golly!
         I'd love to!
      
      
         The only time we did it was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bubba</ENAMEX> lived here, because it's really expensive and we'll all go in together and make the ingredients.
         But uh, it's, and we even made our own little, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> we all, we always made, you know, I got the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> machine and we always make a big loaf of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>.
         Use it to dip in there.
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>'s fine, I said, "You know," I said, "I would love to have some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta</ENAMEX>!"
         So from that time on, every time we'd fix it, me and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bubba</ENAMEX> would fix a big pot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">angel hair pasta</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Um-hum.
      
      
         It's real thin.
         Pour that chapino over it!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX>, it was delicious!
         I mean it's, you use olive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>.
         It's got garlic and um, I'm trying to remember what kind of peppers are in it, but it is so good!
         And you have to, uh, braise the little onions and stuff, you know.
         It's, it's to die for!
         It's awesome!
         Awesome!
      
      
         Cool!
         Yeah.
         I've never had oysters, but--
      
      
         Even my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will eat it!
         Isn't that something, too?
         I mean, once you get to dipping out, you, you don't have to get an oyster, you know?
      
      
         Yeah.
         I don't want no oyster in it!
         
      
      
         Amanda grew up eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oysters</ENAMEX>.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> time she was sitting in the highchair, she'd say, "That's no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>!"
         And then an oyster I bought her at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fish Camp</ENAMEX>, and she'd, she'd bit into it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are normally gray, you know?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         She'd bite it and, "OK, just keep it."
         You know?
         Didn't faze her in the least!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nate</ENAMEX>'s eating, um, real food now.
         He had um, well actually, we tried those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gerber</ENAMEX> ones that have the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peas</ENAMEX> and stuff like that, a little piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> in the bottom.
         And um, he, he actually ate, like he'll eat baby food <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> or sometimes baby food <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal</ENAMEX>, not, you know, not all the time.
         He eats <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> at the daycare.
      
      
         You better watch it!
         I told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>, I said, you know, "Let me think about it."
         Once you've tried table food, can you imagine sucking on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them bottles, you know?
      
      
         I know.
         It won't bother me because he drinks too many bottles right now.
      
      
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasmine</ENAMEX>'s down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> bottles a day.
      
      
         Really?
      
      
         Yeah, um, when we kept her, I gave her, she had one about, about, well, it's always nap time like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 in the morning around 10:00</TIMEX>, one around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:00 or 3:00</TIMEX> and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at nighttime.
      
      
         Well, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nate</ENAMEX> has to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six or seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>.
         And it's getting old by about, I bet we spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180.00</NUMEX> if not more dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formula</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         God!
      
      
         Because he, he...you know I am and he's a bottle freak!
         And I don't know, but I can't afford that much longer and I figure, well he seems--
      
      
         Yeah, well, he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 months old</TIMEX>.
      
      
         It's almost time to, to--
      
      
         Well, I, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, I mean from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that mine turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year old</TIMEX>, I started buying whole <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Absolutely!
         Because even, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> said she's complaining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> she's saying, you know, between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jasmine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darnell</ENAMEX>, she said, "I buy...
         ' they drink <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">at least one gallon</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> a day.
         It's like normally they'll drink a whole gallon and start on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second every day</TIMEX>, so...you're looking at, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine gallons</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>.
         So, but, even at that at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three dollars</NUMEX> a gallon, you know?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         What is that?
         <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27.00</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>?
         Something like that.
         If it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine gallons</NUMEX>
      
      
         I must spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $50.00</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, usually.
      
      
         So you're still saving some, but--
      
      
         Well, I'm ready for it, but now he's decided he'd eat the real <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
         And then, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had this surgery and we went over there and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX> I guess we'll take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> because that's the fastest thing."
         So he went in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX> and got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those buckets with the slaw and everything.
         And um, I shredded up little pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and mashed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> and goes through these phases where he never eats and you know he never eats.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         But he ate that up and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, "He acts like he's a little constipated."
         And I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX> when you get in there, try and get me some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>," because when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen</ENAMEX> started eating real slow, when she got hooked in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> that was it.
      
   
