
   
   
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One two three</NUMEX> testing, testing.
         I am <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee Cheezem</ENAMEX> and I'm doing an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Cheezem</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 12th</TIMEX> um how old are you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         47.
      
      
         In what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> were you born?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States of America</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         In which part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And grew up, where?
      
      
         In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> as well?
      
      
         Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt</ENAMEX>, you understand from the form that you signed that this um interview is part of a research project on storytelling and I wonder what your earliest memories of stories being told to you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> might be.
      
      
         Those would be stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>, experiences they had in the depression wars and things like that.
      
      
         Can you remember the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> story that you can remember anyone telling you some of the first memories of someone telling you a story?
      
      
         Well, it would probably been things like living back in the hills of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TN</ENAMEX> and having to ride a mule to school,
         things like that.
      
      
         Who would have been telling you those stories?
      
      
         This would have been my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Were there other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who told you stories when you were very young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> perhaps?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Grandparents grandfathers</ENAMEX> told me things about
         things he did when he was younger and a construction carpenter and places things he'd been things he'd build.
      
      
         Do you remember anyone in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> telling you stories that were just maybe made up stories or funny stories?
      
      
         Well, I don't think that too many of them were made up some of them seemed kind of funny at the time.
      
      
         Do you remember any specific ones that you could retell?
      
      
         
         Well I remember tales about some of our relations.
         For example, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX> who uh had his own airplane and decided
         one thing he always wanted to do was land his airplane on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> so he arranged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> to coincidentally run out of gas nowhere near an airport so he could have the experience of landing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and taxiing up to a gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> to fill it up and take off again.
         At least that's what everyone accused him of doing.
      
      
         So you're not sure if this was a true story or a made up story within your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I know it's true that he landed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> we had the newspaper clippings to prove it.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>But the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> part// you're not sure about.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> The gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> part.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Yeah, he taxied to a gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> to fill it up.
      
      
         And who told you that story?
      
      
         Uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
         He also showed me the newspaper clipping.
      
      
         Do you remember being read to when you were little?
      
      
         \\Oh yes.
         \\
      
      
         \\Reading stories to you?
         \\ Can you remember the very first stories that were
         read when you were little?
      
      
         Probably one of the first ones that was ever read to me the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one I can remember is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Glenda reading Trumpet the Dog</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         It's one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Golden</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes, I remember all the things about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trumpet the Dog</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Can you retell the story?
         Can you remember all the details of the story basically?
      
      
         Pretty much.
         There was Trumpet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and he was always raising false alarms.
         And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX> got in the hen <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and he went running barking and nobody wanted to believe it was him and he finally drug him out there and lo and behold there it was.
         Something to that effect.
      
      
         So this story was read to you by your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Mostly.
      
      
         How old would you say you were when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> were doing this reading?
      
      
         Well, I was about
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> at the time.
         They were let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> was probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glenda</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10 or 11</NUMEX>.
      
      
         So your younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> was just a beginning reader herself reading stories to you?
         And you remember that one because it was read often or it was your favorite?
      
      
         Yeah, it was one of the ones we read pretty often, it was also the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one I learned to read.
      
      
         Did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> read stories to you also?
      
      
         Some.
      
      
         Did you have any family storytelling rituals, a story at bedtime reading a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible story</ENAMEX> or any of those sorts of things?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, not real continuous or anything.
      
      
         Who in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would have been most likely to read, to read this you a story or tell you a story?
      
      
         Probably depended on which night it was.
         Probably more likely my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> than anyone else.
      
      
         Did you have lots of storybooks
         at your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that were read to you?
         BC: We always had books lots of books.
      
      
         You said that you remembered the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trumpet the Dog</ENAMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> reading to you.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, did that go on for a long time until you were able to begin reading stories on your own?
      
      
         I spent a lot of time at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> from about the time I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> probably I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or nine</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Even after you said that you learned to read the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trumpet the Dog</ENAMEX>, after you began to read on your own did sometimes your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still read or tell stories to you even though you could read?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         What was, well you clearly remember this story, but once you got a little older and could remember a little better, what would you say some of your favorite stories and books were, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> growing up?
      
      
         How old are you talking about?
      
      
         Oh, elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> age.
      
      
         Well, probably the favorite book I had, this is a little different
         I had <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Giant Golden Book of Astronomy</ENAMEX>, which I got when I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade and I read it cover to cover till I wore it out.
      
      
         Yeah and why was that particular <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> special?
      
      
         Well, because it was really interesting stuff.
         It was about the same time when all the space program was getting started off and I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> launched the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> and I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade when the first manned space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">capsule</ENAMEX> was sent up and because of what was going on at the time it was real interesting.
         The book just tied right into it.
      
      
         So that one you really enjoyed and you read over and over again?
         What about um what about and it was of course it sounds like a true book a scientific book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and space.
         What about fictional stories?
         Do you remember storybooks or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s novels that you read growing up or you like?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> had a real interesting history books.
         They were sort of semi-factual fiction history <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, like stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington</ENAMEX> growing up, some of the explorers of the West, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fremont Carson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that.
         ()
      
      
         So you really liked historical and non-fiction kinds of things?
         But I also know that you like fantasy as well?
      
      
         Science fiction.
         I didn't get started on that till I was in about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade.
      
      
         And you learned to read quite young, didn't you?
      
      
         I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> at the time.
      
      
         If I remember correctly the stories that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has told me, you pretty quickly progressed to reading serious you moved pretty quickly from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trumpet the Dog</ENAMEX> to more heavyweight reading materials didn't you?
      
      
         Yeah, I guess so.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, do you um, do you remember any particular books or stories that you feel like had an impact on you as you grew into adulthood stories that maybe the message of the book or story has had a real impact on your life?
      
      
         I'd say quite a few.
         
            Well, let's see,
         there's I guess one of the favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s of mine is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Asimov</ENAMEX> who wrote some of the best science and science fiction that was ever written.
         A lot of his books aren't really fiction but scientific essays that he prepared for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>.
         I guess one of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> I like a lot uh is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.S. Lewis</ENAMEX>.
         I've read several of his books both fiction and non-fiction books.
      
      
         Do you think that um reading these books when you were a teenage and older elementary school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> had some impact in your career decisions, to study mathematics and more technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         It's kind of a, "which is the cause and which is the effect," question.
         Asimov, his writing is very good sound factual.
         It's also very interesting easy to follow for that type of writing.
         I read a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> that weren't, weren't as good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> but also had interesting ideas.
         I think the best combination of interesting ideas and interesting writing.
      
      
         When you think back to when you were younger and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were telling stories to you and reading stories to you, um, it sounds like the time you spent with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> when all this was happening is a time in your life that you remember real fondly?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         Do you think that reading and storytelling is a big part of that?
      
      
         I would say so.
      
      
         Now that, that you're an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> obviously and have had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of your own what stories do you remember telling to your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and reading to your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well, let's see.
         I've read <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cat in the Hat</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 475</NUMEX> times.
         All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Little Monster Books</ENAMEX>, I can't remember what the individual names of them were but I've read them all multiple times.
         RC: Do you remember telling them not only reading to them but telling them stories as well some of the stories that were perhaps told to you that maybe you been passed down to them.
      
      
         Oh yes.
         All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> heritage stories about how hard life was for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And your own stories?
      
      
         Yeah, how my own stories about hard my life was (laugh) and all those sorts of things.
      
      
         Do you um, what kinds of things do you read now other than some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> that you like mentioned.
         Real currently, what do you enjoy reading at the present?
         What <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Let's see, recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> You've probably never heard of any of these, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Benford</ENAMEX> is very good, these are science fiction, uh, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Grant</ENAMEX>, science fiction that is real good.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uh Asimov</ENAMEX>, he died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 8 years ago</TIMEX> but I still find one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of his that I hadn't read yet.
         
      
      
         We were mentioning, we were mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> you enjoy reading now and we had to take a break.
      
      
         Let's see, the others that I could think of that I read recently, there were some <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> books written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Shaara</ENAMEX> and the other by his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>.
         Very good.
         Another book that I read recently is very interesting books The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journals of Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Which is really a story from beginning to end, I suppose.
      
      
         It is a narrative of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year long</TIMEX> trip they took from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> all the way out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> and back.
      
      
         Now, a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would probably look at that and think my goodness I'm not sure I'd want to read all those details () trip.
         What did you enjoy about reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clark</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well this was this was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that anyone had ever traveled here and recorded any of their experiences and they saw the entire western <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the continent for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time.
         No one else been there no one else had ever experienced or written about what they'd seen and brought it back.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years later</TIMEX> most of what they say and experienced didn't exist anymore.
      
      
         So in some ways it was very similar to the space exploration that you were so interested in?
      
      
         Kind of.
         It was something
         that they were in a position to do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and no one before or no one since could ever reduplicate it.
      
      
         Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that storytelling in our culture is, is uh vanishing, because of television and computerized games and email and so many other things that keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from sharing stories and taking the time to read.
         Do you think that story telling continues to be important and why?
      
      
         I think it's important because it's the real link you have to your past and heritage and it's also declining for the same reasons you mentioned.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> just don't have the time or take the time to keep the traditions going
         they just get too busy or too lazy.
      
      
         How do you try to counter that with your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and will continue to try and counter that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are added to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         As I have opportunities, as situations arise in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> purchasing and things like that.
         I try to weave some personal experience into the conversation.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Motorcycle</ENAMEX> purchases?
      
      
         Oh yes!
      
      
         And storytelling applies?
      
      
         Certainly.
         I have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> stories going back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> actually.
      
      
         And now that I know your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is considering purchasing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> those stories hopefully can help him make // a wise decision <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> A wise decision<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// yeah.</ENAMEX>
         I suppose.
      
      
         Well thank you for taking the time to participate in this interview and for you helping with the research project at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNCC</ENAMEX>.
      
   
