
   
   
      
         Hi!
         What's your name?
      
      
         My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Cotton</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX>, what's your age?
      
      
         I'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>.
      
      
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your</TIMEX>, uh, birth <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes, it is.
      
      
         And, uh, I assume, um, that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> is your native language.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Native</ENAMEX> and only language!
         
      
      
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, well, um, we wanted to talk about, um, a favorite story, and, um, do you have a favorite story?
      
      
         A favorite story about anything?
      
      
         About anything.
         It could be a traditional story, like you find in a folk tale, or out of a book.
         Or it could be a family story that gets passed down.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, do you have a, one of those types of stories?
      
      
         Yes, I believe I have.
         It's not a family story.
         It's a story from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bible</ENAMEX>.
         Is that OK?
      
      
         That's great!
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         So it's, it's written, as opposed to oral?
      
      
         Yes.
         Yes.
      
      
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, who--?
         Did you read this story itself, yourself, when you were young, or was it first told to you by someone?
      
      
         No, it was first told to me by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, who is, um, was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first teacher</ENAMEX>, and remains my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.
         Even though she's no longer physically on the planet.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         How old were you when she shared this story with you?
      
      
         My first recollection I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>.
      
      
         That's
         that's very young.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, it's interesting how, uh, stories become so impressionable the younger the hearer.
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, well, would you care to relate the story to me now?
      
      
         Sure.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         Well, this story, and I must tell you, I haven't read this in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bible</ENAMEX>, so I don't know if it's totally accurate, but I prefer to get it like this: There was a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> decided that what he wanted to do was to, uh, entertain the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         And all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> were standing around, not really paying much attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, of course, were supposed seen and, uh, not heard, and not really much being seen, actually.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, uh, actually made all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> move aside, and let the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> come up.
         And he said, "Suffer the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>."
         In other words, you know, it might be painful for you, or inconvenient for you adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but, "Let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> come to me, and forbid them not," don't stop them from coming.
         They have a place here too.
         And he sat and talked with these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and he hugged them, and loved them all.
         And she told me that everyone has to be like a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to God, and that God loves everyone just like He is their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and they are His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, because of what they are.
         And that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> actually, the innocence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, the unconditional love of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, is the way that we, now, that I'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> need to be with each other, and that the greatest lesson in that, when you can be like a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, then you are doing what's pleasing to God.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And also, and the thing that I resonated with as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, was that you always had a special place, and a special protection, and a special love, uh, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and God, and that was another thing that made me feel special as a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         So could you reiterate the message, quote-unquote, um, that you got from the story, from your point of view?
      
      
         The message, again, that I get from the story, for me personally, was that there would always be a special connection between me and God, and actually was just another of the ways my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> put for me to learn, or believe, that I could do anything, I could be anything, because I had a special connection and special protection, um, from not only her, which was more important for me at the time.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         But also from God, and that that would always be there, that the way that she was able to do it was actually by remembering to me to be more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-like, more innocent.
         And that keeps me, as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>, one, remembering to pray like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, and to maintain some of the innocence, which is difficult, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
         And I think that brings a smile to God's face.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, what did you like most about the story, as opposed to what you would like most about it now?
         Were they the same, or different?
      
      
         No.
         What I liked about it was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were special.
         And, you know, with this, you know, it wasn't many opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to be special, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> weren't, you know, you were pushed out of adult conversation, and just really pushed to the side.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Again, that "seen and not heard" kind of thing.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         And I liked the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> were made to wait.
         
         
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         
         And be seen and not heard while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were give a special place of honor.
         So I liked that.
         Yes.
      
      
         Do you have a chance to re-tell this story, um, in your work or to your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
         How have you shared it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>?
      
      
         Well, you know, it's really interesting that we're talking about this, because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, who is now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>, I guess I shared it with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when they were growing up, but not in any particular special way, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is in therapy now, and uh, this is one of the visioning exercises that this therapist told him, that he should do whenever he is angry, to imagine that he is one of the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is putting his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> around.
         And so he came home and told me about that and he and I had a discussion about that, and it took me back to the safety and this warm feeling I had when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         I think in my work, what I remember to do, and what I write into every single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that I facilitate, OK, no matter what it is, if it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, conflict, no matter what, is what I call a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">STAR</ENAMEX> model.
         And it's an acronym for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensitivity, Trust</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Appreciation, and Respect</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And all of that is the same feeling from that story that I had when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>.
         And I try to tell people this is the environment you want to try to tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, to encourage them to embrace the kind of environment where it's safe, to agree or disagree, to discuss anything.
         And be more productive when you have this sense of honoring and valuing.
         I don't say words like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX>," and I don't mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, I don't talk about any deity, um, because that's part of the respect, too.
         I firmly am committed to that.
         That not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are, and I don't want to put up any walls for them.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         So it's more a context that I am interesting in them embracing.
         If they want to say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working</ENAMEX> from the universe," or "Good business sense," or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">God</ENAMEX>."
         I don't care what they call it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I let them use whatever words to describe the behaviors that is gonna get you there.
         So it's that same feeling that is created in my workshops, that I had when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, actually.
      
      
         You, um, tantalized me with the reference to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, and that she is still your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         Could you describe her?
      
      
         Hmm
         Describe her and what she did?
         Why she's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Right.
         What attributes did she have that made you, um, respect her and view her as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> even to this day?
      
      
         She had the ability to, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all, she didn't know any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>.
         And having first met someone she had the ability to quickly make them feel they had been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and not only in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, but a loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         She would make everyone feel comfortable, respected, and more than that, truly loved
         truly, truly loved everyone.
         And as a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> being blessed to grow up with her, I lived with her and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and I, lived with them until I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years old</TIMEX>, exclusively.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was working, and that was fine, the best thing she could have ever done, to take me to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>.
         And she really just instilled in me a sense of centering and acceptance of who I am, a clarity of understanding that I could really do anything that I put my mind to.
         There's nothing that I could not do, if I wanted to do it.
         A sense of strong independence, to the point that I never had, I never had, the problem of worrying about peer pressure.
         When I was in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, high school, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX>, never ever did I have that thing with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, like smoking, so I had to smoke.
         I didn't, none of that, because I was very much my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, and very centered and grounded.
         And I got that from her, truly unconditional love.
         Truly unconditional love.
         She would correct me when I was wrong, very lovingly, but I never ever doubted that she loved me, never.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and I, to this day, I live my life, um, for the most part, in ways that I'm always seeking her approval, and I think she is my touchstone and my benchmark.
         And I think if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> would be pleased with this, it is good.
         
         So, you know, I have my standards, and I match my standards to what her standards would have been, I believe.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         How old were you when she passed?
      
      
         She died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, so what does that make me?
         I was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX>--.
         I can't do that math in my head!
         
      
      
         That's OK.
         Well, you've described a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and that highly complements the story you told.
         I mean, they're so hand-in-glove, that I sort of see it as one seamless piece that you've shared.
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         So I really, I really do appreciate it.
         Was there anything that I failed to ask that I should have, relating to this story that you've told, or background to the story that you've told?
      
      
         No, I would want to thank you for asking me those questions though, because it's given me the opportunity to go back to a very precious place, to feel her love really, really present, and, um,
         you know, that makes me smile all over.
      
      
         Well, the magic is that she can be in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> places at once, because I feel it too.
      
      
         Oh, great!
         
         Wonderful!
      
      
         That embrace is very special.
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX>, thank you very much and I do appreciate everything you've shared.
      
      
         You're welcome.
         Thank you.
      
   
