
   
   
      
         OK uh, this is a story a little while back when uh, me and uh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> grade got a wild hare.
         It was uh, me, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Teague</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Barsley</ENAMEX>.
         And uh, it was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and it had just begun to snow and uh, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby</ENAMEX> it don't really snow that much so we were all pretty excited.
         And uh, we were all spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh, we decided we wanted to sneak out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         Well, it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 1:00 in the morning</TIMEX> and uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> was scared we were going to wake his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> up or his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> up.
         And uh, you know after a little while we ended up talking him into it and uh, so we all snuck out his window in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and um, we proceeded to uh, go over to uh,
         a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that we knew named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Anne</ENAMEX>.
         And uh, so we all snuck out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh, we walked through the snow and it was real cold and we didn't really have any warm clothes on because you know we aren't really used to the snow that much.
         And uh, we had proceeded over to this uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh, she uh, let us in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> when we get over there and uh, we uh, stayed there and watched a movie with her.
         And uh, you know, I mean we were trying to be quiet not to wake her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> up so you know and uh, we ended up watching this movie and this movie ends up lasting until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about um, 4:30</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:00 in the morning</TIMEX>.
         And uh, she's, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> works uh, construction so uh, she told us we had to leave because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> gets up real <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> so uh, we hurry up and get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh, we're walking on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and uh, we're seeing the uh, newspaper car running around throwing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> out.
         And uh, I don't know who thought of it I don't know if it was me or
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff or Craig</ENAMEX> but uh, we uh, we had some cigarettes on us and we were smoking trying to be the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> you know and we had a lighter.
         And uh, one of us thought of the idea of sticking a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in the mailbox and setting the mailbox and newspaper on fire.
         So uh, one of us we were walking down the road picked up uh, a newspaper wadded it up and stuck it in the mailbox and uh, this was uh, metal mailbox with uh, brick around it.
         And we stuck it in there and we lit it and it shot into a big old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX>, you know lit up the whole sky.
         And I mean we were just, you know it got us real fired up you know and so uh, we were walking along a little further and we saw another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and uh, we stuck it in the mailbox and it was another metal mailbox.
         So uh, we were like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cool</ENAMEX>!"
         and we lit it up again and uh, this big old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX> shot out and we all ran off.
         And uh, as we got closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that we were staying at we came by uh, it was a plastic mailbox, and uh, so we uh, stuffed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in it and lit it on fire and we, we weren't really thinking and all the sudden the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> caught on fire and then the whole mailbox caught on fire.
         It, it was plastic and it started dripping and fireballs of plastic came off.
         And uh, you know we were all fired up.
         We came up to uh, newspaper mailbox that was plastic and we lit that on fire, we actually set a couple of those on fire, and uh, I mean by this time, I mean you could, the sun, you could almost see the sun coming up so we run as fast as we can to get back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and we sneak back into the back window and uh, we go to sleep.
         OK, we uh, went to sleep and uh, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour and a half later about 8:00 in the morning</TIMEX> uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> comes in to wake us up and says there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that want to see us at the front door.
         And uh, so we walked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">foyer</ENAMEX> area of the front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at the front door and uh, these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> say uh, ask us uh, what we were doing last night.
         And we were like, "We didn't do anything last night," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> asked us, you know, did we sneak out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> and we all said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No, no.</ENAMEX>"
         We denied it, and uh, the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> said, the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> asked us, you know, "Did you," I mean he said, "Did you or did you not sneak out and burn any mailboxes?"
         And we just denied the whole thing, you know, and uh, finally the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> says, "Well you know I wouldn't have never thought it was y'all but, uh, seeing it was snowing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> and uh, foot tracks go all the way from my mailbox to this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> right here uh, I don't have any choice but to believe it was y'all."
         And uh, he said, "Especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> that was wearing these soles that say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivran</ENAMEX> on them," and uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> has his boots sitting by the door and looked on the bottom of them and had, uh, the sole had, uh, was written, it said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vivran</ENAMEX> on the bottom of it.
         And he said, "These soles right here match right up to it."
         And uh, we were just like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damn</ENAMEX>," uh, so, uh, we finally confessed to it and, uh, we told him yeah we did, we were out there.
         Found out later that the, uh, one of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> got up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every morning about 5:30</TIMEX> and, uh, walked <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the</NUMEX>, uh, around the neighborhood and he saw us, uh, do it actually.
         And, uh, he just followed our footprints back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and waited until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">earlier the next morning</TIMEX> to uh, come to say anything.
         So we thought we were being sneaky, but uh, found out the whole time we were being watched.
         And uh, so after that, uh, the, uh, old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that we burned his mailbox down, uh, told us that, uh, he was going to, he would press charges unless we replaced and fixed his mailbox.
         So uh, that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">whole day</TIMEX> I think we put up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> mailboxes, uh, one complete wood frame and plastic mailbox and that was cemented in the ground.
         And uh, so it was uh, not a very good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> for us not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a very good day</TIMEX>.
         And uh, but one of the cool things that happened was uh, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that morning</TIMEX> in the paper in the write up columns with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> reports and they had a little column, had what we had did <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>, and it said they were looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>, but uh, said, but they never followed through on that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> never pressed charges or anything like that so uh, we got off easy on that.
      
      
         Do you got another one?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Do you want me to turn it off so you can think?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, nah I got it
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX>, another story, uh, when I, uh, this happened uh, senior year over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> after my graduating senior year.
         Uh
         , I live out on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moss Lake</ENAMEX>, it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherryville</ENAMEX> actually, uh
         , me and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> of mine from way back in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, we were best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> back then, uh, I invited him over to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and we were going to go out onto the lake.
         I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> ski and he's got one too and, uh, so we, we went out there and started drinking a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX>.
         And uh,
         we ended up drinking more then going out in the water and, uh, we were out in the water and, uh, we come up and we were going to get another <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> and, uh, he, uh, runs his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> ski up on land, and we had to pull it back and put it in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
         And we check it out and it is all right and by this time we are getting pretty, uh, inebriated, I guess you'd call it, and, uh, we were out there just acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> on the jet skis.
         And, uh, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in time he actually runs into me on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> ski and, uh, bends the handle bars and runs up on my legs and I got a big bruise on my legs, but I'm not feeling it then, I'm pretty well gone by this time.
         And, uh, it's getting late in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> and he says he has to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, and he doesn't live on the lake so we load up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> ski and, uh, put it on the trailer on the back of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and uh, we're going to go back to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to take it back.
         So, uh, we get it back on the trailer and we find out that, uh, we bent the handlebar on it.
         So we take it back to my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and, uh, we are sitting there trying to bend it back and, uh, so his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't get mad at him that he messed up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> ski or whatever.
         So, uh, we are at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> trying to bend it back and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> come down and they are like, "Are y'all all right?"
         We're like, "Yeah, yeah we're fine," you know.
         And uh, they're like, "All right," but they, they didn't have any idea that we were, uh, that we were leaving and we were going to take the, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> ski back to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         They thought we were just going to stay at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         So, uh, we get the handlebar bent back and, uh, we take off and, um, we are on the way to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and uh, I run off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point.
         And, uh, the trailer, the trailer doesn't hit anything but at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point it hits a mailbox, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> asked if I was all right and I said, "Sure I'm fine," you know, I had no idea what I was doing so we get to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and, uh, I found out my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s had, uh, called over there beforehand to tell his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to come out there and meet me and take me home when I got there.
         Well when I got there, uh, I just rolled in there we dropped the jet skis off, and I just jetted right out all of the sudden, you know his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't even know we had got there, and, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX> and he asked me again, "Are you OK to drive?"
         and I was like, "Yeah sure," you know.
         I mean I thought I was fine, obviously I wasn't.
         But uh, I'm coming on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and not really paying that much attention and, uh, just got this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> before this, and, uh, end up not looking at the road I don't know what the heck I was doing.
         And, uh, ran my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> into a telephone pole.
         And I had the window open.
         I didn't know it was happening, and, uh, the side view mirror glass all of the sudden I just felt this bang, and I looked up and I saw I had glass on me.
         And I was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, I didn't know what was wrong.
         And I swerved and uh, luckily enough the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> hit the front fender somehow and I bounced off the telephone pole, and it was still going and, uh, I had no, I mean I was just totally in shock.
         I didn't know what was going on.
         And, uh, ( ) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and I'm like I am all right.
         The first thing I do is I got a cell phone on me so I call, uh, I call a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine that, uh, lives real close to where I hit the telephone pole is at.
         And I drive to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and, uh, I get her to uh, drive my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> the rest of the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         And I call my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s up on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and tell them what happened.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, what not--.
         () Ended up taking about all my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> wages that I earned that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> to pay to fix it.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the hardest lessons to learn.
         
      
   
