
   
   
      
         State your full name.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian DeLucia</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What is your native language?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, my native language is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         My occupation, I work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank Of America</ENAMEX> and I work on a, uh, website.
      
      
         OK.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when do you remember hearing stories as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I remember hearing stories as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> when basically my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> reading stories to me, not so much my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, but more my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> when I was, I can't even tell you how old I was.
         But I just, I know for a fact as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would read to me before I went to bed.
      
      
         Do you remember any stories?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, there was one book that I always remember.
         I don't know if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> ever finished it.
         But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sticks out and it's still, um, at our home in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and whenever I go back up there I always see the book lying around, um, in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> actually, or on the bookshelf.
         And it's actually called the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trumpet of the Swan</ENAMEX>.
         So that's, that's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX>, that's the main story that I remember that, that sticks in my head, as far as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> reading it to myself and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> when we were younger.
      
      
         Can you tell a little bit about it or do you remember anything?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I think the one thing I remember mostly about it actually is just the, the front cover of it.
         And it was just a, uh, uh a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, it looked like, on the edge of a lake and he was doing something, either like feeding, you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">swan</ENAMEX>, or holding out his hand to it, or something to that effect.
         But the actual, um, the actual plot of the story, I probably don't really remember.
      
      
         Do you remember hearing stories that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would tell you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, maybe about their past or--?
      
      
         Oh, yeah.
         I can remember my, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> telling me, um, the story of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> coming from, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> when, uh, they came over.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so that kind of stands clearly in my mind.
         I also remember, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> telling me a lot of stories about, uh, how hard it was for her when she was growing up because, uh, there was about, I think she was one of, um, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> and um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> never really worked or anything like that.
         She was always taking care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was always working like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> different jobs.
         So I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> telling me all kinds of interesting stories about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, as far as, uh, he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>, um, you know, and worked in a, he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bailiff</ENAMEX> in, in court, you know, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> for awhile, like at the same time actually, and he was also doing like a, a security job as well.
         So, those kind of stories.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>.
         Do you read stories now?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I read books and, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, if that, that counts as, as stories.
      
      
         What kind?
         What do you tend towards?
      
      
         I tend to read, uh, mostly, uh, fiction books.
         I'm not really, uh, into, uh, a lot of the non-fictions, though occasionally I'll read a biography or, uh, something like that if, if, you know, I see something in a bookstore.
         But, uh, yeah, I read a lot of non-fiction.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I like fantasy-type stories `cause I always liked that when I was younger.
         The<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, The Dungeons and Dragons</ENAMEX> type stuff and even up until, um, you know, I still enjoy reading that kind of stuff about, you know, swords and magic, that kind of stuff.
         And I've actually always, uh, enjoyed stuff, reading books about like vampires.
         Like, you know, fiction books about, uh, vampires and, and that kind of stuff.
         And I also tend to, um, hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> from, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or, or hear of a famous book from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and I'll read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and if there happens to be a series on it then, you know, I'll start reading those.
         I actually just started reading, uh, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> books of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> series and I think those are intended for a much younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, but I've actually read all, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> that have come out and I've enjoyed them `cause that's basically, it's about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magician</ENAMEX>, basically, finds out that he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magician</ENAMEX>.
         So that kind of, you know, peaked my interest when I started reading it.
      
      
         So when you first started to read you tended towards the fantasy books?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yeah when I started to be able to decide what I wanted to read, as opposed to having somebody read it to me, I tended to lean more towards, yeah, fantasy-type books.
      
      
         Is there a story that changed in significance as you've gotten older?
         Like maybe you've read, you remember hearing a book, and then you heard it again or read it again that changed in meaning or meant something different to you?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, yeah actually.
         I remember, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> actually read to me, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Watership Down</ENAMEX>, which is a story about a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbits</ENAMEX> who, um, get driven out of wherever they're living, I forget the technical term for, for what their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> under, under the ground is called, but they get driven out of that and they have to go and basically find a new place to live.
         And I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> read that to me.
         It's a really big, long book.
         The paperback book is like about like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six hundred</NUMEX> pages long.
         So I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> read that to me and I thought it was just really like cute about the rabbits kind of thing.
         And I think they might have skipped a lot of pages, too, because I actually read it in high school and it turns out it was like, you know, somewhat of a violent book.
         Like some of the rabbits get killed and it's, it's much more deeper and it's actually, it has like political undertones to it `cause it's, you know, different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> of rabbits you know, kind of like fighting against each other and, you know, it was really interesting.
         So that, that kind of, that story like, I remember being younger and hearing it and thinking like oh, it was cute because it was rabbits and then reading it and actually, you know, en, enjoying it a lot more when I was in high school `cause it was actually a really, really good book.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, do you or would you like to read to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, yes.
         I, I'd read to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, but probably not, I'd probably tend to read to my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I don't know how much I'd be into reading to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just</NUMEX>, you know, like a, a program of just reading to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> kind of thing.
         But when I do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, I'm going make sure that either, um, you know, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> reads to them or that, you know, or make it a point that I read to them `cause I think it's, it's really important.
         And actually, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and, um, she's constantly reading to, to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and, who's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years old</TIMEX> now.
         And she just seems like a pretty bright, intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> compared to some other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year olds</TIMEX> that I've, that I've encountered.
      
      
         Are there any personal stories about your past and history and growing up that you're going to tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yeah.
         I'm sure that there's going be stories that I'll, I'll tell them about.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, to tell you the truth, I'll definitely tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, you know, things about, you know, stories about when I was growing up and maybe some things that, you know, you should or shouldn't do.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, in particular I could, I could think of a few things.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I know when I was really younger, I'll tell them this story, about never going near, uh, a frozen pond because when I was really young, um, the lake by my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> had frozen over, actually it was just a pond, but it was a pretty big one, um, and we always use to play ice hockey and what not on it.
         And it started to um, get warmer outside, but there was still a layer of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> on top of it, and a bunch of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> had gone out on to the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX>.
         That is, you know, you could easily get to it.
         It was attached to kind of like the shore, but at the deep end of the pond.
         And we were out there and one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> was kidding around, and I think we were in like, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years old</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> was joking around on it and actually fell through the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, a bystander had to come over and basically fish him out and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> could've died.
         So, I'll tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to, to stay away from thin <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Do you think your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> told you stories more out of humor or more out of, as a warning?
         Like about, stories about growing up with them or their past.
         Do you think they used their stories as teachable moments?
      
      
         Yeah, I think they had a mixture because I think, um, it's kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like two</NUMEX> different, you know, things that they would tell me as far as stories.
         You had the things that they would read out of books, which were purely for entertainment, it always seemed like.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and then if it was anything that was, you know, that I kind of correlated with, if it wasn't coming from a book, they were probably trying to get something into my head.
         You know, trying to like, you know, teach me something in some way.
         So it was kind of like if it was coming out of book, I knew it was for pure entertainment, whereas if it was something they were telling to me, I might be a little more receptive to, you know, maybe trying to find a little, a little meaning behind it and say, " <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, why are you, why are you telling me this?"
      
      
         Now, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandparents</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>, had they told you stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Oh yeah.
      
      
         Can you think of anything?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yeah, I mean they just, they mostly, they didn't really talk about what it was like being over there.
         I mean, they more talked about, um, coming over here.
         Like from the time when they came over here that was hard for them at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to adjust.
         And how they came over with, with basically, you know, nothing or you know, not, not that many possessions looking for a, looking for a better life and you know, just how they had to work hard to get, you know, where they were.
         And that they, their entire lives they were just trying to make a better life for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>.
         So I didn't really hear too many stories about, um, you know, where they came from.
         But more of like the actual journey over and, and what it was like to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> come here.
      
      
         OK.
         I think I've got everything.
         Thank you.
      
      
         You're welcome.
      
   
