
   
   
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my first memories, uh, occurred when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years old</TIMEX>.
         I was living, uh, right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on a very friendly suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and, ah, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one summer day</TIMEX> I remember going out to the back of our yard, which seemed really big then.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I reached into my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> small garden, it had quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> in it, and I just started lobbing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> over the fence, and I kept lobbing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> over the fence, and then my next door <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>, who was probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX>, my playmate at the time, he rode his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Wheel</ENAMEX> down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the</NUMEX>, down the hill there and came and started throwing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> with me and we were just having a great time not thinking about anything, laughing having a lot of fun
      .
         Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had to spoil it all.
         He came, he opened the door and I remember looking back and seeing the expression on his face, and I could tell that he was disappointed.
         He wasn't happy with me, but I wasn't, I wasn't really sure if what I had done was really, really wrong I just knew that he wasn't very happy about what was going on by the way he opened the door and by the way he told me I needed to come into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and I, I came over there and I stepped up and I didn't even say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bye</ENAMEX>," to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and was probably not into that kind of thing I didn't really notice at that time probably I just went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> said he had noticed, he had seen me throwing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> in Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulk</ENAMEX>'s yard, so he told me that I was in trouble and I was going to get a spanking, and, um, I was kind of uh, uh looking for an out so I was smart enough to say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey Dad</ENAMEX>!
         Before you give me a spanking, why don't you just let me have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate milk</ENAMEX> first?"
         So anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> goes and makes this nice big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate milk</ENAMEX> for me.
         I'm not even sure why he did it but I spent so much time drinking that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate milk</ENAMEX>, it was, I must have had that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate milk</ENAMEX> to my face for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>, and for some reason, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> was telling me, you know, talking to me about, uh, you know, what, what I had done and, you know, how it was wrong.
         I remember, yeah I remember that based on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> conversations that I ( ) with him about it, but at the time I guess I really wasn't sure what it was about, but I knew
      that when it all came down to the bottom of it, I knew that what I had done was the wrong thing to do and he told me that I'm going to probably have to go down there and help Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulk</ENAMEX> pick up the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> when it's all said and done, and I remember being a little bit nervous about that.
         I didn't really know Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faulk</ENAMEX> very well she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 80</NUMEX> and, ah, she was a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> I had seen her a few times but I was really nervous about that.
         It was probably the first thing I remember from being a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> about, ah, especially about something that I'd done wrong.
         Ah, another thing that happened there that I thought was interesting was one of the first memories of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, and that was in that very same backyard.
         There was a, ah, a rose garden back there and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, it's ironic her middle name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX>.
         Her name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christy Rose Farrow</ENAMEX>, and she was back there with me and we're going back and seeing these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christy</ENAMEX> was smelling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX> and she started to put the petals up her nose, and I remember watching her put the petals up there, and I remember watching her put the petals up her nose, and I wasn't really sure why she was doing it.
         I didn't really ask any questions I just thought it was interesting that she was putting the petals up her nose, and it kind of became fun to kind of cheer her into keep doing it, so I was like keeping going, keep going, "Yes!
         This is great!"
         you know, and she's stuffing the petals up there and I didn't really know of any consequences.
         I don't think, I was just kind of, I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four or four and a half</NUMEX> and I remember stuffing those petals up her nose and I thought it was great and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> comes down and she was really disappointed in both of us.
         I think she was most unhappy with me because, you know, ah, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christy</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one or one and a half</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and I was the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> so from there I guess I remembered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> being upset with me because ah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christy</ENAMEX> had all those petals up her nose and it took a long time to take them out there was a lot of them up there, but, ah, later on, as I grew older, we moved around a lot when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> I remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> I woke up and there was a moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> I woke up and there was a moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> in my, in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> and I woke up to this sound of that and I looked out the window and there's this moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> moving stuff in and I got up and I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> they're taking our stuff," and I was, and she was like, "Yes, we're moving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," and I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> going on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> at the time and so they're taking our stuff out so anyway we moved and they took all our stuff out and moved and she said, you know, "I told you we're moving.
         You must have forgot," and I must have because it totally took me by surprise, and we ended up at a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> and I remember this, this new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that we were at and, ah, in a pretty area and it had a much bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         I remembered a long driveway and it was surrounded by woods it was really nice area in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arnold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX> and, um, basically it was such a shock because when we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your first day</TIMEX> of school," and apparently I had forgot about that too and I started to get really nervous about that.
         We were watching something on TV.
         I can't remember what it was but I suddenly got really nervous that I was about to go to school for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time and that was probably the most stressful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> of my life.
         I had forgotten that I was moving to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> and I had forgotten that I was, uh, going to be going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         That was, that was a pretty scary day.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, then we moved to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         Ah, oops!
         I'm covering the same stuff.
         Ah, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade was a lot of fun.
         I like to laugh.
         I was probably, just laugh about anything.
         I remember, some of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, I remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time when I went to lunch, and I always had this <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pac Man</ENAMEX> lunchbox, pull out this <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pac Man</ENAMEX> lunchbox, and I would, that I was so proud of, and, you know, do my thing, and I would be talking so much and laughing about the stupidest things that I wouldn't even, I wouldn't even eat my lunch.
         I would just laugh the whole time, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time I did it so much that I never even opened my lunch out of the bag, and it was like a minute before, a minute before lunch was over and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.E.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> came up to me, and he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look</ENAMEX>, this is horrible, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>.
         This is just," you know, "Look you're in trouble.
         You're not eating your lunch," come with him, so I went, he, I had to follow him and remember being really nervous and he sat me down a corner and he told me I had to sit there until I ate all my lunch, and I remember, um, crying for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and I think that basically what happened there was that was just an amazing mood swing because I went from being extremely
      happy, and I was
      extremely sad.
         It was an amazing mood swing.
         I think that's why I remember that.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when I was young we used to go on a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> vacations.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX> we'd go from, whether it be <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MO to IL or IO to IL or KS to IL</ENAMEX>, the whole time I was growing up because in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX> that's where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> lived and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> we'd go up there and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX> with them in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>, and we'd also go down there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> too, but mostly I remember going down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, um, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and it was, ah, a lot of arguing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and I remember sitting next to my, uh, I had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, so the middle one was always in the middle, for some reason.
         She was, she was, uh, the middle one's always in the middle.
         What I mean by that is that she's the next down she was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> younger that me then the other one is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> younger than me, so, uh, basically, you know, you know, she would always sit next to me, and we'd get so mad, I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> swinging directly behind him at us all the time because we'd always be fighting.
         One thing that she really had as a great defense.
         Was, she would eat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter</ENAMEX> cups, and she knows that I hate the smell of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter</ENAMEX>, so she would actually eat the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter cup</ENAMEX> and then breathe in my face and there wasn't really any way for me to defend against that because I couldn't think of any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that she really thought stunk and you know it was like it was it was untouchable there wasn't anything I could do about that, so I would, I would get really mad at that and I'd say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>," and she would say, you know, "She's just breathing," so there was really no way out of it, so I remember a lot of that.
         So when I was in, when I was at grandma and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, we used to have a great time just fishing and hanging out with grandpa, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> would go there and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Fourth of July</TIMEX> we'd do fireworks.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, it was on the river and it was, ah, it was very peaceful.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> were always very, very loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and some of, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were and we'd just have a great time down there.
         And some of my best memories were, um, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox River</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IL</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, um another memory with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that I have is that we had a lot of weddings, ah, and these weddings were always really big weddings, and I've always been told the reason why they're so big is because basically it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>, you know.
         Half of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX>, we have big weddings and I remember at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s wedding I was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years old</TIMEX> going to it and I had a my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> and he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX>, and, ah we went to this wedding and it has like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, he's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.
         He's also really big into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX> and he brought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 50</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to it and the wedding took place in a hotel one of those classic areas where you have, you have the weddings, and it was, ah, basically <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really stormy night</TIMEX>, real stormy and the power went out, and it was open bar so now we've got, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">50 Hell's Angels</ENAMEX>, no power, and it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle a summer</TIMEX>, so it is getting really hot in there, you know, there's, there's no lights so you know there's a few emergency power lights that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> brought, ah, and they had some sort of battery they were using for the ah for the radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> and it was, it was getting really crazy in there because we had Hell's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX> running around without shirts on, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> highly intoxicated, I remember by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottom</ENAMEX>'s up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>!
         Bottoms up!"
         and the reason it was bottoms up was because, was, they serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> to everybody in these weddings that's something I can never figure out and if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>, if you're an adult you get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>.
         Everybody gets <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't drink it so what's left the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> drink so we were going around drinking all this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">champagne</ENAMEX>.
         And before you know it it's time for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hula Hoop</ENAMEX> contest and they've got a stage of course there they do it's one of those huge areas and ah we get up there and they're playing this tune I can't remember what it was and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> and I were up there and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> is really drunk and he fell completely off the stage I remember that being somewhat embarrassing but looking back on it I think it's really pretty funny, um, it was uh it was a really neat experience.
      
   
