
   
   
      
         Male Voice <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">START OF TAPE 1</ENAMEX> AT <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:00</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDE A</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Will it be loud enough?
      
      
         Should be.
      
      
         So, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, right, I'm at work.
         I get a call, it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 9:30 in the morning</TIMEX> and I get a call from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bucky</ENAMEX>, the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         And he's like talking all fast; he's on a cell phone.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         AF: "I need you to do something for me."
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, "You need to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramona</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX>," mind you she's at an office, actually she's in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, all the way across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX>, she's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX>.
         "You need to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramona</ENAMEX>.
         She can help you; she's done this for me before.
         There's some cash flow projections on my desk and, um, uh, it's for such and such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cutty</ENAMEX>," that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s name.
         "He's buying a new business and it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four million</NUMEX> in inventory and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12 million</NUMEX> in fixed assets and so, they can have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12 million</NUMEX> in debt, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four million</NUMEX> in equity," and mind you, I'm writing this down.
         He's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just</TIMEX>, spitting everything out.
         And um, so I'm writing all this down, and he's like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramona</ENAMEX> did such and such at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, she did this for me, she did the same thing for me, she can tell you what you know, she can help you out," whatever.
         Hang up the phone with him.
         "I'll call you back in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX>," he says.
         Hang up with him and I'm like, "Aw damn, all that information," you know, and I don't know if I remembered everything.
         I tried to jot everything down.
         So then I look up, I find out where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramona's</ENAMEX> at, and I call her over there.
         She's like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I did that for him, like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least two years ago</TIMEX>."
         And I'm like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damn</ENAMEX>, great."
         She's like, "But you need to look here, look here," she's gives me like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different places to look in the computer.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And um, it's different, like under each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, is all their files.
         Like whatever we've done for them, it's in there.
         So I have to go, she gave me like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to look up, and then under each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those I have to like open up all like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Excel</ENAMEX> spreadsheets, and I don't even know what I'm looking for!
         I'm just trying to have an idea of what it kind of looks like.
         So it took me like, an hour to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> just to find what I needed.
         Then I get it and I'm like great, "What do I do with it?"
         It's like one file with a whole bunch of tabs, of different, you know, each tab has like a different spreadsheet on it.
      
      
         What's up Angelina?
      
      
         We're talking about my
         .
      
      
         Recording me?
      
      
         Yeah it's recording.
      
      
         ( )
      
      
         ( )
         So, finally I get the thing and it has like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> different parts to it, and I'm just there trying to figure how the thing goes together, how one number flows to another sheet and how that goes, you know.
         Everything is linked, and gosh, I don't even know how long.
         I was just there just trying to figure it out.
         Then I was spinning my wheel for about, I don't know, it seemed like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day that day</TIMEX>.
         It wasn't till like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 or 12:00</TIMEX> that I actually got to start on the on the project.
         And I um, I didn't know how much detail he wanted.
         I didn't know, you know, when he needed it by.
         He acted like, he needed it soon, but the way she had everything done, I would have had to, I would have had to start from the very beginning, and most of it was just like data entry to start off with.
         And then once you get everything entered you can go on from there.
         Well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the day</TIMEX> I was just entering, entering, entering, entering information.
         It wasn't until like before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:00</TIMEX> that I had finished entering something and I was able to look and see, "OK where do I go from here now that I have this done, where do these totals go to, on another <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet</ENAMEX>?"
         So I'm like, "OK he hasn't called back or anything," so I'm figuring I can do it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.
         Well I get there this morning and um, I forget how, I think either I asked a question and he came in there or, whatever.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyhow</ENAMEX>, he tells me, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX> I need it by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> because such and such is coming, coming in and we need to take it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>."
         And I'm like, "Oh."
         I'm like, I know how far I've gotten.
         So anyhow, I call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramona</ENAMEX> back because I had a question about, I was like, "All right, let me hurry up on with it," and I had a question about something I was doing.
         Well, she tells me, she's like, "That doesn't sound right."
         She was like, um, you know, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> she gave me was different from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that I had, there were little things different, slight different things with it, like, one didn't have the same kind of inventory as the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         Little things like that made a big difference in what I was trying to do.
         So, she's like, "Well look, look up this in such and such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>."
         And I did.
         Now what does that look like?
         And how about it looks like exactly what I'm trying to do.
         It's like more simplified, like the one that she had given me was all detailed and complicated and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one is all simple.
         So here I am, now I have the thing that I'm supposed to have and he wants it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, and I wasted all that time on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, just wasted time, because I was doing the wrong thing.
         So now, here it is, he wants it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
         I didn't have time to enter in all kinds of whatever.
         So I just had to take the totals and try and figure it like that.
         Well, I get to a certain point where I'm like confused.
         I don't have enough information.
         So, I go in there, and I haven't even told him yet that I had to start from the very beginning, because I was like, I didn't want to tell him!
         So and let me tell you I got to the point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> where I was about to quit.
         I was like, "That's it.
         I'm getting up.
         I'm leaving," because when he had come in, it was like he was short with me and I'm asking him a question and he's not answering it and he's his final thing was, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX> I need it by such and such meeting," so, just telling me, "I don't give a damn that you're having trouble.
         I don't care how you get it done," he just wants it.
         Well, there's nobody there to help me.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that can help me is all the way across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
         So, with that, I was, I was frustrated.
         I was spinning my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> trying to figure out how I can make it work.
         If there was anything I could do.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lana</ENAMEX> came over and sat with me for a little bit, but she didn't know what to do, and um, you just get to the point where, you know, you're like, you know, you're slamming things down, and you're just, I was pissed, I was really upset, and um, got to the point where I just wanted to cry, and, but I didn't want to get that upset because, you know, if anybody came in there or I knew I had to tell him that I would I might not be able to finish it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, or, you know, I have to start from the beginning, but, then again, I didn't know how much detail, I still didn't know how much detail, you know, I talked to him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in the day</TIMEX> it's like you talk to him, and it's like he completely avoided my questions.
         So anyhow, I think I spoke to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramona</ENAMEX> again.
         No, it was just that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>, and she said that she was going to come back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
         Well, I wasn't even thinking about that, but I was so frustrated, and, I ended up talking to him again.
         Again he didn't answer my question but at least I got a little bit out of him.
         He told me what exactly he needed and that he did need it by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
         He didn't say a time again, so he just got me over there stressing out, and I really don't even know when it's needed.
         But I was like, forget it, I'm going to eat lunch I was hungry.
         Usually you feel like you have to work through, like you just have to keep working because he needs it even though it wasn't your fault that he gave it to you at the very last minute, you know, I was like ( ), and then Lana calls me in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> telling me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramona</ENAMEX> had gotten here and I didn't even know she was coming for sure.
         This time I wasn't even happy that she was there because I was so stressed out.
         I was like, "OK, well that's good," you know, like that.
         Well anyway, I went back to my, my desk.
         I ate real quick, as fast as I could and then she came in there and she ended up helping me with it.
         It was like a little bit close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> when she came in there, and um, I had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that I had to do the same thing for so once I was finished with the whole <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, then I had to do the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one and it was like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:00</TIMEX> and he hadn't asked for it or anything so, um.
         I e-mailed him because he's always on the phone.
         And I asked him, you know, could I do it, um, "Do you need me to stay and do it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> or I could have it done by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, if that's OK."
         Well, what happens the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> walks through the door that needs it.
         So I'm like, "Oh my gosh," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramona</ENAMEX> was standing there.
         She was still in there.
         I didn't ask him till after she left, but anyhow, um, um she told me that he had come in she basically, um, no that was after.
         Anyhow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> comes in.
         She had gone already and she told me just don't worry about it.
         She's like, "Don't worry about it, you know, just take your time."
         Whatever.
         Yeah, well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s here.
         He e-mails me back.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> is here.
         I need it now.
         And I only had one of them done and I just kept on doing what I was doing because I heard them talking or whatever and I kept on doing what I was doing I don't know how he did it but he basically told him that he didn't have it right now or whatever.
         And then I heard him leave, so I'm still finishing what I had to do.
         And here I am thinking he's going come in there and be like, you know, just have it out with me, you know, just tell me off like how could I not have this done.
         Even though I don't see how he could have expected me to have it done.
         I already told him, I tried to explain to him that I was frustrated I didn't have all the information I needed.
         But he didn't care.
         I spoke to him twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> and it was like.
         So anyway, um, he ended up coming in there and he was like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How</ENAMEX>'s it coming along?"
         And I was like, "I'm almost done."
         He was like, "All right, well I'm going go out and run some errands, and um, just put it up on my shelf, and um, if I have any review notes I'll give them to you in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>.
         And I was like "OK," and that was it!
         So all that stressing and I mean, I had every reason to stress <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, it was like, you're giving something you don't know how to do, and it's like here do it.
         I don't care how you do it.
         I don't care how you get it done.
         I don't care if you don't know anything about it.
         And it makes you feel just awful.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anyhow</ENAMEX>, so I finished came home at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and that was my day.
         That was my messed up.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boss</ENAMEX>, he was like with split personality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One minute</TIMEX> he's banging on the desk, the next he's OK, have it on my desk, dah, dah, dah, dah, dah.
         That's my story.
         I didn't talk long.
      
      
         Is it like that all the time?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Yep</ENAMEX> whenever he there, um, which he's not there he's there most of the time but he is gone a lot but whenever he is there, and especially if he gives you something to do it's like you don't even want it because you know it's going to be that way and it's like other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hesitate to come through because they don't want to have said something wrong and then you go back to him well like, you know, such and such helped me and it's not like you're ratting anybody out you're just saying you know such and such helped me and that's how I got to this number but it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are hesitating basically and it's really frustrating.
      
      
         So what is it that they wanted you to do?
      
      
         We were doing, um
         , we were doing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it was, um projections it was financial statement like balance sheet and income statement projections for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that, um, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was looking to buy, well he gave us the information that he had projected numbers for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002- 2003</TIMEX> and we had to put those numbers into financial statements, basically saying they are going to have this much, um, this many assets and liabilities at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2002</TIMEX> going to have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> and then going to have so much income, and you know, like that.
      
   
