
   
   
      
         This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Flono</ENAMEX>, and she grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, and she is going to talk about some stories from her
         childhood.
      
      
         Ok.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> used to tell me a lot of different stories about her growing-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and, uh, especially, uh, she used to talk about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and what it was like during those times.
         She had this one story, and, uh, we called my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granny</ENAMEX>, uh, because we had another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> we called something else, but uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um Granny</ENAMEX> used to tell this story about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>.
         And it was a fascinating story, because, uh, it kind of told a lot about, uh, what it was like being a uh, uh, close-knit black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> during those, those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> when, uh, you didn't have much.
         She grew up on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, and um, uh, what it was like, but, um, like a lot of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> during that time,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX>, uh, if you had a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, uh, and some of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> didn't have anybody in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, you would just kind of let some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> stay with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gran</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother um</ENAMEX>, were among, I think there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, uh, who lived, uh, on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, you know, maybe about, I don't know, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 miles</NUMEX> away, not that far.
         You know, during that time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walked <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 miles</NUMEX> and, uh, they needed somebody to help with some of the farm chores and all that sort of stuff and so they asked my, my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> could come and live with them.
         And you know, they were a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and they loved each other and all that kind of stuff, but it was just down the road, you know, so they said fine, and, and you, you know, he came back on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> and he was with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and all that sort of thing.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but, ah, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> he didn't show up, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, uh, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and so they wondered what was going on and they went to this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, ah, down the road and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> had packed up and left.
         They had just gone.
         Nobody knew where they went.
         They took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> with them, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> said, she said it was such a sad time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> because, you know, everybody was missing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> and they didn't know what to do.
         And so you know, eventually, you know, you know, they kept asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around, and nobody knew where they were, and eventually, you know, they just reconciled themselves that they just wouldn't see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> again.
         And, uh, so uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> grew up, she was like-- I think she told me this was when she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 10 years old</TIMEX> when this happened and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> and, uh, so she grew up and, uh, she uh, got married, and uh, that's another story.
         She got married when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, who was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>, and she didn't know she had to go live with him, but anyway that's another story
         about ignorance, among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but anyway they were sitting on the porch and she was back visiting uh, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, and they were sitting on the porch and it was like this long road, it was like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was like situated at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of this long</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> and you could see all the way down the road <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a</TIMEX>, a long way.
         And she said it was just like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, and it was like maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years later</TIMEX> cause she was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, and they were just sitting on the porch, and they were, and she said, she said she could still remember because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had on, you know, this big straw hat that she used to have on.
         It was like her favorite hat, and this big voluminous dress that she used to have on in the summertime.
         It was really cool, and the dress kind of blew in the wind a little bit--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And they were just sitting out there on rocking chairs, you know, just kind of enjoying the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and, uh, they could look down the road and they could see this dust kicking up.
         And, and, she said, uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> said she got up and she, she looked up and she said, "You know, wonder who that could be?"
         And so she sat back down, and, you know, they were still chatting, and they could still see this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was walking really, really fast.
         And she said that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had this really distinctive walk and she said the more she looked at that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> coming down that road she started thinking "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, that can't be, that can't be."
         And she said, but you know, the closer he got, she said she got up, and she peered down the road and she looked at her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, and she said, she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama</ENAMEX>, you know, I think that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>."
         And she said then her mama, her mama leaned forward, and she looked and she said,
         "Walks like him.
         
         Got that same walk,"
         but she said, "It can't be."
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> got up, and she kind of walked down the steps off the porch and she was walking up towards the road and she then just stood there.
         And then he was coming, she said he was coming really fast--she said could still remember all that dust kicking up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>--and here he's coming down the road, and she turns around and she said, "It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>!
         He's come home!"
         And she said she started running toward him, and they ran and they hugged and they hugged and she said her mama was sitting on the porch and--this is a true story--and her mama was sitting on the porch, and she said her mama was just like dumbfounded.
         She didn't say a word--
      
      
         Aw.
      
      
         She said there were just tears coming down from her eyes and she said, then she said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> came up on the porch.
         And he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama</ENAMEX>, I'm home."
      
      
         Where had he been?
      
      
         He said that they had gone up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>.
         They had wound up starting out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to visit some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of this, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, and they just stayed and he didn't know how to get back, so he just stayed with them.
         He didn't know how to get in touch with them, and he said, you know, you know, as he grew up, you know, he kept thinking about them, and he said he wanted to come back home but he didn't have any way, he didn't have any money.
         And he said finally he know, you know, once he got grown and started working, he saved up his money and he said he was determined to come back and find them, and he didn't even know if they were going to be in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX>\\.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         But he said he was going to find them, and he came all the way back.
      
      
         Do you have an idea what year that would be?
      
      
         Oh.
         That would have to have been
         let's see.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>, she was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         No, she was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX> because she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, and so it must have been like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>, you know, before, before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         Yeah, yeah, about that, yeah.
      
      
         So he stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> after that?
      
      
         Well, I don't know.
         I don't know whether he stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> after that.
         Cause they didn't actually live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX>, they lived in, well you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> was still a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> during that time, even though to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> isn't that big.
         But uh, they lived in a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country town</ENAMEX> outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> still exists, and that's where a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> still, still are too.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hah</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So, ah, and um, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, she used to tell a lot of those stories I mean, especially when talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> being the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> was a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
         and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the, the</ENAMEX>, things that just sticks in her craw is that, and you know, she, she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> uh, were lighter than some of the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> could pass for white, and in fact did pass for white.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> used to tell the story about how her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> decided that they were going to move to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX>, and pass for white.
         And they moved downtown--
      
      
         So her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was light-skinned too?
      
      
         Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was light-skinned too.
         And, uh, they moved downtown and, there was, uh, and it's still like this in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX>, this big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> downtown called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broad Street</ENAMEX>, and it really was just this broad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in a downtown area.
         And they found this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or this apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> or whatever it was that they could live in, and it was right on the edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broad Street</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, they kind of actually stopped visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because they were just, just determined that they were going to be white.
         They just didn't like what it was like being black in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, and that was, you know, I guess, that, that was probably, you know, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1930s</TIMEX>, uh, when they did that.
         And they,
         they wanted to sever relationships with the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, but the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> didn't want to sever relationships with them, even though they were mad at them because they had decided, you know, to do something they didn't think was right.
         My, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was very adamant about, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who try to be things that they aren't, and this, whenever she'd tell this story she'd talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who try to be things that they aren't.
         I mean that was the whole point.
         That was the lesson in the story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who try to be things that they aren't.
         That they shouldn't do that, that you should accept your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> in life, although you should work to improve it, you know, you should be who you are and not try to be something else.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but she used to visit her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, ah, in, in, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX>, and, but she used to have to go in the back door and pretend she was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX>.
         Granny hated that!
      
      
         I bet.
      
      
         She hated that, and she used to tell her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, she said that, that "You are doing wrong.
         You are doing wrong, wrong, wrong, wrong, treating your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> this way."
         And so finally, somebody apparently told, that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were passing for white, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> came to visit them at their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and they were gone, because they had to get out of town really quickly.
         And they couldn't stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> area because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> knew that they had tried to do something that was really taboo and try to pass for white.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and so they just left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, and she, she never did see her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> again, never saw her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> again.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         So it was just really interesting.
         And you know, the one thing that my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, she was so funny about this uh,
         she uh, she treated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, I mean her, her, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>, differently based on the color of their skin.
         But she treated the ones like us who were darker, better--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Than the ones who were lighter.
         And actually when we, we kind of began to understand what was going on because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> were a little lighter, well they were somewhat lighter than we were, and she would not treat them well and we couldn't figure it out, what, what was going on, you know, why you know, we could get anything we wanted and she was very stern with them.
         And, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> eventually told us, you know, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, she has this thing
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you know just really, and part of it has to do with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, you know, uh, when her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> tried to, you know, pass for white and thought she was better than everybody else and she kind of she thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who tried to pass for white think they're better than everybody else, and light <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think they're better than everybody else."
         And the fact is she was light!
         And that was the thing, that was the thing that was so funny.
         She was a light-skinned black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
         And it was like she was rejecting who she was, in some ways, by, you know, the way she treated you know, the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but you know there were just a lot of mixed feelings involved, and she had to deal with her feelings in her own, but when I got older, when I got to be an adult I actually talked to her about it.
         I told her, "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, you know, you are so sweet to us but you are wrong about this, you shouldn't be treating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> differently because of that."
         
      
      
         What did she say?
      
      
         And, she said at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>--
      
      
         Did she really, kind of, know she was doing it?
      
      
         Yes she did.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and she said, she said, she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby</ENAMEX>," she said, "You don't understand about life the way I understand about life."
         But as she got older, um, she never acknowledged that she was wrong but she did change her behavior.
         So--
      
      
         Now this was the one who married at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> and didn't--
      
      
         Yeah, yeah, married my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> who, who, she was light and he was dark, and I don't know whether that was the reason she married him, although it was kind of like one of those arranged marriages--
      
      
         Ah.
      
      
         Where he was a
         , he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, so he had, they had property, and stuff, and they were very well-connected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and very, held in high esteem.
         His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was like, uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastor</ENAMEX> of this big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> for a long period of time and, and, and so I think her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tates</ENAMEX>, really wanted to connect with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keenes</ENAMEX> for that reason, and so they just really just told her she was going to be marrying him.
         And, she didn't really understand.
         She didn't even understand the marriage ceremony, she didn't even know that she had gotten married, really--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         And so when they told her she had to go home with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, she said, "Go <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with him?
         
         He's old enough to be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>."
         
         Well, he was almost, old enough to be her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh, no.
      
      
         And he was, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was not a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         He was nice enough to us.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> keeps telling me, she says, "Sometimes you're just like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, you treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wrong for the wrong reasons."
         
         And I did because I thought he treated, I thought he treated, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> not well in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, because he had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>, and that all sort of thing, not based on color of skin or anything but just based on, I don't know, on whatever anyway.
         My, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> wound up not being one of his favorites early on and, ah, so she was relegated to working in the fields whereas some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> didn't work in the fields.
         I mean they only had, like, they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, one of them died.
         But they were divided about like who were the field hands and who were the house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, it was kind of--
      
      
         Really?
      
      
         Yeah, it was almost like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation system</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         That's interesting.
      
      
         Yeah, it was operating within the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         He would have been born--
      
      
         He was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX> something, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">188</ENAMEX>, I think it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1889</TIMEX>, I think it was when he was born.
         No it was, no he was older than that because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX> and he was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years earlier</TIMEX>--
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1884</TIMEX>?
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1884</TIMEX>, yeah.
      
      
         Hum.
      
      
         But he was, you know, in a lot of ways, just like
         a plantation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> because he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who owned a lot of property.
         \\
      
      
         He had property.
         \\
      
      
         And it was, he never really had to do anything for himself.
         And he was a philanderer, an d oh yeah, he was like out there
         .
         And, ah, so, you know, I didn't like him, but anyway those are my stories.
      
      
         That's interesting.
      
      
         There are many stories in the naked city
         .
      
      
         You'd be surprised.
      
      
         All right.
      
      
         Thank you.
      
      
         You're very welcome.
      
   
