
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I'm nervous.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         OK, can you hear me?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         OK, OK.
         The story I shall talk about today
      is about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and the culture diversities he had when he moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
         He is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and he is from a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tokalleka</ENAMEX> and he came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and I believe it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969 or 1970</TIMEX> and he shortly got married.
         And they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallard Creek</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         
         Uh the problem he had with coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> I guess was
      was that uh, he uh, he wanted to still have the village aspects where he wanted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and all those stuff living in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mallard Creek</ENAMEX> area.
         And this was probably about, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX> or maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years ago</TIMEX> when the area was not so, I guess, rich as it is now.
         It was still cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> but suburbs was still the dominant form.
         So he, we lived in this area.
         We were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he gathered all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, and goat, and he just had so many animals
      .
         And the problem was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> didn't like to stay at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they wanted to go around to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, you know, eat their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and stuff and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>.
         We lived off, um, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mallard Creek</ENAMEX> where currently the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">485</ENAMEX> is now cause then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the like last ten years</TIMEX> we had to move because of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">485</NUMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> had to buy the property and stuff.
         But anyway, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> would get loose all the time, especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX>.
         They didn't want to stay captive.
         They would go, you know, just go out of the fence.
         A lot of times they would get their horns and stuff caught into the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, fences because there were square fences that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> himself put up all around the property but they would get their horns and stuff, and they would jump over the fence very easily so they would be on the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 4</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> times that I can remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> would have to come and say, you know, "You have to get your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>."
         And our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> always told us not to say they are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
         So
      , and I thought this was really crazy because who else in the neighborhood had goats and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> and stuff and so but he was convinced that they could not prove that those were our goats so but it was very embarrassing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mallard Creek</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, everybody knew when you rode a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX>, um, we didn't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and stuff.
         We had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> out there and often our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> would get loose and we had to go out and follow our cow <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or something like that, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the</NUMEX>, um, animal control would come out to like subdue a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> if it would get too far away so that's really the story I have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, um
      it was just really a awkward experience with him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
         Other thing that he did with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> in his culture a goat is really an important <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>; kind of a delicacy, and he even ended up selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> from this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> area and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would come out, pick out their goat, which was really sad for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and I because we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> were our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> stuff, and they would come out and pick out their goat and then they would proceed to kill it on property
      and it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">really horrible</TIMEX> for us as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> it was traumatizing.
         
         To see your little pet or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, you know, have to be killed, skinned, and then they would cut it up and put out their parts there and then they would go off to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, to their dinner or wedding, or whatever, and eat the goat.
         So that's about it.
         He has a lot of pride in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>.
         And unfortunately we moved again.
         When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> took his property, we moved to a smaller, smaller area in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX> where you are not allowed to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> because it's zoned and so that's the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> story.
         That enough?
      
      
         OK thank you.
         
      
   
