
   
   
      
         This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Master Sergeant Clem Francis</ENAMEX>, retired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Air Force</ENAMEX>.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> he is going to talk to us about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third SS</ENAMEX>, the U2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quick</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackbird</ENAMEX>.
         Go ahead Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I'm uh, Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Master Sergeant</ENAMEX>, retired, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> said.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I spent much of my time in, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Activities</ENAMEX>.
         That's kind of unique in that I, uh, spent, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 16 years</TIMEX> of my career in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Special Activities</ENAMEX>.
         I don't want to go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third SS</ENAMEX> that's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Third Strategic Support Squadron</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX> back in, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 and 60, 19 and 52</TIMEX>, when I returned from the, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, I was assigned to, uh, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, which was called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C124 Third Strategic Support Squadron</ENAMEX>, and, uh, one of their primary purposes was to, uh, uh, move atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to forward locations.
         And, uh, one of my jobs at the time was training <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> how to put parachutes on a nuclear weapons trigger to, uh, which detonates the atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> itself.
         But my job was to put parachutes on it and life preservers when we would load it and start to an overseas location.
         I would, uh, put parachutes on the trigger itself, and we use that if, in case we had to throw the trigger out over land when we was approaching <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, we had to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> life preservers on what they call "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mae West</ENAMEX>" on the trigger, so we just threw it out over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
         That was the primary thing we wanted to save
         since there wasn't any way to dump a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>-megaton H-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> off a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C124</TIMEX>.
         If you started to run it back to the elevator, why it would turn the aircraft upside down, so it would if we had trouble the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> itself would end with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, of course.
         The rest of us after, uh, after we got the trigger out, why we, uh, would bale out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, regardless whether if it was water, over land, air or what, but the bottom did go in.
         I want to say that there wasn't any danger of going in with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> because it would not explode, regardless of how hard it hit the ground.
         Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> was on fire, why it, it would uh, burn and it would melt through a lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component</ENAMEX> for the radiation to leak out.
         It would not explode without the trigger.
         But anyway, uh,
         I had a top secret clearance in that, so in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 and 57</TIMEX> why, uh, they started, uh, I didn't know why they was a running the clearance on me to begin because I thought uh, top secret was the highest you could go in security clearance, and, of course, that I knew, everybody in my neighborhood was asking me, "Well what if they're asking about you?"
         And even uh, uh, a neighbor in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> told me that they was a checking with him on why, uh, uh, on why, uh, they was running a clearance on me.
         I didn't know anything about it until about the time, well, uh, I knew about it when they was running the clearance on me when I had a top secret, so I didn't know anything about what it was all about until I arrived.
         I got orders to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Del Rio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>, so when I arrived out there, well, I found out I had to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Laughlin Air Force Base</ENAMEX>.
         I was reporting to a certain place in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Del Rio</ENAMEX>, then I had to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Laughlin Air Force Base</ENAMEX>, which had just re-opened.
         It wasn't nothing but a desert; there was sagebrush out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runway</ENAMEX>.
         Anyway, it was pretty soon after I arrived there, there was, some RV57 ( ) arrived, which used crasher suits as a high altitude photography <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, well, I figured that's what it was.
         I had to start training in course.
         I had already been to partial pressure suit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in my career field, where I was ( ), so I started training with equipment I had never handled before.
         I didn't know what it was all about or anything till I had to go out and train hook in a ( ) in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">RV57D</TIMEX>, which I say now I found it, it was a forerunner to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.
         But at the time I arrived there, we didn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U2</ENAMEX>'s.
         We didn't know what a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">U2</NUMEX> was and nobody knew anything about a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U2</TIMEX>.
         But all of a sudden, we was called out to look at what was flying.
         Well they looked like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big gliders flying over the base and they made a circle and come in and landed and I didn't know whether it was a glider or what it was I hadn't heard the name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U2</ENAMEX> when I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> arrived.
         Come to find out it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> but we couldn't, we could not say one word about what it was; nothing to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or anybody.
         OK, well, I started the training in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the U2</TIMEX> with the pressure suits and everything and uh, I don't know how long it was I suited and unsuited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and just practiced putting them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.
         Well it got to where there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> arrive in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and I didn't know where they're flying to.
         All we done, they never did tell us any place where they was going, even when they left the base to go to somewhere else to stay for a while.
         We didn't know where they were going.
         Anyway it got up to, we had about uh, ah, I don't remember the numbers.
         It's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 or 40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">U2</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, and we'd started the training <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> in them, just all over the, the world that we were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> with.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, but one of the things that I am proud of in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the U2</TIMEX>'s I was the life support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> ( ) uh.
         Of course, parachutes and life rafts packed the survival kits, but the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">U2</NUMEX> kits had what they call a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">F124 hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> in them which was a highly cued <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> breathing pressure and counter pressure in their capstans of the partial pressure suits in case they had a decompression at high altitudes like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">80 thousand feet</NUMEX>.
         You know, you can't, you cannot survive if you don't have any counter pressure, increase breathing pressure in those altitudes.
         If, if your hand was exposed outside of the pressure suit, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> would go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> times the size, if you had a decompression.
         Well of, of course, needless to say, we had a, we could not make a mistake.
         So, uh, I skip a lot of things here that I could say, but they chose me and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.
         That, I was the only 922 which was life support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was a physiological support.
         Physiological support differs from life support in that he handles the altitude <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> which run pilots <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 80 thousand feet</NUMEX> in high altitude <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>, and brings him back down.
         They have to go through a number of altitude <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>, uh, rides before they start even flying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U2</TIMEX>'s or flying with pressure suits.
         Of course they already had done the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>'s bit before they done, well, I had to go through altitude <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> myself because I was working with pressure suits.
         I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX> to go through the altitude <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX> with a partial pressure just like I was working with, and when, when all the training was done on the pressure suits and things, I was chosen with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant secretary</ENAMEX> to go through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, which, we was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> about the size of a nice-size <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>.
         We would go in there.
         The doors were locked when we went in.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Santo</ENAMEX> of<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, of Firewell and Company</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, they was the one that uh, manufactured, uh, invented the high O2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> before that they built fire control on the stove well.
         Anyway, they come up with this invention of the high O2 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX>.
         Say it was a tremendous breakthrough for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Firewell and Company</ENAMEX>.
         Well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Santo</ENAMEX> would start training us in this small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">F24 hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> with we had to tear it down and break it, break it down so many times, and, uh, we had to, uh, set injections on it.
         It's a little screw which set an injection but the, the breathing pressure tube to the pilot and counter pressure.
         Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> has a different breathing capacity and we would have to, uh, uh, bend then individual over in the pressure suit uh, uh, I'd have to have to set it for, uh, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, or which was going through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         Then he'd dress me, and, uh, he'd set the injection on me and you, uh, uh, we'd have to bend down and come up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> in the seat kit itself then we'd come up breathing as hard as we could, and you better if uh, the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the</ENAMEX>, the top portion of your helmet surged, which you had rubber around the neck and the visor closed.
         And, uh, if it surged and just kept surging it would go 'whish,' and, like it was going to pull your head off.
         You'd better get the little screw turned down a little bit because you could damage and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>'s lungs very easily.
         And, well, anyway, needless to say, I had to tear down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> and put it back together blindfold.
         I never did see, and don't know yet why, unless it was just ex, ex, expressing the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the</ENAMEX>, the need to know what you was a doing and whatever.
         The part was, there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">158</NUMEX> parts to it and we had to break it down put it back together break it down and never make a mistake.
         Well, I had taken me about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45 days</TIMEX> ( ), and I, both to get through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will tell you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that I turned gray-headed within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those 45 days</TIMEX>, and not real gray but I did turn gray headed.
         And, uh, but, uh, I would think, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> I couldn't sleep.
         I would think, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I'm, I'm going to let somebody else go," but then I would think, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My God</ENAMEX>!
         They've, they chosen me over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> there, to go to through that school and I'm not, I'm not.
         So I would go back determined, determined to stay with it, and, of course, they trained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more after I had been through, but who did they use to set all the injections?
         And it was myself and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>, the one who went through that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, that, you know, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that we went.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more thing, uh, ( ) while we were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Santo</ENAMEX> was teaching us, we could, uh, take notes, but before we left out of the room <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> would take and tear every one of the notes up that we had and get it down to where you'd rub a pencil over it where you could not read.
         He would tear the, the paper up and put it in the sand, ashtray <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>, set it on a fire and burn it, and then stir the ashes up like that.
         Now that's how classified it was.
         And so, well, anyway, uh, they chose me.
         Also, oh, let me go through this.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About</TIMEX>, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two months</TIMEX> after uh, uh, we finished the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and was set the injections on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Firewell</ENAMEX> and Company come up with an automatic, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX>-proof uh, uh, that uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> adjusted itself with a little valve that moved back and forth.
         It would not burst the lungs, it would not over inflate it, it was so perfect that you needn't even have to open the kit to set the injection.
         It was uh, automatic.
         OK, well, that's where I went.
         They chose me over everybody else, and, of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sergeant Secretary</ENAMEX>, he was a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC</ENAMEX>, but he's the one that went through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with, they chose me to go out of the uh, uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that I was at on the present.
         Now it's on the same base, but they've set, taken me to field maintenance to run <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> in the ( ) altitude <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>.
         You had to run them every so often, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 60 days</TIMEX>, I believe it was, had to make sure that they was, uh, reading exact pressure like at, uh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">20,000 feet</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40, 50, 60</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70,000 feet</NUMEX> and you had to record it.
         If it was off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> iota, you had to do some adjusting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> itself.
         And I thought that was a privilege, and it's still, it's still, I was the only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine two</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ex-O</ENAMEX> which was my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFFC Air Force</ENAMEX> Career field.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I was still the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine two</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that had ever set the injection on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX>.
         I was the only one that uh, ever run the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> for the, the test in the miniature altitude <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>.
         I'm proud of that.
         So anyway, I worked with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 4080th until 19 and 60, late 1962</TIMEX>, well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>, before I left the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">4080th</NUMEX>, and I have some things here.
         Well, if I can find the picture of the ().
         Just give me a minute if you want to cut it off, I'd, uh, go.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, well, of course, you know, () was shot down over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 and 60</TIMEX>, and then we come with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cuban Crisis</ENAMEX>.
         It was, uh, which we, uh, had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Anderson</ENAMEX> in a, a formulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three U2</TIMEX>'s.
         It was from a airbase that flew over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, and of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Anderson</ENAMEX> was shot down.
         He was the only casualty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cuban Crisis</ENAMEX>, and uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX> uh, he got the pictures and flew straight to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrews Air Force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> unloaded the, the film, taken them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">United Nations</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>.
         And uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai Stevenson</ENAMEX>, which was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nation's</ENAMEX>, uh, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>, he sit and told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Androv Gromikov</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, that he would sit there until hell froze over, unless he had admitted to having the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> installed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>; offensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> headed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, targeted for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
         And, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Androv Gromikov</ENAMEX> didn't answer anything, but we had all the information from the films <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the U2</TIMEX> had taken.
         Well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>, uh, blockaded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, and, uh, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> stopped a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> that was headed just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> within, and they found <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> on them.
         Well if, uh, I think this is official history.
         If they would have kept moving with that ship towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, it's my understanding that, uh, we come within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six minutes</TIMEX> of nuclear war because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> would have launched the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> uh, on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.
         But anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikita Khrushchev</ENAMEX> backed down, turned all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> around, and headed back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.
         Of course we were, this is picture of me, now I was at home, stationed.
         And I had put uh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> detachments out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">U2</TIMEX>'s.
         Now I uh, uh, worked with life support, I had to stay there and keep extra gear, extra pressure suits, extra kits, extra parachutes--everything that if I had to in an emergency, that would we'd send these this equipment out to one of those attachments and, and that's what I did.
         And, of course, uh, this is an outstanding job that uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> ( ) that uh, he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX> at that time, gave me an award for doing that outstanding job, and also this is the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX> ( ) that uh, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> giving our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> the outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> award, and until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, I've got it all here in the, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 4080th</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Strategic Reconnaissance Wing of the U2's</ENAMEX>, that I was in at that time, is the highest, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> in peace time there are.
         That still stands <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, of course, I won't go but we, I have just so much I could talk about, but, uh, that is the main things that we, of course, everybody knows now that the, what has happened.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> backed down and that's the good thing to do because if they did not and we went to nuclear war, I was trying to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Del Rio</ENAMEX> and back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, but it happened so fast I didn't get them back.
         Because if their was a nuclear war then, or if there's nuclear bombs started <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> or anything, I would want the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to hit me right between the running lights because this just would be a world after a nuclear war and--.
         So, well I, uh, anyway, uh, uh, this is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, uh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">U2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> that, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General May</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> says to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>, says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gentlemen</ENAMEX> you take good pictures."
         This is the one that went over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and got the pictures they showed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> and of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Anderson</ENAMEX> was shot down, uh, during the flight.
         He didn't get to go.
         That's all.
         And this is a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX> ( ) with some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>.
         And, and we were, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 48th</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Extension Reconnaissance Wing</ENAMEX>, this was after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> crisis, was a voted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">48th Extension Reconnaissance Wing</ENAMEX> was, uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX Ambassadors</ENAMEX>.
         This was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that, that had happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 years</TIMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> had voted a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> being <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX Ambassadors</ENAMEX>, so, needed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX Ambassadors</ENAMEX>.
         
         Late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>, uh, I got orders to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> I didn't know what I was going for or anything, so was to report to a designated place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I went ahead up and it was highly classified, even my orders were classified.
         So I went to, I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> and I didn't go directly to, uh, that, uh, they had told me to on my orders.
         I went to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s that lived there .
         Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in the service and worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX>, and I went to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         They lived just in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX> just outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">beltway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> So I went to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and then I called in to this number I was supposed to call when I got there.
         And I called in and they asked me where I was at.
         I told them my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s.
         They asked a few questions and I answered them and they said, "Get your baggage and leave there immediately, and come to the address you were supposed to when you arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>."
         I go ahead and picked the baggage and went to the address I was supposed to.
         Of course, they questioned me there, why I went.
         "Well they, they live there, and I, uh, needed a place to stay."
         They said, "We're paying for a place for you to stay.
         You don't have to stay there."
         Well after they checked, they asked me about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
         After they checked, found out he was in security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>, they said, "OK," I could go ahead back and stay there if I wanted and they gave me a certain time to report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA Headquarters</ENAMEX>, which I can say that name, and needless to say, I was up there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and I, I can't say anything else what happened or anything.
         But I didn't know what in God's world I was there for.
         I, I just didn't I was just puzzled.
         Of course I came back, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laughlin Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>, and then shortly thereafter I got orders I could bring my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and everything to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NV</ENAMEX> and I couldn't tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or anything about why I was going there because I didn't know.
         And so, we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NV</ENAMEX>, and I reported, just like I did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, to a certain address in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>.
         They told me that, uh, that I would be called in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at the end for me to meet.
         It was another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> and said I would go with him on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> to a certain location, and we never was for many, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, we could not even mention the location, but now I have the declassification of it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roadrunner's International</ENAMEX> right there in it's authorized, and it tells all about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A-12 Blackbird</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> that I was going to in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1963</TIMEX> and I guess it was the most classified thing that there was at that time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> but when I got out and gone out found out what was going into and I looked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, there was actually bile come into my mouth.
         Now that's how, uh, I stay buckled in.
         We had full pressure suits there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> just, just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX> wore, except ours was totally <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>, silver uh, boot and everything, to reflect heat, of course.
         I started immediately, uh, uh, training into that from the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that was at the location.
         They had already had their training in the full pressure suits and it taken me a while if you go into full pressure suits.
         Different, totally different types parachutes and in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX>, uh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the speed of sound, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 22,000 miles an hour</NUMEX>.
         You can't even imagine that and I really can't get over, as, as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> that I put in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, and know, and seen them come in ( ) and go walk up the plank to, to get him out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> and he waits for me to get him out.
         And then he looks.
         When I pull, when he pulls the canopy for me to start getting him out, he points to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> instruments on the left side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> that had actually melted during the flight.
         And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our jobs was to measure, uh, heat on the top of their helmet, which was a piece to tape that went across there and put out by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> that, uh, there was different spots of paint on it.
         And the spots of paint would change <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">every hundred degrees</NUMEX>, it might be red, it change to blue.
         Where, I didn't know what the code was, but, of course, I'd take it and turn it in to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> back at life support but I know that I have measured them and they told me he had <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300 degrees</NUMEX> on the top of his head.
         But you have to remember, he had a tremendous cooling system going in to his full pressure suit and going out to the inside of his hands channels and then down to his feet he's got channels pumping cold air down there all the time and then comes back and exhausts out the outside of the control.
         There's so much you could talk about on that I'll just skip that.
         But uh, think about it.
         You're putting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in there it's risking his life, those tests like what we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Aircraft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
         Test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> that flew them <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou</ENAMEX> ( ), I could name all of them really, but they test the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> first, and then our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> started flying them.
         We were the ones handled, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>, uh, anyway, uh, we set all kinds of records step by step.
         Only lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> while we was there, and, uh, test phase.
         But we only lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> there and really why, uh, there's a modification that we shouldn't have made.
         You live and learn, you know, when you test, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, well it's, uh, the speeds got faster, faster, and faster until we deployed overseas.
         In the meantime the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> bought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the SR71</TIMEX>, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the A-12</TIMEX>, that we were working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>.
         It was one space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> he operated all the cameras and everything and flew the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.
         The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">SR71</NUMEX> was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> which you had a pilot and a systems <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> in the back seat give the pilot a little bit of a break from what the A-12 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> had.
         Anyway, we deployed and I can tell now be, because of this that, that, that, uh, we deployed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kadina, Okinawa</ENAMEX>, and this was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>.
         And I will tell you about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> flight that we made over there that I hooked up.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weeks</ENAMEX> had his name here on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>, and he made the flight over up to the edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> extreme north, back over the middle and back down south.
         Got the pictures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pueblo</ENAMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Koreans</ENAMEX> captured the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pueblo</ENAMEX> and brought it in to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>.
         I don't know if you remembered it or not or ever thought about it.
         Well, we got the pictures of that and, and even got the pictures of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> walking on the gangplank.
         Why this was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>.
         Why I remember it so is that I was the individual that put Mr.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weeks</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> and, and sent him out on his mission and made a successful mission.
         And, uh, one bad thing though, coming back down below <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> between there and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, our battleships launched their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and started firing.
         They see, uh, we flew on radio silence.
         All of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> flew on radio silence, period.
         And, of course, they were going so fast they couldn't move up and down but evidently they got, uh, word back real quickly by mashing the scrambler, a button on the inside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>.
         I don't know that; I never was told that, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> got the word quick like that, but they never could shoot him down anyway, and they have never, never.
         They've had so many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> and they never been shot down yet.
         I stayed with them until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 and 69</TIMEX> before I left there.
         And uh, course I won't go into anything else because I'm not prepared with my information here, but thank you very much.
      
   
