
   
   
      
         This story, it's uh, it's, happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX> and, uh, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>, I have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>, who's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>, who's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>, and, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>, who's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>.
         And we're trying to make a decision whether to buy a beach place, beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, or a lake <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, or a mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         And we'd read this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, you know, you get these articles about um,
         you know, advertisements about these beautiful mountain, mountain lake places and we thought, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gosh</ENAMEX>, this is great, you know, it's a combination of both, it's a, it's a, a mountain place with this beautiful lake, that surrounds this, this mountain."
         So, um, we called, and, uh, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> answered the phone, and he's with the development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, it's up in the mountains, it's near, uh, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Lure</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come</ENAMEX> on up," and he says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wha</ENAMEX>, what will you be driving?"
         and, uh, we said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well, a</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>, you know."
         "Do you, is the van four-wheel drive?"
         and I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, no, it's not," and he says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, you know, some of this gets real rugged, you know, up here, and, uh, it's not fully developed, the you know you can look at some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX>, if you bring your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>, you can just look at some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> that are developed you know, so it'll be, you can drive right up to it."
         So, um, we thought about that and we thought, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, let's just take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, because I have a four-wheel drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, it's got the king <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX>, and we put all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the back, smashed them in that little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> cab part and got in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and drove.
         And we drove <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two hours</TIMEX>, and it was getting pretty hot, you know, kind of, kind of a miserable ride, and we get up, and, uh, get up to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Lure</ENAMEX> into this development, pull into the development; you have to drive, like, meandering through this, this hillside, and we get up to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> and, uh, we thought, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, this is," you know, we thought, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, we'd be able to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>," and, uh, you know, you could tell this development was not that far along.
         So we talked to the development <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, and he, he kind of shows us a map, a real rough map of the area, and uh, so tells us, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, you know, here, here are the key, key kind of sites, and you're looking for what?"
         And we said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, we want a, a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that's kind of in the mountains and that looks on a lake like you had in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>."
         And he goes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, we got, we got SOME of those," and I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> it says you have all your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> are overlooking lakes" and he goes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>," you know, and he could tell we had driven a long way just to, you know, you know, just to see some really kind of rugged area, and we, he knew exactly what we wanted at that point.
         He says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, here's, there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lot left that actually overlooks this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and it's on a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">hilltop</ENAMEX>," and uh, you know, kind of drew it out on this paper map and then we drove out there.
         Well, we start driving in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, you know, I have a fairly large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, and we're driving, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>'s at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paved, and then we're driving along, and then it goes to stone, gravel, and then, pretty much, we keep going, and it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>, turns into a dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, and then, at the end of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, probably the last <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX>, we're driving over tree stumps
         , to get to this location on this map.
         And, uh, we finally get up there.
         It took us <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX>, of rough driving, in four-wheel drive, to get to the top of this hill.
         And we get, get there, and we literally had to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that they'd just cut.
         And, uh, they'd just clear-cut; I don't know if you know, ever heard what clear cutting is.
         Clear cutting is, you cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> down, but you leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> there, then you bring a bulldozer and push them off later.
         Well they hadn't pushed any of these off, so there's these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> on top of this hill.
         And I kind of drove to the peak of this hill, and we could see down on the lake, and it was kind of neat, but the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the</ENAMEX>, the lake, the hill, the grade down to the lake was just unbelievable, it was almost like a cliff.
         And you know, you could it was probably an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight per cent</NUMEX> grade very steep grade.
         So, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Like what degree?
         More than for, less than forty-five degrees, I mean?
      
      
         It was about, uh, probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> degrees, so pretty steep.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>, ah, immediately she looks at me, and she goes, "You keep these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> here, you know, we'll stay, and we'll kind of look around, but, you know, um, just you keep track of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>."
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>, the youngest, of course he's just so sick of being in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, he says, "Get me out of here," you know, just, "Let me out!"
         I say, "OK, everybody, we're going to get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, we're going to kind of look around, we'll do some stuff, and then, we'll probably eat breakfast, and then we'll go or, ea, we had our little bag lunches, and then we'll go down to the lake.
         And, uh, we get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, and we walk about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> feet, and I, I was like, walking over logs and trying to get over to a fairly clear area, and all of a sudden, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX> just goes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snake</ENAMEX>!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snake</ENAMEX>!"
         screaming at the top of his lungs, you know, and it, it just, it was unbelievable how loud he was yelling, how, and I thought, "Oh, my God, he got bit by a snake."
         Well I turn around and I go, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wha</ENAMEX>, what's wrong?
         !" and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX> is pointing at me, and I look down between my legs, and there's this rattlesnake, like I'd stepped in this rattlesnake <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX>!
         And I'm standing there
         and I go, "OK, everybody just calm down," and, you know.
         And I stepped down on the log, and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ja</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX> is freaking out, just freaking out, he's going, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, Jees!"
         you know, my go, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s cussing like I do, you know, I was so scared!
         So we walk, we walk away from that snake, I go, "Oh my God, I'm lucky I'm not dead, you know, they could have bit me and then you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> would have put me in a truck and hauled me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> and I, I, you know, I probably would have died."
         And I, I'm like, God, somebody's trying to tell me something.
         So anyway, we kind of, we stayed away from the snake and we're kind of walking around, and then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>, they, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>'s the oldest, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>, you know, is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>, and, uh, they want to go down to the lake, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>'s going, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, don't let them go down to the lake, just, it's too steep, don't let them go down to the lake."
         And, uh,
         we, you know, they're just saying, "Well what are we doing?
         We're just going to get in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and then go back?
         Let's just at least look at the lake."
         So I said, "OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.
         You <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> can go, go down to the lake, just be careful."
         And, uh, so they kind of walked over to the hill, kind of started walking down, and at a point they just had to sit on their butts and kind of slide down, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> were all cut, so they'd grab <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> as they were going down.
         And, um, I was just watching them, and I was up at the top, and then, I started down, I'd figured, let them go <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, then I'd, I'd go kind of behind them.
         I was probably, um, I'd say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> foot behind them.
         And, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> was first, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> was in the middle, I was at the back.
      
      
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX> was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX> stayed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>, and she was mad at us, because we were doing this.
         She's up at the top of the hill.
         And, um, I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>, everything OK<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
         you know, he says, "Yeah, yeah."
         All of a sudden, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>, and we still, to this day, do not know why he did this, he stood up, on this grade, and started
         running down this hill.
         I mean, the hill's, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> could catch
         that kind of momentum without gravity pulling him down, and he starts running, and he's running, and you could just see, it was like, there's no way he's going to recover from this.
         And he's running, trying to keep up with gravity, so he's going down this hill, and literally, falling down the hill, but instead of falling down, he's running!
         And, what we didn't know, was this hill came down, and then there was a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> foot cliff, with a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> in it, and then the hill kept going.
         They'd cut a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> into the hill, halfway down it, you couldn't see it from the top, where they drove <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> down, and they'd just clear cut this, and down at that cliff, the bottom of that cliff was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> foot in the air, literally, higher than this ceiling, and down at the bottom were just these little like bungee, where they'd cut all this brush and there's little bungee stuff sticking out.
         And all of a sudden I just saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> just run, and disappear off this cliff, and he's just flying, like the last thing I saw was him flying.
         I go, "Oh, my God."
         By that time, I'm running down the hill, just grabbing stuff, like falling down the hill, grabbing stuff.
         And as I saw he hit the ground, flat, like on those bungees, and then flipped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times.
         He hit flat, face <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, flipped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times, I mean, end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over end</TIMEX>, and landed in the, spread eagle, backwards and by the time I came down the cliff, he's just grabbing his eyes, and I looked down, and then I saw those bungees, and I thought, "Oh, my God, he impaled his eyes and his face and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> with these bungee things, uh, oh my God."
         I just flew off the cliff, you know, and by that time I get to him, he's just, he's not even breathing, and I looked at him, I go, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>!
         Are you all right?"
         And I looked at his nose and his mouth and his eyelids, and what he'd done, he'd hit the ground, and it was a real dusty, powdery.
         He'd missed all those bungee sticks, but the dust and dirt had gone in his mouth, and like, his nose was filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>, it backed up in here, and under his eyelids were filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>, he was, he goes, he looked at me, and he goes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uuuugggghhhh</ENAMEX>."
         He couldn't talk.
         He says, "Am I alive?
         Am I alive?"
         I go, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>, what were you doing?
         What did you think?
         Wha, why, what were you thinking to run down this hill<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
         And he goes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I started falling and I couldn't stop myself and I figured, I'd rather run down hill as fast as I could, and I thought that I could, I could outrun it, and I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny</ENAMEX> do it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>, on cartoons."
         
         He thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny</ENAMEX> could outrun, you know, the speeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive</ENAMEX> or, and it, I think his whole mind, you know, like when the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is falling and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Bugs Bunny hops</ENAMEX> out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last minute</TIMEX>, and then lives?
         That's what he was thinking, that's, that's science, that's kinetic energy in his mind.
         Bottom line, we got him back up the hill, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week later</TIMEX>, we bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at the beach.
         
         No way, somebody was trying to tell us not to do that.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Snakes</ENAMEX>, killing our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, you know, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>, it's hot; it was the most miserable time.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> and I still to this day say, "We didn't, we're lucky that we, that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us aren't dead
         , you know, from trying to buy the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>."
         But that's my story.
      
   
