
   
   
      
         Thanksgiving I was hanging out with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, OK, to give you a little background.
         You know, we just went to the movies, or whatever, and then the next night I went to work.
         I was working at a nursing home.
         I was washing dishes and cleaning pots and pans and stuff like that.
         So and then all of a sudden I got this massive fever.
         Which, you know, when you get a fever you don't realize you have a fever at the time, especially when you're that age because you don't know exactly what the symptoms are.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         But I felt like crap.
         I was aching all over and it just hit me like that.
         Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five or 10 minutes</TIMEX>.
         I just felt terrible.
         So then I called my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to pick me up.
         I had driven there but she had to come pick me up; that's how bad I was.
      
      
         You couldn't drive.
      
      
         I couldn't even drive.
         I was that sick but within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half an hour</TIMEX>, I would say that was.
         So she took me home.
         And, uh, while she was taking me home I got this pounding headache.
         I felt like somebody was hitting me in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with a rubber mallet.
         You know, just a thud like this thud, thud, thud, maybe a little slower than that.
         
         But it hurt.
         So she took me home.
         I went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and I was in bad shape.
         I was terrible.
         I was just like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-conscious, just in a lot of pain.
         Well actually, I was fully conscious but I was just in a lot of pain.
         So I looked really weird.
         So I go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, you know, back in high school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> I thought it was cool I had the black leather jacket and all that.
         
         The long hair.
      
      
         Fonzie
      
      
         No, I had long hair, didn't look exactly like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonzie</ENAMEX>.
         It was the heavy metal thing.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, so he asked what drugs I'm on, you know, what I had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.D.'d</ENAMEX> on?
         Nothing, nothing.
         trying to tell him I was just sick.
         So he examines me, and all that, sends me home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, and he had given her instructions on what to do if anything happened to me.
         So as it turns out something happened to me.
         I, lying in bed I passed out while I was lying in bed I fell out of bed, or something.
         I think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> heard me hit the floor.
         So they come in, so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> take me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> know what was wrong with you?
      
      
         He had an idea what was wrong with me but he didn't want to tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> because he didn't want to get them in a total panic.
      
      
         Oh OK.
      
      
         Ah.
         So they take me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and I bang my head a couple of times on the way there.
         I bang my head on the car door.
         
         I don't remember any of this.
      
      
         No wonder, no wonder you felt like a mallet was hitting you.
         
      
      
         Yes.
         And I don't remember any of this.
         The last thing I remember was, you know, being sick <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.
         After I got home from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s I don't really remember anything after that.
         So, you know, I hit my head on the car door.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> told me that, at the time, that I let out a huge
         scream which I don't remember.
         And I remember while my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was driving me around, every time she would hit a bump, you know, that was like the mallet would, ah, increase the pain level <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> times.
         It was a fun trip.
      
      
         I'm sure it was a real fun for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah, oh it was horrible for them.
         So I wake up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days later</TIMEX>.
         And it turns out that I had meningitis.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humph</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I almost died during that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>.
         You know, all these things my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had to call my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and everything and tell them I was in the hospital practically dying.
         So it was actually a lot worse experience for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because, you know, they had--
      
      
         You were passed out half the time.
      
      
         Right, they had to go through wondering for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> whether or not I was going to live.
         For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> maybe not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> for like a, I guess, maybe like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> period or what ever.
      
      
         Right, uh-huh.
      
      
         I could have lived or died or I could have had some major damage done to me.
      
      
         Oh really like permanent stuff could happen?
      
      
         Because meningitis effects your, uh, the lining of your nervous system.
      
      
         Oh OK.
      
      
         And your brain, which is called the meningitis, it gets swollen and that is what caused the pain.
         You know, that is like the throbbing pain it's like a swelling or whatever.
         So then all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> had to get throat cultures because it's very contagious.
      
      
         Oh really.
      
      
         Anybody that I interacted with at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had to get throat cultures.
      
      
         Now where were you working in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning</TIMEX> when you started washing the dishes in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         In a nursing home.
      
      
         In a nursing home OK.
      
      
         Right so I was doing dishes.
      
      
         So did they have to test the nursing home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I'm sure they did yeah.
         And I never worked in a nursing home again after that.
         I kept telling that I was going to come back.
      
      
         They didn't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Outbreak monkey</ENAMEX> to come back.
         
      
      
         I kept telling them I was going to come back but then I never did.
         So.
         OK now another family tragedy.
         
         In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> that drove me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> when I had meningitis with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, she got <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April of 1991</TIMEX> she was diagnosed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> after my niece was born.
      
      
         Now is that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         OK so she had a baby and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week later</TIMEX> she is diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer</ENAMEX> of the what?
      
      
         She had lymphoma.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         It was throughout her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.
         And the way it happened was she her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> went numb.
         They were examining her and trying to figure why her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> went numb.
         And what they figured out was that it was a tumor so the tumor was pressing against a nerve, which made her arm numb.
      
      
         Oh.
         OK.
      
      
         So but then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX> she died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'92</NUMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And so those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> before she died was like, you know.
         The whole time was a terrible time.
      
      
         ( ) So as soon as diagnosed it did they pretty much say that "there was not much we can do because it is all over her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>".
      
      
         No.
         She went through chemo she went through everything she went through chemo, ah, radiation.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah you know she fought it the whole time.
         She never thought she was going to die.
      
      
         OK good, good.
      
      
         She never had that idea in her mind I mean like right up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month or two</TIMEX> before she, uh, passed away she was doing math homework, I was helping her with math homework.
         Yeah, she never thought, she never gave up.
      
      
         She was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Right, basically.
         That's how you can say it.
         She never gave up and, you know, she went through all the treatments, and then, well, then a funny thing relates to that story like, well then the whole story is not funny.
         
         But we had, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks</TIMEX> before, we wound up, going to the hospital a lot, we knew her time was short.
         And then, every time I wound up driving into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, you know, we lived on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Staten Island</ENAMEX>, so I was driving into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, and every time I would park on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, I would get a parking ticket.
         It was like a guarantee.
         I should have learned.
         I should have just parked in the parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>, but the parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garages</ENAMEX> were like anywhere from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14 to $24</NUMEX> a day.
      
      
         How much is a parking ticket?
      
      
         Well I think that a parking ticket at the time was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">maybe $25</NUMEX> or something like that.
      
      
         So it wasn't that much difference.
      
      
         It wasn't that much difference.
         But it could have been, I mean, some of them were like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> I think.
         But this is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> parking and, I mean, if you went a minute over you had a ticket.
      
      
         You mean there was someone there waiting for it to go a minute over.
      
      
         Yeah it was like magic.
         Yeah this is how efficient the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were that were giving the tickets out were, uh, so that was fun.
         You know driving into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> getting a ticket.
      
      
         How was it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to see, just to know that the end is near.
         I mean because you all live there together in the same basic area right?
      
      
         Right we all, most of us live on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Staten Island</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives, my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>.
         She was living at the same place at the time, uh, you know, it was sad of course it was also, you know, it was a binding experience my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> did become closer after that, you know, because you know united in tragedy I guess you could say.
      
      
         Sure.
      
      
         Ah.
      
      
         Did different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to handle it differently?
         How?
      
      
         Oh yes, definitely a wide range of reactions, you know.
         You know, you know, one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> was real upset, you know, ah most of us were pretty mellow like, you know, we weren't really, at the time, we weren't really outwardly trying, you know, we really didn't show a lot of upsetness.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         Because everybody was trying to show--
      
      
         Trying to help her out.
      
      
         Right and help everybody else out.
      
      
         How long, I mean did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> just come and say she has got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six weeks</TIMEX> left or one of those kinds of things did, did you know?
         JG: Yes, yes.
      
      
         Pretty much.
      
      
         Well they said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> they said that she had, she had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three months</TIMEX> which would be like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> towards <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of July</TIMEX>, I think.
         But it, uh, turns out she died right in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of June</TIMEX> so she actually died before the time that they gave her.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         They gave her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>, but she only lived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX>.
      
      
         Did she know that?
         Did they tell her directly?
      
      
         Yeah I think they did, um.
      
      
         I just can't imagine someone saying you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> to live.
      
      
         Well you know, I don't think, did I don't think they did tell her that.
         They told my brother-in-law, you know, whom we are still very close to.
      
      
         Oh that was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Right, yeah.
         He is living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> now with my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nieces, you know, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is still very close to them.
         You know I consider him you know just as close as any of any of my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Sure.
      
      
         My in-laws or whatever.
      
      
         Sure.
      
      
         You know, there was never any, like severance of relations, you know what I mean?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, you know, because of that.
         Anyway so him and my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nieces</ENAMEX> still live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         How old are the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> now?
      
      
         They're, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         Well one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>, no, well she is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and the other one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>.
      
      
         So she never knew her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Well she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year old</TIMEX> when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> died.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months old</TIMEX> so she really didn't, no she never really go that close to her.
         She only saw her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> that time you know during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>.
         So she was, you know, like we kept her at my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> a lot.
         And my other niece she stayed at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father in-law</ENAMEX>'s family a lot.
         Ah, let's see.
         Another funny story was related to that my other niece, the older niece, she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> at the time she still had her pacifier and everything.
         I got to share a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with her this is fun she was a cute as a button.
         But, uh, she would wake up at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> sometimes going, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mimi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mimi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mimi</ENAMEX>."
      
      
         Now is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         No, she had a pacifier she called, ah, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mimi</ENAMEX>."
         So her pacifier would fall out of her mouth at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> so she would just wake up.
         It would be right next to her she wouldn't just grab it a stick it in her mouth she would go "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mimi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mimi</ENAMEX>."
         So I had to get up a put the pacifier in her mouth it was really cute.
      
      
         
         Just so she would go back to sleep.
         
         That is really funny.
      
      
         It was really sweet.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I can't imagine having to tell a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year-old</TIMEX> that mommy has gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         Or whatever.
      
      
         Right.
         Well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> had that pleasure.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         But, you know, I mean she was upset, but she wasn't, well she was upset.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         But I don't know if it totally hit her, you know what I mean?
      
      
         If she had been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five or six</TIMEX> it probably would have been very different.
      
      
         Right.
         But she would go through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stages</ENAMEX> where she would be upset, you know, like she would realize, I mean she realized what happened, and, of course now she is really aware.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         But at the time, I guess, you know, I guess she would forget, you know, and sometimes she would remember.
      
      
         OK, I see, interesting.
      
      
         I guess, you know, but.
      
      
         Well I think we have got enough.
         Thanks a lot.
      
   
