
   
   
      
         Just start talking.
         Go!
      
      
         OK, um, let's see.
         I remember when I was probably around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>, somewhere in there, we used to play outside a lot.
         We used to play kickball a lot.
         We had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of us that would get together and play <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kickball</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> until it got dark, so dark that we couldn't see, and then we rode our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX>.
         And back then, it was colder in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> area than it is now, and we would have snow at least once or twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and it wasn't unusual to get a foot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>.
         And we all had ice skates, so we would ice skate up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>; I remember doing that.
         We missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least two weeks</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> for snow and we always had heavy coats and mittens, stuff that you don't have now here.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>!
      
      
         Yeah!
         And the only place, there were no skating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rinks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         The only place that you, there were no roller skating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rinks</ENAMEX> at all.
         The only place that you could go ice-skating was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Coliseum</ENAMEX>.
         And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> we would have hockey games and during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> they would, you know, redo the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and then you could ice skate.
         So that's what we did during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>.
         And, let's see, I used to climb <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.
         Once I climbed a tree, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pine tree</ENAMEX>, and I got to the top and it started swaying.
         And I was afraid, and I couldn't come down, and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> had to get this really high ladder and come up it and get me down.
         You know about that don't you?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         
         Been there, done that!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, let's see, there was, uh, obviously, no VCRs or any of that.
         I remember when color, we had a little black and white TV; that's all anybody had.
         And I remember when color TV came out and I was so excited!
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> finally bought a color television and the first thing that we watched in color was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonanza</ENAMEX>.
         And I was madly in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Joe</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And I remember running around outside being really, really hot thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonanza</ENAMEX> would come on at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>.
         And we'd come running back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to watch it and we'd be all hot and sweaty and dirty and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would make us sit on the floor and we'd sit there watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonanza</ENAMEX>.
         And let's see, and the other thing that I remember that was my favorite movie was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX>.
         That was my very favorite movie.
         And then let's see, movies, very different from now.
         The only theatres that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manor Theatre on Providence Road</ENAMEX> and what was called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carolina Theatre</ENAMEX> up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
         That was the only places to go to the movies.
         There were no shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we would ride the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>; a big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">treat</ENAMEX> was to ride the bus uptown to go shopping at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivy's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belk's</ENAMEX>.
         And for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> they had these elaborate window displays and we would ride the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> uptown on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> to look at all the, and walk all through uptown to look at the window displays with all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">decorations</ENAMEX>.
         That was the big entertainment.
         I remember when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> Place <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> was built, that was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>.
         Everyone was excited about that.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we used to go shopping there.
         When I was your age, I worked uptown and, um, there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wachovia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and all the rest of it were parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX>.
         So it's, it's changed a little bit.
         
         I can't think of anything else to talk about
         .
         We didn't, um, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 50s and 60s</TIMEX>, they didn't have the big orange school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX>, and we either walked to school, because everything was neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, so in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> we always walked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         And there was like a thing where we'd cut through the woods.
         That's to tell how different it was.
         It was totally safe; you never locked your doors.
         We cut through the woods walking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and then when I got in junior high, we started riding city <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         I'm not sure how that worked or how the route worked, I just remember doing it.
         And we had sock hops on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX>.
         Once a month we'd have a sock hop and we'd walk to that
         , or we'd thumb.
         And the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I ever went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX> I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 years old</TIMEX> and it was, we went with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine.
         Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were renting a place and she and I and another one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriends</ENAMEX> went.
         And we would go up and down the main drag there at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pavilion</ENAMEX> is and we would thumb up and down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the</NUMEX>, and we would just hop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and ride up and down and yell and wave to everybody and then we'd get tired of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and we'd hop and go hop out and hop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with some more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.
         
         It was totally safe!
         You never worried about it!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, then all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> stuff started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 60s</TIMEX> and that was during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.
         When I was in, uh, junior high and high school there was big letter writing campaign to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> I was in high school with got drafted.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, hmm, I'm running out of things to say again
         .
         I was dating a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> beside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> would see me going up there to visit him or see us going out and stuff.
         And then, um, a neighbor that lived across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from me, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jump Club</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> was "jumping" then, and she had a cookout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>, invited some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over, and I went over there and, um, I think I was the youngest one there.
         They were all going out to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> or something and I wasn't old enough to get in, but I went with the rest of them.
         I think I was kind of at the end of the line and I snuck in anyway and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> thought I was really cute.
         And then he got home and I don't know how he got my phone number.
         He got it from somebody and called me.
         And I wasn't really dating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that seriously, so I decided to go out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>.
         So I went out with him.
         Then I was dating this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.
         And then one of my girlfriends that was living with me at the time, we worked together at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Union</ENAMEX>, she bet me that I couldn't date a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 weeks</TIMEX>, so I did that.
         
         I thought you'd get a kick out of that one.
         I used to be cute!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> and I dated, I guess, not quite a year, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about nine months</TIMEX> or so, and then we decided to get married and then he took it back, and then we decided to get married and then he took it back, and then we decided to get married and then he took it back again!
         What else?
         Hmm
         .
         Ask me a question.
      
      
         So did you get married?
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 years ago</TIMEX>!
         
      
      
         Obviously!
      
      
         Yeah.
         There were no, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> so if you wanted to go out, like to listen to music and dance, there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> places to go.
         So most everything, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment complexes</ENAMEX> would have parties.
         Like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> there would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the clubhouses of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment complexes</ENAMEX> and that was pretty much where you would go to dance and just hang out with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, things escape me!
         
         Oh!
         When I was in high school the big excitement was cruising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoney's</ENAMEX>.
         There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoney's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and you would ride from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, it was like a big circle, and you would ride from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to the other and everybody would hang out there because it was a drive-in then, so all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were parked outside.
         And you could cruise through to see who was there and if it wasn't any cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> there or anybody you liked then you would cruise to the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         They were spread out around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> so it would take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> to drive between all of them.
         And they had the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoney's Big Boy</ENAMEX> was always sitting out front.
         And that was the big thing for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, was to steal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shoney's Big Boy</ENAMEX> and try to get it on top of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and go riding down the road with it on top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, once when I was in high school, I spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and we snuck out and pushed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s brand new Camero out of the driveway and halfway down the road then we started it.
         And then we went cruising and we had an egg fight with some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> riding down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence Blvd</ENAMEX>.
         We were leaning out the windows throwing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> at each other and everywhere the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> hit it knocked the paint off her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         So we had to get jobs and earn the money to repaint the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         
         I was a little wild.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Family things.
         All my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> so we went there several times a year to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunts</ENAMEX>' and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>'.
         I had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> that were my age.
         And I spent a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX>, I spent like a whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month in the summer</TIMEX> there with them.
         We, this was at the beach, and we'd go to the beach during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and the movies or stuff at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would come up here.
         The most traumatic thing, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> decided to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> when I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">10th</NUMEX> grade so, and he literally built the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and when we moved into it there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet rock</ENAMEX> on the inside and the plumbing wasn't hooked up yet.
         So we had a garden hose coming in through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> window for our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the sink in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>.
         We had one toilet in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that was flushable but since there wasn't any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sheet rock</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> we hung these big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> blankets to the studs, nailed those to the studs for privacy.
         And all my aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> came up to help move in and work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         So we had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> when it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> of us staying there with one toilet, the hose going in through the kitchen
         and piles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> and then the porch wasn't finished and we had boards going up to the porch so you had to walk up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> to get in.
         So I had my dates pick me up at somebody else's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> because I was embarrassed for them to come my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         
         But I know how to put sheet rock up and do shingles and all of that.
         That's the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are still in.
      
      
         Really?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Neat!
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> built the whole thing!
      
      
         Wow.
         Well, did you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> ever play together?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I didn't like each other growing up; we fought all the time.
         We weren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> until we were in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20s</TIMEX>.
         There's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and half years</TIMEX> difference in our age.
         That's a big difference.
         She was my bratty little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid sister</ENAMEX> that got in the way and tattled on me.
         I remember when we were both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>, she would sneak in and take my clothes and we would fight over that.
         But then once we got, we lived together for a while before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> and I got married.
         So once we were grown, we were very close.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't have much money.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Douglas Aircraft</ENAMEX> and then they closed up and they didn't want to move so they stayed here and he had, it took him a while before he found jobs.
         He had a gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>, he tried several different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, and he had a gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>.
         He had that on the porch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and I used to sit out there and help him load <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun shells</ENAMEX> and we used to go target shooting and stuff.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so we just didn't have much money.
         When I was in junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>, the big thing was, um, alpaca sweaters, A-line skirts, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pappagalo</ENAMEX> shoes.
         So I had a little part time job.
         So that all I could afford to do was get the shoes and the sweaters and I made all my skirts and made my blouses.
         And the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I ever, we, we camped, we would go to the mountains and go camping that was the only thing we did as far as a vacation.
         Never flew; I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years old</TIMEX> before I'd ever flown on a airplane.
         I was a teenager before I ever went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, there weren't many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.
         We just didn't eat out.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> worked.
         So when she got home I was responsible for doing the cooking and having all that done when she got home from work.
         We just didn't, the big thing was to go to a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dino's Pizzas</ENAMEX> and get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, is that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 minutes</TIMEX>?
      
   
