
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Tom</ENAMEX>.
         What is your last name?
      
      
         My last name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>.
         Well, actually my whole name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas R. Goedeke</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Ah, OK!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> I'll be asking you some questions and this will be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         What stories do you remember family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> telling you when you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha</ENAMEX>!
         How about a ghost story?
      
      
         Oh!
      
      
         When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> dies in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> they're supposed to visit all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> that are alive.
         And that was, that was a story that we used to hear.
         Of course when my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">99 years old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> died, she didn't visit anybody.
         
      
      
         Who used to tell you this?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         I was kind of disappointed that she didn't remember to visit me after she passed away.
      
      
         Do you remember usually in what places she used to tell you?
         Like at home or special occasions?
      
      
         No.
         Just uh, when uh, I don't know, when, when we talked about family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
         But, but as I recall, I never asked her if she'd ever had a, maybe she did, she did tell me that someone got on the end of her bed when she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and it was a departed family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>.
         It kind of,
         it scared her, but at the same time she knew whoever it was had uh, passed away.
         
         How about that?
      
      
         And it never happened to you?
      
      
         No.
         Is that wild?
      
      
         Yeah, wild.
         Do you tell that to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         No, no I haven't so far I haven't.
         
         Yeah, I might have told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Uh huh.
         And, and do you remember your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?
         How it looked?
         How it was?
      
      
         When I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>?
         Oh sure, very much.
         But I didn't grow up around here.
         I grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And your grandma was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> too?
      
      
         Yeah, she was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, and she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that was not far from our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and it was just a little old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and you know, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> grew up there, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>, my aunts.
         And I remember stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX>, how they had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> in the backyard.
         They had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">grape arbor</ENAMEX>, where the grapes grow, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to this day hates having <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grape</ENAMEX> anything.
         Because in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> they had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX>.
         You know, grape jelly, grapes this, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> that, lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX>.
         So.
         --
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>!
         That is interesting.
         What about stories from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>?
         From your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         From my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>?
         He talks about being in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> and they were very poor, and they had to get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX>.
         
         They had to uh, heat their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and there was a place where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> had to slow down on this hill as they climbed with, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would get on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> with big sacks, big heavy sacks called burlap sacks and they would steal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, put it in these big bags, throw the bags off jump off before the train got rolling fast again to go down the hill.
         And that's how they kept warm in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX>, and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> were very severe.
      
      
         Do you remember how old your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was?
      
      
         He said uh, you know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX>,
         you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>, just young.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         What about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> talks uh, tells stories about picking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> and she used to pick <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> a bushel and a bushel is a big basket and they would,
         she'd work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>.
         Maybe it was, no, I think it was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> picking these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> and they got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> for it.
         This may or may not be true.
         It,
         maybe it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX>, it was a very small amount of money.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Beans</ENAMEX> are a pain to pick.
      
      
         When she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah, when she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>.
         Sure.
      
      
         And where?
         In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> too.
         They're both from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Wonderful.
         What about reading?
         Do you remember something about reading?
      
      
         I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welsh</ENAMEX> trying to teach me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welsh</ENAMEX> and she would sing nursery songs to me and tell me little poems in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Welsh</ENAMEX>.
         I've never forgiven her for it.
         
      
      
         And why?
      
      
         It is a very difficult language.
         It's got clicks and it just doesn't sound like anything that is even, that we are even familiar with.
         Like a <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Romance language</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.
         This is stuff that's totally, "whoo," over the mountain and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welsh</ENAMEX> is a dead language.
      
      
         And do you remember anything?
      
      
         Oh yeah, I remember the sounds of it.
         Like "orrorrrrr" kind of like "rorrrroruh," click, and she'd click and say funny things with the clicking sound.
         The clicking was fascinating, how she can talk and click at the same time was fascinating and then she wore dentures too and that made it even more fantastic.
         
      
      
         But um, favorite books when you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         My favorite books?
         Oh, I always liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kon-Tiki by Thor Heyerdahl</ENAMEX> and he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> and he demonstrated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polynesians</ENAMEX> could weave basket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> together and travel all around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> and to me that was fab, fabulous.
      
      
         So, you read those books.
      
      
         Oh Yeah.
         And I still have them.
         I actually looked at them once in a while and reminisce, you know, an unfulfilled dream.
      
      
         Wonderful.
         Thank you very much.
      
      
         Is that it?
      
      
         Yeah.
         You want to add something else?
      
      
         No, I guess that's about it.
      
      
         OK.
         Thank you very much.
      
   
