
   
   
      
         My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Goodroe</ENAMEX> and the accent you hear is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Georgian</ENAMEX>, where I was raised, even though I was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>.
         And the story I want to share is based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX>.
         There's a lot talking about it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.
         I was an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eleven-year-old</TIMEX> when, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>, and I remember very clearly, um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that I walked out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday School</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, and walked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, a big, open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">atrium</ENAMEX> there and a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, and saw grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> slapping their fist clenched fist in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX> of their hands, and I remember clearly the jaws that were clenched and the anger that was there in their faces.
         And then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were crying, standing around weeping.
         And, of course, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juniors</ENAMEX>, which I was in the junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, started saying, "What's happened?
         What's happened?"
         And then they said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> had been attacked.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, uh, had been sunk and that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, many, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had been killed.
         And so, of course, I joined the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juniors</ENAMEX> crying as well.
         It made a huge impression on me and was a big thing.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Benning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, where the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry school</ENAMEX> in the world at that time was there, and as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> walking to school, and believe it or not, I did walk <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> to school and I would go up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown Avenue</ENAMEX>, which was at that time the only <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that would allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convoys</ENAMEX> to come through.
         And I would walk along the road to school and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convoys</ENAMEX> of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> would, uh, ride by in the backs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and I would wave at them and it was not a sexual thing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>.
         It was just a friendly thing that these were young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that were going off to war all of them, most of them, well all of them enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or draftees.
         I can remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time specifically that, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom home</ENAMEX> with one bath.
         Had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and we each had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> began to knock on our front door and asking if we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to rent.
         And every place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> at the time was full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         I mean there was no, no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> to rent.
         We had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> in the back yard and had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> that we raised.
         We backed up to a pecan <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grove</ENAMEX>.
         And, oh I don't know how many, I don't just want to estimate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> would ring the doorbell and ask if we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to rent and we would, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> would, say no.
         And finally this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Duffind</ENAMEX>, who came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Erie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX>, and they knocked on the door and he was a lieutenant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX> and headed for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.
         And they said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, if you would just let us uh, uh stay in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>," and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> answered and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, it has a dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX>."
         And they said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, we don't care we don't mind that.
         We'll just bring us some cots from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and we'll go to the, uh, service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>," which was several blocks away.
         There was not an open place, a service station <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very corner in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>.
         We called them filling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> instead of service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, uh, no I just can't imagine you staying in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>."
         Said, "It's drafty and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> you would be cold," and I think it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of the year</TIMEX>.
         And they looked so forlorn that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, come in and we'll talk about it."
         So I moved in at that juncture with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.
         We moved the twin beds back there and moved his bed up in the front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and for, until that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>, the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> went off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> we didn't know whether he'd ever see his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> again, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>.
         And we just became very, very close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and loved them dearly.
         And, uh, he did go off to war and did come back and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> after that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly every year</TIMEX> they would come down to see us in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Erie</ENAMEX>.
         In fact, when he came back, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time he gave me a beautiful large pearl, perfect pearl and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX>, when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, I had, took some of the money that I got from his inheritance and, uh, bought a heart and placed that pearl in the center of the heart and now wear it; one of my treasured possessions.
         That's just kind of a little aside from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the war days</TIMEX>.
         But I can remember at that time that we'd go out to have uh we played softball and I happened to be, when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years old</TIMEX> I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> in high school.
         In fact, uh, I had skipped a grade in grammar school is why I was so young to go off to high school.
         When all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> ask me, uh tell me how smart I was to skip a grade.
         Then I have to admit that the grade I skipped was kindergarten
      because I was taller than the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and so that's, we only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> grades in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> and so I graduated when I just turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> which was entirely too young but I'm getting ahead of myself a little bit.
         We played softball at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> in high school and I remember very clearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> somebody said uh, "There's an airplane," and we all stopped.
         The game stopped, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> stopped and we all looked up in the sky and tried to find where the airplane was.
         And it just shows how much our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> has changed because there were so few <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> falling passing over in the sky at that time that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at high school would stop and look for it to see if they could find it.
         And finally, uh, we could see it just very vaguely.
         In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> it wasn't up wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> didn't have the jet stream.
         Uh I also remember other things that happened during that time of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> I remember sitting at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the feet</NUMEX> of my, the radio.
         We had a nice sized one that sat on the floor and listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>, uh, give his famous speech of a day that will live in infamy and us sitting in total silence, uh, as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> listening to it.
         I also remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warm Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX> was not very far from where I lived and that's where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> would come as uh, uh, when he had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> when he was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I think.
         At any rate he would come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warm Springs</ENAMEX> and he'd come through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>.
         And at the time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> I was, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and I came out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
         We rode the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> because we only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> moved when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX> to, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus</ENAMEX>.
         He moved, he was making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and I remember as a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> I had my tonsils out of all things at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> saved <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and at the time that I had my tonsils out she had saved <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> and that's what it cost to get them out at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a week.
         And I'll let you figure up how long that took to save <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>.
         But back again to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the war years</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we came out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and I was just standing on the corner and along came <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with no roof on it no top on it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, well he was driving.
         It was equipped for a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">polio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to drive and he was driving.
         There was someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with him and I don't remember anything about that.
         But I do remember that we stood and watched him go by and waved at him.
         I don't remember whether he waved back or not so I did get to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> himself and in person so that was a big thrill for me as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, there are so many things I remember about those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
         I had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buster</ENAMEX> was sent to, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle of Guadalcanal</ENAMEX> and all of the big, he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">infantry</ENAMEX> and in all of the big battles over there from island hopping.
         And I, one of the regrets that I have in my life, now that I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 71</TIMEX>, is the fact that I threw away his V mail.
         That was, he just wrote beautiful letters and he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only about six years</TIMEX> older than I was, maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, so I corresponded with him and wrote him very faithfully a couple of times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and I wish I had kept his letters because they were so graphic descriptions.
         I do regret getting rid of them.
         I also had another young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that wrote gorgeous letters and beautiful letters, and was in a lot of the fighting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>.
         So we also had letters from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duffinds</ENAMEX> that I mentioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>.
         I wish I'd kept them.
         Another experience that I remember very clearly was riding on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> from, we were going down to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bradenton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palmetto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX> actually below <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa</ENAMEX>.
         And we would go down there and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month or six weeks every summer</TIMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and we had to change <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jacksonville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> would drive me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>, drive us to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX> to catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and it would be full of enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> heading off to the war.
         And sometimes they would be standing up in the train trying to get leave before they went overseas and there I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 or 12 years old</TIMEX> and, uh, I can remember very clearly the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s face that taught me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> new games of solitaire that I still teach my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> how to play now and still play myself sporadically and remember that time.
         I also remember how gracious they were and there was no cursing and no ugly language and they were very gracious to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who was traveling with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years later</TIMEX> when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> myself and had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> I decided I would rego that route and I actually caught a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palmetto</ENAMEX> to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> who were dead then but to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, and, uh, I saw how hard it was for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to travel on a train.
         I had a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> had a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and-a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>.
         And I can remember that I had one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> boxes of disposal diapers and I stood up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> in the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">restroom</ENAMEX> and take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX> and change her diaper and she went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and it all came down my dress and down her leg and puddled on the floor.
         And so much for disposable diapers.
         I never tried them again.
         But I can see now how they have become a boom to motherhood.
         We now have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them has gone to be with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> at age <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>.
         We have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandchildren</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I have been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51years</TIMEX>.
         We've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August of 1998</TIMEX> and we came here to live, uh, near our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> who live here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>.
         And there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last little thing.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> we're picking up all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> and we're all going out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:30 a.m.</TIMEX>
         to watch the meteor shower.
         It's going to be an adventure and then we'll go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> for breakfast.
      
      
         That's good.
         Thank you.
      
   
