
   
   
      
         This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Gubbins</ENAMEX>.
         She grew up near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Coliseum</ENAMEX>, and she has some interesting stories to tell about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And with no further ado
         .
         I grew up on a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-acre</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, which is hard to believe, now near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, which was not nearly as intrusive as it is now, because this was backing up to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s, who came down here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>, looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> way of life, to get away from all that snow.
         They bought this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> off of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilmont Road</ENAMEX>, I think it's still <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wilmont Road</ENAMEX>, anyhow it's near the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Coliseum</ENAMEX> on Tyvola
         and proceeded to turn it into a working <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX>, at least that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>'s ambition.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> helped them build the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story white stucco with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> furnace in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, or so the family history goes.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> met, shortly thereafter, and married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May of 1938</TIMEX>, I think, because I came along <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years later</TIMEX>, and grew up with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> there, to kind of, well, I remember when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years old</TIMEX> and we had settled down for the long haul on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> finished traveling around and taking us with him to various uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> assignments out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and, oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX>.
         He was in the Reserves.
         So we were kind of back and forth.
         But, I think, about the time I started <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade he stopped traveling, and my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>, who ruled everyone with an iron hand, had been living in what we called "the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">big house</ENAMEX>."
         
         I'm, I'm going on too much.
         But, anyhow, moved her over to the cottage so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> could have a little life of their own, and the little cottage was right across one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> from us and her other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> lived in a little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down from the cottage.
         So it was like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borden</ENAMEX> compound
         .
         When I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade, uh, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings</ENAMEX> ran out, pretty much, so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> told, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was being a gentleman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>.
         During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these years</TIMEX> we raised <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Angus cattle</ENAMEX> and ate very well, with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> from the garden, but we didn't have any money.
         So my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> came to live with us to take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> both found jobs in town.
         And the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> had nothing in common but each one really gave me quite a gift.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandmother Tina</ENAMEX> had traveled, uh, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> herself and had a real interest in adventure in other cultures, uh, the out-of-doors and I remember when I was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> she would take me by the hand and say, "Where would you like to go for a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">walk?</ENAMEX>"
         and I'd point and we'd go, off in that direction--
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         Across the fields and through the woods and over streams and I think what it did was wet my appetite for exploring new places.
         And she was so sweet to me.
         The other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> probably had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighth</NUMEX>-grade education but a fabulous mind for invention because she came up with these stories.
         When I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was pregnant with my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, they sent me to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> toward the end of her pregnancy.
         And that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was staying with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX> while he was getting, uh, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PhD</ENAMEX>, and I would be homesick and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, we called her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, her name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millie Frances</ENAMEX>, would make up these stories about this great white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snowy owl</ENAMEX> that would carry me home to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh, how neat.
      
      
         Of course if I thought about it now, I'd think of him carrying me home in his big claws
         but for a child it was very comforting.
         And then she came to live with us probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX> more later, while I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade so it would have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years later</TIMEX>, and she loved gardening and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>.
         And I think I got some of that from her because I still, whenever I'm out in the yard gardening I think about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.
         And when I'm traveling I sometimes think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> and how much she would have enjoyed it.
      
      
         Well, that's a neat mix.
      
      
         Yeah.
         So--
      
      
         Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> ever tell you stories about her travels?
      
      
         She didn't.
         Mostly she told me stories about all the things I would inherit from her once she was gone
         .
      
      
         Did you?
      
      
         I did.
         She, she collected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> furniture and rugs, and that sort of thing, while they were based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>, and she took great pride in them.
         Pride of possession, I suppose, but also loved the thought that it would pass on to me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>.
         And I still have those things in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         I have, for a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working journalist</ENAMEX>, I have really nice furniture
         , thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>.
         And back then she bought them really cheaply because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> was a free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">port</ENAMEX>, and she would get these really nice wooden, carved things from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 dollars</NUMEX>--
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         That, I don't know what they'd be worth now, but I have rosewood screens that are hand-carved, that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 15 years ago</TIMEX> were valued at something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1,800 dollars</NUMEX> apiece.
         JM: Wow.
      
      
         And the rugs are out of style but, and they're rolled up underneath our beds, for the most part.
         But it's still a nice reminder of her.
         At first I kind of resented having to take all this stuff because it meant I could never decorate the way I wanted to decorate, but I got over that, and realized you can have an eclectic mix of stuff.
         And it's nice to have some good pieces of furniture that have that history attached to them.
         And the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> had nothing really of her own to leave us, except a rocking chair that I think was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s.
         It's not real comfortable, but it has a place of honor in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Hum.
         That's neat.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, did they both live with you until they died?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granny</ENAMEX> did.
         She got senile, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> before she died and I had graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was taking care of her and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had died and we kept her at home and under control with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thorazine</ENAMEX>.
         And I remember a terrible time when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had gone to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and had left me, I was there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from, I worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gastonia</ENAMEX> at the time.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, it was a time <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> had missed her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>, and she was getting strange.
         She got real agitated.
         She'd see bugs crawling up the wall.
         And I tried to make her take her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>, and she hit me and I hit her back.
         Not hard, but it just shocked me that I would do such a thing.
      
      
         Probably shocked her too.
      
      
         It shocked her, and she took her pill
         .
         And settled down
         .
         And the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> had a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX>, and my poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, who was widowed,
         was she widowed then?
         No, she was widowed shortly after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> died, uh, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was working and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, I think, was kind of in charge of finding housekeepers to take care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>, who loved nothing better than to order <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around.
         She was hard to get along with, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would quit, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> would rehire them, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> would fire them, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> would rehire them, and she finally wound up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huntersville</ENAMEX>, at what's now the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Huntersville Oak</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         I think.
         And I was in college when she died.
         But she was artistic.
         That's something else I got from her, I forgot.
         Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twenties</TIMEX>, no, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> painted, hand-painted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">china</ENAMEX>.
         It was the thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of leisure to do.
         She was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of leisure but she always fancied being that, so she would get this, this, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">barrels</NUMEX> of fine china and hand-paint them and fire them and initial them.
         She insisted I be named for her so I could inherit her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">monog-</ENAMEX> rammed stuff.
         She was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Petric Borden - Petric</ENAMEX> was short for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petrechek</ENAMEX>.
         She was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czecho</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX>, and that was her maiden name, but it was shortened to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Petric</ENAMEX> when they came over here.
         So she was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Petric Borden</ENAMEX>, and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had no choice in the matter - I had to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn</ENAMEX>.
         Well, she had the choice of the middle name but it had to start with a P and she thought about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penelope</ENAMEX> but luckily settled on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Borden</ENAMEX>.
         So here I have all these monogrammed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linen napkins</ENAMEX> that sit in this, uh, pigskin trunk that was hand-painted by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass clasp</ENAMEX>.
         It's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> too.
         And lots of this hand-painted china--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> and I split up when she died.
         She didn't specify who would get what, and when she died and the time came to settle up stuff, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ok</ENAMEX>, how are you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> going to do this?"
         And so we said, "We'll flip a coin and see who goes first."
         So that's how we did, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> would pick something, and then I would pick something, and then if one of us would pick something the other really wanted we'd work it out and so that was--
      
      
         You <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um huh.</ENAMEX>
         No, uh, she left things to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>.
         Her other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different marriages.
         And I guess they
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>, I don't know how they figured that out because I wasn't around when that was settled, but I know that they, we all got something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX> plus furnishings.
         Stuff.
         They each got stuff I didn't even know about.
         Until recently, when I went up to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX> and she unrolled this wall hanging, this thick rug, that was hand-woven, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> immortals.
         And it's in pristine condition.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> has the matching <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX> has this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX>-type log <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and said, "This rug, it, there's nowhere to put it."
         They had things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stuffed animals</ENAMEX> on their walls.
         Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a big game <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Oh, you mean like stuffed heads of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah, yeah.
      
      
         So what did she do with the rug?
         Did she give it to you?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh huh</ENAMEX>, and now it's under another of my beds at home
         .
         It's really beautiful but maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> I'll have a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wall</ENAMEX> that I can put it on.
         I don't know, sometimes possessions can be a real burden.
      
      
         But that's neat she wanted you to have her stuff, and I mean she--
      
      
         Oh yeah.
      
      
         She planned that.
      
      
         Oh yeah she did.
         But I really got tired of her talking about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when she passed on and I would get all these things.
         I thought of it as kind of emotional blackmail in a way, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> I don't really think it was.
         She was just, she was wanting to establish that connection even after she was gone.
         She really, well, both our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> just were the best you could have.
         They never criticized us, and they spoiled us.
      
      
         That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> are for.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Why did you call her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> though?
         From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> came up with that nickname.
         It has nothing to do with her name.
         She, uh, all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> called her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Kathryn</ENAMEX>, or whatever, but, I guess because she's little or was little, maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> kind of sounded like teeny
         .
         I asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> how she came up with it, and she said she didn't know, it just kind of fit her, and so from then on she was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         Hum.
      
      
         I would never have thought to call her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, she wasn't the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">granny</ENAMEX>" type.
         Whereas my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, who used snuff, and was very, very religious to the point of being a fanatic, uh, was a perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">granny</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> made her <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX> dresses that came down below her calf, and she wore these shoes that are now in vogue, the black--
      
      
         The granny shoes.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granny</ENAMEX> shoes.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton stockings</ENAMEX>.
         And a pretty little apron.
         She always wore an apron.
         She did a lot of cooking for us.
         She made great fried apple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX>.
         Oh.
         And wonderful skillet cornbread.
         Those are the things I most remember about her cooking.
         But it was sad when she started to lose her memory because she would pull up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> out of season.
         She'd still want to garden and things would be coming up and she would think it was time to pull them out.
         You'd have to kind of go behind her and say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whoa</ENAMEX>"
         .
         But she was a, she was a sweetheart, they both were in their own ways.
         And of course you never appreciate them and think to ask them stories--
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         Like, until it's too late.
         Because I know my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cabarrus County</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and she inherited her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX> out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>.
         Poor old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> would come all wrapped up in layers of clothes, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> told me this not long before she died, but she said when she was little she remembered her granny showing up and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> saying, "The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thing I'm going to do is unwrap this cocoon."
         
         She wouldn't have changed her clothes since the last time <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> had seen her probably--
      
      
         Oh no.
      
      
         Well maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>.
         But she had just layers and layers and it was just, I can imagine her just grabbing it and going, "bloop,"
         and throwing all that in the wash pot and getting her cleaned up.
         She was an ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
         She was great big and looked very sour
         , but, uh,
         they all had stories of their own.
         I don't, now, let's see which one was it, I'll tell you this one last story because it's a great story going back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>.
         And it might have been this very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, who, when she was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, this would be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX>,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maryann Joyner</ENAMEX>, uh, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> went off to fight in the war, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> side, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cabarrus County</ENAMEX>.
         And he didn't come back, which left her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> kind of in limbo.
         They presumed dead, the war ended, he never came back, they never learned what happened to him, and so she took up with this, I guess he was a traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> and a mule.
         And she put her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryann</ENAMEX> and her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maryann</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 12</NUMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> at this point, and they took, they moved down, or were going to move down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>.
         But he, what happened?
         I think they both died
         of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">malaria</ENAMEX>, which was pretty prevalent along the coastal area, and left the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on their own.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryann</ENAMEX> took her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> by the hand and they walked back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Wow.
         PG: And were taken in by this old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who was probably, I guess, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>'s, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 50s</TIMEX> maybe, who had a sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and a flock of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         He brought them in, took her in, I guess both of them, with the understanding she would take care of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> died, and he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maryann</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         So, I don't know what the age difference was but it was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 35 years</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         And she had several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> by him.
      
      
         Wow.
         That is an interesting story.
      
      
         Yeah, I tried to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, well I did have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> on tape te lling about it and then I lost the tape
         .
         But there's so many things like that I wish I had known to ask both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX>.
         Because on the other side, of course, they fought with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>
         .
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> or maybe my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, uh, fought in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> and he was captured and went to
         , what's that awful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         I know what you're talking about.
      
      
         That a book was written about--
      
      
         I can't remember the name.
      
      
         But, anyway, he survived it.
         A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't, um, and he walked back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Wow.
      
      
         No, I take that back.
         They were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, and he walked back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charleston</ENAMEX> area to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> after the war, like so many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had to do because there was no other way to get there.
         
         Andersonville!
      
      
         That's it.
      
      
         Yeah.
         That takes it back, the little bits I know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         That's back about as far back as I can go.
         Except for, well, there's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>, who grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> in the central part of the state while it was still <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> territory, and you know, you know the dining table at my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         Have I told you the story about it?
      
      
         No
      
      
         It was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s table, and chairs, and it was the table that she would put all her weekly baking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Monday</TIMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         She was widowed fairly young and had these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         And she took in laundry and raised her family as best she could.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> was like the youngest of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and she was, I guess, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine</TIMEX> when this happened, but they, everybody, I mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> were part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, although they kind of kept to themselves, but they knew what was going on and they would have dealings with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>.
         Well, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>, who was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, got sick with some fever, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was staying up with her night and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and was just exhausted.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>, some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> knew about it, and they said, they said to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, "You go get some sleep.
         We'll take care of your little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>."
         So they brought her some sort of herbal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concoction</ENAMEX> and broke her fever and she got better and they went away.
         And they came back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next Monday</TIMEX>, after the baking was done, and they gathered up the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> corners of the tablecloth and took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">baking</ENAMEX>, out the door, which they figured was their due
         .
      
      
         Without saying a word?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>, you have any idea what year that was
         ?
         Can you trace it back?
      
      
         
         Yeah, it would have been, let's see, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> would have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 20s</TIMEX> at that point, so
         early--
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1885</TIMEX>?
      
      
         Yeah, thereabouts
         .
         It was truly the wild frontier
         .
      
      
         And here you are.
      
      
         And here I am, eating off that table
         .
         Things have calmed down pretty much since then.
      
      
         Well, I don't know, sometimes--
      
   
