
   
   
      
         This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candace Walton</ENAMEX>.
         I'm interviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Hicks</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 24, 1999</TIMEX>, and she is going to tell us a story that she remembers from her childhood.
      
      
         The story I'm about to tell is about this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         Ah, she grew up in a interracial family background.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she had very big dreams of wanting to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she, was, at the time, there was a lot of racial tension that was going on, so she felt like she wouldn't be able to make it.
         She was kind of confused of what background she wanted to u-, what ethnic background she wanted to use, so she decided to use her black heritage, um background.
         And so she moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and she went to school there, she made it through school and she did become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>.
         She later was going through problems because they found out that she was a black ethnic and not white, so they would, she could no longer work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, they had no sufficient reason as to why they wanted to cancel, didn't want her to be, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so they told her she wasn't doing good with her cases, so she decided finally, she left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.
         She got married and she married this, uh, very predominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who's very, very well-off and they moved back to their, her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA.</ENAMEX>
         So she decided that she would go and visit her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> who raised her, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was telling how she told her it would be hard and for her to make it once she let it known that she was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afro</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>.
         So she decided that she would start an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, and I can't remember the name of it, to where, it has something to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Black American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>'s something and, to, she, um, let me see what else.
         She, um, she, um, oh, started this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
         She started the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and I can't remember the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and, um, she helped out a lot of, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that uh, that were black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that were having problems being able to make it in society because of their, their color or their culture background.
         And, um, let's see she didn't she, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> passed away and she, um, after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> passed away, she moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, she did have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and, um, so she moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and she, uh, after she finished helping with this, um, women <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, um, she went back into law practice.
         That's about all I can remember of this story.
         I read this story and it was a very good story and, um, it was just meaningful and touching that how, you know, we as, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> can criticize our own color because of being a little shade lighter or hair is straighter than your hair or whatever.
         But I really enjoyed it and I got a lot of good insight points on it.
      
      
         So it was a book that you read?
      
      
         It, actually it started out as a story that I had to do for a, my senior project, senior exit.
      
      
         Oh!
         So y'all made it up?
      
      
         We made the story up, but actually the story, there was story very similar, um, same name everything.
         Everything was the same except our name wasn't
         in the copyright nowhere but, ah, it was a story an actual truthful story.
      
      
         OK well thank you very much for sharing \\ your story \\ with me.
      
      
         \\ You're welcome <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>.
      
   
