
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Okay</ENAMEX>, this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Martini</ENAMEX>.
         Ah, it's ah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14th</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six o'clock</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and we're here with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Hodges</ENAMEX> and he's going to tell us a story he heard ah when you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, is that right?
      
      
         Yeah, basically when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And how old were you when you heard the story?
      
      
         Umm, I'd say I was in actually <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cub Scouts</ENAMEX> at the time so I guess that would put me about probably about, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or nine</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> that's--
      
      
         So--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Pretty</ENAMEX> long time ago huh?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> So this was this was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX>, um this was late, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1970s</TIMEX> about `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Cool.
         And, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>, ah, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX> and he was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX> and he is, um, he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasian</ENAMEX> male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> who has education of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS</ENAMEX> in international business and um I think we're ready for the story now.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Okay</ENAMEX>, good, um.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         The story actually started out and I heard it first when, when I was growing up as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> but as I mentioned earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cub Scouts</ENAMEX> were actually out camping so it's definitely a story.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         It's a horror story no doubt so you have to picture the setting that it's around.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX>, um, um we were out camping in the back basically in the back of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange County</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Which is the county right next to where I lived.
         He basically they had basically woods outdoors and there were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> there with us but we were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only eight</NUMEX> so we're learning how to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp um</ENAMEX> we actually slept <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> in a tee-pee, uh, uh an original tee-pee that uh were used by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, sort of as a historical artifact.
         So we're getting ready for bed, we've eaten dinner, we're around the campfire, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the property, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dwayne Hobgood</ENAMEX>, I guess I can say his name.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boys</ENAMEX> I've got a story for you.
         ''
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Now picture this.
         There's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six or seven</NUMEX> of us, little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>-years old, this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that's going to be giving a good story.
      
      
         
         Right.
         And we'll take a little break here while we answer the cell phone.
         Do you want to hear or do you want to keep?
         
      
      
         Where was I before we were interrupted?
      
      
         The uh, you were uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobgood</ENAMEX>'s property and.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         A bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are listening and he's got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> I've got a story for you now.
      
      
         "Eh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, I've got a story for you," and we're sitting around the campfire he goes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gentlemen</ENAMEX> let me tell you the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Feathers</ENAMEX>."
         He goes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Feathers</ENAMEX> was," and this time political correctness wasn't.
      
      
         
            Right.
      
      
         Wasn't par for the course wasn't nomenclature.
         He said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boys</ENAMEX> I've got this story about an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> for you.
         His name is, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ah, Two Feathers</ENAMEX>.
         He grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange County</ENAMEX>," or what was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orange County</ENAMEX> it wasn't named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange County</ENAMEX> at the time.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX> and act and he says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Feathers</ENAMEX> was, um, once again was an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> who, uh, lived there back before, before it was settled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>."
         He says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Feathers</ENAMEX> grew up, he hunted he fished bas, basic, the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> life um until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> when he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX> he was out hunting and he was hunting a mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>.
         He came across a mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And um they got into a tussle.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         He stabbed the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> a few times, the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> bit him a few times.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         They struggled back and forth struggled back and forth.
         Finally the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> ripped off his arm his left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And, uh, takes off with it, goes.
         So he doesn't know but he, he doesn't die he survives um and grows old becomes an old, old, an old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> and, um, um, becomes you know one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> but he's always got this one goal is to find that mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> that got his arm and really he doesn't really care that much about the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX> he wants his arm or somebody's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Right.
         
      
      
         So, um, time goes on and, um, he dies but he comes back as a ghost.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and what happens is as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> move in, he actually finds um, because he doesn't want to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, you know, from his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> but he needs an arm so he's spending all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">eternity</ENAMEX> hunting for his arm and, um, as, you know, time comes on and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> start in, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> wakes up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>; he's bleeding; he felt like he doesn't have an arm and he sees this ghost of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an Indian</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         He's got his arm and uh he's trying to put it on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and it didn't fit and it's too short and it didn't look like his arm so he throws it aside and goes on.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, this happens all throughout history and he was telling us how it keeps going on and on.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         And you know as an adult it's not, it's, you know, he, it's a good story but as an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you're worried about your arm.
      
      
         That's right.
         
      
      
         And because he usually catches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but when they're out camping or sleeping.
      
      
         In a tee-pee right.
         
      
      
         In a tee-pee yeah.
         So.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         He tells us his story, he says, you know, "You've got to watch out for your arm.
         Spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>," um, you know, "because if he comes his name's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Feathers</ENAMEX>," but there's a chant, um, in regards to you know to getting him away and it goes something like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Feathers</ENAMEX> be gone I want my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>!
         ''
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX> and there's also other things you can do to deter him.
         You can also, um, in front of your tee-pee you have to stack <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> in a certain manner in order to say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey</ENAMEX> I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX>, I'd like to keep my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>."
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         So he proceeds to have us, um, build the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> and, um, you know, learn the chant, we're chanting, and sends us off to bed.
         Now we all spend the whole night staying awake listening for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Feathers</ENAMEX>.
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Feathers</ENAMEX> is coming, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feathers</ENAMEX> is coming.
         '' He would do that to us in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>.
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Feathers</ENAMEX> is coming."
      
      
         That's terrible.
         
      
      
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, so you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> scared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Feathers</ENAMEX>.
         Now I don't know if this actually applies as a story I heard sort of an embellishment on this story in regards to I give you the details but.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, a good campfire, um.
      
      
         It's a good campfire story, um, so it's, I guess something to start with.
      
      
         Yep that's good.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah, that's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 15 minutes</TIMEX> I'd say.
      
   
