
   
   
      
         Female voice <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">START OF TAPE</ENAMEX> AT <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:00 MINUTES</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDE A</ENAMEX>
      
      
         This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer House</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, some remembrances of growing up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> area.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I'm going to share a few little stories I remember, uh, happened at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX>.
         I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> telling a funny story about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, and they had purchased this huge like little general <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> type thing that had all these, um, boxes and cartons and stuff that you would put together, and, um, it was actually like a little store-front thing.
         Well they lived in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really small</TIMEX>, tiny, little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>.
         And they had spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> with a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of theirs
         , assembling all of these toys and boxes, and, you know, the stickers on the boxes.
         And then, um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> woke up and was sick and my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, measles, and was sick and screaming and crying, and they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> full of all these little boxes and things from this, uh, toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> that had been put up.
         And it was so miserable and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was so crowded and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were so wild that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> by that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> they had taken everything down and boxed everything back up again just to get it out of the way just because they, uh, were so miserable that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had been so sick.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, another time, this was for the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, um, the one that had been sick as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, they bought him, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>, all this um cowboy and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> stuff, and again all this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> was required, and, um, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that had helped put together all the boxes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years earlier</TIMEX> for my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, um, had come over and they had to put all these decals and stickers on everything and then had to individually dress all the different <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>, and, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um cowboys</ENAMEX> and you know the tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and the little itty-bitty tiny holsters that they had to put around the waist of all the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX>, and, uh, then, you know, all the little, um, suits and headdresses and everything that had to go on all the little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and the saddles and all this kind of stuff.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> said they were up till like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> getting all this stuff put together and were just exhausted and about dead.
         And then, um, of course, you know, both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> woke up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five a.m.</TIMEX>
         or something
         , so they just absolutely didn't get any sleep at all.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and it was just another miserable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, I think, because they were so tired.
         And, you know, I think by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> the toys, and, you know, half the little pieces and all this kind of stuff and, um, it was very frustrating, um.
         Then I remember, um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one Christmas</TIMEX> for me, um, I had been begging and begging for like this, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>-head thing that you could, you know, put makeup on and style the hair and all this kind of stuff, and, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> worked, uh, for a textile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
         He was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX>, and he, um, had to travel around to lots of different mills and stuff, and so, um, everywhere he had been he just could not find this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>-head thing, you know, and it was just you know getting closer and closer to the time and he was starting to panic.
         And so finally, you know, some little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that, you know, he had had to go to, um, he found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, um, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
         And so that was my big <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> present well when I put makeup on her, um, it just wouldn't even rub off, I mean it was just like this, you know, permanent stuff that you couldn't even smudge off or wash off even with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.
         It just absolutely would not come off, and so it was like one time and you were done and that was it.
         And I remember being so disappointed and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was just furious.
         I mean he was ready to kill me because I, you know, didn't play with it anymore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the day</TIMEX>.
         And I kept trying to tell him, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>," you know, "The makeup is not coming off."
         You know, "Nothing is smudging off and I can't redo her makeup because it's on there and," you know, "It's not coming off."
         And, oh, he was just furious.
         
         He probably would have sold me to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX> at that point or maybe even the lowest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX> to just get rid of me.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and, um, I remember another time, um, being told about a time when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was up in the mountains.
         We had this place that we would go to and they called it our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>.
         But it was near, um, on the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chimney Rock</ENAMEX>, I think, and it was just off the side of the road and, and where the river was and there was a great big old flat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> that sort of jutted out into the river and, um, we would go up there, you know, occasionally on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and have like a picnic and stuff on the rock.
         And, um, to the side of the rock there was like a little pool where the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> wasn't too swift and you could, um kind of play around.
      
      
         
         Classes, may I have your attention?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and so there was an area that you could swim in, you know, to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side.
         But in front of the rock on, you know, the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of this big rock the river was very swift.
         And I remember them telling me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, um, that my youngest, well not youngest but the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the middle, um, had just, you know, jumped off into this swift- moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">river</ENAMEX>, and, um he was always quite the daredevil, and still is, even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 40s</TIMEX>, um but he just decided he wanted to go swimming in the deep water and he jumped off.
         Well, you know, he immediately was swept down the river.
         And, um, then my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and the rescuer, and so, well, he jumps in.
         So now here's both his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> in the river getting swept down.
         So then, of course, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had to jump in and, uh, fortunately for them, no one was, you know, smashed against another rock or anything like that.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and they he finally caught up with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and got them out.
      
      
         
         Staff, may I have your--?
      
      
         And he caught, uh, he managed to catch both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, and, uh they got to the side of the river, and so, of course, now, you know, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> I think, um, was pregnant with me at the time.
         So here she's standing on this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>, you know, about to burst with a baby and, you know, screaming and crying because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of her family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are getting swept away in this river.
         But they, uh, finally got out and managed to make their way back up to the rock.
         But that was, you know, a very traumatic event.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I remember another time, uh, being told, uh, about a storm that had come up that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had taken, um, my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, and, um, I can't remember if I was with them or not.
         I think I was.
         I think I was around at that time.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> are quite a bit older than me, um, and I think I was young and, um, he had taken us, and I don't know, maybe a few other of the neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was at, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> practice at that time at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, and so he had the rest of us like at a little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> that was down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, all of a sudden one of these, you know, really fast, violent summer storms came up and, um, everybody was just petrified.
         And he said somebody had like, I don't know, a little drum or a stick or something I can't remember.
         So he says, we ended up underneath one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX> and that was the only, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> in this whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> because it was all wide open.
         So we have all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> underneath this big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> and we were marching around the picnic table singing and, you know, marching and letting the thunder kind of be like the cymbals, you know, of a marching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>.
         And just, um, he said he didn't, he didn't have any idea how many laps we did around that table but it was just through the whole storm
         , and we just marched and sang for that whole storm just round and round and round that little table, um, underneath the shelter.
         He said it was the only thing he could think of to keep everybody from crying and screaming and not just absolutely petrified of this storm, um, and I remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other time when I was little, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, as I said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> traveled a lot with his job, and, um, there were also times when he had to travel out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, when I was very young, um, you know, he would be gone maybe, you know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month or two</TIMEX> and then be home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three months</TIMEX> and then be gone again, you know, and so each time, you know, he came home there was a period of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so</TIMEX> that was a real adjustment period for me, you know, because he'd been gone and then coming back.
         And so, I sort of had to, you know, build my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> with him again, you know, each time.
         And we had gone to, um, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
         I don't know if it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K-mart</ENAMEX> or something like that, you know, a big old, you know, store and I was with him it was just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> had insisted that I go with him, you know, to just have sort of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father daughter</ENAMEX> time, I guess.
         And, um, we had gone and he had he was looking at something and he told me he said, "Now stay right here," and, of course, you know, I'm only like three
         or something.
         And, um, so, of course, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year-old</TIMEX> is not going to stay right anywhere and I just kind of, you know, wandered down the aisle looking at something else or I may have turned the corner, I don't remember.
         And, of course, you know, after whatever it was lost interest for me I looked up.
         Well, you know, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> wasn't in sight, and, of course, you know panic hit, you know, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year old</TIMEX> and you know I start crying.
         Well a stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> or somebody found me and took me up to the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, to the desk, and, uh, they were asking what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s name was or what he looked like and I remember saying, "He's just a bald-headed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>."
         
         And so they, over the intercom they had to just say, "Would the bald headed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> who owns a little red- headed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> please come to the service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX>?"
         And so he had to come get me and was just absolutely mortified.
         Here, you know, he had just gotten back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from</TIMEX>, you know, out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and, you know, takes his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> somewhere, and then loses her, and I mean I wouldn't get near him.
         I wouldn't hold his hand, I wouldn't speak to him.
         And I remember getting home, and oh I mean I was just bursting in the door just crying wanting my mama.
         Well she happened to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> at the time taking a bath and I remember just bursting into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> just sobbing and just "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mama, Daddy lost me</ENAMEX>."
      
      
         
            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> everyone.
      
      
         So anyway I remember bursting in on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and just you know sobbing and sobbing.
         And, uh, I mean it was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>
         before I would go anywhere with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> again ever.
         I mean I was just convinced he was going to lose me and every time he would ask me to go somewhere I would be like, "No you're going to lose me again," and, you know, it was just the longest time before I ever trusted him enough to even go anywhere with him.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and, I think that's most of like the little funny stories that I can remember.
         And, um, I hope they amused you.
      
   
