
   
   
      
         Testing, one, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three, four</TIMEX>.
         I'm here with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Jamieson</ENAMEX> he's going to be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> and I'm just making sure this recorder's working good.
         OK we're here with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Jamieson</ENAMEX> he is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> here in the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, project and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean</ENAMEX> is from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX> originally.
         And, uh, how would you describe your, your accent, the way you speak or--
      
      
         To, to well I guess I, I of course I don't think I have an accent.
         Ah, I speak like ah everybody I grew up speaks, so, speaks the same way but, ah, to the extent I have one it's a, would be Midwestern I, I think more generically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> than specifically <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, to me, sound is, is more nasal and more pronounced and sounds like ah sounds surprisingly close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>.
         But I don't think I speak like that however you may prove me wrong.
      
      
         But you're from the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>suburban area.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> Suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> that's right.
      
      
         So that may have something to do with that.
      
      
         Um-hum.
      
      
         And, and how about living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>?
         Do you think that's actually, ah, I mean when, if when, you go back up <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey</ENAMEX> I can tell you're picking up some `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">y'alls</ENAMEX>' or something."
      
      
         I have not heard that to the to the best of my knowledge I have never knowingly used the term "y'all."
      
      
         
         But, ah, maybe, maybe the words are slightly as far as you know.
      
      
         They might be I don't know, ah, you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I hang out with in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> by and large are, are not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I work with and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> tend to be transplants as well.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper business</ENAMEX> recruits nationally and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I work with are from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That's right.
      
      
         And only a minority, I guess, are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> here are, tend to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other places as well and rather than, rather than, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southerners</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotteans</ENAMEX>, so I don't, ah, I'm not although when I'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and when I'm out and about in other places yeah I hear the Southern accent but I don't I think my speech patterns are probably pretty much set at this point and, and I don't think I'm picking anything up.
      
      
         OK, so and we're talking, we're talking about, um, I guess going back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and um your, you want to talk about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> //um on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> Yeah I was.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">// Trying</ENAMEX>, trying to think of a subject to talk about and I I'm, I'm not good at remembering stories.
         I don't remember jokes and I don't remember stories which is, which says something about the way my brain works but I do remember you know hearing about family history and such and, and uh had asked about it since then to, to figure out how everybody, ah, came to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> which is where is where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is from and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> came down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the 60s</TIMEX> when he was working for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>, which is outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> and met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> in at that time and he settled down they settled down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> suburbs and, and spent their whole lives there.
         Ah, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side were born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Cork</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>.
         They both immigrated well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> immigrated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> I believe and then made her way up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> where I believe she worked as a domestic.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> ran away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> as a very young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and became a sailor and sailed back and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>.
         I know that much and I don't know where all else he sailed but, ah, eventually got tired of that and left his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and, and was spending, was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and this was I guess about the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWI</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Do you think he was fishing or was he doing.
      
      
         He was working he was doing some sort of work.
         I don't know exactly what, this is, this is a little bit, ah, hazy.
         I don't know if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s, if I've ever, if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s told me that I don't recall exactly what it was and then, my, so my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> I believe in an immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Army</ENAMEX> was recruiting from among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> because I believe at the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> did not, uh, did not draft, did not draft during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWI</ENAMEX>, and try need, but they needed to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and so the they decided that a good place to recruit would be among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant communities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, particularly among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had immigrated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Isles</ENAMEX>.
         And the promise was that if you made it through the war you would have a shot at some, ah, you know, there would be money for you at the end, ah, you'd be able to settle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>.
         And so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit</ENAMEX>, and joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, fought in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, was wounded, and eventually made his way back to, I guess, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and then up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> where he met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         I don't know the exact sequence of events here but he met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and then moved to, to, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario Canada</ENAMEX> where- -
      
      
         He had a farm waiting for him right?
      
      
         Where he had a, where he became, tried to become, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> and this was an area <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 60 miles</NUMEX> southwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> in what at the time must have been a pretty remote part of part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>.
         Turns out he was not very successful as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> and gave that up and moved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX> which was a decent sized a free standing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> outside of, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> but much smaller than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> and build a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> there and became, did a variety of jobs ah I don't believe I don't know if he had a particular trade other than being a sailor so he worked in a variety of jobs.
         I know during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> he worked as a, as a night <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchman</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> and he was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> talked about how he, how my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> felt very fortunate that he didn't lose his job during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>, that at least he was able to keep a job all through the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> working as a night <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchman</ENAMEX>, and they built a house which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> owns as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
         In fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> who just died within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last month</TIMEX> was living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> built when they first moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX> very old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>-framed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> and at the time this wasn't a big deal but now it is, there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a hundred yards</NUMEX> of, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> yard wide strip of forest behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and then behind that is a private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country club</ENAMEX>, and a very nice <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and so the land the land has become very valuable.
         At the time obviously it wasn't a big deal to live on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and now it is, so that, that property is still in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, um, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> my I used to go, we used to go up there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> for family reunions we would ah drive from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit</ENAMEX> up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         To the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         To the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> had had built and, uh, attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and I guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of them married and everybody had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that my aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> had varied I guess from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three to six</NUMEX>.
         So there was a pretty good, good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> at the reunions.
      
      
         
            .
      
      
         Typically <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 75 to 80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at each at each reunion which is held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>.
      
      
         You ever count how many <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> you have.
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I'm not sure I know.
         Somebody has these numbers but I'm not sure, but, ah, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> were so, ah, spread out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> they're at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years at least 20 years</TIMEX> from the oldest to the youngest so my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> had married fairly young he had fought in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX> and he was married during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX> and I believe he and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> had their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>, and that, that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> of mine named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>, who I, oh, when I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> met him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> I thought they were my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> but when I got older I realized that they're actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first cousins</ENAMEX> they were just old enough to be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and so it seemed to me like they were too old to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I associated with being my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> were my age or relatively close to my age, uh, and they were a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but these other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were like, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' age and hanging out with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> at the reunion and you know drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> under the tent and shooting the crap, and I just thought they were my
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, but they were actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>, uh, and that was because--
      
      
         It's like their, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> beared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> other--
      
      
         Yeah, exactly, exactly.
      
      
         Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s probably, ah, oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Right that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so there was, and then, then there would be different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would show up at different reunions so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> there would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there who I didn't know and then I would, we're fairly close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> but I didn't know who they were and so I would always have to be asking or would kind of wait for an introduction of some sort.
         So it was quite, you needed a scorecard to keep track of who was who.
         And it got even more confusing when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> got older and would bring girlfriends or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> who I never met before to, oh, the reunions and it all just, ah, so, it's still, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, I was at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX> a reunion and there are still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 75 to 80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who show up consistently every year although it's, it's a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they'll be, you know, there's a group of maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 or 25</TIMEX> who don't come to every reunion like me but there'll be a different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 or 25</TIMEX> in there.
         So the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who show up is pretty consistent it's just that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> changes somewhat from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year to year</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are, are available to make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> or aren't.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Um</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Is it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they have the reunion?
      
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every year</TIMEX>, yeah we do a reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>.
         And it was, was my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> who owned my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Pat</ENAMEX> who had the, ah, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>' old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, who was instrumental in getting these started and keeping them going because she realized she told me this just within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> that she thought it was very important to have the reunions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> would stay in touch with each other cause otherwise I would never have known my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> because the only things we might have gotten together for would be maybe at weddings and funerals which are not good opportunities to do much mixing and mingling because there are other things on the agenda.
         At a wedding or a funeral it's really hard to catch up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         So my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> had been, had been real smart about, about scheduling those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and trying to get as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there as possible so that we all, ah, kept in touch and we all know who our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> were.
      
      
         So who's going to, ah, start doing that, who's going to be coordinating that now that she's?
      
      
         Ah, one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> apparently is, well, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> are, are keeping it going in fact.
         I just had a phone message <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> saying that the date has been set for this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> on the reunion and, ah, it's not clear who's going to host it but, ah, there's still quite a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX> and somebody is going to end up hosting it.
         Ah, the reason that, one of the reasons my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Pat</ENAMEX> was always good at being the hostess for it is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> on this dead-end <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, so there was a lot of room for everybody to kind of spread out, put up a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX> or whatever, have barbecue grills out there, and, uh, a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> to run in and use the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>, whatever, so there's just a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and, uh, but it's not clear if that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is going to be sold or not now that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> has, ah, passed away.
         Apparently in her will she said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> should be sold and the money given to a, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of my aunts and it's not clear if a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> is going to buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and sort of keep it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or what's going happen to it, but I'm hoping that they keep it because it's, it's, ah, there's so many family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> there that you think somebody would want to hang on to it and it's such a nice set up with really sort of an extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that always sort of lived right on this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX> and uh I'm thinking would probably want to keep, hang on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         How many of your, um, um I guess that's these are all the, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> of your, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> yeah.
      
      
         How many of them live in is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         It's the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX>.
         Yeah it's named for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> I believe and I'm not sure.
      
      
         How do you spell it?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-U-E-L-P-H.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         And I'm not sure why it's named for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> but it is.
         There is let's see I've got an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are still there.
         I've got an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>.
         I, I'm running out of fingers here but, ah, and then an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> or ah, a, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and, let's see, that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> right there that I can think of off the top of my head and then quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and their and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> area some of, some of them have moved away and come back, ah, but everybody, most of them have sort of settled in and around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX> area in the suburbs in one direction or another.
         Oh there's, in fact, there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and their, ah, their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who just moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX> after having been ah, ah his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> had taken him away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> but now they're back in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX> so that's number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>.
         So I'd say there must be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 20</NUMEX> uh, immediate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> that are still living in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Um now how big of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is that?
      
      
         I want to say it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90 or 100 thousand</NUMEX> or something like that.
         There's a couple of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> of similar size nearby so it's almost getting to be like its own metropolitan area, small metro area.
      
      
         Right.
         So it's, um, almost like you'll, you'll meet, ah, if you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guelph</ENAMEX> you'll meet someone will probably know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamieson</ENAMEX> there.
      
      
         Yeah, yeah because some of, like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> who just died was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bookkeeper</ENAMEX> who worked at a lot of local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and was extremely gregarious, so I think she was probably on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name basis with a awful lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who shopped downtown or whoever went downtown she was she lived there all her life and just knew a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they sort of come out of that kind of, that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> tradition like everybody's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, everybody's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that, ah should be fairly casually, she'd greet those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by name and know a little bit about them, ah, and so yeah she's, ah, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>, has a couple of businesses in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and I think is relatively well-known is on some sort of city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, or something like that.
         Yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is big enough and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is small enough I think that you would run into a decent number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamieson</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
      
      
         Or at least somebo dy married to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamieson</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         That's right.
         
      
      
         Interesting.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And then, ah, I guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion is, when is the next one you're going to go to?
      
      
         It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 12th of this year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 12th of 2000</TIMEX>, and, uh, don't know, don't know too many more details about it and don't know if I'll be able to go.
         I went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and didn't make it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and I'm, I'm, now I'm kind of sorry I didn't, because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> passed away in the meantime, and I knew she was in poor health <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
         Oh but there's just, um, just a couple of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> left.
         It's, they're starting to get up there and, and a lifetime of bad eating habits is starting to catch up, although my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 75</NUMEX> when she when she died so she had a, she had a long run.
      
      
         Sounds like she was getting out and meeting a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         She was, yeah right up, right up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, ah, when she fell, and I think she fell and broke her hip, if I recall what put her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.
         She was, ah, I think she was, ah, downtown, I think she had taken the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> downtown, and had, uh, met with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady friends</ENAMEX> to have lunch or something.
         She did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every day</TIMEX> and I recall that she slipped and fell, and then, as happens with a lot of older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, developed complications while she was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and, ah, never, never recovered unfortunately.
         It sounds simple breaking your hip but you just, it is, I, I'm sure, you know, older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've had that happen to them, you get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and you end up catching an infection or something like that from somebody else and your immune system is kind of weakened and she just, um, um, didn't make it unfortunately.
      
      
         It sounds like a big loss for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> just because there was so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and she organized the family reunions but you know at least you know you've got somebody that's going to take over and start putting that back together there.
      
      
         Yeah but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aunt Pat</ENAMEX> was definitely the matriarch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matriarch</ENAMEX>, huh?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matriarch</ENAMEX>.
         That's a good, that's a good vocabulary word.
         You can, you can probably add a whole chapter in the report of my use of the word matriarch.
         
      
      
         That and a couple of others too.
         I'm sure.
         OK.
         I'm not sure if I said, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean</ENAMEX>'s name, but this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Jamieson</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, and, um, and, uh, you know, he's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, um, subject.
      
      
         I think you did say that.
         You might have said my name at the beginning.
         I'm just not positive.
         Is it?
      
      
         And, uh, I think we did a little background on your dialect, or how you think you speak.
      
      
         That's right, that's right.
      
      
         OK that's, that's, and that should wrap it up there.
         Thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean</ENAMEX>.
      
   
