
   
   
      
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Fourth of July</TIMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> decided to take a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
         .
         We decided to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>.
         We left early on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning around 10:00</TIMEX>.
         It was about a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-hour</TIMEX> drive.
         It seemed like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten-hour</TIMEX> drive with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> wanting something to drink.
         They were fighting.
         They were cooped; they didn't like being cooped up in their seat belts, so we had to stop quite often.
         We finally got to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX>.
         We checked into a motel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at the south end of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle</ENAMEX>.
         We were right on the beach.
         It was great.
         After we checked into the motel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>
         we decided to take a walk on the beach.
         It was a beautiful <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 80 degrees</NUMEX>.
         We walked for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about thirty minutes</TIMEX> and then came back and sat on the beach
         .
         After we sat on the beach, we decided that we should get ready to go out to dinner
         .
         After we got ready to go about to dinner, we drove around looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>.
         We finally found an all you can eat seafood buffet.
         They had crab legs, crab <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cakes</ENAMEX>, shrimp, oysters, clams.
         It was great.
         We ate until we were all stuffed
         .
         After we ate dinner we decided to go and play some games in the arcade.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> went bowling, shot <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, and just ran around crazy.
         It was getting late, but we decided that we should go on the bumper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>.
         The bumper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were a blast.
         We kept stalling and bumping and going around in circles, and we just had a wonderful time on the bumper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
         .
         By then we decided we should go back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
         It wasn't that late, it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about nine o'clock</TIMEX>, so we decided to get some flashlights and go for a walk on the beach.
         We went out on the beach and started to hunt for little sand crabs.
         They are so much fun to try and catch.
         You blind then with the flashlight and then you catch them from behind.
         But watch out because it's, they like to pinch.
         We got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand crabs</ENAMEX> in a bucket and then decided to let them all go.
         They all went crazy.
         The beach was beautiful, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> were out.
         It was calm.
         It was a great <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> just to sit and relax
         .
         The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> we got up around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine o'clock</TIMEX> and decided to go sit out and play on the beach.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> built sandcastles, and played in the waves and laid out in the sun.
         My <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> decided to bury each other.
         They dug a humongous hole, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> helped them.
         We put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in one hole and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in the other hole, and we covered them all the way up to their shoulders and their heads were just sticking out.
         They thought it was a blast.
         We decided to just leave them there for a while because they couldn't get into any trouble
         .
         They finally got themselves out of their deep holes and they went in the ocean and took some rafts and tried to ride the waves.
         By then it was time for lunch.
         We decided just to go down to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hotdog</ENAMEX> stand and get some hotdogs to eat.
         And to chill off in the shade since to was getting kind of hot.
         So we sat around and ate hotdogs and milkshakes and then went back out in the sand for a while longer, I took a nap, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frisbee</ENAMEX>.
         
         It was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>; so we decided that we should get off the beach for a while and let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> take a rest.
         After their rest we decided to eat dinner out on, on the beach at a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, they had a nice little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>.
         The firecrackers were already being set off.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> were running around with sparklers.
         It was getting wild and it wasn't even dark yet.
         We sat around and listened to music and then decided it was time for us to let some of our own firecrackers off.
         We had a blast.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had a blast.
         Everybody was going crazy.
         It was a fun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX>.
         I was afraid I was going to step on a hot firecracker because they were all over the place.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> weren't even looking where they were shooting them off.
         It was just, "Bang!
         Bang!
         Bang!"
         But they were really pretty and it was a wonderful evening
         .
         We took a walk on the beach and so we could see some more fireworks.
         They were everywhere.
         We went down to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> and someone was letting them off on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX>.
         They were all so pretty, it was so much fun.
         Well, it was getting late so I think it is time to go home.
         So, we went back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and we all fell asleep.
         We were going to have to leave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>, so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> we decided to play on the beach until late in the afternoon
         and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late in the afternoon</TIMEX> we decided that we had better get on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were exhausted.
         They slept in the car all the way back and that is the story about our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long weekend</TIMEX> vacation during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Fourth of July</TIMEX>.
      
   
