
   
   
      
         How are you doing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?
      
      
         I'm doing fine.
      
      
         You ready to tell a story?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         I'm trying to think of a story I should tell.
         
         OK.
         Well, I worked as a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four and a half years</TIMEX> until recently.
         And I'll tell the story of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my chases and if that doesn't go enough time I'll tell the story of another chase, vehicle chase.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um,</ENAMEX>
         <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> after I had arrested my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> DWI, I took the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWI</ENAMEX> down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">intake center</ENAMEX>, that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> in downtown, took him down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> and him processed and got him in.
         And on my way back home, I take <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence Blvd</ENAMEX> on the way back into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>.
         And about at probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idlewild Rd</ENAMEX>, no, probably at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albemarle Rd</ENAMEX>, I got in behind, uh, this is still in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> so it wasn't in my jurisdiction, I got in behind a ,uh, an old, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'69</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cutlass</ENAMEX> that had a paper tag.
         And I didn't think anything about it.
         
         I did, I did notice it and that it had a paper tag and that it was primer, primer black, black primer.
      
      
         Paper tag?
      
      
         Paper tag, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-day</TIMEX> tag.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         And which you can track them, but it's real hard to because it's so, it's common to switch them.
         And I, we, we were headed outbound on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence Blvd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway 74</ENAMEX> and I noticed he was running <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 50 miles an hour</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50, 55</TIMEX>.
         So I got in behind him, or not behind him, but I was in the lane beside of him and he was little bit ahead of me for the turn, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> was a little ahead of me.
         And I didn't think anything about it.
         Well, uh, I noticed he, he sped <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">up to 60 miles an hour</NUMEX>.
         And so I sped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 60</NUMEX> just to see what he was doing, just to kind of let him know, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX> you're speeding!"
         you know.
         And, and we, we're still headed outbound, we cross over, um, we cross over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idlewild</ENAMEX> and, um, no actually, no this is right prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idlewild</ENAMEX> and he's running <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 miles an hour</NUMEX>.
         And then he goes, he starts going <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> as we, as we cross over Conference.
         And so I'm going <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX>.
         And, um, I got on the radio with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> thinking he might be impaired or you know, drunk or something like that.
         So I try to get in, get on the, the radio with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         And as I'm going down the road <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">65 miles an hour</NUMEX> I see the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> on the right hand side sitting in front of, uh, um, that shopping area right, right prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Is that where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris-Teeter's</ENAMEX> at?
      
      
         Yeah.
         He's, he's sitting right back up there.
         And I try to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> that we just passed an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and needless, to say, uh, they didn't get up with him.
         And so I called my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> and let him know that I was coming inbound.
         By this time we were running <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70 miles an hour</NUMEX>.
         We're passing, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> were wet, it had been raining that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
         And, um, we pass, um, we pass, uh, uh, the car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealerships</ENAMEX> on our left hand side.
         We're running <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> as we come past probably the, probably at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris Blvd</ENAMEX>.
         And so I went ahead and let my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> know up ahead as soon as we got into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>, he's getting blue lighted.
         And I felt that he was impaired to go ahead and start another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> then.
         And so we're running <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>, probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70</TIMEX>, a good <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">70 miles an hour</NUMEX> and we go, we pass over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sardis North</ENAMEX> and right as we get into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> about where, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown Point Executive Dr</ENAMEX> is, I, uh, told them I was initiating a stop.
         So I flipped on my blue lights and it was on!
         He took off and was running <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 90 miles an hour</NUMEX> and I'm right in behind him, um, I'm keeping radio contact with, um, with dispatch and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>.
         And, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um, Rich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Rich</ENAMEX>, evidently came up, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Newell</ENAMEX> and got in behind me.
         I didn't see him because I was worried about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.
         We're running, we're heading past, we're probably at, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pep Boys</ENAMEX> now, maybe where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Market</ENAMEX> is.
         We're running probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we got up to, the fastest we got up to on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">74</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 110</NUMEX>.
         And, um, he's still getting on along and, uh, I'm still sticking with him and I felt uncomfortable on the wet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX>, of course, was asking me during the chase, that's, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergeant Stevens</ENAMEX>, was making sure that the traffic was, was OK and that I felt OK with the chase.
         And the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the, the</ENAMEX>, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> was doing, you know, keeping up with all the locations and landmarks which I, I do pretty well; I was ready with that.
         And dispatch is, you know, telling me whenever I'd call out I'd say, "OK.
         Independence and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter Square</ENAMEX> Dr." And they'd say, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Independence</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter Square</ENAMEX> Dr." And I said, "Still continuing eastbound on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway 74</ENAMEX>."
         And, um, so we're running, we're booking on along <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 110 or so</NUMEX> and I say, uh, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headquarters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> are wet.
         I don't feel comfortable anymore.
         I'm going to go ahead and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> the chase."
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-22</NUMEX> is `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disregard the Chase</ENAMEX>,' you know, go ahead and, and let back.
         I had already called <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-43</NUMEX>, which is `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pursuit</ENAMEX>.
         ' The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX> you call <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10- 43</NUMEX>, basically all radio traffic ceases and you are the, you're the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich evidently</ENAMEX> had gotten in behind me and I <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>'ed the chase probably about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway 51</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> maybe a little past it.
         And so as I'm backing off, I'm, I'm still keeping an eye on him if he's slowing down a little bit and he goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews-Mint Hill</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX> makes a left hand turn.
         And so I went ahead and, uh, got back in the chase again because I figured, um, you know, I just figured I'd go ahead, go ahead and chase him because I knew that he couldn't keep up that kind of speed on the, uh, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews-Mint Hill</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> was in behind me by then and so we head on the way down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews-Mint Hill</ENAMEX>, we probably running <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around 80 or 90 miles an hour</NUMEX>.
         We get to, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> or, uh, I'm sorry, we get to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Highway 51</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews-Mint Hill</ENAMEX> and he makes that right turn and he slows down for that and so I'm right in behind him, blue lights and sirens all the way.
         Give them my location and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Rich</ENAMEX> is behind me.
         And, uh, we're heading out on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idlewild Rd</ENAMEX>, we're, or we're on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews-Mint Hill</ENAMEX>, both being the same now.
         We get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petro</ENAMEX>, we get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petro</ENAMEX>, now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idlewild</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX>, he makes a right heading towards <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union County</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, so we start heading down that way and, uh, we're going on down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idlewild Rd</ENAMEX>, keep right on going, cross over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">485</TIMEX> construction, which it was under construction at that point, and, um, we're, we're running a good clip.
         And, uh, by that time, what I had done, was, you know, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 51</NUMEX> or so I had switched over, I was talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mecklenburg</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrol</ENAMEX> on my main car radio and talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> dispatch on my hand held, as, as I'm driving.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Um, Rich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Rich</ENAMEX> is still behind me and as we didn't have our new radio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> up, had we had the radio <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> up, I would be able to maintain contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> on my hand-held, but the hand-helds don't transmit very well.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so, I mean, I was still maintaining contact and they could still hear me on, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutual Aid</ENAMEX>, but the thing was I should have been on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>, uh, main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> on my car radio because it transmits stronger.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh,</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>'s still behind me and, um, so I'm getting on with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrol</ENAMEX>, trying to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrol</ENAMEX> come and, and meet with me because we're heading towards <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union County</ENAMEX>.
         Not that I can't chase into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>, but I'd much rather have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrolman</ENAMEX> out there myself, because they'll ram somebody off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> in a heart beat!
      
      
         
      
      
         Not really, but, uh, they're better at chases; they've had training in chases.
         And, um, so we start going over some hills down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idlewild Rd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Rich</ENAMEX> loses me.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, or I should say, both of us lost him.
         I'm still maintaining contact with, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrol</ENAMEX> and, uh, they're hearing me fine and, uh, they're trying to get somebody out there to me.
         But as we down to, we're heading, we're getting into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union County</ENAMEX> a good ways and we get down to, we cross over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stevens Mill</ENAMEX>, and there's the next road pass <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mill</ENAMEX>, I think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Mill</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indian Trail Rd</ENAMEX>, I'm not exactly sure.
         And there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX> station right there.
         They lost me and I'm still transmitting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mutual Aid</ENAMEX> because I didn't see any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> around me and I knew we were headed towards a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, because they're down there on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seacrest Short Cut</ENAMEX> and pretty soon <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unionville Rd or Idlewild</ENAMEX> I think turns into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seacrest Short Cut</ENAMEX>, I believe.
         And, uh, so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> gets on the radio and says, uh, you know, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">321</NUMEX> if you can copy me.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> your chase!
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> your chase!"
         And so I disregarded my chase and parked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and, uh, advised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrol</ENAMEX> that I was being <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>'ed by my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, so I parked there and kind of calmed down for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> and here comes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> and here comes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergeant Stevens</ENAMEX>.
         And so he, both pulls in, they both pull in, you know, and I let them know that I lost him and then a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrolman</ENAMEX> comes up and, uh, asks, "Which way did he go?"
         and I say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He</ENAMEX> went down that way."
         And so he heads out that way spinning tires trying, trying to catch up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.
         My best guess is what he did was, when I <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">22'ed</NUMEX>, he probably took a side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> and uh, headed, headed out into the county somewhere.
      
      
         So he was never caught?
      
      
         No.
         Never caught.
         My, I probably, he was either, it probably wasn't a stolen <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or anything like that.
         Probably what had happened was his license was revoked, or he was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DWI</ENAMEX>, or something like that, and, uh, but, but the whole thing about it was, had I maintained contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> on my main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">radio</ENAMEX>, we would have probably caught him or at least been able to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrol</ENAMEX> up there and they could have assumed the chase.
         And of course, I would have to have been the secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> because I, I started the chase.
         So-
      
      
         Did you get into trouble?
      
      
         No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> just told me, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next</ENAMEX> time be on your radio."
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dispatchers</ENAMEX> up there, he goes "We didn't have to do anything.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, you were contacting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Patrol</ENAMEX> and you were contacting us and basically you were doing our job for us."
         But I knew that was wrong thing to do.
         But at the time I didn't know where any of my other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> were.
         I knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich</ENAMEX> was behind me but I had lost sight of him.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> said he was just afraid that I had, uh, that I had wrecked or something like that.
         That I was, you know, in the woods somewhere up against a tree in my patrol <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> after running <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">90 miles an hour</NUMEX> down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idlewild Rd</ENAMEX> as it gets curvy.
         But that was the story of my one chase.
      
      
         Thank you.
      
      
         You're very welcome.
      
   
