
   
   
      
         When I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woonsocket</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX>, and when I was younger, I guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight, nine years old</TIMEX>, every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and I would go to visit our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woonsocket</ENAMEX>, and we usually left on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 22nd of December</TIMEX>, and I remember it being a really long car ride <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, who was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> younger than me, would often fight in the back seat, and when we got there, um, we would stay in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suisse Chalet</ENAMEX>, and it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Smits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Smithfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX>, which was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 20 minutes</TIMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woonsocket</ENAMEX> where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> were from, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Woonsocket</ENAMEX> we would visit both my sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>, who lived there, and it's tradition in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> we would eat dinner at, um, my grandparents <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s side and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> would cook a huge dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> dinner and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> dinner, and we would open one of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> presents, which I thought was a great
         tradition, and it's a tradition that we still practice to this day, and usually on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year's Day</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had a tradition of renting a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> or a restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> that was sort of a reunion, um, so that we could see all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, and I remember spending time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> who, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie</ENAMEX>, who were about my age.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, at the time, when I was a sophomore in college at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX> I decided to go on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spring Break</ENAMEX>, which happened around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late March</TIMEX>, and I decided to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boca Raton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX> with my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from high school.
         Her name was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX>.
         And so, um, we met in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>, and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boca Raton</ENAMEX> and we stayed with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>, and we would stay with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least one night</TIMEX>, uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boca Raton</ENAMEX>, and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the week</TIMEX> we spent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> called The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sanddollar</ENAMEX> in a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lauderdale</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX>, um, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX>, and it was fantastic time and when we had the chance to spend time together and just go out on the beach and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> we would go out to dinner I remember going to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Benihana Japanese</ENAMEX> steakhouse, and we just felt like we had freedom, and then we weren't yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> so we weren't allowed to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Lauderdale</ENAMEX>, so we basically spent our time, uh, watching movies in the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> or just walking along the strip and I remember going out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> and just walking along the boardwalk it was very, very peaceful time, and the worst part of the vacation was getting sunburned, um, because I'm extremely pale, and going out on the beach
         everyday for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on end turned me into a lobster, and, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal</ENAMEX> would always joke with me and call me, um, her lobster.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> growing up, um, was named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Martin</ENAMEX>, and I met her when I was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Andrew</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic School</ENAMEX> and we became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, um, almost immediately because we learned that we lived close to one another and it was about maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second or third week</TIMEX> of school when she invited me to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and she lived, um, in an oceanfront <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and, uh, we went, um, we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> watching TV, watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX>, which was both of are favorite shows, and we would walk on the beach, and we would play with her <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and then we would walk down to the pond and feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> and we would ride our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> all around the neighborhood.
         And I remember, in particular, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> had called our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         It was an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, and there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> told me that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, who lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RI</ENAMEX>, had died, and I guess at the time I wasn't able to deal with my emotions or that I was in denial that it happened and I remember just running away to my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and not even telling my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> where I was going, and I got to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and I told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> what had happened and she could tell that I was really upset about it, and so I just felt I'd just run away.
         We went on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycles</ENAMEX> and we told pretty much the whole way, and I guess that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dottie</ENAMEX> had called my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and told her that I was OK because I'm sure that she was worried.
         You know, I all of a sudden ran out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with no explanation, but it was very comforting to spend that time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, and I didn't want to be alone and it was a really good experience.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Cartsokalis</ENAMEX>, um, who I went to school with at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Andrew's</ENAMEX>, and we became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> when I was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade and she lived across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from me and I loved to go to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> because she had a pool and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did not.
         And so I would go over there and we would watch TV on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>, and usually I would spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>, and, um, so we'd watch TV during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and then we would go shopping at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> always gave us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> dollars to spend on anything we wanted so that was always fun and I remember we would during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> watch music videos and just hang out and have fun, and she had an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>, and it was in high school, and we were in grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at the time, and we would always try on her clothes and because she was really stylish and had the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Guess</ENAMEX>?
         jeans and the jean jackets, and the cute, you know, skirts and tops and I don't know what happened to our friendship, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years later</TIMEX>, when I was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade, we got into a fight at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> involving another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, and I don't even remember what the fight was over, and it seemed like a silly reason at the time.
         And what's amazing is that we didn't talk for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least three or four years</TIMEX>, um, because of that fight, and it was sad for me because she lived across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, and I felt like I couldn't talk to her anymore, and it was only our senior year in high school that, um, we finally were able to patch things up.
         She, her locker was next to mine and I remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> we just said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi</ENAMEX>," to each other for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time after ignoring each other for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire year</TIMEX>, and, um, it was liberating, it was great that we could finally talk and make up, and since then, um, you know, we've kept in touch when we were both in college, and I ran into her here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX>.
         It seems that we go to the same church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and it was neat to see her here because I didn't realize she had moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         I thought she was still living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX> where her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> lived so.
      
   
