
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Resident</ENAMEX> with me and the most from my childhood was, ah, the story about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> I'm, I'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was from here as, well she died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1992</TIMEX>, and she the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         She had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>.
         I had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of them are still living.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, but one of the stories, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>, yeah, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>, and she lived to be, ah, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">102</NUMEX>.
         So she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and, of course, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had been slaves.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         So, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> grew up out near the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>, near, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Steele Creek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, for all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th century</TIMEX>, basically, lived out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX> of her life.
         She came and lived with us.
         But she had her leg amputated so she moved in with us and we took care of her.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, but before that she was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> use to talk about how as the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she would have to wash dishes and do the domestic things, so even at dinner, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> dinner, if their were a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, if they had fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had to wait for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> to eat the choice pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and then she could eat a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> or a back or a neck and to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> she died that's how she was.
         If she fried some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> for us she'd always eat the smallest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX>.
         The meager looking pieces.
         So my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> use to sit back in her chair in the den and talk about how one <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Granny</ENAMEX>, uh, had decided she was going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and you know back then, you're talking, oh probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930s</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1930s</TIMEX>, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> would've been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 or 12</TIMEX>, somewhere around there, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, uh, went to the train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> to get on the little trolley <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, whatever they had at that time to come downtown.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Well during her absence my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was suppose to clean the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and probably prepared dinner and stuff like that.
         This was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.
         Well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> thinking, "Oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>'s gone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>."
         She's gone hang out a little bit.
         Well after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about</TIMEX>, I don't know, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two hours</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half hours</TIMEX>, I think, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granny</ENAMEX> came back and she was quite upset.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> hadn't done any work she was suppose to do, and she got a beat down, all right, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> had sat about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> at the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX> and she hadn't noticed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> had been moved.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         So there was no longer a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> that ran there and so,
         I don't know what the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, I don't know what the rationale was for all of that.
         I guess they just changed the route and what not, but, uh, she laughed about that all the time, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> did, she didn't laugh at the time she was getting beat, ah, but she use to always tell us that was really the only time that she got beat <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> and, and she never beat her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> could did no wrong in her mind.
         So that's probably my favorite story about, uh, or from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> that I recall.
         I believe, yeah.
         And then, hum, there's another story, well this is a, this is not a, this is not a story she passed down this is a story of mine, I guess.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         That happened with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reda</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK.
      
      
         Now bear in mind that I told you <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> moved in with us, um, towards the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> of her life, and when she moved in with us I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">10th</NUMEX> grade, so I was just starting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, you know, going through puberty and dating and playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and stuff like that.
         That, that was my favorite sport.
         So my senior year, I went to the health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, to get a physical.
         That's required for those who are playing sports.
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         You got to have a physical.
         No problem.
         I was up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beatties Ford Road</ENAMEX>.
         Everybody knows where the health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> is there.
         Well, standard procedure back then, I don't know what it is now, is that you come in, someone comes in and they give you, now I don't if it's like this now, but back then they would give you a bag of prophylactics, condoms, all right.
         So they gave me a bag, and I didn't really, you know, pay any attention to it.
         So I said, "OK, fine," and I actually put them in my trunk, trunk of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         This was like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
         Now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> never drove, her entire life she never drove, so I took her wherever she went.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Took her to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, took her to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, stuff like that.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> never drove either, even before she had her leg amputated.
         So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> comes around and this particular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> we're taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> to her home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steele Creek</ENAMEX> area, out past the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>.
         And that's fine, you know, I'm driving.
         I got, ah, at that point I was driving an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile Delta</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>.
         It was a diesel.
         And so this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> we had eaten breakfast and we're getting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> situated in her wheelchair and everything and that was pretty much my job, and I told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> to go out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and open the trunk.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita</ENAMEX> did that.
         All of a sudden we hear these yells.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         "Oh my goodness something's happened, Mama!
         Come back here."
         I'm thinking they found a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, or, you know, something in the driveway, backyard.
         Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> goes, uh, "Oh Lord, help me."
         
         I say, "What is the problem?"
         And so, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX> get out here right now!"
         I mean everybody in the neighborhood.
         I mean it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and this is an old black neighborhood, everybody knows everybody.
         And so, I take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX> out, wheel her out, through the front door.
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I say <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Granny</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX>'s calling me.
         Something's wrong, but let's go on out and I'll get you situated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>."
         And, um, get her in there and around to the back.
         "Explain this," and I said, "Explain what?
         I just told you to open the trunk."
         Well low and behold the condoms, which are multi-colored, had fallen out the bag.
         So they spread out all over the trunk, red, green, blue, whatever.
         And it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, we're on our way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.
         I'm like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>," I'm speechless, what am I going to say, they already convicted me now, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>.
         So, needless to say, that, that ride to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> was very quiet and they said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Excuse me</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> you and your nephews," my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, who are my age, uh, "we're going to have a talk after dinner."
         And so we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX> talk after dinner.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Now remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was at that point, at that point, she was probably, she had me when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX>, so she was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close to 60</NUMEX>, yeah she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close to 60</NUMEX> at that point.
         And it's hard enough talking to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> about sex if they're fairly young.
         It's definitely hard getting it from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 year old</TIMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Now, of course, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> never talked to me about any of that stuff, but that's another story.
         So we had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> dinner and we went through the do's and don'ts of sexuality.
         Needless to say, my nephews and I were quite embarrassed and didn't want to be there.
         But they were just convinced that they were getting ready to just ruin our lives, but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were going get us to do some stuff they didn't need to do and we were going be some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, and that's my story in terms of, um, um, something we still laugh about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I, yeah.
      
      
         Thank you
      
      
         That will work.
      
   
