
   
   
      
         What's your name?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Solomon Lidington</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And this for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charlotte Narrative Project</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Well, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, who's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX>, used to be able to tell me a lot of, you know, a lot a stories that happened in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and since I was a history major in college and I was studying and I was studying about formation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and so forth, particularly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, I thought this one was really interesting, but it's really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         And it was back during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, and, you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was in a depression, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> lived with her, mm, lived with, lived with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
         In other words, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, which would be my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, your great great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         And my
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great grandfather</ENAMEX>, my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of a woolen <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>.
         I believe it was a woolen <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> because, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>, oh, in a lot of parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolinas</ENAMEX> there were a lot of different types of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX>, woolen <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mills</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and he was over this woolen <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>.
         And at that time there was a movement to unionize, and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and so forth were against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> at that time.
         But my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was sort of open to it.
         He was a very, you know, nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and very good mannered, supposedly.
         And, um, not only was he over that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>, but they, he also owned, or co- owned or rented or something, some small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>, some small, I guess, we would probably call them shanty type houses `cause they were very small.
         Ah, and they were used by some of the, you know, some, some of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and some of the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this little small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
         And everybody knew everybody even the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> knew the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
         And, um
         anyway there was this big push to unionize and I guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was, great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was trying to be open-minded about the whole thing, but apparently, there were some real problems, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one afternoon</TIMEX>, one of the, uh, union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX>, who was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, who was actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> because they had brought, because lots of times they brought in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> to help form these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was actually from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>, was actually a neighbor, but he had a history of mental problems.
         And, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> he, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that afternoon</TIMEX> he came over and got very, I guess he was very demanding and, uh, was, I guess he was also acting very strange.
         For whatever reason he shot and killed my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> over a union issue in his front yard, in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s front yard, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> all witnessed it.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was never charged with murder or anything because he was so mentally unstable.
         So he was just, you know, trotted off to a mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> for the rest of his life.
         But the one thing about it was that
         my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, who was a very strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, knew, OK, knew that all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> depended on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> for different things, and, um, even when times were really bad my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> would great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> would help you know some of these really poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out and there was this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was just a really hard worker really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but he was having a really hard time and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grand great grandmother</ENAMEX> and my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> took a great big, anonymously took a great, big basket of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> to their door and he knew that they would never take this stuff from anyone that they knew was one of those real proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and so they took it like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX> and right before they put it down, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> slipped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> bucks, which was a lot of money back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, into the basket.
         And he never told or anything.
         Well the thing about it was in, I'm sort of telling this story out of order, but my grand, after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> died and my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was sort of alone, um, it must have been right around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> and she was feeling real depressed or whatever and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> came and invited her to come to dinner, and when she, and so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> didn't think she really wanted to go and everything, but she thought, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, OK," she'd go ahead and go.
         And so she went in.
         When she went all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, all these different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the place she said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of them, you know, I guess they, back then, I guess they called them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vagabonds</ENAMEX>.
         A lot of them were just, I, or what we would call I guess homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but they were also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they knew were there.
         And so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was talking to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> saying they couldn't believe that she had prepared this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>.
         It must've been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> for all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and that she didn't know, and some of them she did know, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> said, well she said, well, what happened was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years back</TIMEX> when she in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> were having such a horrible time <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>, they got a great big basket of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 dollars</NUMEX> in it.
         And she said and that tied them over for the longest time, and they never found out who it was.
         And they thought, well once they got on their feet if they could repay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> somehow.
         This is what they would do, and so they, you know, every time, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of year</TIMEX>, or whatever, they would have this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>, and, I guess, you know, she's just hoping that some day she would pay back the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> perhaps that had given them that money, because she didn't know who it was.
         And she didn't know if it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>, and this way they invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>.
         And so she said that was why they had this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> between, it must be between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>, or something like that.
         And so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> told me that, and, uh I, I thought it was just a really a nice way that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had, had actually, she didn't know it, but had repaid her kindness because it had been my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         But my great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> never told her that she was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and yet, at that time, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> was inviting my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> over to this dinner and everything, um, anonymously.
         And I just thought it was just a really cute, or not cute but really sweet way to be thankful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of year</TIMEX>.
         So I guess that's a little confusing but I thought it was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> story.
      
      
         Is that it?
      
   
