
   
   
      
         OK, this is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> interview with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabatha Lloyd</ENAMEX> who also lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, where I live.
         Have you lived here all your life Tabatha?
      
      
         Yes,
         all but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> and we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robinsville</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And where is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinsville</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, it's at the tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>, it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> but it touches <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And that's where you have family I think, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s family lives there.
         Can you tell us a little bit about it?
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yeah, both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s family
         all live there, and um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> moved here with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke Power</ENAMEX>, um, in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about '73</NUMEX>.
         I guess they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was transferred here, and the, so the rest of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lives there, um, and we're the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live here, and it's just a total redneck <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincolnton</ENAMEX> or Robinsville?
      
      
         Robinsville, um,
         what, why is it redneck?
         I guess, well, the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> consists of nothing but white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> that is in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingle</ENAMEX>'s grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, we used to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hardee's</ENAMEX>, but they took it out.
         We do have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papa's Pizza</ENAMEX> now
         , and the rest of it is just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX> family-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.
         There,
         there's probably, I don't know, the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> consists of one block basically.
         It's just a big circle, uh, and, there's nothing to do there.
         If you want to go shopping you have to go <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about thirty miles</NUMEX>, other than grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, um, you have to, everybody goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Asheville</ENAMEX> to shop, because there's no, there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> to shop there except for just like family-owned, little clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and stuff, stuff nobody wants.
      
      
         Isn't that where they filmed the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nell</ENAMEX>, and weren't your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> a part of that film?
      
      
         No, they, they did film the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Nell</ENAMEX> there but, um, they, the pool <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>'s pool <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> that it was filmed in, but no my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> had nothing to do with it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> did rent out his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool hall</ENAMEX>, and in the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> scene, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> are in the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> scene, and I guess that's all the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> I have in there.
         They've totally, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> have destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, the little cabin in the woods where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nell</ENAMEX> was filmed.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, they've just went up there and took planks of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> and stuff off of it and totally destroyed the whole place.
      
      
         Do you like living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here as opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Robinsville</ENAMEX>, do you think they're nicer, um, I mean friendlier, and just in general do you like living in this area?
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I wouldn't live anywhere but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, I don't think.
         But as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> goes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Robinsville</ENAMEX> are much friendlier.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Th</ENAMEX>, like I say, there's no, you can't go shopping or anything so there's a lot of family time spent, you know, you, there's a lot a<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
         a lot of visiting, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take time for each other up there, there's not the hustle and bustle that's down here, so, life's a lot slower pace there.
      
      
         What about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>'s definitely fast <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">paced</ENAMEX> here because everybody's always busy, an nobody visits anybody, we just don't have any of the old, the old school tactics I guess that uh, they practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Robinsville</ENAMEX>.
         Nobody has time for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around here.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wow</ENAMEX>, and this is considered a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might live in larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> like even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gast</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, uh, did you like going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincolnton High School</ENAMEX>?
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, no, it pretty well, no, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincolnton High School</ENAMEX> pretty well sucked.
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I think I made it there like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy-five days</TIMEX> out of my senior year, and I still managed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with a B plus average.
         
      
      
         This is something we're all proud of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tabatha</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         Hey I'm proud that I got out a there.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, OK, well, so, do you think you'll ever want to travel, or, and if you do, where do you want to travel to?
      
      
         I would like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> I know, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, um, just because I think, the, I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX>'s beautiful, I like the accent, and I just think it would be a neat place to go.
         I'm not really, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, doesn't really drill me, um, I'd like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, and of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, everybody wants to go there, but, that's um, I guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> would just be the place I'd most like to go.
      
      
         OK, um, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> also lives here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX> and I've never known a, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and I'm talking about you, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, who is more close in such a functional yet dysfunctional way.
         
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Tell me a little bit about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and the things that you appreciate in her, or things that you remember about her best when you were younger.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we are really close and I guess that's because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who raised us.
         She had to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> jobs our whole life to take care of us.
         So growing up she wasn't really around much, um, but she's always been our best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s just always kind of, she's the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, and she's always just kind of took care of me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>.
         
         And, um, I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, so, momma just always left everything up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonya</ENAMEX> to take care of us, and that's why I guess we're so close, because we all had to depend on each other, and we didn't depend on anybody else to take care of us.
         We, we all leaned on each other and we all took care of each other.
         We're, we're all best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and it's kind of hard for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to fit in, you know, it's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of us and then everybody else I guess.
      
      
         OK, and what about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, do you, I know you're not as close with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> as your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> even though you do love him, um, do you remember your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> being together when you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, and, you know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> or anything like that, that you remember them being together?
         I don't, I don't remember how young you were whenever they got divorced.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Christmases</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, um, because, I remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> we got every, we always got everything on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> couldn't wait.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and I remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that um, I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> and I was getting ready to go to kindergarten when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> told me that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> wasn't coming home, and um, it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> before I went in kindergarten.
         And I was sitting in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s chair waiting on him to come home and, uh, my uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">momma</ENAMEX> told me <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> wasn't coming home, but uh, that's really the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> things I remember about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> being young, uh, I remember <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one other night</TIMEX>, with uh, when he took my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> to a, um, a race <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, um, a race or something, but I stayed at home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, and that's really the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> times that I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, before they split up.
         And as for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, you know he's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, I love him, but he's set in his ways, and he's always right, he's never wrong, and you know I'm too much like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> so we're not the best of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, but that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tabatha</ENAMEX>, um, we spent a lot of time together when we were younger, um, a lot of good times, a lot of fun times.
         What are the, now that we're both <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> old married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, what are some of the things that you remember and miss about our younger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, especially <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our years</TIMEX> in high school when we had to kind of rely on each other as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nonconformists</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincolnton High School</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I guess I miss going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> together because you know we were always in the same youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
         And of course I miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galen Radebaugh</ENAMEX>, but
         , um, I definitely do not miss the short period of time that I had to live with you.
         
      
      
         Oh God.
         
      
      
         Because that was immortal hell!
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, um, I miss making fun of Alynne I guess.
      
      
         I hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alynne</ENAMEX> never goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Charlotte Narrative</ENAMEX> collection and pulls this interview up.
      
      
         
         Alynne we love you if you do, um.
         --
      
      
         Tell us about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alynne</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         Alynne was crazy, and speaking of my dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alynne</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> wanted to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alynne</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alynne</ENAMEX> was crazy and probably on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>, and, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alynne</ENAMEX> tries to kill herself you know, as we hear, she, she's constantly trying to kill herself, and, she contributes all her problems to the fact that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, I don't know,
         that she wasn't with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> I guess.
         But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alynne</ENAMEX> thought she had beautiful feet and she thought that she was holier than thou, and,
         she, she was just a spoiled brat.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Um</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         
         Golly!
         Besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alynne</ENAMEX>, can you remember any fun things that we did together?
      
      
         Fun thing--
      
      
         What were the funnest memories.
         I know, I know I remember staying at your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>, ordering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> whenever we didn't have any money to do so, and having to steal money from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, or just--
      
      
         Count out change.
         
      
      
         --count out pennies,
         , and, going swimming at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> where your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> use to work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> when nobody was there and we weren't really allowed to be there, that was fun.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um,</ENAMEX>
         so, what are your fondest memories.
         
      
      
         I have no idea.
      
      
         Oh that's nice.
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I guess, I don't know, just hanging out, um, we use to hang out with like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Waites</ENAMEX>.
         I guess we had a lot of fun with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX>.
         We use to just hang out and have a good time all the time, we stayed with each other all the time, and, um--
      
      
         \\ You taught me how to smoke.
         \\
      
      
         \\ Yeah I taught you how to smoke.
         I'm sorry.
         
         \\
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\Cigarettes\\</ENAMEX>, which we have both quit smoking, thank, praise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I guess the funnest times we ever had I would have to say was right after me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX> got married, but, I'm not going to talk about that so
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>, I don't know.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Th</ENAMEX>, that was the really memorable times, um, seeing who could stand outside the longest on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">deck</ENAMEX> in the snow--
      
      
         Oh I remember that, that was fun.
         It was never about partying, I mean we did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, especially after you and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX> got married, but it was never about that.
         I think when we had our funnest times, I mean those times were fun, but we also when, when we were involved in youth and stuff like that we had fun then too, so we didn't--
      
      
         Did you go to the beach with us?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Caswell</ENAMEX>, yeah--
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         Like a lot of my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in high school all we did, was like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> together and that's the only memories I have of them, when I ever want to remember something about them it's always, "OK, well, we did, we drank <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> and did <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this that night</TIMEX>."
         But, with you and you, and just, and maybe one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> from high school really, we really had a friendship that didn't involve stuff like that all the time.
         We had good times without having to do that crazy stuff.
         So, I think that's good because a lot of people can't say that.
         But I digress, I'm sorry, anyway
         .
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I've been asked, I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> the same question because it's such a cheesy question, but I'm going to go ahead and ask you, since we're coming upon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year two thousand</TIMEX>, what was your favorite movie of all time and why?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I guess it would d, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da</ENAMEX>, probably <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dirty Dancing</ENAMEX>.
         It would be a close tie between <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dirty Dancing and Up Close and Personal</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         \\
         Oh God.
         \\
      
      
         \\ But uh.
         \\
      
      
         \\ Please.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Dancing</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         I, I just love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Dancing</ENAMEX>, and um, it wasn't because I thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Swayze</ENAMEX> was beautiful or anything, it was, because I really don't think he's that good looking, I just, the story was sweet, and it was a good story.
         I always needed that older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to come take me away
         .
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX> took me right here, to uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>.
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and if it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Up Close</ENAMEX> and Personal it would be totally because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX> standing at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the escalator</TIMEX>.
         
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX>, you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have been together for how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, not, not just including the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you've been married.
      
      
         We've been married for, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, and, I guess we've been together <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>.
      
      
         OK we had to flip the tape over.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, do you remember the very first time you ever saw or um, met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX> in high school, and can you talk about that a little bit?
      
      
         The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I ever met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX> was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Covenant</ENAMEX>, and he came to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of ours <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Taylor</ENAMEX>, and, um, he um, he had, I don't remember if he had a mohawk then or if he was bald-headed, I'm guessing he probably had a mohawk, and had on a green and brown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">flannel</ENAMEX> shirt, I would guess, and he weighed a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and twenty six</NUMEX> pounds and was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six four</NUMEX>, he looked like he was dying with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>,
         , he was pathetic looking, I felt so sorry for him, and he was a total freak, he did not talk to anybody, he was just a skater and he was just a total freak.
         And I decided I was going to be his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, and I talked to him at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, but he was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uh</ENAMEX>, uh," was all he would ever say.
         And then finally we had a class together when I moved and, because I switched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> grade and when I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, um, well to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincolnton High School</ENAMEX>, I had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with him.
         And um, he, the way we started talking is he had shaved his head bald, and he was going to let some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> draw a picture on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with black magic marker and I felt sorry for him and I told him that they were not going to draw on his head, and we just started dating.
         And, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time he ever called me, I was on the phone and he called, I was talking to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, and I switched over and I'm like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAMA</ENAMEX> IT'S <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DOUG</ENAMEX>," and he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Huh"</ENAMEX>, I had forgotten to switch the phone over before I screamed in his ear.
      
      
         Were you excited that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug</ENAMEX> or horrified?
      
      
         I was very excited, um, I liked him a lot though I just think really, I really felt sorry for him, and I just wanted to kind of take care of him, and now he takes care of me.
         And, um, you were talking earlier about being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, um, one thing I think through being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and stuff and uh, not all being about partying, is we have a friendship that we, I think we'll always be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> whether we're always together or not, you know, It's not, a, it's not about you know, seeing each other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> or hanging out all the time, its deeper than that and I think that's because God's at the root of it.
      
      
         I agree.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, oh, I wanted to ask you about your, I know you love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you've always worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, since you've been out of high school you've wanted to pursue a career with child care development and why do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because I don't see why but, uh, maybe you can explain to us why you like them so much.
         
      
      
         I don't know, I've always liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, I guess because I've, I guess it has a lot to do with the fact that I was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and I've always, you know, I was always just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> of the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and, um, there was times that you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> wasn't around or whatever, and I just, there were times he didn't treat me like he should have I guess, and I just wanted to be good to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and I just want to show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love, and even if they have dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, or if things aren't the way that they should be, that's, that they have somewhere to go, and somebody who loves them, and, um, you know, its not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's you know, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>, I have a heart for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and though sometimes that's got me in trouble, I still have a heart for them and I still, you know, someday really want to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, OK, it's very understandable why, seeing it from that perspective why you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so much.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I'm going to ask you just maybe one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more questions.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, OK, one of our favorite things to do is to tell ghost stories and scare the heebie-jeebies out of each other, um, tell me one of your favorite ghost stories.
         You have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> who lived like way out in the boon docks, and some scary stuff occurred at her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX>, can you tell us a little bit about that.
      
      
         Yeah, well,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>, I had, OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>, I, it been like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days about a week or so</TIMEX> and I hadn't had time to go up and see her and I spent a whole lot of time with her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>,
         this is before I got married, so you know I spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> with her a lot, and um, we, we were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and I went to lay down with her little boy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> to put him to bed because he wouldn't go to sleep by his self and I had worked all day so I was really tired and I went and laid down with him and me and him fell asleep.
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> came back there and she woke me up, and, um, she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabatha</ENAMEX>," and I'm like "Um huh," and she's like "Tabatha get up and spend some time with me you hadn't, you know I hadn't seen you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> , please get up and talk to me for a little while," and I was real sleepy and I'm like, "OK <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>."
         Well I opened my eyes and I like tossed my head over to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>, when I opened my eyes she was going back down the hall, I tossed my head back over to look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> because he was laying on the other side of the bed, and uh, when I did, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> was in the bed with me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>, she was laying down between me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> or on the other side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> was in between us, and I woke her up, I'm like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> you got to wake up now," because, and I told her what had happened, and that hadn't been the only time something like that had happened, um, there had been times when, um, we were like we were going to sleep or something, and, um, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> I'd spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> with her and some stuff had happened that night I forget what all had happened but-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ Didn't you stay the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> with her a lot because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> worked at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, or, something?
         \\
      
      
         Uh yeah, he worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">third</TIMEX> shift, and, um, she didn't like staying by herself because you know stuff did happen a lot in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, but, uh, I spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> with her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patrick w</ENAMEX>, was actually <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> and s, some stuff had happened, you know we'd heard some noises and stuff and she'd ask me if I would come sleep in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, she's like, "I'll make you a pallet at the end of our bed just come in there, you know, um,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>, I'm scared," so I'm like "OK <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer"</ENAMEX>, and she made me a pallet at the end of her bed and we were we were asleep and I was almost asleep and all of the sudden we heard this noise and it sounded like it came from the bed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> said, "Tabatha I hope that was you," and I said "no I was hoping that that was one of y'all," and she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, it came from down there," and I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, it came from up there".
         Well, she looked at the clock and she's like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabatha</ENAMEX>, get up get up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and come in the living room," and we went in the living room and sh, and I'm like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Jennifer"</ENAMEX>, you know I wanted to go to sleep, and um, she said, "Did you see what time it was?"
         And I said, "No I didn't see what time it was," and she said, "It was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:15</TIMEX>," well at the time that meant nothing to me, but um, she explained to me and later we watched the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amityville Horrors</ENAMEX>, and then it really started making sense to me, and speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amityville Horrors</ENAMEX>, my house
         looks just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amityville Horrors</ENAMEX>, have you ever looked at it?
      
      
         Yeah.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but uh, um, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>, then some other weird stuff happened, and I really think the reason that such weird stuff happened there was because I was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> influence in her life, and I think you know, I really believe that her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was possessed
         and I believe that you know they probably wanted to get rid of me, but.
         --
      
      
         Tell about her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> knowing about her grandma.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, um, he, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years old</TIMEX> um, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX>'s his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was dead, and well, by that time his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was dead, but one time he was talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, and it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">momma</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> were dead.
         OK, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> was talking to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and he told his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, he said, "I know," he said, "Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX>'s crying."
         She said, "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX>'s crying, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX>'s, hey, you know, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX>'s gone."
         He said, "But he was crying and he was running through the woods and, um, um".
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Debbie</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>, she's like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>, you know, what are you talking about?"
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> had never heard about this, and, um, he said, "He's crying and he's running from somebody," and she said, "Who's he running from?"
         And um, um, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> said, "I don't know, but he's crying, he's running through the woods, and, she," he said, "and she shot him.
         And um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>'s grand, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s grandma asked, "Who shot him?"
         And said, "h, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> shot him," and her, um, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandpa</ENAMEX> had been shot and killed but they had never found out who had shot him, they never knew who had killed him.
         And then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX>
         he had never heard it, heard them talk about it before, so I mean he just knew, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spencer</ENAMEX> would sit, like he would be sitting in the living room a lot of times too and he would just look off into space and he would just get terrified and start screaming, and he would run to you and just cry and would be still be looking at whatever, he was just off in space like something was just scared him to death.
         And um, there was another one I was just thought about, oh horror stories, oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> always told me also about this um, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who, she got this call <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and she it, it was this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and he said, "Um, I'm lost and I can't find my way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, and can you call my mommy?"
         And, and um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> said, um, you know, "Yeah I'll call your mommy, do you know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mommy</ENAMEX>'s phone number?"
         And he um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">s</ENAMEX>, he gave, he gave, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> his, his phone number and he, she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX> where are you so I can tell your mommy where to come get you at," and the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> gave her the address of where he was and said, "Please call my mommy.
         I'm lost and I want my mommy to come get me".
         Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> called the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, the number that the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> had given her and um, the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> answered the phone, or, I believe it was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> actually who answered the phone and um, the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma'am</ENAMEX>, um, your little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> called here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>," and she said, "Your little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> just called, your little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> said that he was lost and that he couldn't find his way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, and he gave me the address of where he was and he wants y'all to come and get him."
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma'am</ENAMEX>," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> got really mad and she was really angry and she said, "My little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s dead and I cannot believe that you would pull this joke on me," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX>'am your little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> just called here and you know I would not play this joke on you."
         And she said, "Let me give you the address of where he said he was, because, you know, I would not make this up."
         And she gave the address, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> went, she gave the address, and, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> told her, she said, "That's the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we lived in, where my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> got killed at," or not had killed but I think he had died in that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or whatever, and, um, so um, the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, I guess, was just looking for his way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         Is that enough?
      
      
         Yeah, thank you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tabatha</ENAMEX> for those spooky stories.
         Now I have to drive home by myself.
         But, um,
         just wanted to mention again that that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabatha Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd</ENAMEX>, sorry I'm use to calling her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabatha Lewis</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>.
      
   
