
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hey Jessica</ENAMEX>, this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally</ENAMEX>.
         I thought I'd talk to you for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>, maybe starting about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>.
         You never got to meet my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>, neither did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, actually.
         But I had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the most awesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> in the world.
         I called my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Didad</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Didad</ENAMEX> never took a music lesson in his whole life, but he played in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>.
         That's where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> got his musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>.
         Nana was one of the sweetest, most incredibly sweet and giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the whole world.
         Little, tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, she wasn't even <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five feet</NUMEX> tall.
         She was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, which is just amazing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s world to think of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that full of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Memaw</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Pop</ENAMEX>.
         Right now I want to talk to you about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memaw</ENAMEX> that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m-e-m</ENAMEX>-a-w cap the first m and it's all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> word.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Pop</ENAMEX>, by the way, was incredibly awesome too.
         He took us out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">breakfast</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pancakes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single Sunday</TIMEX> that we were ever around him.
         He didn't take up golf until after he retired.
         He was such a fun <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
         But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Memaw</ENAMEX> is the one that used to tell stories.
         Memaw was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> lived on, well, I'm sorry, the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lived on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> worked on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>.
         He didn't own it, he just was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
         So you can imagine that they didn't have a lot of money.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memaw</ENAMEX> said she was only spanked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time in her whole life and that's when her pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> died.
         Well her pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig</ENAMEX> died because she snuck it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, took it upstairs, and gave it a bath and it died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">pneumonia</ENAMEX>.
         The only other time that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memaw</ENAMEX> said that she got into trouble was when it was her job to bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at night</TIMEX>.
         And this one particular <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> she just wasn't into it.
         You know, she just didn't feel like going up on that hill to bring those <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> down.
         But she had to, so, the obedient little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that she was, she did it anyway.
         Well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> wouldn't cooperate they just would not hurry down that hill back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>.
         She got mad at them so she tied their tails together so they would stay together and come down the hill.
         Well with their tails tied together coming down the hill along came a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and they straddled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> went to the right <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> went to the left.
         Course the tails were tied together, they got hung up, the knot wouldn't come undone but one of the tails did.
         I don't know if it's true or not but that was one of the stories she told us.
         The other story that she told us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, when we asked her about her upbringing, brought us all to tears because, like I told you, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> worked on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, they didn't have a lot of money and yet they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         That's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to feed when you don't have a lot of money.
         So, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had to walk her down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, she can remember holding his hand and walking down this dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> with a little suitcase, and in it was everything that she owned.
         And he took her to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s and she became their foster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
         I think that they actually had to do this with some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> also.
         So from then on in, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Memaw</ENAMEX> was being raised by this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> and was happy and had a good time there and a good life, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year later</TIMEX>, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> was killed in a car wreck.
         Memaw was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>, so I guess this foster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was tooling around in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model T</ENAMEX> or something, but they were killed in a car wreck.
         So then they had to find another place for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memaw</ENAMEX> to live.
         Now this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WV</ENAMEX> and I don't know how they found this next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, but there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MD</ENAMEX> that wanted to adopt her.
         So off she went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MD.</ENAMEX>
         And it was a wonderful, wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who met her at the train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, took her to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         She said she had never seen anything this big in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, I'm sorry, in her life as his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         She walked in the front door and there was this great big tile floor, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">foyer</ENAMEX> had a huge ceiling and a spiral stairsc, staircase.
         So she climbed the spiral staircase with him to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and just couldn't believe it.
         They had dolls all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for her and a great big bed that was all hers and she really did have a wonderful life.
         This gentleman put her through nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Memaw</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>, was working in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, and was taking care of this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in particular, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had just given birth to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> and had complications.
         So in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weeks</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> that she was ministering to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> actually, she was also getting to meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and it was, and was, becoming involved with them.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> died.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, who she later married, and they raised these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> like their own in addition to the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that they had.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memaw</ENAMEX> had to quit driving once she had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of her own because they cried every time she took, drove, drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         So she never drove again.
         She died when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">96</NUMEX>, as did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nana</ENAMEX>, and both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfathers</ENAMEX> died of heart problems when they were each <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">72</NUMEX>, that's kind of amazing.
         So that's one little story for you.
         Now I can tell you about the story, I can tell you the story about how I met your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.
         I was playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Charlotte Indoor Tennis Club</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Nyy</ENAMEX>, that's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-y-y.</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra</ENAMEX> now lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX>.
         Well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra</ENAMEX> and I were getting ready for a tournament and we were practicing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Pennington</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Calman</ENAMEX>, I think.
         And there was other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there, I didn't know anybody except for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>.
         Well there was this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> out there, who was really cute, that had twinkly blue eyes and he was playing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> next to us.
         And I was in one of my little phases where I really didn't want to have anything to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> because I'd just had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really horrible</TIMEX> experience and it just, I didn't have room for it in my life right then, but I did think he was cute and I asked her who he was.
         And she told me.
         Well, we played tennis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next week</TIMEX>.
         The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time we played was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, then we played again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next Monday</TIMEX>, and low and behold there he was again, although he wasn't on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> right next to me, but I noticed him, and I noticed he kept looking over at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, but I wasn't going to make eye contact because that was flirtatious and I was way too shy to be flirtatious.
         So we finished playing and I watched him walk behind our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and onto the common area and speak to someone.
         And I still wouldn't make eye contact with him.
         But I still asked her who he was.
         Well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week later</TIMEX> I get a phone call at work from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Pennington</ENAMEX> who asked me if I would like to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, mixed doubles with she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> against me and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Lowrance</ENAMEX>, and I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who is Hugh Lowrance?</ENAMEX>"
         She said.
         "Don't you remember?
         That's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at the tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">club</ENAMEX> that you asked me about."
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX> have you called him?"
         And she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, I haven't called him yet."
         But I think she told him that she hadn't called me yet either, so I don't really know who she called <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.
         Anyway, I said, "Sure, I would love to," and he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yep</ENAMEX>, that'd be great."
         So I show up at the tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night before six o'clock</TIMEX> so that I won't be late.
         Didn't want to be too fashionable, you know.
         Well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was casual day at the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> where I worked, so I had on my nice little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linen shorts</ENAMEX> and my nice little shoes and a cute little top.
         Well the parking lot where I worked was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two and a half</NUMEX> blocks away, so we would oftentimes wear our tennis shoes in because that's a long hike in heels or whatever, and I had walked in, in tennis shoes, my tennis shoes that I was going to play in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> and promptly left them under my desk downtown.
         So here I stand at the tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, looking oh-so-cute dressed all in white with a little white vest, who I've never met, and we're talking like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little magpies, and I said, "We have a problem."
         He said, "Yeah, I see the door to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> is locked."
         I said, "Well we have a bigger problem than that."
         He said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What's that?</ENAMEX>"
         I said, "I don't have any shoes."
         He said, "What do you mean you don't have any shoes<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX> I left them under my desk at work."
         He said, "That's no problem.
         We'll go get it.
         Where do you work?"
         I said, "Downtown."
         He said, "We have a problem."
         See he hates to go downtown.
         So he put me in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and we went to the nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omega Sports</ENAMEX> and bought me some shoes.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that waited on me, I was able to tell her, "This is a blind date.
         I've made a hell of an impression already I know," as I said tongue in cheek.
         And she said, "Oh, my gosh!
         Well he's cute so," she made sure I had hangers in the dressing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and I tried on a pair of shoes and they fit, put on my tennis clothes and we were back at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX>.
         That was impressive.
         But we had a neat opportunity to talk in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and we talked and laughed `cause we were both kind a nervous and kind of silly, and we go out to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> and we're still being silly and talking and laughing and playing against our good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>, who we never should've lost a game to as we proceeded to lose the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> set because your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> couldn't keep the ball on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, basically.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ha</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ha</NUMEX>, but I know he'll say the same thing.
         Anyway we decided we weren't going to lose the match, so we settled down and we played and won and had a good time, and I thought, "Well cool.
         I bet we go out to eat now.
         It is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight thirty or nine</TIMEX>."
         But nope, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> goes, beelines it right for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> gets in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and leaves and doesn't even ask for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX>.
         Well it wasn't that unusual that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> didn't ask for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX>, but I knew we'd had a really good time.
         So I was kind of, um, surprised.
         But my little antennas perked up and I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girlfriend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>," you can put that in quotes because that's what I was thinking.
         So I decided to make him tell me that he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>.
         Actually, I was just looking for another excuse to call him.
         So I picked up the phone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks later</TIMEX> and called him and told him that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jazz Charlotte</ENAMEX> was going on, nope it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz Fest</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> I worked for had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle bus</ENAMEX>, which it did, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> signed up for it and you got to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz Fest</ENAMEX>, and it was a lot a fun and, and I said, "I don't know your status.
         I don't know if you're dating anybody at the time, but if you're not and you'd like to go, I would love for you to be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>."
         And he said, "Well you know, I would really love to go, I really mean that, but I am dating somebody right now and I can't."
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX> that's all right, but I had a great time playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> and maybe I'll see you over at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> sometime."
         And he said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cool</ENAMEX>."
         And I hung up the phone thinking, "Darn I wish could meet somebody just like him that didn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>."
         But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six weeks later</TIMEX> I get this phone call from someone asking for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chrissy Everett</ENAMEX> identifying himself as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Connors</ENAMEX> and it was, guess who?
         And he said there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, an anniversary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that he worked with and did I want to go, and he was sorry that he didn't get to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jazz Fest with me</ENAMEX>, but he had been dating somebody and it was somebody that he used to be engaged to and then wasn't engaged to and they had reconciled, but he knew it wasn't going work out, but yet they were still dating when I played tennis with him but, they're not dating anymore.
         And I said, "Well cool."
         So we went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and we had a great time and we've pretty much been together ever since.
         And I bet I've talked for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight minutes</TIMEX>, but I hope you enjoyed my stories.
         Talk to you soon.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bye</ENAMEX>.
      
   
