
   
   
      
         OK, um, just to give you a little bit background on my heritage my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, but I am a born native of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, if you can't tell by the accent.
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I have traveled back and forth to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, the story that comes to mind the most for me, um, I guess in my life, is the story of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> who's now presently <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85 years old</TIMEX>, and actually, had flew down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Friday</TIMEX> after the tragedy, so it was, um, I think it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">fourteenth</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> she flew by herself from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to here to visit us, and is still here until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 24th</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, her story actually is what impacted me the most in my life, um, when I think of the things she went through growing up, and, um, how my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was conceived and everything on that nature, which it gets a little personal, but it's, you don't think of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> telling you that, but she did.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was in the error of the war, and so they were constantly moving.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Italian</TIMEX>, full-blooded <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>, and he was, um, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> of war for a while.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he did escape and get out, and so him and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> were like, he would travel, get missing, and come back, you know, but he would always be back with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and everything.
         And there was one particular incident where they were, um, there were bombs going off, because again, this was like in the war with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> and so forth.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and they thought, they literally thought they were going to die because they were on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> that they were on wasn't hooked to the caboose.
         So when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> pulled off to get from away from all of the stuff that was going on, they were left behind.
         So they thought they were going die, so they decided, I guess
         , what better way to die than, um, to make love on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, and that's how my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> actually was conceived, was on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> had told me about that, you know, the different things they went through with that.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, OK, um back to me.
         When I grew up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> taught us <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.
         It was me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, and she taught us <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> before she thought us <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and I remember as a child mixing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> languages, like I might say a sentence in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and throw in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, um, because we learn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> in the household, and then <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         And all my life she constantly brought us back and forth from, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> to, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, um, to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there.
         So I still am fluent in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and I am very thankful for that, um, because recently, when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> came to visit, she has never had heart trouble, and, um, never had anything go wrong with her heart or anything, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, while she was here, which was, here recently her heart rate dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">real</NUMEX> low, so we had to, um, rush her to the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and this was something very scary for her because she doesn't speak any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>.
         She speaks like one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> words of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>, um, not to mention, she doesn't like to, going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, so it was like we had to hit her over the head to bring her there.
         But, um, we finally got her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and they, um, ended up doing surgery on her that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>, and placing a, putting a pace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX>, um, so for her, you know, to be here, you know, and get treatment under, under those circumstances was kind of scary, but she's doing better.
         OK, now she's supposed to still be going back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 24th</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and when they say it rains, it pours because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, um, recently moved back in with me, but I don't know how long that will be, but, um, she did and she had been up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> from, she had gotten up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> at like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five o'clock in the morning</TIMEX>.
         By the time I had got home from work, and so forth, it was like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 o'clock at night</TIMEX> and she was extremely tired, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who constantly has to go and do something, she can't sit still, it drives her crazy.
         So she thinks she's going to make, you know, she moved all her stuff back in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and she thinks she's going to clean it up all in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, so my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is like a tornado hit it by this time, but, you know, I'm fine.
         I haven't said anything about it because, you know, I know it's going take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>, but she wants to do it all in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, so she's still up at like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 at night</TIMEX>, going back and forth between the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX>, which, you know, in the<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">, in</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">attic</ENAMEX> is in the top of my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         You have to climb a ladder, a pull-down ladder, to get, to it, and I was telling her, you know, she'd needed to be careful, she needed to go to bed because she was tired, and, furthermore there is like a hairline crack in my ceiling in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>, um, where apparently she had stepped wrong or stepped on the wrong place or something before, and it created a hairline crack, and I was telling, and I stressed to her, you know, "Be careful," you know, "don't step in this area."
         There's a hairline crack in my ceiling.
         So I'm sleeping, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>, you know, it's past <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>, and all of a sudden, I hear this big loud noise
         , and I look up and she's hanging through my ceiling.
         
         And here's her feet dangling, and, of course, it startles me, but I'm a very quick reactor, so I jump out of bed, and I was pushing her feet up so she wouldn't fall all the way through my ceiling, um, but, mind you this is after I told her to specifically not to walk in this area, but I tell you if, you know, anything about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, it's like I can talk to the wall better than I can talk to her and tell her something.
         But, so then, if that wasn't bad enough, um, we were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and my instincts told me not to let her drive my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, but I'm thinking, you know, if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> can drive my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> from time to time, then why can't I let my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> drive my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> from time to time?
         Dumb question because I know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and I know how she drives and she's doesn't, she's not careful but I'm thinking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         OK, so I'm thinking <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 minutes</TIMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, what can happen?
         Well she's gone, and no sooner than she comes back, what do she tell me?
         "Oh I hit something."
         She hit something.
         So not only has she torn a hole in my ceiling, which still isn't fixed, by the way, but now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is all dented up.
         
         So I'm just like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, by the grace of God, just let me get through this."
         But, um, you know, she felt real bad about it but this was after I specifically told her.
         I'm like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mommy</ENAMEX>, you know you're real emotional right know," I'm saying, you know, you know, "upset, and be extremely careful, what you're doing, you know, when you drive my car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>," and she said, "OK, OK."
         And then she comes back and she was like, "Don't ever let me drive your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> again," and I was like, "You do not have to worry."
         
      
   
