
   
   
      
         Hi my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Manser</ENAMEX>.
         I was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warren</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is actually from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX> and I'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s side and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when I was young my, the story that stands out most in my mind is this story that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would tell me that he learned from, I think it was one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Joe or Uncle Johnny</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, it was a story about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jehilehi</ENAMEX>.
         And this is obviously just some made up name my, uh, great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> came up with, but, and my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> loved these stories as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> himself and related them to me when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>.
         And--
      
      
         Sorry, can I just ask you how old you were when you heard these stories?
      
      
         Ah.
         Well I guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> started telling me these stories when I was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three, four</TIMEX> up until whenever, still, I mean sometimes he'll be joking around at the dinner table and still tell me these stories.
         But, um, and the thing was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jehilehi</ENAMEX> was this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, this brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and he had this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX>.
         And
         he, he would always be saving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> from some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bear</ENAMEX> or something or some, some, some wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>.
         And he would, you know, at the climax of the story my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would, you know, the stories were always varied and they were improvised never the same plot but he would, you know, get on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> and speed away into the mountains and fight this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX>, and save the damsel in distress, and they were just pretty exciting stories, especially when you are a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, you know?
         And then, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, I remember her.
         She would read me a lot of books actually and, and she would sing me a lot of songs.
         She wouldn't actually make up stories out of the blue, but, um, and the songs that she would sing, um, I can't remember the name of this one but I always remember it was about.
         I sort of remember the words, but she told me them when I was very little, like, I don't know, like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX>, maybe even younger and it was always about how, um, her and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> loved me so much and there was always, I don't know.
         See there was candy in the story.
         I just remember, like, it about, it was being about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX> and sweetness stuff like this.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, sorry I'm being vague, but, and, um, she would read me, um, a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grimm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy tales</ENAMEX> often, and the one I remember most is, um, the one about the, oh what was it, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the, hang on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hansel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gretel</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I now recall the stories she would read to me.
         It was the one about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, the dancing shoes, or something like this these princesses had, uh, cast a spell, cast on them and they had to dance <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> with these shoes and until the shoes wore out and their feet were all sore.
         And then, finally I, I forget how the story went, but I always remember her reading me this one story and I just loved it.
         And she, oh well this, this I guess both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> imparted to me was this, this album they that we used to have.
         It was, um, actually the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hansel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gretel</ENAMEX> and they, I think I would like listen to it everyday because I just loved it and they would put it on the record <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and, ah, I would sit in a little rocking chair that we had in our living room and listen to it, and I was kind of scared at the part where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witch</ENAMEX> was going to put them in the oven, but
         , and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> would come in and he'd sit with me and comfort me.
         But I loved it so much even though it was scary to me, I don't know why, but, um, and also, actually my grandma, which I call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Situ</ENAMEX>, and that's "grandma" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>.
         She, um, told me stories about when she was young.
         When I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> I would ask her like, you know, where, where she grew up and what it was like in her neighborhood, and she would tell me that, oh when she was little that all of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and all of her, she had a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and stuff.
         They all lived on the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Youngstown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>.
         And back then, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Youngstown</ENAMEX>, supposedly she tells me, was a much nicer place than it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>.
         You know, crime <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of the world.
         But, um, she, she would tell me about how, the kind of trouble they would get into, and, and how strict her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were.
         And if she, she would go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and buy them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>.
         And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> she went to buy them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and she came back with the incorrect change and so her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> got very angry with her and made her go back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and, and I guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had given her too much money back and she hadn't told him that he had made a mistake and so she got in trouble way, way too much trouble, you know, unnecessary trouble, and she had to walk all the way back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, and I don't know, she just made it out that to seem like in a lot of ways, back then, times were, seemed so much better, and yet so much harsher in a lot of ways.
         And supposedly, you know, it snowed more back then and, ah, but, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was closer knit, I guess, so, you know, pros and cons in every, every case but and my, my grandpa, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jidu</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Arabic</ENAMEX>.
         He told me stories about when he was in the war he flew a fighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>, and he, well when I was young he never really got much into the details, being as I was little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, but he would tell me, um, about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> he met, um, during the war and some of the turmoil and stress it caused him and, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side, as, I guess you can tell now, is obviously a lot closer than on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s side, ah, because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s side, well his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did and, and also my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> died when I was too young really to remember anything they would have said.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so ,so also, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, they spent a lot of time with me when I was little and they, they made up little tales about
         my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> has, has a very imaginative and inventive kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and they would always be making up these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and telling me stories about them.
         Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Fredimecusson</ENAMEX> and, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um, Connie, Connie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bujane</ENAMEX> and um
         um
         , oh let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Rasselbossum</ENAMEX> and--
      
      
         And how old were you when they told you these stories?
      
      
         Well I was, the age at which they told me stories, just, it varied.
         I mean it was really pretty much all through my childhood, you know, up until I reached a certain age to where I didn't find it so interesting anymore, but, um, I guess it would be somewhere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 10 or 12</TIMEX> that they would tell me these stories, and, um, it usually would be at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and we'd be back in this little bedroom I always would sleep in.
         And when I'd stay the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at my grandparents <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it'd be a holiday and all the aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> of mine would be at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and they were always very loving and, and, you know, actually, um, some of the stories I remember very much so were the ones that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Dave</ENAMEX> would tell me.
         We'd, we'd build a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bonfire</ENAMEX> outside because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> they lived out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and we'd build a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bonfire</ENAMEX> and he would always tell these scariest ghost stories and he would make everyone of them up and they were so incredibly intricate.
         The plots, I just, I just remember, just being so well told.
         We would sit around the fireplace, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy</ENAMEX>, and he would tell me these stories about, you know, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>.
         I remember this one where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> they were, um, they were driving down the road, and actually I think this one might be a generic tale, but, uh, um they went to a gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> or something, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> gets out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to pump <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s been sitting in there but it's been a while.
         So she looks around for him in the parking lot and she doesn't see him and she's worried, you know?
         Because he's spent, you know, going on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes and minutes</TIMEX> now.
         And, um, so she gets out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to find him and the gas station <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX> runs out of the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the, um</ENAMEX>, the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and he tells her not to get back in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         He's like yelling at her, "Don't get in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>!
         Don't get in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>!
         !" And she's, she's scared because this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s all frantic and so she runs around and gets in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s side and she decides to drive off.
         Well she's driving down the road and she going down this dark country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
         And he said the name of it was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Duck Creek Road</ENAMEX>, which was actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> lived on.
         He's trying to scare us even more.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, um, stops underneath this tree to catch her breath she's really nervous and scared.
         She doesn't know where her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> is and she hears this after a little while she's sitting with her head on the steering wheel she, she, she hears this thumping on the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Sorry, can you just give me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one second</TIMEX>?
         
      
      
         So she gets out to check what this noise is and she's, she's looking on the car she sees nothing, and so finally, she sort of warily looks up and sees her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> hanging from a tree limb and his leg is brushing against the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and she's, she's so obviously scared at this point.
         She screams she runs down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> just to get as far away from the scene as she can, and, honestly, after that I don't remember what happens but something
         happens.
         And anyways, the point is my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> told these stories so much better, and he, he, just the way he talked and the way he enunciated certain words, and the way and the level and pitch at which he would speak was just he was amazing.
         So, uh, thank you, thank you for this time for listening to me ramble about my stories.
         I hope you have a wonderful, wonderful day.
         Thank you.
         Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bye</ENAMEX>.
      
   
