
   
   
      
         Female Voice <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">START OF TAPE 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDE A</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>.
         My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin McCloskey</ENAMEX> and, um, I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years old</TIMEX> and, um, I've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> since I was born, and, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KY</ENAMEX>, and I have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> up there that, that have some pretty crazy stories that, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> used to tell me about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, which was, he was autistic and, um, he did some funny stuff.
         Like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> got a doll for her birthday, or something, and she wouldn't let him play with it.
         He kept bugging her and bugging her and she just wouldn't let him mess with it, you know.
         And so, he threatened, he said, "I'm going to go sit in the fire!"
         And she said, "Go ahead!"
         So he goes and sits down inside the fireplace with the fire on.
         He got <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> degree burns all up his back, went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, you know, he's pretty crazy.
         He keeps a goat in his front yard because he doesn't like to mow the lawn.
         It's pretty funny.
         I mean, it's nothing to laugh about, but, you know.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he can play the harmonica like it ain't nobody's business.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, that's why they say he's retarded, but I really think he's autistic because he's really good with musical instruments.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, they tell me pretty crazy stories.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> said when she was little she had, um, she had a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> and every, everyday it would run around the yard.
         It would just run and run.
         And she watched it everyday, run, run, run, run, run until it couldn't run anymore.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just fall</TIMEX> over on the steps, you know.
         And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> she was mowing the lawn and they used to have a little push <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mower</ENAMEX> instead of, um, like an electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mower</ENAMEX>, and, um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> hit it and the dog split in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>.
         Like straight down the middle.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, she was crying and everything and she took, I forgot what the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> was called, but it was that stingy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> that really stung when they would put it against you, and, um she poured that all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and wrapped it up in bandages and, um, she put it in a box and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> she heard it barking.
         So she ran over to the box and, um, when she saw the box she, uh, she saw that she had put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> on backwards so its legs were facing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different directions.
         And then, because she was trying to rush it, you know, trying to keep him alive, she said he would run on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two feet</NUMEX>, he would run around the whole yard, whole yard and as soon as he would get tired he would jump, do a flip, and go on the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> feet and just keep on running.
         That's pretty funny.
         I don't think it was true though.
         And, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, he used to be very wealthy before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> and, uh, this one time his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> played the world champion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billiards player</ENAMEX> at that time.
         And they, they played <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> games and he cleaned him out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> times, you know.
         The other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> didn't even get to touch the ball.
         So, but, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> and, um, she used to tell me when they were little there used to be a creek over by their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and, um, she used to run, they used to get vines off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and just, they would swing on them, and like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>, just being stupid, would break their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> or break their leg, break fingers or something and go crying home.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are just, they would never show them, they would always have the perfect swing but they would always point to a bad one and they would just cut them down and just have it, and everybody would just keep breaking their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and stuff and, um, I don't know.
         I just thought that was pretty cool.
         There's no real end to that story.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I don't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story in particular that they told me, I mean they're kind of short but I can just tell you a bunch of short ones.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when I was little my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> used to tell me this story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> that lived on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pirate ship</ENAMEX>.
         His name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ketchup</ENAMEX> and, um, everyday the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> would always lag behind, you know, he would always drag when the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> were running real all fast.
         And they would always go, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ketchup</ENAMEX>!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ketchup</ENAMEX>!"
         And this happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX>.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> kept getting, you know, he was tired of being left behind all the time, he never got to do any of the fun <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> stuff.
         So, um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> he got roller skates and, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> they were like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ketchup</ENAMEX>!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ketchup</ENAMEX>!"
         And he went and he put on his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roller skates</ENAMEX> and he beat everybody back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pirate ship</ENAMEX>.
         And then they were like, "Wait up, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ketchup</ENAMEX>!"
         And, uh, now that I think of it, that wasn't the greatest story but I thought it was cool.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandma</ENAMEX> always said, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> they would always, they said, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> said that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> were just like the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> ever.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would tell me as soon as they got done, as soon as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> they would just start going at it.
         They would pull each other's hair and fight and cuss and yell at each other, you know, fighting, and, uh, my grandma was always, um, she always thought they were real nice.
         They still fight to this day, not bad but they'll argue every so often.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and my other grandpa, um, he used to tell me about how he used to fly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-52s</ENAMEX>, and he said, uh, he had to escape <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> times.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> time he went and, hold on, sorry, anyways he would, he told us he had to parachute out of the plane <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three or four</NUMEX> times, I can't remember.
         But, um, he said he used to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that could speak <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and he jumped out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> and he landed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Army</ENAMEX> and, um, he um-
      
      
         Who you talking to?
      
      
         -he had this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that could speak <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and, um, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, you know, he fell in with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and the he was like, he said something in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> because he thought they were the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> and he was like, "Yeah, I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>.
         I'm just s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, spying on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>."
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tried to attack him because he was, um, because he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.
         But, um, my grandpa he jumped out of a parachute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that his boots were too big when he got them but they were like, "Wear them anyways!"
         When he jumped out of the plane his boots fell off!
         But see that's pretty serious because when you land he could break his ankles easy!
         But, uh, lucky for him, he fell in like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vineyard</ENAMEX> and fell into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and it was in the, I want to say it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX>, or maybe it was in the equivalent of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and, uh, they hid him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or four weeks</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, um, just to save him.
         But he used to tell me often about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, which, who was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green Beret</ENAMEX>, and he, um, he, everyday they would take him <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five miles</NUMEX> out or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six miles</NUMEX> out and just drop him in a different place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX>.
         They had to find their way back to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and he said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time he got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX> purple hearts, but, um, I remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> would tell me, I thought it was pretty cool, but, um, he um, he um, he was fighting, you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and, uh, not the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>, but, you know, he's fighting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon</ENAMEX>, him and a few of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Green Beret</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and um, he went and, I'm not sure if this was the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>, but, um, I mean, not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.
         But, um, whatever happened, he was, his whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> went down and he was around quite a few dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and he pulled a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> over him.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saw him and so they shot a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> through the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and it, um, it went through his mouth and, but it didn't break any of his teeth or break his jaw, it just went through his mouth and he didn't make a sound.
         And that's how he escaped.
         So I thought that was pretty neat.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I don't really know.
         There's a lot of stories that he used to tell me, but, um, I remember hearing when I went to a carnival <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, a story that was pretty good.
         It was, it was about, if I can remember correctly, it was about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'s tail.
         And it was something like, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taily-Po</ENAMEX> or something and whatever would happen is whoever, uh, I don't even remember, I think it was like who somebody cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'s tail off and he ate it and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> he would hear, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taily-Po, Taily-Po</ENAMEX>!
         I want my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taily-Po</ENAMEX>!"
         And finally <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> he woke up and his belly had been cut open, but, uh, I don't think that's how it went because I was little when I heard it.
         Maybe I made up my own things too.
         I do that, I make up my own stories sometimes.
         You know, I'll do something like I was in a baseball field <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>.
         Oh!
         I remember what I used to do when I was little!
         I used to, the stories I used to tell.
         The stories I used to tell my babysitter was stuff like, uh, well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in gym, the gym <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> made everybody do back flips and I was the only one who could do it all the way around the gym when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX>, I mean, and, um, and I thought she believed me, but, um, I just hadn't learned about sarcasm yet.
         But, um, also another story that I used to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but wasn't true, was that when I was little my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, my little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> ran me over and stepped on my nose and gave me a scar on the side of my nose because I couldn't think of any way to do it, any cool way of making my scar, of how it got there, and so I just made up stories.
         I did that a lot.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I used to, um, I used to like hearing stories from, mostly from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.
         I heard some stories from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> about sports, but, um he used to tell me about when he played <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>.
         Some of the stuff, I believed it all, but I mean some of stuff, it was like, you know, you want to make yourself sound better than you really were sometimes.
         I do it all the time.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> I got a hit in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game.
         It was a hit, but I just, it could have been counted as an error or a hit, and I just made up a story about that.
         So, but, um, uh, I don't know too many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> stuff, I heard some stuff about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, oh yeah!
         I remember this story when I was in pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that I really liked!
         It was about this, this, uh, little guy and his name was like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tee</ENAMEX> or something, I don't remember.
         And he, um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> he was walking with his, uh, walking with scissors and he snipped his finger and cut his finger and it hurt, and, uh, he would never let his, um, he would never his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> let him get his hair cut because he was scared that it would hurt too bad.
         And I always thought that was pretty cool.
         But, um, I don't know, I always liked ghost stories.
         I remember when I was at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Camp Clear Creek</ENAMEX> when I was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cub Scouts</ENAMEX>, there used to be a, there, there's the lake <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bebe Parker</ENAMEX>, it's more like a big pond but we called it, it was a lake.
         It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bebe Parker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bebe Parker</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that, um, got sucked into a drainage pipe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and, um, he died.
         And, uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> I'd go there, they would take the whole troop out there and I'd be so scared!
         And they'd be out there, they'd be like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bebe Parker</ENAMEX>!
         Are you there?"
         And then you would always hear, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Help me</ENAMEX>!
         Help me!"
         And I was really scared.
         I was always so scared of that.
         And I never knew how they did it!
         And I always thought it was really scary, and like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> we would run down and try to talk to him, try to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bebe Parker</ENAMEX>, but, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bebe Parker</ENAMEX> wouldn't ever talk to us back.
         And we always thought he must be sleeping.
         And then when we were, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webelos</ENAMEX> or whatever, they're called the highest you could be in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cub Scouts</ENAMEX>, they would they gave us a, uh, they let all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webelos be Bebe Parker</ENAMEX> and all it was, was a big storm drain behind the, there was like this big opening down the hill that they couldn't see from the hill they couldn't see it from up there and you just yelled into it, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Help me</ENAMEX>!
         It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bebe Parker</ENAMEX>!
         Help me!
         Save me!"
         You know, and stuff like that.
         We would scare all the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
         And I was so amazed because I thought it was the coolest thing.
         And we used to go snipe hunting when we would go talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bebe Parker</ENAMEX>.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scout leaders</ENAMEX> would go, "I see a snipe!"
         and he would jump on it and he would shake the bag, like the big trash bag, around.
         Everybody would be yelling and screaming, "Agh!
         It's a snipe!"
         And then, um, it was pretty cool, I used to always try to catch snipes too.
         I wasn't very smart when I was little.
         I wasn't very, I don't know, I was book smart but I wasn't too clever.
         I believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, silly stuff too much.
         But, um, eh, I don't know, I used to like to read the stories about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berenstain Bears</ENAMEX> a lot.
         I liked the one about where, were at, or he, where they went to the movies and there was, they went to the ballet movie
         .
         They, they, um, went to the, I forgot what it was.
         It was like, I guess it was equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Rangers</ENAMEX> pretty much, and it was like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Ranger</ENAMEX> movie, but it wasn't.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um the</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> bear, they both had nightmares about each other's stuff and it crossed over.
         It was really neat but, um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>.
         My name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin McCloskey</ENAMEX>, I was, I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years old</TIMEX> and I was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         That's all I have to say!
      
   
