
   
   
      
         I'm going to, um, tell you something about my, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, whose name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX>, and, ah, I, I, I'll give a little bit of background, just, it needs to, it needs to be put into a little bit of a context.
         Ah, I was very, very fond of my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, um, she was, she was a very beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, both physically and, and spiritually.
         She was very tall, she was very elegant, um, and she also just, she had a, a radiance about her, it was really, ah, irresistible.
         She had an irresistible quality, she just drew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to her.
         And, um, she was, her, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, was highly neurotic, dramatic, dissatisfied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, who had been married a couple of times before she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and, uh, when she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, he had, he was, he was a<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, a</ENAMEX>, a very sort, ah, of reclusive, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>.
         He was a philosopher and also a psy, uh, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX>.
         And he, he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at, at, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunter</ENAMEX>.
         But he came from a, an extremely exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, um, they were, his name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston Welch</ENAMEX>, and it, it's a very old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingston's</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welch's</ENAMEX>.
         And when they combined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, they, they, ah, he was sort of their, the legacy is in him, was that he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livingston Welch</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
         Anyway, he was a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Livingston</ENAMEX>.
         And a brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, uh, but, incredibly eccentric.
         And he had been in love with my, with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> since they were very little.
         They grew up on, on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>, sort of in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Gatsby</ENAMEX>-land.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um, in Sand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX>.
         My, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were, were in a little area called, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plandome</ENAMEX>, which is next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manhassett</ENAMEX>, which is right next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX> is, is perhaps where the, the richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> live.
         And, um, they, ah, they knew each other and he was in love with her, but she wouldn't have anything to do with him.
         She, because he was, he was a nerd.
         
         A very rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerd</ENAMEX>, but a nerd!
         
         And um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were probably nouveau riche in, in, in their estimation.
         My, my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were both <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>.
         They didn't meet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, they met here, but both, both of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> had immigrated to this, to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and, um, they, my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> was in banking, and, um, they, he made obviously a very nice income.
         But not quite on the level of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welch's</ENAMEX>, um, who subsequently lost all of their money, which is always the way it is, in life.
         Ah, but, anyway, so there was this whole social thing.
         And they were, they were a part of a social milieu that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were close to but not quite in.
         And, um, ultimately when my, when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> finally went through her other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>, ah, she decided that really she was ready for some social status, and perhaps some money, and so she acquiesced to, to marry my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>!
         
         And, they had a very peculiar marriage.
         And, at some point along the way, and I don't know the historical details, they, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welch's</ENAMEX> did lose all of their money, and they, they had had this beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> on, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX>, um, and it was right at the very tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sand</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX> and they had an absolutely beautiful town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in, um, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">65th Street</ENAMEX>, ah, right between <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Avenue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexington Avenue</ENAMEX>, so it was the sort of the place to be, so to speak.
         And eventually they, they were, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Livingston</ENAMEX>, in his older, in his old age, was relegated to the<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
         to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> in the sub-basement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> because they sold it to, to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>, but they'd kept that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and he loved it, that was, for him that was like, that was the greatest.
         Ah, by that time, he and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> were living in, in, uh, you know, sort of, uh, uh, an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> in, on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">East 57th Street</ENAMEX> that was just one of those sort of, those little run through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>.
         And it wasn't a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, but nonetheless it was, you know, not certainly my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>'s idea of why she might have been ma, been marrying my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>
         !
         It wasn't quite what she had in mind.
         And they had also stuffed all of this really beautiful furniture, um, from all over the world into this tiny
         little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, so it was very cluttered.
         Ah, and ah, first she, she got pregnant and I don't know how they ever managed to consummate the marriage because by the time I knew them as a couple they were, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> dressed all in black and, uh, she, as I said, she was very neurotic, she was also very, very dramatic and everything was over-stated and, they obviously could, couldn't stand
         each other by this time, although they were never rude to each other, they just lived completely separate lives.
         And she hurt because she had worn really high heels, and she'd been a model when she was, she was, she had been really, stunningly beautiful, in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX>, and, um, when she had modeled.
         And uh, but she had worn these really, really high heels because she was incredibly vain, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">arches</ENAMEX> had fallen
         , so she had to wear these big, thick black shoes which she hated.
         
         So she would be sort of roaming around the, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> with all of her, her drama and her, her overstatement, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, who barely ever came home if he could help it, ah, would live in this one tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at the very, very front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> that overlooked <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">57th Street</ENAMEX>, and, uh, he had nailed down the windows because he didn't want to have any fresh air because he, he believed that fresh air was really bad for you.
         
         But he basically spent all this time in the, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> in the sub-basement of what had once been his family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         And he had a, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>, um, who everybody knew about, ah, who sort of took ca, took care of him and looked after him and adored him, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> couldn't be bothered with him.
         Anyway, out of, out of this wonderful marriage he'd produced these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, one of whom was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX> who, as I said, just was this incredibly beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
         And, ah, my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are, are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Episcopalian</ENAMEX>, hardly practicing, but nonetheless that's my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> had been a very, uh, very religious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and she, she was, she made sure that, that all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christened</ENAMEX>, and, um, and that certainly my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I were, um, Confirmed
         .
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welch's</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>.
         And, ah, for some reason, and I don't know who made this decision, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre, both Pamela</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX>, my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>, were sent to, ah, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrytown</ENAMEX> and, um, they for some reason, according to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, who was very hysterical about the whole thing, they always recruit some of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX> according to her
         .
         So, as I said, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX> was extremely beautiful, very elegant, and all of these things, so she was not perceived as, as being a candidate for quote, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> put it, "to escape from the world," but to be out there in the world with all of her, her charms and graces and, and what have you.
         And, ah, anyway, she, she decide,
         she said that she was, that she made this decision that she was going to go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX>, and become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>.
         And, of course, everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was absolutely hysterical and put out about this, but my, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, her, her, her, her response to the whole thing was that she needed to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>, meaning my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> needed to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> to get her over the<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
         the pain and the loss of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> having made this decision.
         So, uh, but anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX> was really, she, she, she was a, she really believed that that's what she wanted and that was what she should do.
         And, uh, as I go along, I'll, I'll talk a little bit more about, you know, my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of this whole thing because that's part of what when I, when I think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deirdre</ENAMEX> and I think of the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deirdre</ENAMEX>, some of what I try to come to terms with is why, why my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> interpreted her choice the way they did.
         But, um, because the, the general consensus was that she was too scared or somehow felt insecure and she couldn't be a part of the world they never, they never said, "Oh, she, she did this because this is what she believes."
         You know, it was simply that, "Oh, she doesn't know what she's doing, and she's misguided, and she's scared," that was the general consensus.
         Anyway, she became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>, and, um, I would go and visit her.
         And, um, she was, she became, she was a teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX>, she taught in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marymount</ENAMEX> was the name of the, uh, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX> and, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and they had a, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrytown</ENAMEX> but they also had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>.
         She ultimately ended up teaching art, because she was a very, very gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, um, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marymount</ENAMEX>.
         And when I would go over, first she was at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrytown</ENAMEX>, initially, and I would go over and I would visit her from time to time, and it was always just a joy to, you know, to see her.
         And at that time, this was, this was before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>, and she was fully garbed and it was, and it was strange, because I had been very close to her, I was very little when, but she was very, very kind to me, and she was always very interested in me and would take me places, and include me and so it was strange for me to, you know, suddenly see her in, in, in, um, all in black, ah, with profuse robes, and, she had a<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, the, um</ENAMEX>, head dress was very, it was, it was shaped like this, it was, so you, um, really could not see very much of her face, so that was, that was a very strange thing for me, but she always seemed happy.
         So in that context, I never questioned it.
         You know, it was just wonderful to see her.
         And, um, and then there was a part of it too where I felt like she looked beautiful in wearing what she was wearing.
         I mean they were, they were in some way just, the garb is very medieval, and it's, it's, it is certainly more interesting than some of what we wear, you know, in, in that sense.
         But, so there, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, there was that kind of, uh, a sense of it was strange but it was also interesting, you know.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, at some point she was sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>.
         And at that time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and I, and I am not very good on dates and, and, um, historical happenings, but at that time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX> was, was in, um, was in control in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and they were, there was, there was, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> was not, um, was definitely repressed, and there was a lot of political things happening.
         But that's where she was, and so there the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was obviously concerned because she was in a, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that was under a lot of strife and conflict and, and, she was an in a part of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> that was definitely, not only not supported, but was actually persecuted.
         And, um, she at that time she contracted <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, but nobody knew about it because they, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th, th</ENAMEX>, the situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> was, was such that there wasn't a lot of medical, um, assistance for, for nuns and other, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX>.
         So it, it went undiagnosed.
         By the time she came back to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, um,
         she wa, she was diagnosed, and she had cancer of the uterus and she was completely, I mean she just was, she was very, very sick.
         So they had to operate and they ha, they took out everything.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and uh, but of course, you know, it would be obviously more
         of a tragedy if she was somebody who was planning to get married and have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         So she was, I think that she was, she was comfortable with it in the sense that she, it wasn't part of her destiny, so to speak, but it was, it was still a very traumatic thing to experience
         .
         And then, she, she was, she, she was, because she was convalescing, they, she stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, they, they didn't send her overseas again.
         And she, she was teaching at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marymount</ENAMEX> and I would go in and visit her.
         And, um, she, she was also taking classes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>, and I was taking classes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>, so we would pass in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>, and she would show me what she was doing, and, um, and as I say, she was a very gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, and she loved teaching and again, she still seemed very, you know I never got a sense with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX> of there may have been discontent
         , there may have been a sense
         
            that maybe she had made wrong choices, but, um, she never expressed that.
         At some point this was, right about the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>, because she started to wear different clothes, and it was, it was very, um, it was very discreet, I mean, she didn't suddenly just go out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomingdale's</ENAMEX> and buy a whole lot of, you know,
         fashionable clothes, but, when I would go in to visit with my, um, with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, and if she was, if she was there, she was dressed in, in, um, very, very, uh, very elegant but understated, you know, suits and things like that, but she definitely was no longer in the full garb.
         And, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> at that time had, was diagnosed as having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung cancer</ENAMEX> and she was very sick.
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX> took, was, took a leave from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX>, she was given, um, permission, to, um, for temporary leave, and I don't know logistically how that works, but she was, she was allowed to go home and, and be with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, to help her, um, go through, she was going to die, I mean everybody knew that she was going to die, but to be with her through that whole period, and, um, she did have some operations.
         And, um, at that point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX> made the decision, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> did die, and it was, it was all very traumatic, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was very sick, he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">manic depressive</ENAMEX>, so we were going through all of that, and he was very upset with the medical profession for how they were treating my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX>, and this and that.
         But anyway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre</ENAMEX> made the decision that she wasn't going to go back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX>.
         And she had already taken final vows, so it was a big, it was a huge thing, for her to make that decision.
         But she did.
         I never sat down and had discussions with her about it, so I don't really know what was going on in her heart and in her, in her mind.
         But she made the decision that she was going to, to leave and she, and she started to, she continued to teach, she, she continued to do the things that she was always doing but she just slowly started to, to live what would be considered a normal life.
         And she started to date and, she had several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX> and, uh,
         she was, she had met this one, this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, and they were going to a, some kind of social gathering, in, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rye</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>.
         They went out and on the way back, ah, it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX>, um, they were on the, on the train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> waiting to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> back into the, into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, and this, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, who was drunk, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> went out of control and hit both of them, and they were both thrown against the, uh, the railroad tracks.
         And you know there was no train coming, but they, they hit the rails, their, and she, both of them had severe head injuries
         .
         And, um, she went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they thought his condition was much worse than her condition; they felt fairly, um,
         and I remember we got the, the phone call came, it was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, who was a, was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>, but he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neurologist psychiatrist</ENAMEX>, so um, anything to do with, with the brain and the nervous system was, um, something that he was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on, and he went over and ah,
         the prognosis at that time was that sh, they thought that she would pull out, um, but she never did.
         
         And she, she was in a coma for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, and she just continued to decline whereas this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that she was with, he, he got better, and he was really in worse condition when, when they brought him in, and yet he, he regain, he regained, and within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> he'd regained full consciousness, and he, you know, and she just, she just, um,
         she just never came back.
         And, um, I just had a, I had a feeling that she made a decision not to come back.
         And she died when we were there, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I were there and, she just suddenly just she just let go, and she just died.
         And I think she died because she knew we were there, and she made a decision for some reason that she didn't want to live in this world.
         And, um, I've often pondered that ev, you know, that
         this whole thing about, that she, that she became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> because she didn't, um, she was scared to live fully in the world.
         That there was something wrong with her, that she made that decision, that that was, that was the impression, that it was like the worst thing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could, could decide to do.
         And I, you know I, I can't ask her because she's not here, but, you know I wonder well, "Why, why was that always the interpretation?
         I mean, why wasn't, why didn't we as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> try to support her more in the decision that she made, and to see that maybe, that there was, that there was, that she wasn't trying to run away from the world but that there was some greater truth that she was somehow privy to, that she was actually running towards<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
         And, um, you know, I, I, I wrote a long poem, actually, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> page poem about this, and I, you know, I, my question to, you know, to her, would be, you know, "Were you happier when you, when you actually left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">convent</ENAMEX> and you came into a world that was just, you know
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX>, striving after money, and social status, and all of those things, I mean, was that, was that really a better choice, you know, was that really, um,
         you know, did you, did you feel more alive, making that choice, and actually dying, under those conditions?"
         
         But I can't ask her, I can only just go on asking myself, sort of rhetorically, you know, When did you feel more real?
         And then you know, the question for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is, "Why couldn't you accept her decision?
         Why couldn't you believe in what she was striving for?"
      
   
