
   
   
      
         Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wadesboro</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westburg</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Born in a cabbage patch.
      
      
         Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wadesboro</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">W-A-D-E-S-B-O</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wadesboro</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Born under a collard green.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         It's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anson County</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anson County</ENAMEX>.
         That's in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         My--
      
      
         Your earliest recollections that you remember?
      
      
         Jumping off a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Jumping?
      
      
         It gave you a sort of high.
      
      
         A tall <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well, tall to me then, but it wasn't really all that tall.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         
         Playing in the woods.
         
         Which you can't do nowadays there isn't hardly, there isn't any.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         [long pause]
      
      
         Well, what you mean?
      
      
         Well.
      
      
         What was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> like and stuff back then?
      
      
         The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one I ever saw had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird braid</ENAMEX>, with a part of the A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Model T</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         No, there was the A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         They made a funny sound, "click, click, click, click."
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         
         There was a, let's see.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> of us then, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lived with us.
         We lived in this little <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-room <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Did you have wire, electricity?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         Oh, well.
         
      
      
         They had a fireplace in that little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         It looked more like a little dollhouse then a, you know like a little playhouse or something.
         
         It had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">porches</ENAMEX> on it.
         
         And um, we had rabbits.
         Pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rabbits</ENAMEX> and I had a pet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>.
         And I taught a pet and asked her where her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> were.
         And she would take me to them.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> sold them to the grocer and I wouldn't ever eat another <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> that came from the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
         I was afraid I`d be eating my pet.
      
      
         I don't--
      
      
         That's right.
         
         I was afraid I would be eating my pet.
         And so I never ate any more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> from that grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
         I remember down in the woods.
         I had this like a--.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Partner</ENAMEX>.
         Stepping on them <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>.
         And climb them <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.
         The taller the better.
         Guess I was a tomboy.
         Tammy was too.
         
         
         It's a small thing, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> was an alcoholic.
         And sometime good times and sometimes not so good times.
         
         It's pretty good up and until he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>.
         And went along on them long hauls sometimes.
         Went up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and everything.
         And get snow bound.
         Got gas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>.
         Driving a truck to him was like a habit or something, you know.
         He'd hear the sound of a truck and tell you what it was.
         That's a white.
         That's a diesel, and then he couldn't drive it anymore.
         
         He became a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">plumber</ENAMEX>'s helper, you know and it killed him.
         He had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a fifth</NUMEX> grade education.
         [Long pause]
      
      
         How's that?
      
      
         I remember we were coming up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> to visit.
         They still had um, the way they delivered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> was in a<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">,</ENAMEX>
         with a horse.
         The thing they pulled.
         I can remember waking up to the sound of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clip</ENAMEX>, clop, clip, clop."
         And I don't know, it sort of made you feel secure.
         And that's the way they brought around ice too.
         They didn't have any refrigerators then.
         Maybe some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't.
         
         And believe it or not that was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 40</TIMEX>'s, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>'s.
      
      
         That's during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>?
         You probably don't remember that do you?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-huh.</ENAMEX>
         No.
         I know I was living then, but don't know.
         I remember some little things.
         They were playing war games, near our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wadesboro</ENAMEX> and they got, them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama</ENAMEX> to bake them a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>.
         Is that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> of recording?
         
         
         Well, I just told you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> was an alcoholic.
         So, when I was a teenager.
         I was so embarrassed, you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> would come by.
         It's a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
         So everybody knows that he's one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> drunks, I mean there were quite a few of them.
         And I told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> that it was darn right embarrassing he'd get drunk, you know, like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> time and then he'd get as far the yard and pass out.
         I told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> it was embarrassing for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to come by there, ride by there, there he was laying in the yard passed out.
         So the next time he started to lay down in the yard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama</ENAMEX> told him, she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clayton</ENAMEX>, if I were you would not lay down in the yard and go to sleep."
         He mumbled something or other and laid down in the yard and went to sleep.
         She took him by his feet and we had steps to go up on the porch.
         And pulled him up, his head going, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bump</ENAMEX>, bump, bump," all the way up them steps.
      
      
         It's bad when you don't even feel it.
         
      
      
         Oh, he was saying: oh, oh, oh.
         He felt it.
         
      
      
         He was just to drunk to do anything about it.
         Wasn't he?
         
      
      
         Drinking I don't understand.
         They say they drink to forget their troubles and then that's all they talk about.
         
         Me, when I'm drinking I get sick on the stomach.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> said that God has blessed me and made me that way because I could have been like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> and could have been an alcoholic.
         
         I can't understand how anyone likes the taste of it.
         
         Where's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         When did you, uh, get married?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huh</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         When did you get married?
      
      
         Well, I came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> to live with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         I was engaged to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wadesboro</ENAMEX>.
         But I came up here and--
      
      
         So you were running from him.
      
      
         No.
         I came up here to work.
      
      
         Did you mean to leave him?
      
      
         He left me first.
         He was in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>.
         He went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh.
      
      
         And I'm still writing to him up here, but I met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Watkins</ENAMEX> and I really don't know how to pick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.
         He um, believe it or not I met him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, but he turned out to be a paranoid schizophrenic.
         And his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> said he was dangerous and it was best that I got away from him.
      
      
         But you didn't listen to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>, did you?
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         No, you waited until he ran you out the door.
      
      
         I was out the door that time.
         I just had on black shorts and red shirt and I was a witch.
         Living with him you had to be careful of what you wore.
         What colors.
         How you picked up anything on the dresser and put it down or you were arranging some witchcraft stuff.
         The reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> say I shouldn't live there is that.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he thought the bible said, well it does say don't suffer a witch to live, so he might kill me.
         I was teaching ya'll, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> witchcraft too he said.
         
         Well, like I told you Tammy I could tell bits and parts of my life story and make, I don't know how many books.
         If I could just get into it, sit down and think about it and do it.
      
      
         Sitting down and writing it should remind you of some of the battles.
      
      
         I would read the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Story</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> sometimes and think, "Good gosh she didn't have it any rougher then I did.
         And why did she go out and become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heron addict</ENAMEX> or--"
      
      
         Was your whole life bad or did you have anything good happen?
      
      
         I had fun.
         I danced.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I sang.
         And my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Ruth Hare</ENAMEX>.
         And
         we went everywhere together.
         Well, we didn't go to many places because we couldn't sneak out that much.
      
      
         You were quite an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> too.
         You love to draw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothes.
      
      
         A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> is what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> said I ought to be.
         I did.
         I'd draw them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, would make them.
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when I had fun was after I went to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schmick</ENAMEX> in wiring electric duck heaters.
         I had fun doing that.
      
      
         You loved that job.
      
      
         I love wiring electric duck heaters.
         And--
      
      
         You love the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too, it was like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Made you feel at home.
      
      
         And then they closed out the electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>.
         You know the heaters.
         The wiring they say just um, air conditioning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and all those things were big and everything, but I still enjoyed working there because I knew the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         I worked there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten years</TIMEX>.
         And then--.
      
      
         You made very good money for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> during that time too.
         For a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Yeah.
         I was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in that place making the kind of money an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> made.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Electric duck heaters</ENAMEX>.
         But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> weren't jealous of me like they said you know that they were.
         Most places.
      
      
         \\ The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>-- <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX>
      
      
         \\ The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> helped me get the job.
         
         \\
      
      
         I noticed that about mine too.
         They helped.
      
      
         They taught me what I ought to know.
         To get the job right before I was to go for the interview they told me everything I suppose to know when I went in there I knew it.
      
      
         That's good.
      
      
         They said, "You got it on your own.
         You remembered things real well."
         
         I had been going over there and helping the temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> anyway.
         
         We had to learn about the air gauges, how much air would go in them things that make those, I can't even remember the name of them now.
         Fly open and shut when you put air to it.
         
         And then, I married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Earl</ENAMEX> and along came <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX>, call her Buttons on there so--.
         And um,
         that made me stay young I think, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         You got with her what you couldn't have with us.
      
      
         Because I had to work all the time with them.
         I worked quite a few with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole</ENAMEX> too.
      
      
         But you got to do more--
      
      
         Went to the beach a lot.
         
         At that time I had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of all ages, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> grown up, one thought she was grown up, and
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX> was just real quiet,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX> was never quiet.
      
      
         You had all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-huh.</ENAMEX>
         
         I had a miscarriage.
         Swore it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.
         
      
      
         All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>'s.
      
      
         I was born the last you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'39</NUMEX>, so <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'49</NUMEX>, I wasn't nothing but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 10 years old</TIMEX>.
      
      
         So the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>'s were when you were a teenager.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         What did you wear?
      
      
         At the last of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>'s?
      
      
         What you wear the most?
      
      
         What I'd wear?
      
      
         What music did you listen to?
      
      
         I listened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Berry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fats Domino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Richard</ENAMEX>, uh,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Platters</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> wasn't your favorite was he?
      
      
         He was everybody's favorite.
      
      
         Everybody's favorite.
         
      
      
         Except the daddies
         and mamas.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> liked him pretty good.
      
      
         What about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boyfriends</ENAMEX> liked him?
      
      
         They liked his music.
         They didn't particularly like him.
      
      
         They didn't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> liking him so much.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-huh.</ENAMEX>
         They liked his music.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> likes his music.
         And, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> is sort of a legend.
         If he had become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX>.
         He had the charisma to.
      
      
         \\ To bring in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>.
         \\
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">\\ Uh-huh</ENAMEX>.
         
         \\
      
      
         Tell me about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elma Ruth</ENAMEX> before she run away from training <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         She came to me then I hurt her feelings because I told her she couldn't stay there, but I was staying with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         How old was she?
      
      
         15.
      
      
         Why was she in training <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she was with this girl named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX> and they told,
         they looked older then what they were.
         Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at the car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> should have asked for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> license.
         And they use to let you take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and drive them around with nobody in them, but now you know they stay with you.
      
      
         Yes.
      
      
         And they went on a joy ride in it.
         
         They took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and went on a joy ride.
         But, it was called stealing because they didn't take it back.
      
      
         They didn't give them any warning or probation like they do nowadays?
      
      
         Well, she'd, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elma</ENAMEX> had a lot of warnings about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         She didn't go to school?
      
      
         Playing hooky.
         
         They put her there.
      
      
         You said she was beautiful.
      
      
         I thought she was.
         She had jet-black hair.
         I mean it was black as ace of spades.
         And a pretty complexion, but I got along better with her then I did with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         How long have you been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Since when we were little tiny things and sliding down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>--.
         Red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mud</ENAMEX> in little white panties.
         
      
      
         When did you stop seeing her?
         When you moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well, we saw each other after I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> when I go back down there to visit, but when she moved to um, some,
         I can't think of the name of the place.
         Just lost touch with her.
         She got married and moved.
      
      
         So ya'll were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on up until you were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-huh.</ENAMEX>
         I talked to her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time when I lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie</ENAMEX> gave, called her, found out where she was, what her phone number was and called her and had this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> way calling and we talked to each other.
      
      
         It's quite common now, but it was new when Debbie done it.
      
      
         It, it wasn't the same.
         I guess you just can't go back, but I still would like to see her.
         But when we uh, drive through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wadesboro</ENAMEX> going to the beach and everything, nothings the same down there either.
      
   
