
   
   JBM: Let me see. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um,</ENAMEX>
   my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> she died, you know, before I really, you know, knowed her. I was small, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, it was just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us, you see, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> didn't have but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, she didn't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. And out of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> didn't but one have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. And then she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX> and myself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX> was older than I was and I was second. But when she died she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years old</TIMEX>, so they told me. And, um, was then when I got up, you know, and they told me she died when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>, I knowed I was going to die when I got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years old</TIMEX>!
   So I got scared! Yeah, I knowed I was going to die. But I said it, it, uh, you see what, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX> and I was going, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX> was, would want me to, he'd go out with them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and learn, you know, things. Well he'd want me to do everything, he'd come back and want me to do it. He'd want me to, to, wanted to try to learn me to ride the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bicycle</ENAMEX>. I always was scared of everything, you know. And he'd get mad. Well they'd go out there and they'd get rabbit tobacco-
   
         
            JBM: -and they'd chew it, come back, and he have me, want me to
      chew it, I mean smoke it.
      
      
         
            JBM: And he said, "Just blow it in, then blow out," then maybe I'd go choking.
         I'd go to coughing and go out there and then he'd get mad at me!
         
      
      
         
            JBM: "Oh you can't do nothing!"
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Honey</ENAMEX>!
         Oh, we'd have a time and fussing!
         And then of course, you know, he was awfully mischievous and anything that was done, you know, "Who did that?"
         He'd put it on me.
         They would believe everything, because, see, he was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and they catered to him, you know, he was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, and I'm the one had, I'd have to get a whipping.
         They never believed nothing I said, but whatever he said, it was the truth.
      
      
         
            . JBM: Well then, after he got up pretty good size, you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, they'd have little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, you know, and things like that and they'd ask, you know, tell, ask for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX> and myself both to come and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX> would tell me, "No she can't go.
         That's not for her.
         She can't go."
         I never would get to go to nothing, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>.
         
            JBM: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, say, he going to get up there and say a little speech, you know,
      and then, we had, you know, a little store out, well it wasn't far from us, you go out a little dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>, you know, and then you'd have to turn, turn to your right and then back to your left to the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
         And she'd send me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and I'd have to repeat it, what I was going after
      all the way to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> so I wouldn't forget!
         So much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>, I'd have to say, "Ten <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX>," so whatever it was, I'd have to say it, you know, if I didn't I'd forget.
         Well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX>, the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> lived up above me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charity</ENAMEX>, well she was going the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> with me.
         Well along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> there just was this <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX>, just covered, you know, `long there, that big pretty vine there.
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charity</ENAMEX> said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Let's</ENAMEX>, let's get some of it and rub it on us."
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"
         She said, "Yeah."
         She got some made like she rubbing it on her face.
         Well I got some and rubbed on my face and it was, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> poison ivy!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Poison ivy</ENAMEX>!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">//</ENAMEX>
      JBM: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>!
         And my face!
         Oh it was a sight!
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charity</ENAMEX> didn't have a little, little place and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, my face puffed up!
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> she had to use, I don't know what all, it taken her for the longest to get my, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, because I rubbed it in, you know!
         I thought that, she was making that she was doing it and I was so dumb, you know!
         
            JBM: I didn't know no better!
         
            
				JBM: She was a little older than I was, you know.
         Yeah, just dumb, dumb, dumb!
         
            JBM: I didn't know!
         
            JBM: I thought, I thought everybody was like me, tell the truth!
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, you know, she was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foster mother</ENAMEX>.
         But she tell me, she say, "You tell me a lie, I'll kill you!"
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, and I thought, I didn't know she was lying there herself!
         I know she didn't lie, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>.
         Honey I was scared to tell her
      `cause I'd know she'd kill me, you see!
      
         
         JBM: Yeah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, I know!
         And then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time, then, when I went to school, you know, well they would, well, you know, we'd have to carry our lunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday</TIMEX> and then you, you had a boiled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>, and you'd have a baked sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX> and, uh, these little, uh, little old sausage, whatever you call them, you know, what I'm talking about, because I see them now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>JBM: Then that little, them little cans, the stuff that you make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> out of, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> sausage?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Potted meat</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vie</ENAMEX>-?
         JBM: Yeah.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Potted meat</ENAMEX>, and, and then them little sausages, you know.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>JBM: Well, I'd taken, I think, I don't know what they put a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> in that potted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> or something but anyway they'd make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX>, you know.
         And, uh, so then when I get to school, you see, I didn't like nothing but the white of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>.
         And I'd have at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX>, they was all, was out begging for yolk, begging for the yolk!
         
         Oh I had plenty!
         I had plenty
      when they got ready to eat lunch and this one was begging, this one was begging.
         I didn't say I'd give you this day, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, give you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">da-</ENAMEX>, they would all be around me for that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>!
         
         Oh Lordy!
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> time then they, uh, they was, uh, one little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> there and she was and so they was, I think they must have put her, you know, you know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> say, "Why don't you hit her?
         Why don't you get her?"
         When you start walking home?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>JBM: So they put, put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josephine</ENAMEX>, that was her name, and I told her, you know, I said, "Leave me alone, now.
         You go on, now," because I was scared, you know, to bother anybody because I know I'd get a beating if I did!
         And, uh, she kept on, she kept on after me, and all of them was around there, you know, just, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> was terrible then, you know!
         But they was doing that just wanting to see, you know, just wanting to see a fight or something.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josephine</ENAMEX>, she kept on.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josephine</ENAMEX> was a little old, real bright little old gal and she was
      she was, so she kept on.
         She come at me, she go, "Go at the little gully here when we leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, right here."
         Right here was a little gully.
         Right here was a little patch to get out in the big path you know, to go home.
         And so she kept on!
         She coming after me and I turned around and I take her and I just grabbed her and I clawed her face all up!
         Just clawed her to death!
      
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">JBM: Bet</ENAMEX>,
      bet all of them, "Whoa!
         You're going to get it yet!"
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Y'all</ENAMEX>," I say, "All of you leave me alone!"
         Because I knowed I was going to get a beating!
      
      
         
            JBM:
      I went home and, of course I, it was there before I got there, you know.
         
         Yeah, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>!
         Lord help me!
         It take a good while.
         I don't know what they kept, what they did about her face, but anyway I know it take a good long while to get her face like, yeah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>!
         I clawed her to death!
         I bet she didn't look at me no more!
         
            JBM: Didn't none of them, didn't none of them bother me no more!
      
      
         Huh-uh!
         JBM: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX> if, if you had get me mad, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, I'd do you, I'd, ooh!
         The strength would come to me, you know, and I got mad, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>!
         But <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, when I got home I knowed, I dread to go home, because I knowed I was going to get it!
         
         JBM: Ooh!
         She could beat so!
         Ooh, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>!
         That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>!
         Those switches!
         She could beat you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>!
         And talk about now!
         They talk about
      they'd have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in jail <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> if
      it was like it used to be!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Child</ENAMEX> that gets angry just, just take them up there and keep going, because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, they're going to beat you!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, and you're going to know it, too!
         Ooh!
         And sometime <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Charlie</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> I'd be glad, you know, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Charlie</ENAMEX> come home from work and we'd be sitting and she'd say that she going to beat me.
         Well she beat, me and he say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie</ENAMEX> now that's enough now, Winnie!"
         And he'd get over me-
      
      
         
            JBM: -and she, she'd just beat him then, too-
      
      
         
            JBM: -until she got through.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, he'd take a, take a lot of beatings!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O Lord</ENAMEX>!
         I thought he was the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> I ever had!
         
            JBM: I just loved him to death and I hated her!
         
         I thought, "She the meanest old thing I ever-."
         Oh!
         I thought she was so mean, you know,
      `cause she, `cause she beat me, see.
         I didn't know after while I'd appreciate it, you know.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>JBM: But honey, I thought she mean thing.
         And <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one evening</TIMEX>, I come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         Well, I had dresses because the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would always give me clothes.
         And so she said, ah, "Go in there and get that."
         She had a little, it was a little old straight dress.
         "You wash that dress now, because that the dress you going to wear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>."
         And I wondered why I had to wear that dress.
         But <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, I went in there because there was water in that place.
         We had, we had big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wash pans</ENAMEX> then, you know, had big old, like kettles like where you heated your water in.
         Well I went in there, I got that dress out, washed it out, and I rinsed everything out and went and hung it on the line.
         I can see it hanging now!
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honey</ENAMEX> ( ), and, you know, directly she went out there, I went in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, she went out the door, out right then and I went to the window and looked see where she going.
         She went out there, she went out there, she getting the dress pulling them seams open; pulling at it, you know.
         I got that thing, oh my, oh my, my, that thing hurt, you know.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, she was going there in them seams now looking and all.
         I said, "What is she-?"
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>!"
         
         that's the way she called me, oh my Lord!
         I said, "What's so wrong?"
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ma'am?</ENAMEX>"
         
         I went out there, get the dress down, and take it and wash it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, I had to wash that dress <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times-
      JBM: -before,
      before I ever got to wear it.
         I said, "If I live and get grown, I'm going to carry all of my clothes to the laundry!
         I ain't going to-," saying it to myself because you'd better not say nothing and let them hear you!
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX>!
         They'd kill you then!
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Honey</ENAMEX>, I tell you the truth, yeah!
         And I got a whipping every time, you know!
         Oh Lord!
         Did I like laundry?
         No!
         I didn't want to learn no-
      , I didn't want to learn nothing about no laundry work!
         Not from that dress!
         
            JBM: Good gracious alive!
         Huh-uh!
         Oh Lord!
         All them, all they could go around there just so pretty, they might come out.
         But me?
         No!
         No, don't give me nothing
      to wash it out!
         After I got grown, the only thing I liked to, to iron was little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> clothes and hancherkefs Nothing else, no, no, no!
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> time we lived down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Sara</ENAMEX> and she taking care and she did laundry for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX> out there on, uh, I can't call the place now, but anyway and she'd come then she'd get <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Winnie</ENAMEX> and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to help her, you know, do the washing and ironing.
         And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> then, I, I think we didn't have to go to school or something, but I went down and, Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheeler</ENAMEX> was her name, she said, "Don't you want to iron a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shirt</ENAMEX>?"
         "Oh yeah, but you-," I said, "I can't iron."
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, you try to iron."
         Put me in there on an ironing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
         And every time I'd iron there, then there'd be a wrinkle here and every time I iron there, I said, I said "I don't want to go down to Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheeler</ENAMEX>'s
      no more!"
         I wouldn't go down there no more either.
         I couldn't iron no white shirts or nothing else `cause I hated it!
         
            JBM: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ooh</ENAMEX> laundry, I hated it!
         I was so mad but you better not act like you're mad!
         Huh-uh!
         Don't you act like you're mad because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, you're going to get it!
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yes ma'am</ENAMEX>, yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ma'am</ENAMEX>, ( ) yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ma'am</ENAMEX>!"
         Ooh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>!
         And then they're in everything you do, "Who did so and so?"
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>," he'd call me, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> did that!"
         
         He'd call me <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>, I'd say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX>!
         I didn't!"
         " Yes you did, too!"
         Well I'd be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to get the whipping.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, I got so many whippings!
         Oh, it was awful!
         And, you know, then, they had, uh, wooden floors and you had to get down on your knees and scrub them.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, get down, and in them cracks!
         You'd better not leave not nothing in them cracks!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ooh Lord</ENAMEX>!
         On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, that's when you had to scrub them floors!
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe</ENAMEX>, he'd, he would get mad, you see.
         He'd put everything on me!
         He was supposed to be helping me and then he'd make me do it, you know!
         Oh, when it was awful!
         I said, I'd tell anybody, I'd say, "Please,"
      "don't let none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> be home ( ), because it, you do so sure going to catch it!"
         
         Oh me!
         I'll tell you, I had it rough!
         Talking about it,
      , talking about it, ooh, my Lord!
         I said, "Um, um, um!"
         Ooh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, I hated it a whole lot!
         I still hate laundry!
      
      
         
            JBM: I, I, do.
         
         ( )After, after that, he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">caf�</ENAMEX> and he'd, most all the time he'd send these shirts, you know, to the laundry.
         Well then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> up there, he wanted me to wash the tie, I mean, you know, wash the things what you use in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and then he give me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> white shirts to carry over, over to the washerette with, right across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> then, right across ( ).
         And I came over and he said, he said, "Now you got to put <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bleach</ENAMEX> in there in the towels to get them clean," he told me.
         I said, "All right."
         So I put the towels, shirts, and everything together, poured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bleach</ENAMEX> all over them!
         
         I didn't know
      about using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bleach</ENAMEX>, pouring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bleach</ENAMEX>!
         When his shirts come out, they come with little holes-
      JBM: -all over!
         All over!
         
         He didn't ask me to wash no more shirts!
      
         
         JBM: They, uh uh!
         He sure didn't ask me
      to wash no more shirts!
         Little holes, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX>, all-!
         "I thought you knowed how!"
         I didn't know how, didn't want to know how
      so I-
      
   
