
   
   
      
         Let me start off by asking what is your full name and is there any story behind your name?
      
      
         My full name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Kate Morris</ENAMEX> and there's really no story of any importance or interest.
         I was named after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> Katie Sharp.
      
      
         OK.
         Do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> normally name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> after family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Oh yeah, it's a big deal in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we've got more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catherines</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Margarets</ENAMEX> running around than I can count.
      
      
         That is interesting.
         Well, my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question leading into the whole reason for the interview <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, is childhood stories, and what is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> story that you remember from your childhood?
      
      
         I think the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> story I remember, is um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rapunzle</ENAMEX>.
         
         you know, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rapunzle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapunzle</ENAMEX> let down your gold hair."
      
      
         Hum.
         Why?
         Did you like that story?
      
      
         I guess.
      
      
         Do you remember who told you the story?
      
      
         My mother
         .
      
      
         Was that your favorite story?
      
      
         I think so, I heard it a lot and I think I maybe um, related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">princess</ENAMEX>.
         I think all little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> do, because we both have blond hair.
      
      
         OK.
         So you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> used to play-act out some of these stories?
      
      
         Oh sure, I think all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> play-act things they hear from their childhood.
         You know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping Beauty</ENAMEX>, that kind of thing.
      
      
         So of all these stories, what do you think might have been your most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> from your childhood?
      
      
         I guess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapunzle</ENAMEX>.
         That's the one I heard the most.
      
      
         What part of the story did you like the most?
      
      
         I think when she'd let her hair down and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> would climb up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower room</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         OK.
         What was it about that that you liked so much?
      
      
         
         I don't know, I just thought it was kind of neat.
      
      
         The fact that her hair could be that long or something?
      
      
         Oh yeah.
      
      
         What was your least favorite part of the story?
      
      
         I really don't think I had a least favorite part.
         I thought the whole story you know, was very interesting at that age in my childhood.
         The whole thing was just amazing to me.
      
      
         OK.
         Of all the stories you read as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, do you think any of those childhood stories had an impact on your life?
      
      
         Not that I can really say, you know.
         As you get older you realize that they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> stories and not based in any real truth, but that they were happy times for you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
         But I can't say that they made any real impact.
      
      
         At what age do, did you realize that they were more for the fun or mythology or--
      
      
         Oh I don't know, probably around
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>, something like that.
      
      
         OK.
         Speaking of your reading habits, as you got older, as a teenager, what type of reading material, what type of stories did you read?
         You know how were they different?
      
      
         Oh, I don't know that they were so much different.
         I read the um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Drew</ENAMEX> books, and I read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hardy Boy</ENAMEX> books and um, whatever was,
         Black Beauty things of that nature.
         You know whatever was popular with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my age at that time.
         You have to remember, this was a long time ago
         .
      
      
         Reading into your young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> life, what type of reading materials did move into then?
         
         And why?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, there was a series of books I read, as I got farther into my teenage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and for the life of me I can't remember the name of the character, but it was um, a series of books about a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>.
         And um, I think those made, must have made some lasting impression on me, because here I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      
      
         And what's your profession now?
      
      
         I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         So I, so, I guess in some small fashion you associated with some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         I'm sure.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alright</ENAMEX>.
         Do you have a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, yes.
         His name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Perreti</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What types of stories does he write?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and he writes very dramatic stories uh, concerning um, such issues as, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> coming, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Satan</ENAMEX> being among us, and they're not, they're not so much preachy gospel type books as they are very good um, drama, you know, almost scary type stories, but they're very good.
      
      
         So what was it specifically that drew you to these particular books?
      
      
         Well to tell you the truth um, it was the fly page on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the books that I read.
         It was the little synopsis on the back, on the inside cover that drew me to the book.
         And I had no idea that the gentleman was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> when I bought the book.
         It just sounded very interesting and uh, I've become quite a fan of his.
      
      
         OK
         .
         What uh, does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> have any collection of books or anything like that?
         Childhood books that maybe they passed down through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, that maybe, that was read to you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or anything like that?
      
      
         Not myself specifically, but I know that we still have a copy of a um,
         book your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had from childhood that we read to you as a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What was that?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">101 Dalmatians</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         
         Let's see.
         Going back to the stories about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>.
         Would you say that story had an impact on your life, or do you think that was just coincidence?
      
      
         No, it probably, in the long run it probably did, because it made me think about the you know, the desire to do for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         The interest and excitement I guess there is in the medical field.
         Working in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, specifically emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, was always uh, a thrill for me.
         And um, I guess that kind of, those books kind of set me to thinking, as a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Were any of your childhood stories somehow related to that, in any fashion?
      
      
         No, uh huh, they were the typical little golden book childhood stories.
      
      
         How many stories do you remember from your childhood?
         You know, what types of stories do you remember?
      
      
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, oh, books like, your typical childhood books, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> Beauty.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golly</ENAMEX> let me think.
         Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Grimm's' Fairy Tales</ENAMEX>, um
         books of that nature, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cinderella</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping Beauty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snow White</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Dwarfs</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Now you said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> read some of these stories to you.
         Did you ever read any of these stories on your own time?
      
      
         Oh sure we had, we had, like I said the little golden books that came in sets, and other storybooks.
         Um
         , I remember reading them myself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, and certainly as I got older um, reading was important.
         It's still important to me now, because I have such um, a reality based profession that when I, that when I do read it's solely for the purpose uh, of escaping reality.
         I'll read, I'll read just about anything I can get my hands on, that does not have anything to do with the medical field.
         Which I can't say is particularly, that's not completely the case, because I have read several of the, several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Cornwell</ENAMEX> novels and her main <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">character um</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologist</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Scarpetta</ENAMEX>.
         So, but that's not really the primary sense in her book.
         Hers are, of course, murder/mystery type novels.
         Um
         , I read, yes I admit it, I've read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis L'Amour</ENAMEX>, uh, but mostly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sackett</ENAMEX> novels, because that deals a lot with um, the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that I was born and raised in.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and I enjoy reading novels about that, but as far as reality based reading material, I don't, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> about as reality oriented as I get.
      
      
         So where were you born?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albuquerque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Do you think that particular area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> had any influence on the types of things that maybe you read as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, probably starting in high school it did, because my high school <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher um</ENAMEX>, is a published <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and is very popular in that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
         And I've noticed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of years</TIMEX> that they're starting to sell his novels out here too.
         And uh, which really thrills me to see that, because he's such a talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Do you remember what his name is?
      
      
         His name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolpho Aniya</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What types of stories did he write?
      
      
         His books, course you know they always say you should write, write about what you know.
         His books are centered in that part the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and specifically in the um, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> culture.
         His <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> uh, book is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bless Me Ultima</ENAMEX>, and it was about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, and the rest of his books are kind of, have kind of a mystical quality to them because there's a lot of mysticism in the uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> uh, religion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> culture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>.
         And uh, they're quite interesting.
      
      
         Would you say that some of the stories that you read growing up were more geo, geographically based in that area?
         By <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, I mean.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, having lived in that area, obviously having a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> influence, were some of the stories integrated in that fashion?
      
      
         Oh uh, sure they were.
         You always heard stories about that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, about the conquistadors coming into the southwest and a lot of the reading material and, and uh what not centered around the history of the area.
         Because there was so much of it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, books like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolpho Aniya</ENAMEX>'s books, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Hillerman</ENAMEX>'s books, even though they're basically fiction, delve a lot into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> culture and history.
         And uh, that area the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> especially the area they call the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Four Corners</ENAMEX> area.
         Really brings a lot of that to the fore there.
         They do a lot to help promote the uh, culture of that area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         I say, going back to some of the childhood stories in specific.
         Did you ever hear any stories, you know, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s stories, not necessarily even books, but uh, maybe stories that had sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> nature to them?
         Or background?
         You know like a bedtime story or scary story or anything like that?
      
      
         Oh, sure they're your usual scary stories.
         I don't remember any, any childhood stories about, specifically about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, like, like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tales.
         But I remember um, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story in particular about uh, it's pretty similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, the one they have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>.
         About the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> at the beach that lost her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and she walks, you know, the, the beaches at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
         This is similar, it's about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who lost her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, they were killed, and she walks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of what we call out there "arollos", they're, they're runoff ditches for flood <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, calling for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         I think every culture has a similar story in it.
      
      
         All right.
      
   
