
   
   
      
         I was born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Ann Snyder</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vicksburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou</ENAMEX>--.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, excuse me.
         The reason I said <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> is because that's where I lived all of my life.
         Everyone went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicksburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> to have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercy Hospital</ENAMEX> because we had no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Providence</ENAMEX>, the most beautiful place on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>, surrounded by um, lakes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cyprus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, right on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX>.
         And so when I was born my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> went over there and stayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, with her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tummy</ENAMEX> strapped afterwards because that's the way you did it back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 30</TIMEX>'s to assure yourself of a flat tummy when you got home.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I grew up in a very um, warm, loving, together, traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, good manners were extremely important, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> would send us from the table if we laughed.
         We all had special places at the dinner table and I, being the oldest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, sat at the end opposite my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> sat to his left and he served the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and she served the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was passed around to everybody.
         And at the end of dinner I would get to serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dessert</ENAMEX>.
         But, if I would spill a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>, which I often did, then I was sent from the table, but I would often be tickled.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was extremely um, uh
         firm but fair, totally unemotional and maybe you might be surprised to hear that because I am extremely emotional.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, was a, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Darling this</ENAMEX>, darling that, I love you."
         Constantly.
         Constantly we were told how much we were loved and maybe that made a great,
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>, that was a great influence to me but, on the other hand, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad um</ENAMEX>,
         kept a level of, of intensity, a level of, of uh,
         of wanting to do the right thing always, um, especially to please everybody.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he died when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years old</TIMEX> of a heart attack.
         It was a congenital <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart condition</ENAMEX> and I've often thought that he would still be in my presence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> had we had the medical advances then as we do now.
         When I married my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, soon after, well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> after he died, I cried <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> and didn't realize how much his presence was in my life until he was actually gone.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
         Very, very spoiled.
         Always wanted her way about everything and she was courted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of all ages after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> died.
         She remarried, much to my dislike.
         I don't think my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> mind so much of the time, they were young, they were still in high school, uh, but my stepfather was a very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> older than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.
         He was a party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and he had sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">florid</ENAMEX> face and I, it made me a little suspicious.
         But it turned out that they were married actually longer than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.
         And I really began, and continued to, love him very much.
         And his name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and I were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> apart and I loved him but not until we were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>, I think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 and 11</TIMEX>, we were typically quarreling siblings
         .
         We went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> on a family <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation one summer</TIMEX>.
         The only vacation, by the way, that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> ended up taking us because all the way from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> to
         <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> was almost too much for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to be together for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-day</TIMEX> period.
         But coming home we stopped in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had been on a roller coaster in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and he thought it was such fun and so we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pontchartrain Beach</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and that was nearing the end of the vacation and he said he wanted my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX> and me to go for the experience, he thought it was going to be so much fun.
         So we were all excited about it and got on.
         My <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> younger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> did not, they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and seven</NUMEX> at the time so they were not made to do this.
         And so we got on and, as we climbed the first little hill, it just looked wonderful; we could look out over the, over the beach and wave to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>.
         And then we got to the top and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and I were at either end of the seat, we still were not too fond of being, of sitting together so we got up and then suddenly, in our lives began to flash in front of us we were going so fast.
         Faster than the speed of sound I know.
         And I looked at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX> and he looked at me and the only thing I could say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear God</ENAMEX>, if you will let me off of this thing, then I will never ever again fuss with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>."
         And so, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ashen</ENAMEX> faces, we finally got back and I have never yet, by the way, been on another roller coaster.
         That was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX>.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and I, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, curiously, became very close.
         I don't know if it was a pact we both made.
         I have no idea what he prayed for.
         But, um, anyway, that was an um, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early remembrance</TIMEX> of family relationships.
         I was extremely close to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> because I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> older than the baby and I virtually called her my own.
         I helped rear her because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>.
         Every, it seemed like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other day</TIMEX> and she would have her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady friends</ENAMEX> and I would have to go in and tend to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and make sure that they were dry or had their pacifier or their bottle.
         And, then, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> younger and I felt the same way about her.
         And we've remained close all through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these years</TIMEX>, we're extremely close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         We connect, we talk.
         Every little family happening we get on the phone.
         Everybody has to know all of it, whether it's good or bad and sometimes it is bad, or naughty.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, where was I?
         I was talking about my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>.
         There are just so many things that I remember of my childhood.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Providence</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         And it was um, lined with wonderful little um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX>, small town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hardware</ENAMEX> stare and we all worked there.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSU</ENAMEX> and majored in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physics</ENAMEX> and he opened a radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> in the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
         And I used to work there and I, the most fond memory was that I had my own special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> on the cash register, which was a great big piece of equipment in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
         And it's really strange but I still dream about that hardware <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
         I love to um, weigh nails.
         If somebody wanted to come in and, and purchase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some</NUMEX> type of hardware then I would get the nails, put them in a sack, and weigh them.
         Then I would go to the cash register and punch my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> in and hand ring the cash register.
         That was really exciting.
      
   
