
   
   
      
         I would say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of 7 to 10 years old</TIMEX> it, was a really big thing to go to the movie on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX>.
         And one particular movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> we went to, they would show serials every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, which were a continued story.
         So if you missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one Saturday</TIMEX> you would miss what happened in a particular episode and you, um, wouldn't know what had taken place.
         So we would go every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.
         And also at this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, they gave prizes to different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the way they gave prizes was, they would take big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> photos and everybody, and there were stairs going up to a balcony, real wide stairs.
         And the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would go stand on the stairs and there would be probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 or 40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the picture.
         And they'd take the picture and then you would go back the next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> after they had been developed and they would have circled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the picture and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose head was circled would get the prizes.
      
      
         Is that for real?
      
      
         That's for real!
         That really happened!
         And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time I can remember, I think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, um, he, and they would give treats like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>, I don't even remember what all kinds of prizes the would give.
         But for some reason, and I think this is really true, he got <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream sandwiches</ENAMEX>!
         Like a box of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream sandwiches</ENAMEX>.
         And of course there's nothing to do with a box of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream sandwiches</ENAMEX> when you're at a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2-hour</TIMEX> movie!
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         They're going to melt!
         And another, um, that was in, that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">High Point</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         And then we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and we used to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">�</ENAMEX> and I don't think its even still there I don't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> is or not � but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dilworth Theatre</ENAMEX>.
         I lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dilworth</ENAMEX> area, and we would go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dilworth Theatre</ENAMEX> and I do remember that it cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9 cents</NUMEX> to get a ticket to get in.
         And we would, could go to the movie.
         We would get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">maybe 15 cents</NUMEX> each to go to the movie, and I sound like I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95 years old</TIMEX>-
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         -with those kinds of prices.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but we would go to the movie and then you would go in and get your, your snack that you wanted.
         And there were several different choices.
         I don't ever remember getting popcorn at the movie until I was a teenager or in my adult life.
         But we would, uh, buy, lollipops is what they call them now, but we called them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> and we would get often a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2-cent</NUMEX> sucker.
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         Are you making fun?
      
      
         No, I love this story.
      
      
         And the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2-cent</NUMEX> suckers is what is referred to now as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tootsie Roll Pop</ENAMEX>.
         And we called them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2-cent</NUMEX> suckers because every other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX>.
         Except these were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 cents</NUMEX> because they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tootsie Roll</ENAMEX> in the middle.
         And there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> that cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> and we called that an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX>, just because you couldn't eat the whole thing for the entire movie and you would really just have that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long.
         And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other form of refreshment that we got, which really embarrassed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> because she didn't know anything about this until she went with us to the movie <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one Saturday</TIMEX>, there was a bakery next door to the movie theatre.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and myself were not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that did this; all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that would go to the movie knew to do this.
         We would go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bakery</ENAMEX> and we would ask for-
      
      
         
            
         
      
      
         -a nickel worth of scraps!
         
         
      
      
         And we didn't even have to ask for it because the bakery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> knew us and she knew to have all this ready for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> going to the movie.
         And what it was it was broken <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> and broken pieces of whatever happened while they were baking, mistakes.
         So they would fill little bags for us and we would give them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a nickel</NUMEX> and we could take that to the movie theatre with us.
         And that's all the stories I can remember about the movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>.
         I do know that I did used to go the movie downtown at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carolina Theatre</ENAMEX>.
         And when I was young, it wasn't a strange thing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to just go off and go to a movie.
         I mean, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> knew where we were going and she knew when we would get back, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you wouldn't send your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven or eight year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to a movie theatre alone even if they were with their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>; you just wouldn't do it.
         And we could skate to the movie or ride a bicycle to the movie and we would do that.
         Which is kind of sad that you can't do that anymore and it's not just because things are, there're bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world but it's too much traffic.
         You have to check everything about a movie, check it out to see what the content is and just wasn't like that when I was growing up
         .
         Also about that same time period in my life, I guess again between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX>, which seems to be what I remember most vividly, my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> uh, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Josey</ENAMEX>, and she was a next door <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> also, and we remained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> up until, uh, she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 35</NUMEX> and she passed away with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
         But we, we remained close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         In fact we shared an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>, first apartment either one of us ever had.
         And when we were, um, little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> we used to play "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Career Girls"</ENAMEX>!
         
         We did!
         And we used to try to dress up and pretend we were businesswomen.
         And we would go to work and pretend we had an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> together and then when we grew up, we sure did; we got an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> and I also used to play other kind of dress ups and it just, it seems like, I remember we both had like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s long skirts, or the skirts would be long on us and we would literally wear dress up clothes that belonged to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>.
         But we had, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> had one pair of pearls or beads of some sort of necklace that was her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s and I didn't have the necklace.
         And it was really beautiful and I really, really wanted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
         So we only had the one necklace and we, er, we decided, I don't know if it was jointly or if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> was just extremely nice of whatever, but she said I could wear it part of the time.
         And we would literally time the amount of time, we wore it like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes or 15 minutes</TIMEX> or whatever.
         And the way we decided who got to wear it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, and this always kind of bothered me because I know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> did this intentionally, she said the youngest one got to wear it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and she was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> younger than I am.
         So, it, that became
         a normal thing with us.
         Whenever we only had one of something she would always say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I think the youngest one gets to do it, or wear it or whatever <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>."
         And, that just always stuck in my mind, that in, in our adult life I brought that up to her and she sort of acted like she didn't know anything about that and I thought to myself, "she does," and then she laughed about it and she realized that she had kinda held a trump card on that one.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, also we did a lot of pretending and as I said we played career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and the dress ups.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and I used to pretend also and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill</ENAMEX> is about 2 years younger than I am, maybe <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX>, and we used to play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> except we didn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maid Marion</ENAMEX>, we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saretha</ENAMEX>, I don't know where in the world that name came from.
         But we would switch playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>, one would play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> and one would play <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saretha</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saretha</ENAMEX> was the counter, would be the same thing as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maid Marion</ENAMEX>, and, why, again, I don't know why we didn't use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maid Marion</ENAMEX>.
         But in my mind I can remember playing that, like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long.
         And we would go over to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>' and they had a a big white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with a big front porch and, uh, banisters on it and a lot of rocking chairs out on the front porch.
         And it was just a great place to pretend and we would climb up on the porch and on the banisters and we could make those our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> or, uh, it could be a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX>; just do many things with it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and when we were still living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">High Point</ENAMEX> in our back yard we had a huge, I don't know, I guess it was an oak <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>, but it was a really big tree, but it was a climbable <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.
         And it had real large, thick branches extending out to the side and they were fat enough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> where as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight and nine years old</TIMEX> we could straddle the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX>.
         And that was another game that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill</ENAMEX> and I used to play; we would pretend we were in the jungle and we would climb up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and we would straddle the tree <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> and pretend it was our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>.
         And in the yard, we had an old tree that had been cut down and just the stump was remaining and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had planted, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> all around that stump and we would use that stump as a, as a throne and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">princess</ENAMEX> got to sit up on that stump on that throne and have all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> around her and that would be the throne and she would be the queen or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> or whatever.
         When I was a teenager, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audrey Hepburn</ENAMEX> movie came out called Wait Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX>.
         And I think I was probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 or 17 years old</TIMEX>; we were of driving age.
         And I had a group of girlfriends that I ran around with and there were, golly, there might've been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8 to 10</NUMEX> of us who were good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         Everybody had their own "best" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> but then we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that we used to do a lot of things together.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and we would, had that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> but we would only go out in a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and I remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Belle</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW Beetle</ENAMEX>, and we'd fit like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VW Beetle</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Belle</ENAMEX> turn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         No, huh-uh.
      
      
         She didn't?
      
      
         No.
         So we went out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> to the movie, but before we went to the movie we went to get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> and then we went to, and I think the name of the place was The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open Kitchen</ENAMEX>, and we didn't have chain pizza places like we do now, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Hut</ENAMEX> and all that.
         This was just a really neat pizza place that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would go.
         And we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open Kitchen</ENAMEX> and we would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and we would order <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> and all share it and everyone would only get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> piece and I think we would make the waitresses mad because we didn't have money to leave tips.
         We would also <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink water</ENAMEX>.
         So it wasn't a good situation for the waitresses, but we had fun and we didn't even think about it.
         We just did what we could get away with.
         Anyway, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> we were gonna go see Wait Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX> and I think it was on at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Manor Theatre</ENAMEX>, and I just remember when you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like 10 or so</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> going somewhere to the same place it's kind of a, pretty much of a spectacle; we're all in this long line and we're giggling and laughing and cutting up and having really a great time.
         So we bought our tickets and we went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Manor Theatre</ENAMEX> and we found a row of seats and we sat, file, all filed in.
         And I just remember seeing, and I was sitting in a middle section, I was not on an end so I had girls I knew on both sides of me.
         And I just remember that movie was, had a lot of hype about being really scary and suspenseful and it's nothing like these movies that are out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scream</ENAMEX> and, what is it?
         Nightmare on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Elm Street</ENAMEX> whatever it is, where they're actual horror movies.
         This was, uh, a real intense, um, drama and, just very scary; kept you on the edge of your seat.
         And there was a scene in the movie I remember where every one of us, and it wasn't just our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, but so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the theatre, they screamed out at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time.
         And that's really all I remember <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about that night</TIMEX>, it was just a lot of fun.
         And I really hope that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> have had some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> like that and has had good times like that, that I can remember going out with good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
      
   
