
   
   
      
         I'm supposed to give like an introduction like ( ).
      
      
         ( ) say your name, how old you are, where you're from.
      
      
         My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Nesbitt</ENAMEX>.
         
         I'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, been here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and a half years</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Oh didn't ( ).
      
      
         
         It's all right, you know, but, um, I got a cold right now, so I sound kind of funny, know what I'm saying, though, um, I got a story for you.
         When we first came, me, me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fianc�</ENAMEX>, when we first came to, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, we had got a job at, um, at, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Market</ENAMEX>, making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">75 cent</NUMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we got the job through her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, you know what I'm saying, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> there, so she hooked us up well.
         At the time, we thought she hooked us up.
         It was crazy.
         Anyway, the damn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> name was, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Little</ENAMEX>, blond, blond-haired, older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dude</ENAMEX> like, you know, late forties, I mean early forties.
         And, um, we was working there for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>, and, um, he was talking about getting himself a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, getting himself a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maxima</ENAMEX>.
         He had a old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maxima</ENAMEX>, like a, like a `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">90</ENAMEX>, like a `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>.
         He was talking about he was getting like a `<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96</TIMEX> it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'97</NUMEX> at the time, so he, you know, I'm going to get rid of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and I'm like, all right, talking about the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maxima</ENAMEX>, I said,
         "I could use, we need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>," know what I'm saying, me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         He said, "Yeah," you know, all enthusiastic and shit, like really, this the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, mind you, he was like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX> you got," you know, "You been working for me," you know, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Been a</ENAMEX>, been a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>," you know, "A nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.
         I like you," you know.
         "You and your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fianc�e</ENAMEX> and um, I'll, I'll sell you the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX>."
         Scratch that.
         He'll give it to me for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX>.
         That how crazy lost, no doubt we'll do that.
         Let's do that.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> he set it up, he was supposed to do it, he drove his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         He said, um, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> wanted to hold on to it for a little bit longer.
         "Until we," you know, "Pick up the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maxima</ENAMEX>."
         So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> go by.
         We ask him about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> again.
         The price went up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX>.
         But he'll definitely give it to us, you know what I'm saying, it's no problem.
         I said, "All right, cool."
         He said this driving us on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX>.
         This is how, this is how we interacting, so I'm thinking everything is cool, you know, funny dude at the job, you know, get along with him real easy-going compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> that was there, you know what I'm saying.
         He, um, he'll drive us home, if we need to pick us up from the bus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> if, you know what I'm saying, if we need him to.
         Now he going to sell me this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maxima</ENAMEX> that I know is good because he drive it everyday except <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> he supposed to sell it to us for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX>.
         He a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         I said, "Yeah, we can do that.
         You can take us to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">ATM</ENAMEX> right now.
         We'll get the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, we'll get the money for you right now, and we'll give it to you."
         Threw him off, you know what I'm saying.
         Like I said, we making <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five seventy-five</TIMEX>, we brand new to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         He knows this you know, he know the whole situation, so I think we kind of, kind of threw him off.
         We was able, you know, to produce that kind, that amount of money right on the spot.
         So immediately, uh, you know, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uh</ENAMEX>, not <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>," you know, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> we'll do it."
         "All right, whatever.
         That's cool."
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> come by, he don't drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         He don't drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> got it.
         This go on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week</TIMEX>.
         Next thing I know, we in this little, like it's, like this little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, it's not even a parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, it's like a driveway, and it's got to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Market</ENAMEX> and a uh, uh, beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">salon</ENAMEX> on the side of it, and some other thing, I think maybe, I don't know, you know what I'm saying.
         They share the same parking lot.
         Little, small, and, um, they got this beautician over there.
         Dude
         , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maxima</ENAMEX> to the job that, that we was supposed to been buying, and, uh, she didn't know me.
         She probably only knew me by name, you know what I'm saying?
         She comes in into the, uh, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Market</ENAMEX> and ask me do I know where the dude, uh, the beautician is, do I know where he at, you know, is he in, something to the effect.
         I ( ) said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"
         "Because," she said, "I'm trying," uh, "I have the title to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and I'm trying to give it to him."
         She didn't know, she didn't know that, you know.
         So she goes to have a seat in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>.
         She goes and have a seat.
         <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Two minutes</TIMEX> later the beautician comes, walks in, you know what I'm saying, walks in sit down with her at the table.
         They talk or whatever, whatever, whatever she gives him the title to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that we was supposed to have been buying, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> said he going to sell to us for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX>, knowing the situation, knowing that we need a, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, knowing the situation, I thought, you know, this a real dude here.
      
      
         Never told--
      
      
         Came through, coming through, you know big up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>, but that's when I seen how, how dirty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Carolinians</ENAMEX> are.
         They some dirty motherfuckers.
         
         That's my word.
         I mean I never been around on, on, I never been around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are, are, that are conniving at this level.
         I mean they, it's dirty.
         I they're dirty.
         All scales, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, old, young, black, white, fat, tall, short, cute, ugly, all that.
         Dirty!
         Dirty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, you know what I'm saying?
         I done been around here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and a half years</TIMEX> working a lot a different places and shit, but came in contact with a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the, you know what I'm saying, of the spectrum.
         That's why I know that this little, that right there is void, you know, it should be.
         Revised at least at the bare minimum because I done dealt with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and you can't, can't put them in, you can't box them!
         You can't, we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
         And they always sit there and try to say because they want to make a link or make a point, and then they want to box us.
         Other than that, we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, you know.
         Everybody is everybody.
         That's what makes us special.
         There's only one of, you know what I'm saying--
      
      
         Not really.
      
      
         Now, but you hear what I, I'm saying though.
      
      
         I understand what you're saying.
      
      
         But anyway that was my story, you know what I'm saying, and it was just, it was just crazy.
         But that was our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> lesson, you know what I'm saying, to let us know we wasn't home, you know, wasn't home anymore.
         We got to bite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX>.
         We don't have no, uh, no, no, uh, refuge.
         This is it, know what I'm saying?
         We jumped in, both hands and feet, jumped in you know what I'm saying?
         We here.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and a half years later</TIMEX> we got a accounting degree, you know what I'm saying, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>, you know what I'm saying, all later models than that, that, you know what I'm saying, uh, uh than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Maxima</ENAMEX> was, so fuck <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>,
         you know what I'm saying?
         I'm serious, you know, so, but it let us, you know, where we at I dealt with shit like that to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the present day</TIMEX>, you know what I'm saying, from different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the spectrum.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> that, when I came in, I guess, I had them boxed and they let me know that they not contained, they just a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, you know what I'm saying?
         That's why, you know, that's why I said what I said about that.
         That's it.
         I forgot another thing.
         Since I'm talking about it, I'm going to get it off my chest too.
         I got to get it off completely though.
         After, after that, you know what I'm saying, after I witnessed that that happened, you know what I'm saying, after I witnessed what had happened, I sit up there and confronted, you know, I didn't confront, well I did.
         I kind of confronted him like, you know, "What's up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>?"
         You know what I'm saying?
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> still didn't know that I seen the transaction then.
         He didn't know that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> came to me.
         I just so happened to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> she actually talk to, you know what I'm saying?
         Told me what she was there for, you know what I'm saying?
         He trying to act like he still got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, they still got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> here, you know.
         They still waiting for this, that, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, so after that, I just wasn't feeling him no more, you know.
         I, I, I hated him, you know what I'm saying?
         I like, I mean because he just, he smack, then I felt like he, you know what I'm saying, like he violated, you know.
         So he just, and then I had to work underneath of him.
         Then he was smug about it, trying to lie about it, trying to act like, you know, nothing happened, you know, anyway <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days later</TIMEX>, he, he fired me.
         Yeah, talking about he don't like my attitude because when I come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, I don't smile at him, you know what I'm saying, I don't carry on a conversation with him.
         I just go on and do my job, do a good job, and, you know, and I go.
         That wasn't good enough for him.
         He too, came to the side, told me, you know, actually he pull me in the back, said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can</ENAMEX> I talk to you?"
         I said, "Sure."
         No he didn't.
         He sent that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX>, what's that, what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> name?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhonda Shasta</ENAMEX>, I hated her.
         Shasta the kind of female just thought that the sun rose when she opened her eyes.
         The sun rose, you know what I'm saying, bottom line, she was ugly.
         She was piggish.
         
         And I don't mean, I don't mean, I don't mean it as in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, I'm talking that, but including her, her physical.
         When you looked, you get kind of like a piggish
         , you get a piggish vibe from her, for real.
         And she, she was very animated, you know, very animated, real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
         And she just thought that she was the shit.
         She was there first whatever, whatever.
         I'm supposed, I don't know, I'm supposed to tip tap,
         you know, I don't know, but, you know, but, I'm sure they assumed, when they seen a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, that's it.
         And they assumed, "OK, well he's this he's that."
         And they said, "Hold up, she's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">white</ENAMEX>!
         So that's a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with a white, so that changes everything now."
         So now they got to try to make a different analysis of, "OK, so he's like this and like that and she got to be like that," you know what I'm saying, and that's the way it is.
         And then we got to work in them, within them compounds.
         We got to work and we got to survive, know what I'm saying, like that's what I was saying before.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> automatically want to make up these, these, you know, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> but it's not true not for each and every one of us.
         And then the ones that those, uh, uh, particular things that, uh, uh, classify that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, soon as I get, know what I'm saying, uh, affected by it, or have to go through, I'm either caught off guard, or it hurts me, or shit, sometimes it could destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         I mean, because that's not me and I'm caught off, I wasn't expecting that, you know what I'm saying, but anyway he fired me, fired me.
         Because he didn't, I wasn't smiling and laughing and all that stuff like that.
         Told me he didn't like my attitude, didn't think my attitude, you know, he think it'd be best if uh, uh, uh, that's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time I heard it's not working out, not working, can't stand that shit.
         That shit make you want to put a pin in they fucking eye, for real ( ).
      
      
         \\ All right now don't make me stop\\ this tape.
      
      
         \\ You know what I'm saying.
         \\ ( )
      
      
         Would you hurry up?
         
      
      
         No you want to hear the voice, this is for real, I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24 years old</TIMEX>.
         I been dealing with this since I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 years old</TIMEX>.
         Never, never in my wildest dreams.
         I don't know, it's crazy.
         It's crazy because all you ever heard of was "southern hospitality."
         That's all you ever heard up north.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classifying</ENAMEX>.
         We classified a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.
         We just said, "OK, this is how they are.
         They just, they love you to pieces," you know what I'm saying?
         Everything is laid back.
         They feed the hell out of you, you know what I'm saying?
         Everything is just, you know, the weather's beautiful, you know what I'm saying?
         You, on farms you see <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> or some kind of fucking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> or something, you know what I'm saying, that you can eat, you know what I'm saying, running around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, or whatever.
         Dog stuff, like that, old grandma cooking everything <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX>.
         But it wasn't like that.
         I come to realize when I came down, mind you, you got to think this is the last place that held on to slavery as long as they could possibly hold on to it.
         Just about, you know what I'm saying, you know what I'm saying?
         So you got to remember that that's still here that's here.
         It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>, it's the essence, it's the essence.
         Right now they in the process of trying to, you know, perfect the masch, but I'm looking past the masch I'm looking at, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> or what have you, you know, classify.
         I'm looking at it like that, you know, it gave me all new meaning to, uh, uh, southern hospitality.
         Now I understand that.
         I, it's just crazy, it's crazy, it's crazy.
         That's why when I do go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here, I'm going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here for dirt cheap because I been living here since they robbed us with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angie</ENAMEX> and everything, so I'm going to go for cheap, hurt them, and then I'm, I'm gone.
         I'm leaving.
         I'm not going to put no money into the, into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, I'm not going to put no money into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, or anything.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> can just forget about it, I'm just gone.
         I don't want nothing to do with this no more.
         I'm tired of it.
         Shit, by that time it'd be, what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> that's a long, that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.
         That'd be enough, though.
         That's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>, that's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>.
         It's interesting too, you'll read about it too, and be like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damn</ENAMEX>, that's all right," you know what I'm saying.
         But, um, that's it.
         I just wanted to tell you about how he sandbagged me.
         Cut me at the knees.
      
   
