
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hi</ENAMEX>.
         My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris O'Connor</ENAMEX>.
         And um, I'm a host-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hye-Jin</ENAMEX>.
         And I'm, I'm, um, I'm honored um, to participate in the project.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, what I would like to do is explain to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hye-Jin</ENAMEX> an experience I had, um, as, as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, uh, something that um, has stayed to me really all of my life and is especially meaningful now that I live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.
         Because I was born in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>, I was raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North I</ENAMEX>, you know, truly am, um, I consider myself a northern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, um, and quite by surprise um, we came to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years ago</TIMEX>, um, mainly for work reasons.
         Both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I had lost our jobs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>.
         So, we came south, because this is where the jobs are and fortunately, we were able to get work and re-located here.
         So, this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years later</TIMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I are employed in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, and I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX>.
         And um, we find ourselves in a very diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, which is all good uh, we find ourselves um, working with many many more uh, black or Afro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than we were ever exposed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>.
         And that has um, made me remember um, that when I was in um, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade, I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX>.
         And I was um, growing up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">DE</ENAMEX>.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>.
         And we had never lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> before, except for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other brief, brief time I should say we had lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SC</ENAMEX> um, where act, actually one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> was born.
         But when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>, we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>, and um, we, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and we were enrolled in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>, and um, they wanted us to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.
         So, I went to, I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade, and I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacred Heart School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>.
         And I became friendly.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friends</ENAMEX> when I was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade, their names were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Callahan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Emanuel</ENAMEX>.
         And their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were southern born and bred.
         But um, in time we became very close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and then to our childhood friendships, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> became good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         So, most of our social life was spent visiting back and forth in each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would have dinner together and they would get together, and have parties, and they really had a wonderful time.
         And um, as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time</TIMEX> wore on and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> became better acquainted, I can imagine that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> really being the only northern born and bred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> began to see the differences in their attitudes, uh, in their racial attitudes as opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and by that I mean um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had been raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>, and there were never um, very many black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around.
         But they were never raised with any prejudice.
         I guess I can say they were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>, they were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um</ENAMEX>,
         I don't believe um, they really had any predisposition or any prejudice toward black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         And I think that when they moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and they saw the prejudice of their good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
         I think it really uh, really bothered them to the point that they wanted to make sure that their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> did not grow up with those prejudices.
         And I can give you a good example.
         Now, it was very common, when I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX> and I was the oldest of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> hired a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> to help her once a week.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX>, and she was a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>.
         And she would come to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> once a week, and she would help my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> clean.
         She would do all kinds of household, um, activities, because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, very close in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> and I'm sure she was a big help.
         It was, it was just a very acceptable thing to do among middle class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         I don't think I really thought twice about it.
         So um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> learned of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX> from her very close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX> and we all went to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> together and the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> together.
         And so that's how we found out about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX>.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX> come to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> once a week, and then she would help my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, and then at dinner time, I can remember we all sit at our dinner table uh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">McDonough children</ENAMEX> and my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX> always sat at the table with us.
         I remember it very well and she was just part of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         She was like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>, she just ate dinner with us.
         But I'll never forget when we went to have a lunch at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX> also worked.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX> fixed lunch for us.
         And it was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and me, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and we all sat down at the dinner table together to have the lunch that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX> fixed for us.
         But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX> had to sit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> by herself.
         It was not considered appropriate, I guess it would be the word or it was not considered acceptable in that household to have a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> sitting with, sitting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sameï¿½ï¿½ M ï¿½ ï¿½</ENAMEX> *
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">bjbjï¿½=ï¿½=</ENAMEX> )<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> ?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX> ?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">W M& 8 ï¿½ï¿½ ï¿½ï¿½ ï¿½ï¿½ l , , , , , , , @ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ 8 4</ENAMEX>
         @
         <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">@ % X X</ENAMEX> " <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">z z z z z z</ENAMEX> ï<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ $ ï¿½ ï¿½ j ï¿½</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">z z z z z ï¿½ ï¿½ , , z z ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ z , z , z ï¿½ ï¿½ z ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ , , ï¿½ z L</ENAMEX>
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ï¿½$ jï¿½ @ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ ï¿½ 0 % ï¿½ e ï¿½ e ï¿½ ï¿</ENAMEX>½ @ @ , <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">, , , ï¿</ENAMEX>½ HJ: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hye-Jin Jung</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interviewer</ENAMEX>)
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris O'Connor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interviewee</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">START OF TAPE 1</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDE A</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hi</ENAMEX>.
         My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris O'Connor</ENAMEX>.
         And um, I'm a host-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hye-Jin</ENAMEX>.
         And I'm, I'm, um, I'm honored um, to participate in the project.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, what I would like to do is explain to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hye-Jin</ENAMEX> an experience I had, um, as, as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, uh, something that um, has stayed to me really all of my life and is especially meaningful now that I live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.
         Because I was born in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX>, I was raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North I</ENAMEX>, you know, truly am, um, I consider myself a northern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, um, and quite by surprise um, we came to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years ago</TIMEX>, um, mainly for work reasons.
         Both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I had lost our jobs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>.
         So, we came south, because this is where the jobs are and fortunately, we were able to get work and re-located here.
         So, this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years later</TIMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and I are employed in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, and I'm a coher about it later.
         And um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> I remember this is what I remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s saying.
         This made such an impression on me.
         She said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, don't you ever tell Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callahan</ENAMEX> that you slept in the same bed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX>.
         Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callahan</ENAMEX> would be shocked."
         So, I just, I just remember that very well and I never ever let this be known that it happened, although it didn't bother me, because I was very comfortable with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX>.
         You know, I didn't even think twice about it.
         And I certainly don't think I was damaged by it at all.
         I just got the very strong message that was not something that should be repeated to this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> and the particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> was a very fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>, but she had been raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.
         And that was totally, totally unacceptable to her way of thinking.
         So that's my um, recollection of um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ira Lee</ENAMEX>, of um, growing up um, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 50</TIMEX>'s probably.
         So, I just um, would like to share that story.
         I think we, I think we've come, hopefully, we've come a long way from, from that um, mode of thinking.
      
      
         So that maybe that kind of thinking has changed.
         Do you think maybe?
      
      
         Well, I think there has been, I mean, if you figured that was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 50</TIMEX>'s.
         Oh, I know there have been a lot of good changes.
         I mean since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> and all of that um, I still think, I still, I still know though that there is still prejudice.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, both ways, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to black, towards black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> towards white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and with all the races, it's not just limited to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.
         That was just my own personal experience, but sometimes now not that I dwell on this, when I think of my present working situation were I work in a school really there are, the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are, there are more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> are, it's pretty even but a little more black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         And you know, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, we have a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman principal</ENAMEX> whom I respect very much.
         I think she is a very fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
         And a lot of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, I think I respect them very much.
         I will say that I'm quite impressed with some of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         I notice um, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh, I notice that at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX> when we sit down to have lunch they immediately stop and say a silent prayer immediately, that's just routine of them.
         And you know, I admire that very much.
         And it's really I see it more with the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than I do with the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         Um so, um yes, we've come a long, long way since when I was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         But we still have a long way to go too.
      
   
