
   
   
      
         My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Phillips</ENAMEX>.
         I'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX>.
         Been lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23 years</TIMEX>.
         The story that I am going to tell is about my great, great, great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">granddaddy</ENAMEX> who was a bootlegger from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yanceyville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I think this story, well the story been told through my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because of, uh, what he had and what they tried to take from him.
         And he was a bootlegger and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX>, I guess, evidently he had the best <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">moonshine</ENAMEX> in all of Yanceyville
      so, so the, uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>, you know, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with them, you know, and use to get his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> from him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> and stuff.
         And he own a lot of land up there.
         Had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bulls</ENAMEX>, all that good stuff, lake on the property, and, um, a couple of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX>, a couple of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KKK</ENAMEX>, and, um, and what, uh, else did they use to say?
         They said, I mean, he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, you know, they said back then you ain't see too many black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> with brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and stuff like that, but he had the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and, ah, he also ran numbers too.
         They said that he ran numbers and, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputies</ENAMEX> use to tell him, you know, to watch out, you know, some of the cooler ones that won't in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klan</ENAMEX>.
         But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>, you know, always said, you know, he told him when it was really time for him to get out he needed to get out.
         Evidently he got smart and got out but the story goes, you know.
         He was going on and on and on and he was mixed at that, you know, he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> white and black, but they ain't really didn't too much bother him about that because of the fact his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> was black and his momma was white, you know.
         They had a problem with that but, um, um, he had a lot of money, from what I understand.
         He had a lot of money and then things got thick.
         A lot of them white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start getting jealous and start trying, you know, take the property and stuff doing little stuff, going out killing his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>.
         They ain't mess with the his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bulls</ENAMEX> or nothing.
         They use to come on, he use to charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come on his property and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hunt deer</ENAMEX>, and they use to sneak on and stuff and he catch them out there but he couldn't shoot them because he know he'd get lynched if he did that.
         And then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, um, somebody got jealous, came down, and burnt down the trailer, he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> on the property, then came and burned down the trailer and burnt up the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken coop</ENAMEX>, but eventually he got all that back.
         Kept on bootlegging and they still getting jealous and I remember going to, after getting all of that back, you know, back.
         It's still there now, but I remember, and I still do when we, when I go to the family reunions.
         We go out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken coop</ENAMEX> and it stink.
         I don't go in there though, but I always go out to the, uh, where they got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bulls</ENAMEX> at, and check them out and go and get up on desk stand and see where they at.
         And, um, he even still got some of those old kettles back there they broke and all mess up and stuff, and his kettles were hidden inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken coop</ENAMEX>.
         And, and, um, um, um, what am I trying to say?
         Oh.
         When it really got thick, when, um, it got to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point where him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> fell out, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>, you know, he wasn't really, I guess, evidently, let them tell it, he was the cool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.
         And the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Klan people</ENAMEX>, um, found out, you know, what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, or whatever, what was going on.
         And they were already jealous, a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> making money, or a half back <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> making money, or whatever you want to call it, and they came and burnt the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> down, burnt the chicken coop down, and they killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>, or a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>, I ain't too sure about that, but I think they killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> or a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, they tried to take his land from him and they took it from him for a minute, and he went to jail for a little bit, and he got out, and still, you know, couldn't get his land, but he bought, bought, and bought, and he got his land back.
         And, um, now, you know, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion is held there and, and, um, the land is divided up, you know.
         Every little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the family done bought <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a acre</NUMEX> of land or how many acres they wanted to buy.
         Chicken coop back but ain't no <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> in it though
      .
         I don't know what they did to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>.
         But the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, it's a bull out there and I think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cows</ENAMEX>.
         They're all over the property, and they still sell the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, you know, they rent the land out during I guess deer season to, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         They got to pay though, you know, to come on the property because there're <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX> stand all throughout.
         And I think they should make them pay to fish because big ass lake, a big old lake out there, and they, you know, I want to go fishing there, but I'm driving from out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and it ain't like I'm carrying some fishing rods or nothing.
         They got, they got, um, I think they should make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pay to fish too, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his</TIMEX>, it's his niece, that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Claudia</ENAMEX>.
         She the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> live on the land.
         Well she live in, she got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> out there and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> out there.
         They rent the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> out.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Hubert</ENAMEX> own the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.
         That's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his</TIMEX>, that's his son, or somebody, but he own the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         He rent the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and now it's nice.
         They got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wheeler trails</ENAMEX> and stuff out there now, and all kinds of stuff, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheelers and stuff.
         You can turn that off.
         And we got, what else?
         I mean it's a nice story because I would have like to live back in them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, you know, the bootleg and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">moonshine</ENAMEX> stuff, myself.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, you know, up there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yanceyville</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, what else?
         We, oh you ride pass there now, you know, like we going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion, you just be riding down because you got to ride.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord</ENAMEX>, let me tell you about the ride.
         You ride down way out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> first of all, then you make a left turn.
         That's all I remember.
         Yeah you make this left turn and you driving for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about five miles</NUMEX>, and then you past part of the lake, you go on down and then you see the mailbox.
         You think it, you think you are at, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt, well Aunt Claudia</ENAMEX>, well she live, you know, directly on the property, but, um, my granddaddy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen</ENAMEX> property, my great, great, great granddaddy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen</ENAMEX> property and the mailbox is at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, and you turn, make a right and get on this dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
         And you driving for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> more miles
      , <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two more miles</NUMEX> and, I <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> you not, you driving for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two more miles</NUMEX>, but that's, um, that's is the prettiest scenery you will ever see because you, you see the lake on the right.
         You see deer running in and out, you know, just crossing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and carrying on, but they need to pave that road because ain't nothing but a buck of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> and you get on down there.
         But the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on the property is sweet.
         I know why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Claudine</ENAMEX> don't live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         She want to live in the trailer.
         I'll quit renting that out but it ain't her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> anyway, ain't her property, but anyway, back to the story.
         Yeah they finally done took all of his stuff, well tried to take all of his stuff but he got it all back and he was a popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, you know, and, um, he start bootlegging again and, you know, still the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> or whatever but he, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>, they squash their little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>, or what not, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> told him, you know, was telling him when he really need to get out and finally, he got smart and he just did it.
         And he stop for real and that was that.
         But everybody talk about how cool my, my, um, great, great, great granddaddy was.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granddaddy Owen</ENAMEX>.
         That's who I'm named after, and I think that's why I am so cool too, and uh that's that, I mean.
      
   
