
   
   
      
         Welcome back to our show!
         OK.
         This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX>, and I don't know your last name.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polk</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh that's good.
         From <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Polkton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Polk</ENAMEX>.
         OK.
         And where did you grow up?
         Were you born in this area here?
      
      
         I was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cottonville</ENAMEX>.
         Right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norwood</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stanley County</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Oh, OK.
         When you were little, did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> read you books, or did somebody read you books in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mama</ENAMEX> read to me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         What kind of books were your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX>?
         Do you remember any that were maybe a real favorite of yours?
      
      
         Mm, I kind of liked them all.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I didn't really have a favorite.
      
      
         No?
         Any particular types, like ones with pictures or
         .
         Can you think of a story that they told you that you liked for them to read over and over?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I think my favorite was like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Red Riding Hood;</ENAMEX>" I loved that book.
      
      
         "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Red Riding Hood"</ENAMEX>?
         So when you read to yourself did you read different stories than the ones they would read to you?
      
      
         Mmm, basically, something different.
      
      
         Did you get to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> when you were little?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh-huh</ENAMEX>, all the time.
      
      
         Yeah.
         So, you would check books out?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         Mostly, I liked to spend time reading encyclopedias--
      
      
         Oh, really?
      
      
         --when I was little.
      
      
         You like to read encyclopedias.
         In your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, do you remember if there was any storyteller?
      
      
         Well, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> was always telling stories and, uh, we had this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from where I grew up that was old and he ever finished it.
         He started it and he told stories that, um, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> being in it that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and stuff and for us not to go outside <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at night</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Would he scare you?
      
      
         Yeah.
         So we, at a certain time, we were scared to go over there because we'd always go outside and look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, did he tell stories to big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, or just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX>?
      
      
         Just to our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and all of us that hung around each other all the time.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         Now, do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         No.
         Only, only on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>: my niece and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         Do you like to read to them?
         Do they bring their books over?
      
      
         I read to my niece.
         She likes the pop-out books.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
         How old is she?
      
      
         She's, ah
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six</TIMEX>.
         She likes the pictures that pop out at you.
         She likes for me to read them to her.
      
      
         Can she read to herself yet?
      
      
         Not yet, but she tries to.
         Mostly, she just looks at the pictures.
      
      
         Is she, what grade is she in?
         Do you know?
      
      
         She's in kindergarten.
      
      
         She's in kindergarten?
         OK.
         That's pretty much all I need to know, about how you liked reading and things when you were little.
         Is there anything else you'd like to say about this, that comes to your mind?
      
      
         No, not so much.
      
   
