
   
   
      
         My earliest recollection is with my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Mary</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> were married on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>, and that was my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mama</ENAMEX>'s birthday.
         That's when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> were married and they both are from here.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Wilson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Propst</ENAMEX> and he was born and raised, uh, downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX>.
         If you remember the sign, it was down next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Pig</ENAMEX>, right on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Corben Avenue</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         They just tore that old building down where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, uh, grew up on, in an area near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blackwelder</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyland</ENAMEX>.
         Do you remember that?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         I don't know if you remember that or not.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         But, uh, she grew up where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">7-Eleven</ENAMEX> is now.
         There's a real pretty, old, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-story <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">clapboard house</ENAMEX> and that's where she grew up.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but they were married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX>, and had, uh, my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I. But</ENAMEX>, uh, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1969</TIMEX> of lung <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WI</ENAMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayo Clinic</ENAMEX> up there.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> never got over that, um, just really, really close to him.
         And she just, after all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, she never got over it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, but she did an admirable job.
         I think so far.
         She is still living and, uh, somewhat healthy.
         She does have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         But other than that, she's a lot of fun and has a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and she both came from big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> came from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calloway</ENAMEX>.
         Her mother, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s side was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howell</ENAMEX> and that was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howell Baptist Church</ENAMEX> down towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">601</NUMEX>, down towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monroe</ENAMEX>.
         So that's where they were from.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> came from a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         He, he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, as I said he grew up in town but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> originally lived out on the eastern part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cabarrus County</ENAMEX>, which is, uh, they lived out <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gold Hill Road and Irish Potato</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, probably sometime around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the century</TIMEX>, just prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the turn of the twentieth century</TIMEX>, they did move into town
         and they built an old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and lived
         , excuse me, where, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heilig-Meyers</ENAMEX> is.
         I think your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> just did a thing with, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         But there was an old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> there next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown Livery Stable</ENAMEX>.
         That's where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Propst</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Etta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caroline Etta Ritchie Propst</ENAMEX> lived.
         But as I said, what I'm getting to my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Mary</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had a sister
         had several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>, but there was one, her name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Propst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Elizabeth Propst</ENAMEX>.
         She never married and lived to be, she was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August tenth 1901</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ninth</TIMEX> rather.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> and she was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX>.
         She lived to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 95 years old</TIMEX>, never married, was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX>, I like to say, all her life.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         As most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are, uh, which is, I guess, the first thing that I learned to admire about her.
         And, uh, that's where my respect for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> comes from, from her.
         She was also a principal.
         She was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolteacher</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> at what was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clara Harris</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, and, um, but--
      
      
         It's hard to believe that somebody could be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">\\</TIMEX> both a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and a principal.
         \\
      
      
         \\And she was.
         \\ There's a story.
         I guess probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some 10 to 12 years ago</TIMEX>.
         We had one of many bond referendums, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> bond referendums, that I was really working hard on.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, uh, read in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> about the bond referendums.
         It was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23 million dollars</NUMEX>, an incredible amount of money, and she asked me to come down.
         She wanted to talk to me about this bond referendum.
         She wanted to know all about it.
         You know, "Why are we doing this?"
         "What do we need the money for?
         How is it going to be spent?"
         She genuinely--
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         She was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>.
         Although she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">92 or 93</TIMEX> at the time, she was going to get in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and go vote one way or the other.
         And so, I would try to explain to her how it was very important, with all the growth we were experiencing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cabarrus County</ENAMEX>, to keep the, uh, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 30</NUMEX> if we could, and we weren't meeting that with the growth.
         So we needed to fix up some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and try to keep that.
         And she said, "I understand.
         I understand," and I went on further to say, you know, just, just, I gave several reasons that she, she agreed with.
         And I went a little bit too far I said, uh, "And besides, you know, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 30</NUMEX>, a classroom size of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> could never do it without an assistant."
         
         She said to me, she says, "An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>!"
         She says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My</ENAMEX>, when I was coming up, you know well I, I had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 and 50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and I didn't have an assistant and I was principal."
         
         She didn't say it that way she didn't mean it that way.
         I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yes ma'am</ENAMEX>."
         
         But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> didn't come prepared like they did then.
         They didn't come disciplined, uh, now as they did then.
         And, um, and I believe that.
         But, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Mary</ENAMEX>, again, she was a very instrumental part of my life.
         I love history and I love genealogy and it is because of her that I do.
         Um
         , her, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, pardon me, yes, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Propst</ENAMEX>.
         I forgot now that when he was born, probably, uh probably sometime around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 1828, 1830, 1831</TIMEX>.
         He served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">57th Regiment</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cabarrus County</ENAMEX> and he didn't die, uh, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 20</TIMEX>'s.
         Lived to be almost, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost a hundred</NUMEX>.
         And as I said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> never married.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And she lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> there at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corben</ENAMEX> and, and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Church Street</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX> died, sometime in the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> came back with, to live with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>.
         And she took care of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
         And to this day, it's, it's phenomenal, it's a fantastic story.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, initially, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette</ENAMEX> really couldn't understand why I would get so excited about it.
         But here I am, I knew and became very close to someone, my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Mary</ENAMEX>, who in turn took care of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX>, and knew well, was old enough to recollect, you know, his stories.
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         Not only of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, but of his childhood.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And it is fascinating.
         It's fascinating some of which I've got on tape.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she would never allow me to video.
         But I got a good bit of that on tape and, uh, just interviews similar to this, uh, fascinating.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         I recall her talking about how she cared for him once he did come back from the war and he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox scar</ENAMEX> that he always had problems with, which I understand there was a lot of that.
         But, especially through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the war years</TIMEX>, he would write her and talk about, you know, his arm and she knew exactly what it was.
         But, uh, uh, or, or she didn't know at the time, but later he, he described that, and she recalled taking care of it even, even in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> of his life.
         Just a lot of different stories.
         But she, he had, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandfather</ENAMEX> had written a lot of letters, during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, home to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, fortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> kept them all those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, and then when she passed away, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, she left them to me.
         And so it's amazing reading the history of those letters, not just, not just the history of the war, but the letters, what they talked about.
         They have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plantation</ENAMEX>, probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">600 acres</NUMEX> out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Potato Road</ENAMEX> at the time, and a lot of what the letters talked about to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-grandmother</ENAMEX> were ideas of what to do.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         If you could imagine and, and let me say this, some of the letters that I have, that I love the most, that are dearest to me are some of the letters that, that she wrote him.
         And he were, he was able to get.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And to know that he kept them and then brought them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         So these are some of the dearest letters.
         And in reading her letters to him, wherever he might be, a lot of the letters come from, obviously in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fredericksburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1862, 1863</TIMEX>.
         And, uh, she would ask, "What do we do now about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX>?
         What do we do about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oats</ENAMEX>?
         What do we do about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>?
         What do we do about this?
         What about this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">timber</ENAMEX>?"
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         You know, "You always talked about doing--.
         So and so has called me.
         Do I trust this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>?"
         You know, you think about it, uh, probably prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, she, she didn't have this information.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         You know they probably, she, if you think about it, she, not that he kept anything from her, it's just that, uh, she probably took care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, if you will.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And he, in turn, took care of the other affairs.
         And all of a sudden he's up and gone for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three and a half years</TIMEX>.
         Similar situation happened with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, uh, just, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX>.
         But, uh, then he would respond, you know, "Well you can trust this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or you can't trust this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>," or, "I would suggest that you do this."
         But always to a "t."
         He would always, you could see the respect <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in him for her.
         "But you do what you think is right.
         Here's, I'm trying to answer some of your questions, but, and this is what I think maybe you might want to consider doing."
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         "But you, and I will support you.
         Here I am not knowing if I'll ever come home."
      
      
         Right.
      
      
         And so it's just, it's just a wonderful history.
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> established, I guess, what I was getting, she established the love I have for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      
   
