
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Purdie</ENAMEX>.
         I've been asked to recount the story of how I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> came to be going out with my present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, who, more than likely, I will end up marrying in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year and a half or so</TIMEX>.
         Well the story goes something like this: Late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early December</TIMEX>, don't remember which, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990, 1990</TIMEX> I had a dream.
         I was marrying this one particular individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
         And as I drove to school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> with my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> I've known longest in the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Mossier</ENAMEX>, we discussed this dream I had.
         And, we discussed it, and he said, "Wow!"
         And I said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>, I'm probably going to marry this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>."
         And, well, that was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years ago</TIMEX>.
         [Clears throat] So, you know, we got to know each other a little better; we'd gone to school together since the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade.
         And we started doing that flirting thing, you know, acting like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>, flirting, doing this, that, and the other, but nothing officially ever happened.
         So <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, a band fruit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>, a very nasty day, kinda funny, I asked her out to a movie.
         It caught her a little bit off guard and she said, "Yes."
         And we went and saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the poorest movies I've ever seen in my life, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Men and a Little Lady</ENAMEX>.
         It's the sequel to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Three Men and a Baby</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Anyway, we went and saw that movie; both of us hated, hated it and I think we may have actually hold, held hands together in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last half</TIMEX> of the movie.
         Didn't kiss.
         Then we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baskin-Robbins</ENAMEX> and she got some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Chocolate Gold Caramel Ribbon ice cream</ENAMEX> and I got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mint Chocolate Chip</ENAMEX>, and we ate and we made a mess and I drove her home.
         And that was our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">date</TIMEX> and how we met.
      
      
         
         So what happened after that?
      
      
         Oh, after that?
         All kinds of things.
      
      
         Because obviously you're still dating her and it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>.
      
      
         We went to the prom together, junior year.
         That was exciting.
         She was wearing this big, huge, green <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella</ENAMEX> dress that she won't allow me to mention any longer because she hates it now.
         And then, I ended up giving her my high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> ring, cheesy!
         And on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, this is a good story, playing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frisbee</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween Day</TIMEX>, and I dove to knock the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frisbee</ENAMEX> out of somebody's hand.
         I dove in front of them, and as I dove in front him, he grabbed the back of my shirt, sent all my weight forward, and I ended up landing on my thumb and my index finger of my left hand, right hand, and broke a couple of balls in my wrist.
         Had to wear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six weeks</TIMEX> and then another little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six weeks</TIMEX> after that.
         Stinky hand because I couldn't wash it.
         Anyway, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> afterwards, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, we had gone to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greensboro</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gastonia, Ashbrook</ENAMEX>.
         And, after the game was over, we got back to school and we talked out in the parking lot for what seems to be forever.
         And I asked her if she wanted to wear it since I couldn't, because it would, you know, the hand had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> on it.
         Anyway, she said, "Yeah, sure," and we giggled and laughed and then we went our separate ways and went home.
         So all senior year, we went out about every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, movies, hanging out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, doing whatever.
         And we had a very, very, we went to the prom together.
         Then, sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, after we graduated, we had a really long talk about what we were going to do because we were going to different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were you going to?
      
      
         I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>, she went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wake Forest University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winston-Salem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         And it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only an hour, hour and a half, hour and 45 minutes</TIMEX> drive, depending on the traffic, depending on how fast you fly above the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>.
         But we had a talk about whether or not we wanted to continue dating or whether we wanted to break it off or whether we wanted to continue dating but allow the other to date other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> while we were in college.
         And well, the consensus was, we should probably keep in touch but that we should give each free reign to, to date other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
         Well, low and behold, that never happened for either one of us.
         And we made it, all through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of college, together, discussing quite often whether or not we were going to end up marrying each other.
         And while, she ended up taking a job in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, which was a little bit further from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winston-Salem</ENAMEX> was, and she wanted me to move down there.
         And well I hate the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s too big for its own good.
         But I did try to get a job down there, teaching.
         Didn't make her happy at all.
         But well, we've gone through, some little fights here and there about whether or not I wanted to be down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and whether I really wanted to be with her, and whether she really wanted to be with me, if I didn't really want to follow her at all, all the way down there.
         She thought that.
         But anyway, she, is probably going to move back here and we will probably get married, and have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and live the happily ever after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX> little story because I am <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charming</ENAMEX> and she is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess</ENAMEX>.
         What other story shall I tell?
      
      
         If that's all you want to say, that's fine.
      
   
