
   
   
      
         Just talk?
      
      
         Just talk.
      
      
         OK, um, we, um, live in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         We are here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>.
         We've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 13 years</TIMEX> and we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Wes and Megan</ENAMEX>, who, uh, one just finished college and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other one is, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Megan</ENAMEX> is a junior at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> this, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we have enjoyed, I guess, our move here, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we've met and all, just the differences, I guess.
         We kind of had some, uh, not reservation about moving, it was an elective move for us, but certainly, um, living in a different part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> than we were used to was, uh, something which was a change for us and something that we had thought long about.
         But coming here, rather than, um, perhaps picking up and focusing on the differences, I think we tried to look at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the</TIMEX>, uh, you know, just the<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">, um, the</ENAMEX>, the special points about the, uh, life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customs</ENAMEX> and I think it's been something that we've always, uh, valued.
         Some, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, uh, either, uh, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> don't value the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North and</ENAMEX> vice versa, but I think it's been a real positive thing, our move for us, in many ways.
         And, uh, it was a little harder on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, particularly, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wes</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he was at a, just, uh, had a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, that he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with and did lots of things with.
         And when he came here, uh, you know, having to start all over for him was difficult.
         And I think it took him a little while, uh, longer than our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, who fit in I think with a group of people pretty quickly.
         We've been involved in the area, in our neighborhood.
         
         There's a neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> we've been involved in that pretty strongly.
         We've, um, we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> and have been there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost the 13 years</TIMEX> that we've been here and have had various, um, areas of participation and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> there, and have been pretty much a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we have a fairly strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in all parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or at least this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>, this part of the, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eastern United States</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KY.</ENAMEX>
         And just had a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> move here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">KY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>.
         And, uh, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is scattered, uh, back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">OH</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO.</ENAMEX> But we find that a, a fairly intentional way, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, of getting together and we enjoy just, uh, doing some fairly mundane things.
         But when we get together, we, um, that is, we just enjoy eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, we enjoy putting puzzles together, we sometimes go to the beach and just do as little as we can as possible, and just enjoy, you know, doing things together.
         So we have a fairly, um, I would say, strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and important to us, and are fairly intentional about getting together as often as we can.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Um-</ENAMEX>
      
      
         What are some of the differences you noticed when coming down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from</TIMEX>, that you mentioned-
      
      
         Differences, well, it's uh,
         I think there's, you know, just different, uh, phrases, and different ways of saying things.
         I think that, uh, it will take a while for me to get used to "mashing" a button on an elevator or, or, um, I'm just trying to think of, instead of taking someone home that you would "carry" them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or carry them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>.
         We picked up pretty easily the<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">, um</ENAMEX>, phrase for, you know, "Hello," or a greeting is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey</ENAMEX>!"
         And usually that was something you said up north to get someone's attention.
         Like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, you!"
         or "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hey</ENAMEX>!
         Over there!"
         But here it's just a greeting and we've gone back to visit in OH or elsewhere and we, pretty much it's just become a part of our language or usage as well and, um, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ask us about it.
         But we've picked up some things and then certainly there are other things that, language wise, we, um, still find, uh, a little different to get used to.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, I think that, I don't know, I guess, in terms of pace of life, I don't know that it's a lot different from what we were used to.
         I think that maybe in the northeast you would find maybe things to be more hectic or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be perhaps less friendly, but I think it pretty much depends on who you are and where you are and the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you are as, as to whether or not you, you know, make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> easily or whether, you know, you actually put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off.
         To my mind that doesn't really matter what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you are from.
         It seems if you're used to, if you're, if it's in your nature, you know, to treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with respect that you don't have that, you know, problem fitting in.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, but if you try to emphasize I guess, differences then I think then that's probably another issue.
         One thing that was kind of interesting, too was that we, uh, you know, just some strange things about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, in fact, is that when we came here, well, we're, back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">OH</ENAMEX>, I mean, there's a fairly, uh, developed, very well developed library system.
         And there, I mean, just good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> and large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> in neighborhoods and certainly the downtown area.
         When we came here they were just finishing the new main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in uptown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, but still there were, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">storefronts</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Independence Blvd</ENAMEX>.
         There was a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> over on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Rd</ENAMEX>.
         or actually on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairview Rd</ENAMEX>.
         , it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Library</ENAMEX>, and a very small <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> and, and the rest were just hither and yon.
         And now we have one of the, I guess, well-recognized library systems and probably the better ones in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
         We have regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> that have just seemed to have grown up in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> area and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rea Rd</ENAMEX>.
         and, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> and other places.
         And it's just amazing how much change there's been, a, a dramatic change there has been just in that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> alone.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and you look at other kinds of things and I think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, and maybe it's typical of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, but I think that, uh, maybe there hasn't been as much growth here before and when you have growth and you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming in, who, looking for services.
         And you, and you also have a, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, um, who are, are really ready to take that challenge as opposed to just deciding that, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, listen we're gonna do things the way we've done it for the last, you know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 years</TIMEX>, whether new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come or need services or ask for amenities or not, we're going to keep things the way they are."
         In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX>, I think, um, at least my understanding is, is that when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence Plantation</ENAMEX>, uh, reached a certain point in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> they, they wanted to be annexed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews</ENAMEX> because they thought maybe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> would annex them and so they wanted to, that they petitioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> to annex.
         But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> at that point said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>," because they were afraid that all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other places would come in and be a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> government and change things.
         And so they decided to, you know, basically vote the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> out and it will keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, uh, small.
         But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> has grown many times, uh, just in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 15 years</TIMEX>.
         And, and, and certainly the, the leadership has changed there.
         And, uh, you know, there is a more inclusive, uh, government there.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, other differences, uh, I think we, we miss a park system, a little better organized park system.
         We were used to, um, probably some smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and, and, and larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, regional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>.
         But we would often go to, to hike, and actually they had cabins and things like that, other activities and, with them that we did.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-wise, I think we've, we've found <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be probably pretty much the, what you hear about in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.
         And that is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, hospitality and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are, for the most part, warm and friendly and, um, and, and that's been a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a</NUMEX>, a really a nice, nice part about moving here.
         I think that I, it just depends on what the accent is, but I could sit and listen for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to, to certain southern accents.
         I enjoy listening, uh, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have grown up in the area and who speak with that accent.
         It used to be when you could come here that uh,
         that still the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> were the greatest number of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
         And now it seems like, at least in the place where I work and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we run into, a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, uh, seem to be from other places and fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, you know, are just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> to uh, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolinas</ENAMEX> or, um, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.
         Um
         just trying to think of other things that might be difference
         .
         Well, I guess, I work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and I'm probably partial, uh, to, to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, but I worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Dayton</ENAMEX> before and also with a regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>.
         And I think that, um, that in terms of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, if the, if the city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is, is, is at all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of, of just the politics here, both in the private sector and the public sector, there's just a real interest in, in uh, in, in getting things done.
         And, and also, I think, not necessarily in reinventing the wheel, but in looking at everything that you do to see if there's some way that you can't do it better.
         And to reengineer processes, to, uh, to try to, again be, you know, I guess good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stewards</ENAMEX> of the public's money and to, and to act in a, in a very reasonable and responsible way and to provide basic, good basic services.
         And I think that whether we're talking about, um, you know, that or we're talking about a can-do spirit to do other civic projects, public projects, partnering with the private sector, I think that there is just a real attitude to, again, be a place of excellence and to find a way to get things done.
         And that's been, uh, something which I haven't in, in other places.
         And I think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> is, is recognized as not only as a, it's a business community and a growth <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, but also as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that has one of the best, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, uh, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> for, for at least <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>, cities our size.
         I think we're nationally recognized, uh, for what we do from just a managing standpoint.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and so that's been a, I think a good change for us, uh, since I work in that environment.
         One thing, is it's been difficult trying to, now, now that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> starting to move down here, I think that the one drawback was, uh, just moving probably <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> away, driving time, from um, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX>.
         But now most of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is in other places and so that's probably not as much of a factor.
         
         So I guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question might be how I met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I guess that's a, I've known my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, we grew up in the same, uh, city together.
         We went to different high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but we went to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>.
         And our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> and so we were acquainted that way, but it wasn't until I was probably a sophomore in college that, uh, we started dating.
         And, um, she went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miami University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">OH</ENAMEX>, and I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> in IN, so visiting was, uh, problematic but we, we did find a way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every couple of weeks</TIMEX> to, um, to get together.
         And I guess that started in probably `<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">71</TIMEX> and we were married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> of `<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX>.
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> still had, uh, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to finish.
         I was in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and then we, I graduated and we went to, moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, she finished up.
         Even though she went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> she still had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> to make up, and so she went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baldwin Wallace</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> and finally graduated with a, with a degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she had lost some credits in transferring.
         But we had a, it was a good way to, to start out in life.
         We, uh, lived in married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> housing, we, we had a fairly, uh, tight budget.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, you know, I had an assistantship with, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> so we were pretty much sufficient on that.
         But we learned, uh, to uh, to do with, uh, very little and to, um, just enjoy, you know, getting to, I mean being together and, and knowing each other and finding neat things to do.
         And so, I think that we've, we've pretty much carried that through, uh, the rest of our life in many ways.
         I think we enjoy, you know, being together, we enjoy, um, you know, talking [clears throat] and doing some of the simple things.
         If we have other things that's great and we, we seek those out, but we're not, I mean, we're not, we enjoy spending time together and don't necessarily seek time apart.
         And we've been doing this now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 28 years</TIMEX>, so it's been a, a good marriage for us.
      
   
