
   
   
      
         Well, I was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>.
         And, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October twenty-fifth 1976</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are still living up north.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX>, off of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Throgs Neck Bridge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bayside</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poconos</ENAMEX>, which is known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stroudsburg, PA.</ENAMEX>
         I've been down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, I would say, oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> now, going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>.
         I came down here originally on a, to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> area at, uh, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh, I guess I'm what you would refer to as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Damn Yankee</ENAMEX>" because I haven't left; I'm staying.
         Well, at least for a while I was.
         I'm presently going to be going on my way out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> for a job opportunity.
         But, um, the reason, uh, I guess I came down here again was to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NY</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years</TIMEX>.
         His side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian Jew</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side is, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic Italian</ENAMEX> from, uh, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>.
         And, uh--
      
      
         That's an interesting combination.
         
      
      
         That is definitely an interesting combination.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, so, I don't know, um.
      
      
         When did your, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Well, he, he, I believe he is, I guess it would be, you'd refer to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I think it's his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that came over.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, as far as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side I'm not too sure.
         It might be roughly around the same.
         She's either she's either <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> generation.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Um</ENAMEX>--
      
      
         Do you know why his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> came?
      
      
         I think just like everyone else, for an opportunity.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, an opportunity to come over here, I would, I would say, to practice medicine.
         It seems like everyone in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is, uh, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, the, just the same on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side.
         Just for that opportunity to come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
         So, but, um, for myself, I love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         It's a beautiful area.
         It's a lot different from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX> that's for sure.
         Can't say that I've come to love grits
         , but, um, I've met my future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Is she a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         She's a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>.
         She's a religious background, religious background upbringing, which I cannot say I've been a part of.
         And, um, she's going to calm me down a lot I think and, uh, instill a lot of, instill a lot of positive aspects of my life that have thus far been deferred.
      
      
         How did you meet her?
      
      
         Well, I was fortunate enough to meet her in college, in which we were best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two and a half years</TIMEX>.
         Until, uh, finally, I don't know, the light came on, I guess, for her I should say because for myself the light came on pretty much as soon as I met her.
         And, uh, she'll be following me out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> myself.
      
      
         Has she been up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX> with you?
      
      
         She has.
         She, um, we've been up recently.
         I proposed to her in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>.
         We were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> seeing my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         And my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> was in town who, both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> were born and raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>, not too far from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yankee Stadium</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         And, uh, so I guess you're a big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Big time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>.
         .
         It's been a good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years</TIMEX> for us <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> here lately.
         And, uh, we were down on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifty-Third Street</ENAMEX>, which is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> blocks away from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>, and, um, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fianc�e</ENAMEX> had just passed her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> and it was our anniversary, so I decided to surprise her with walking down to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> off of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fifty-Eighth</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, it kind of just worked out perfect.
         I proposed to her.
         I was lucky enough for her to say, "Yes."
         And, um, so, yeah, she's been up north a couple of times and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PA</ENAMEX> area as well the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poconos</ENAMEX> where you hear the honeymooners always go.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         And, um, so--
      
      
         Well it sounds like you have a pretty bright future ahead of you.
      
      
         Not too bad.
         It's getting brighter and brighter, it seems, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.
         And, um, it's going to be a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> for us going out to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>, with me being a pharmaceutical sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fianc�e</ENAMEX> being in the medical profession as well, being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>.
         And, um--
      
      
         I've heard that's a beautiful area.
      
      
         Yes it is.
         It's a lot to do.
         A lot of hiking and mountain biking.
         I don't ski.
         I think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fianc�e</ENAMEX> does a little bit.
         But, um, I don't know how much we'll do of that.
         But I would, would suspect that we would end up back up, maybe, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> area.
         If not, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> for sure, um--
      
      
         That would probably make your in-laws very happy.
      
      
         Very happy along with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, as well.
         Because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> seems to be a little far.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, but it's good we get to start our lives together out there, and hopefully, uh, start maybe in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three years</TIMEX> tops, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, start working on a family of our own.
         
         And, uh, that's something that I very much look forward to.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, creating a family of my own.
      
      
         Now if you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> would you want them to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> too?
      
      
         I would, I definitely would.
         And I would probably encourage them to come down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> area to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>.
         It's been a great experience for me.
      
      
         What was, what did you like best about playing?
         Well it was always an escape for me.
         Kept me, uh, motivated.
         Kept me out of trouble.
         
         which was the big thing, and, um, I like being competitive, I know my fianc�e is very competitive as well.
         So, I know if we do have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, even a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, I know there might be a good chance of being some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         So, uh, yeah.
         I'll definitely want them to pursue <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, but, by all means, it's probably going to be whatever they want to do.
         I don't want to force them or anything so--
      
      
         So where do you see yourself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 10 years from now</TIMEX>?
      
      
         In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about ten years</TIMEX>, definitely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> area.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, the beach is real appealing.
         If not maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, probably down by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wilmington</ENAMEX> or some sort.
         Definitely like to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         And, um, have done a lot of things by that point.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh-huh.</ENAMEX>
      
      
         Done a lot of traveling with my, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and seen a lot of things.
         In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years from now</TIMEX>, start setting some sort of, ah, foundation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we're raising, in some sort of steady home.
         And no more making big trips out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>, or making a big move for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, or something of that nature.
         So, I think, uh, we should be doing OK in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 10 years</TIMEX>.
      
   
