
   
   
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>.
         Hi, I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Ragonese</ENAMEX>, and I'm currently living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntersville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX>.
         I've been there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two and a half years</TIMEX>, but I grew up in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and I basically came down here um, just <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, but then I landed a job, so I've been staying here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">working</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and I happened upon <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntersville</ENAMEX> area just on the Internet.
         I was looking for a city down south and I kind of wanted an idea as to something new, something upcoming, and from what I understand, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> is a quite growing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
         So, it seemed like a really good place to come to, and so far I really like it.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I'm going to tell you a story about a trip I took with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and we're all about a year and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> apart and we're going to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Coral</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>.
         So, I think it was maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> and um, we left, actually just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and I went.
         And um, we left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and we were driving down, we were driving in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>'s um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Escort</ENAMEX>, which she'd had for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half</TIMEX> and uh, we were driving and everything, anticipating good weather and I think we were just about right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savannah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX> and I was driving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is standard and um, the clutch went out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.
         So, I was driving and I said to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Di</ENAMEX>, I don't think, I think something is wrong with the clutch," I said, "Because it seems to be on the floor," meaning it, it wasn't, didn't feel like it was connected.
         And I um, she said, "Pull off the side of the road," so I pulled off into this um, I guess it was like a rest stop.
         But, there weren't any pay phones, a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">truckers</ENAMEX>, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, whatever, so we stopped and definitely the clutch was broken.
         So, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CB</ENAMEX> and so we tried to radio some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, that didn't work.
         This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> came through with a cell phone, so we called for help and this
         "honky-tonk" kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>,
         I don't know where he was from, he was operating basically his machine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> or his repair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> right out of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>.
         He didn't have a license plate on his truck
         .
         He didn't have a decal saying where he worked or anything.
         So, it was kind of shady.
         But, so, it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three or four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock</TIMEX>, anyway, so we sat on the curb and waited for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.
         He comes first and assesses the situation and said, "I think that your clutch cable snapped and it's not really a big deal, we can <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> it up, so you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> can get to where you got to go, you just have to get it fixed."
         So fine, so he leaves.
         And we flag down an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and he comes and he tries and tells us, he proceeds to tell us there was a black belt, wait the murder belt?
         I don't know
         this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was crazy, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>, he said that we were in a really bad section of where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were like murdered and killed and like thrown like behind like the rest stop.
         So my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> are sitting on the curb thinking, "Oh, my God, we're going to die, right?"
         And not to mention it's getting later in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and it was about, I think it was late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early April</TIMEX>, it had to be.
         But anyways, so the sun had started descending, going down.
         Anyways, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> comes and he fix, he must have left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> times, I don't know where he was going, but I don't know where his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> was, but every time he comes back with some crazy thing and he eventually fixed our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with some uh, chicken wire, I think he rigged it up with.
         We have no idea
         .
         Anyways, we got in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and it got us to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savannah, GA.</ENAMEX>
         And we arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Savannah</ENAMEX>, um, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mardi Gras</ENAMEX>, was it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mar</ENAMEX>, no it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day</ENAMEX> and let me tell you there were some crazy things going on.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, the desk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendant</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> we checked in well, first we couldn't find any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, because it was booked, apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savannah</ENAMEX> is like really crazy around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>.
         So, um, we got there and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had long green nails on, it was kind of crazy.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she was like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OH</ENAMEX>, you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> came for the perfect time, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um St.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day</ENAMEX> and we're having parties and parties, and all this stuff.
         So, I couldn't go out, I think I was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 years old</TIMEX> and you have to be like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>, uh, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> to drink, and we decided not to go out, considering everything that had happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>.
         So, we woke up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX>, we went down and we drove down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FL</ENAMEX>.
         I think it took us in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all about 23 hours</TIMEX>, maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>, because she, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Coral</ENAMEX> is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>.
         So, we got there and my grandma is of course excited to see us and we unpacked our stuff and everything and we proceeded to lay out in the driveway, and my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>, um, being her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the sun, decided she didn't want to use sunscreen, because she really wanted to get a good suntan, she got a good suntan, she got a sunburn.
         After we yelled at her for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three hours</TIMEX> she decided to slap some sunburn on the back of her, suntan lotion on the back of her leg, and it left a nice white print, like hand print on the back of her leg, and the rest of her got sun burnt.
         So, then we basically um, we visited with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> and I have some step family that lives down there, so <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> we went out with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy</ENAMEX>
         and we uh, went out to some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> with him and everything.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, and then we went to, let's see For, I want to say it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Myers Beach</ENAMEX> I think, the beach is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>, we went down, it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandma</ENAMEX>'s and uh, it's a really nice beach, it's uh, was pretty warm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>.
         I think, we all got some color, but they were having an epidemic of red tide and so all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> were washing up on the shore and um, luck be it, since we were having such a good time um, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Allison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>, and I decide we are going to take a walk along the beach and there were <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish strewn</ENAMEX> everywhere so we were careful not to step on them.
         However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allison</ENAMEX> wasn't paying attention and she stepped on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and it got a barb, which is one of it's defense mechanisms, stuck in her foot, so it was really painful and her foot swelled up and everything.
         So, we go to this gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and they tell us we have to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, so we go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Coral</ENAMEX> and I think we were there for probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten hours</TIMEX>.
      
   
