
   
   
      
         Can I talk now?
      
      
         Yeah go ahead and try it.
      
      
         OK, I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX>, from what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> tells me I was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX>, and I was walking on the beach with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> and apparently I stepped on a sticker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bush</ENAMEX> and I had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> stickers in my foot
         .
         And it just stressed me terribly and I was crying and crying and I kept on just saying, "I need a doctor
         , I need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>!
         Get me a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>!"
         
         And I guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> convinced me to take them out of my foot and I lived to tell this story.
      
      
         Good thing.
      
      
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okey</ENAMEX>-dokey
         .
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, let's see, some other stories that I remember, let me think.
         Stop me, can I, stop me while I think?
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, um.
      
      
         What stories do you tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gage</ENAMEX>?
         Like books do you read to him?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we read, what do we read?
         We read all kinds of books.
         Whatever he pulls off of the shelf.
         And he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> books.
      
      
         What's his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he doesn't really have a favorite; he picks whichever one is going that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
         He just got a book it's called, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Boy</ENAMEX>, and it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a</NUMEX>, um, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> on the CA coast, who does, uh, they run out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in the area where they are.
         And ( ).
         Anyway, so it's about this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> on the CA coast and wherever they are, they run out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and they decide that they have to move.
         Well, this one little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> had always, um, been real nice to the eagles and thought they were really cool and all this, and, um, for whatever reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> decides that they need to leave him behind, and they leave him on the beach as they paddle off.
         Well, he was starving and an eagle came by and dropped a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX> down for him or some <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and he was able to eat.
         And it's because he had always been nice to the eagles and talked to the eagles and all that and they saw that he was in trouble.
         Well, he really liked one of the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who had gone off with the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> and so he told the eagles to drop her some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> because he knew they were starving too and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eagle</ENAMEX> did.
         And then they realized that it was all because of the, him that the eagles were dropping them food, and so they came back and got him and it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big happy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> again.
         And the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> married and lived happily ever after.
         And so that one he just got, and he likes that one.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, he likes, what other stories do we tell?
         He really likes to make up stories.
         He'll like, it's usually about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Ranger</ENAMEX>.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Ranger</ENAMEX> has to overcome some huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> and it's usually a bloody battle
         , but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Ranger</ENAMEX> always wins.
         He'll make up those from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eden</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greensboro</ENAMEX>, which is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 minutes</TIMEX> long, and you have to do it.
         And so, he, that, he usually does that with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>, and they make up a story the whole way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
         And he tries to get me to do it, but I cannot talk to like that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 minutes</TIMEX>, so we just usually make it halfway with our stories.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, what other stories do we tell?
      
      
         Any good life experience stories?
      
      
         No
         .
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gage</ENAMEX> about, like we'll tell him about like if you do this, you know, could be hurt.
         Like, um, "When I was little I knew a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who stuck his head out and got hit by the by the telephone pole while he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and killed him.
         Don't stick your head out."
         Um
         , like when he, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we were at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and she had just made <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pies</ENAMEX> and he saw them come out of the oven, and he knew they were hot but it had been sitting on the stove for a little bit.
         And he went up to grab it and he burned his fingers and so we told him, you know, times that we burned ourselves and that it hurts and that it will stop.
         And plus, you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX> can talk away fire so we had to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> and tell him to talk away <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gage</ENAMEX>'s fire.
         And, um, so we tell him about that.
      
      
         How does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX> talk away this fire?
      
      
         He, he does some, I don't know.
         See, he can't tell you
         , but he does something like this, and then he has to know your birth date, your birth date, your age I don't know, something else and it, it works, I'm not kidding.
      
      
         It makes things stop hurting?
      
      
         It makes your burn stop hurting.
         The next time you burn, call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX> and he'll say, "How old are you and what's your birthday<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
         and then you just hang up and it will go away.
         He does, he says something; it's very weird.
         I'm being serious though, it works.
         I've burned myself and called him and he does it and it stops hurting.
         Now maybe if I never called him, it would just stop hurting anyway, but I don't know
         .
         So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX> can do that.
         Let's see what's another story?
         Um what's something else?
      
      
         Anything good you remember just like childhood story like something you did when you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, teenager?
      
      
         No teenager stories
         .
      
      
         ( )
      
      
         When you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had that hearse, that convertible hearse?
         Well he used to like, there was like-
      
      
         A convertible hearse?
      
      
         You knew about that.
         You knew the hearse that he, anyway we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> who said, "I bet you can't take a hearse and make it into a convertible," and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> said, "I bet I can."
         
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX> went out, bought a hearse, cut off the top, and painted it like bright yellow, and it had red velvet seats in it.
         He had a convertible top made for this stupid thing.
         I mean, oh my gosh, it was in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> for years
         .
         Anyway, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> made this convertible hearse and he used to take all the neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and there was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> of us.
         He put us all in the hearse and we would go hooker hunting downtown.
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hooker</ENAMEX> what?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hooker</ENAMEX> hunting
         !
         So, we'd go downtown and go, "There's one!"
         
         But see, and really it was just to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dairy Queen</ENAMEX>, `cause you had to go downtown to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dairy Queen</ENAMEX>, and he was really taking us all for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>
         .
         But we used to call it hooker hunting
         .
         And so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would come over and go, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> can we go hooker hunting<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
         We'd do that and, um, that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>!
         What else would my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> do?
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> did all kinds of crazy things to our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         He would he had the canoe strung up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> on a pulley system so all he would have to do is pull the car up underneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> and he'd let the canoe down on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, unhook it
         back by the hearse was the canoe in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.
         Damn, to be me.
      
   
