
   
   
      
         Hi my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Reid</ENAMEX> and I am part of a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, um, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> have passed away.
         During our young <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> we were very poor.
         
         We did not have very much but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> always found a way to keep us busy or keep us entertained, and one of the ways that she kept us entertained was by telling stories, reading poems, and singing to us.
         <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the stories that I would like to share with you is the story that is pretty scary and it sticks out into my mind, I guess, mostly, mainly because it was scary.
         Even though my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> told us lot of scary stories she was always there to hold us in her arms and let us know that the story was not true and that it was we were OK.
         Out of all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> I was the laziest one of all, as far as working around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.
         All of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> learned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> by the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>.
         I learned after I got married
         so I was a pretty lazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> when it came down to cleaning up and cooking.
         So <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> asked me to go inside and wash the dishes.
         Naturally, I start crying, and one of my main ways of getting out of work was always saying something hurt me, either my stomach, or that I had a headache, or something was wrong with my leg.
         Just anything to get out of doing my job.
         So after she noticed that I was going to be just a little stubborn and not follow, do what she tell told me to do, she asked me to come around in the living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with her and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         So she began to tell this story.
         Once upon a time there was this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
         And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> asked the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to please go in and wash the dishes so that she could go to bed early and not come up, wake up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and see all those dishes on the table.
         And her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> just complained, "I don't want to wash the dishes.
         I don't want to.
         My leg hurts, my head hurts.
         I don't feel good."
         The little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> disappointed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> so badly, but her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> said, "How in the world am I ever going to get her to wash these dishes<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
         So she said, "Little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, if you don't go in there and wash those dishes like I asked, you something really, really bad is going to happen to you."
         So the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> just said, "OK I'll go in there and wash the dishes."
         And she was in there stomping and crying and mad and taking all her good time.
         All of a sudden the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butcher</ENAMEX> knife came out of the drawer and it began to roll around in the air.
         And before you know it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butcher</ENAMEX> knife came around and cut the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s head off.
         And when the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> went to heaven she was crying down to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Daddy, Daddy</ENAMEX>!
         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mama</ENAMEX> cut my head off with the butcher <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>."
         Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>, when I went to sleep it really scared me.
         But the wonderful thing about it my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was always there close by to let me know that I was OK.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Now</TIMEX> after that, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> continued to tell us many, many scary stories and tell us many, many, many poems.
         I'd like to tell you about how I got into becoming a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX>.
         All my life I always wanted to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> even from the time I started to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         That was my dream, to teach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         As I told you, in the past we were a very poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and I never got the chance to go to college because of this.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, while I was in high school a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> of mine noticed that I had an extra bone in my foot and she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra</ENAMEX> we can use this as get toward, on your grant to go to college."
         So she said, "Go <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and talk to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> about it and see if we, you know, can follow through with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applying for a grant</ENAMEX>, scholarship grant for you."
         So <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> I went home and I asked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> about it and she said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby</ENAMEX>, I really want you to go to college.
         It's always been my dream that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         But because there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there are other things you're going to have to have to go to school and I just don't have the money."
         At that time my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> at the time, so it made it really hard for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>.
         I sat there and I cried but I tried to be as understanding as possible because I knew my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> struggled really hard to even keep <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> on the table for us.
         So I never got a chance to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         Did anybody?
      
      
         Yes, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         He went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livingstone</ENAMEX> and then to transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson C. Smith</ENAMEX>, so to make it easier on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, to, as far as, you know, him staying at home and going to school too.
         So he graduated from, um, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson C. Smith</ENAMEX>, here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>.
         I had another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaston College</ENAMEX> where she got a business degree there.
         I, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX>, I went on to college some but I didn't complete the, uh, whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I remember once, when I was working in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX>, and I was spinning yarn, and I was saying to myself, and, I was praying actually, and I said, "God, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> I want to work in the school system.
         If I could just work, even as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher assistant</ENAMEX> I would be happy."
         As the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> went by my prayer was answered and I got the chance to work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> as a cashier and the principal there came up to me and said, "Have you considered being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher assistant</ENAMEX>?"
         I said, "I would love to."
         So they told me about some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> that I could take at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Piedmont</ENAMEX>.
         I'd never gone to college before.
         I was really afraid.
         But he told me to go ahead and try it, so I took the entrance test, and they accepted me into at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and I took some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> there.
         After a while, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> said, "I would like for you to bring me your, um, transcript so I can see what your grades are like."
         Luckily I had all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX>.
         I did very well.
         And he asked me to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> assistant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next following year</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, my dream, my prayers were answered.
         I enjoy my job very much.
         I can't think of any job that would make me any happier.
         <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years later</TIMEX>, um, I had the opportunity to apply for a scholarship to further my education.
         At first I didn't want to apply for it, but the principal called me during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer months</TIMEX> and said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra the time</ENAMEX> is running out, you need to apply."
         And he told me I would have to write this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>.
         Well I didn't like writing at the time
         but I took it upon myself to go ahead and write a paper.
         And I went to, um, one of my staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and I asked her if she would proofread it, and she thought it was an excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>.
         And I went ahead and mailed it in thinking uh I won't get the scholarship.
         Who cares?
         I don't, just so I can work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> I'll be happy.
         But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> I came in and I looked at my mail and I was accepted.
         
         I couldn't believe it.
         Out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> who had applied for this grant <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 16</NUMEX> got the opportunity, so I felt very proud of myself.
         So I went on and took the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, and as I started I think I was taking economics.
         I think that was the last class I took.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> became very ill with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and I had to make a decision as to whether I would continue my education or take care of him and I felt like I needed to take care of him because he stood by me so much while I was going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      
      
         But you would have been able to be a, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> if you had continued?
      
      
         Yeah, and at the time, I was also working in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>.
         I guess you'd say as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that I was working with at that time was pregnant and she had to take a leave of absence.
         And they hired a sub but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub</ENAMEX> didn't do that much.
         I had to take over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>.
         So I worked maybe like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> and that highly put a damper on my wanting
         to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> from all the responsibility along with the fact that I was taking care of a very sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
         After all of this was, after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>, I decided not to continue I've never pursued the fact of going back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
         I just got to a certain age and I said, "No I can't do this anymore," so I never went back.
         But I love what I do and, uh, anytime I get a chance to teach in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> I go for it so.
      
      
         How many different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> did you teach at?
      
      
         I've only worked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
         The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> I worked at was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Enderly Park</ENAMEX> and then it was closed down.
         So I was in those situations where I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, come first, transfer last, come first to transfer out.
         So I had to, I was offered a job at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ashley Park</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berryhill</ENAMEX> and I chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berryhill</ENAMEX>.
         I didn't particularly want to come here and when I came here everybody noticed that I was really, really sad because I loved being at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Enderly Park</ENAMEX>.
         But then, after awhile, I fell in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berryhill</ENAMEX>.
         If I'm not mistaken I think I've been at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berryhill</ENAMEX> for I think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 18 years</TIMEX> I've been here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berryhill</ENAMEX> so and I hope I never have to leave until I retire.
         
      
      
         And why did the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> close down?
      
      
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um, the</ENAMEX>, you know, I really don't know.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, that, I really don't know why they closed that school down because it was a really nice school and everything, but they eventually tore it down because I was there I think the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year I went there was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> they built a really nice gym, and I don't think they used that gym no more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>.
         I really don't, I don't remember why that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was ever closed but it was.
         And I enjoy what I do.
         That's it.
      
      
         All right thank you.
      
      
         Thank you.
      
   
