
   
   
      
         My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Rindner</ENAMEX> and I was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TX</ENAMEX>, and the story I'm going to tell is about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, a little background <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.
         Her, let's see, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time.
         They owned car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealerships</ENAMEX> and extensive land.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I don't know if they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> or not, but I know they were land <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, um, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">many acres</NUMEX> and, um, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was raised in wealth.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> came and apparently everyone lost all their money.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, she was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">MO</ENAMEX>, and she married a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, this is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> I'm talking about.
         And they were very poor by this point, and they had, I think, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
         And one particular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, things were very, very difficult.
         There was no money to buy any presents at all, um, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, who was killed when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>, this was, of course, way before that, um, he must have been a very positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> because what he did with the situation was he, he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that there were no presents this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> because they had given them all to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX> to take the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and this made the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> feel happy and proud of themselves and it gave them a good feeling that they had done something very nice for someone less fortunate than themselves.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I felt like that was a way to face that situation with such hope and with joy and with love.
         And although I never met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>, I have never forgotten that story and when I hear of him I think what a wonderful, wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> he must have been.
      
      
         And how long have you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>?
      
      
         Oh, I have lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, um, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, I lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>.
         We came here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, we lived here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, then we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and now we've been back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>.
      
      
         Well, good.
      
   
