
   
   
      
         OK.
         Are you ready?
      
      
         Ready.
      
      
         All right.
         This is the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> is, uh, or was, way back when, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, as she grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that was put together by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Englishmen</ENAMEX>, um, they were all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>, and each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> had a name, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> or something to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, there was some land, that would have been so many <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">acres</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>, um, had fond memories for my mother
         .
         But the story I want to tell happens more, um, as I was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, so it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years later</TIMEX>.
         I was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, we were at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, which was a different farm at that time, but it's still in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, uh, area.
         And my aunts were all visiting; my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> were there also.
         And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the aunts, or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, said, "Let's go see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>."
         Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> had been, they moved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> from there, uh, so we all piled into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>.
         As we drove up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>, you could tell it was left to the elements.
         There was grass, waving in the breeze and it was rather sad, no paint on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, but you could see it had been a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time.
         We went up the back porch uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> was open, anyone could've fallen into the well, it was in the back porch, or the side porch.
         Went in, and, uh, it always, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had always talked about the staircase and how beautiful it was, and indeed it probably had been.
         As we walked up the stairs, the window was broken and the shade was flapping in the breeze, and the wallpaper was wet from the rain, and the elements had been coming in for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>; as we walked through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, and I have fond memories of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, I was probably in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade, I would imagine.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, we went outdoors then, went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>, and there was a dead calf in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>.
         Now, whether that calf had just wandered in, or whatever I don't know.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, we ourselves lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, so we went home, uh, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpa</ENAMEX>'s farm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Uh,</ENAMEX>
         and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> sat down, probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that first week</TIMEX>, and she wrote a poem and, uh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poem</ENAMEX> tells a lot.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s name was, uh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Berry McGovern</ENAMEX>.
         
         The poem is titled, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Place of my Childhood Dreams":Nearer and nearer my footsteps</ENAMEX> led me Back to the place of my childhood dreams.
         Cautiously, I opened the door; I remembered no key had been turned in the lock.
         Slowly, I entered each battered room And saw the cracked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plaster</ENAMEX>, the discolored walls.
         Lastly, I ascended the old, open stairway, Once the pride of my joyful, young life.
         At the landing, I gazed out the window, And there was the woods in the distance--- The woods where we had gathered wildflowers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX>.
         And then I remembered our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s voice calling from somewhere, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Children</ENAMEX>, be sure to put them in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>---'tis cruel to pluck them, and then let them wither and die."
         Slowly as I had entered, I walked, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of my childhood dreams
         .
         As if from some sacred tomb I'd walked down and out and into the bright sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> air.
         The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, I could hear them singing.
         How I had loved any one of those songs.
         Our favorite rosebush was gone, I saw, And wondered if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> had loved it as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX> From the distance, the town hall clock was striking, the school bell was ringing, I could hear, from the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> away.
         Then suddenly, the thought came.
         The sights and the sounds of the world could go on forever, But the place of my childhood dreams could never again feel the same inside.
      
      
         It's beautiful.
      
      
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, um, had a wonderful life, really.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX>, they moved into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> as a brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>.
         It burned within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first month</TIMEX> that they were there.
         It was then rebuilt, and they moved in.
         And I believe, after a time, they really couldn't afford to live there any more.
         So, they moved to another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>, and lo and behold, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> also caught on fire.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, as I grew up, we lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> until I was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade.
         And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> then purchased an old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX>, and remodeled this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farmhouse</ENAMEX>, it took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">al</ENAMEX>, took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a year</TIMEX> to remodel.
         It wa, it was a wonderful uh, farm, it had wonderful gardens, as you might tell, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX>.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when they were still remodeling the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christmastime</ENAMEX>, and we still lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, the phone rang uh, whether it did or it didn't, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> said it did.
         And we went, uh, he said that we had to go out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> because, uh, someone had left the light on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>.
         So we piled into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX>, and it was snowing, so beautiful.
         Typical, as I remember, dream <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas Eve</TIMEX>.
         And we went out, and we drove up the driveway, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daddy</ENAMEX> went down to the bottom, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>, and as we opened the door, a horse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">whinnied</ENAMEX>.
         And it was our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> that we had, it was, uh, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas present</TIMEX>.
         And I still can picture that with the, uh, the light, the outdoor light of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> and the snow coming down, it was really, beautiful.
         But, uh, we lived there, we moved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> of `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">48</ENAMEX>, and uh, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 10 of 1959</TIMEX>, I got a call and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was on fire.
         It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, and of course, there wasn't any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and, uh, they just had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in the tank <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was gutted out, as a result of that.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> at the time, and he died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month later</TIMEX>.
         So my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> then left our home, and, uh, didn't have a home to go to, and built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, then, uh, was happy there, although she was lonely, I'm sure.
         And, uh, created another garden, but was never the same thing.
         There was a piano that was always in each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.
         My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> still has that piano and, uh, still has the best tune of any piano I've ever heard.
         Sorry for my crackly voice.
         It's been difficult, but I loved her
         .
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Um</ENAMEX>, when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> passed away, she passed away in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and, uh, after her funeral, we went out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>.
         By then it, someone else had built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on the same spot; what had been a dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> was then a four-lane <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>.
         We pulled into the driveway, and someone was living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, of course, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX> was still there.
         I mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that they had built on this property.
         Where there had been a formal garden to the left of the driveway was then, a woods, as time had taken its toll.
         And, um, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were very happy to see us.
         And it was a very healing experience; we walked the property somewhat.
         We walked down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">creek</ENAMEX> and the watercress was still growing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">creek</ENAMEX> as it had as I grew up.
         <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, it was interesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was sensitive as we are, and he said that they would go to certain corners of the fields on the property that was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">sixty-seven acres</NUMEX> and, you could still feel Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX>'s presence.
         And, uh, I liked that
         because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was a very sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, although he came across as he was being very gruff, he was not
         .
         OK.
      
   
